<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #919 - Atlanta - BI Edition 2019</name>
    <startDate>10/19/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatATLBI</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft</name>
      <street>8000 Avalon Boulevard, Suite 900</street>
      <city>Alpharetta</city>
      <state>Georgia</state>
      <zipcode>30009</zipcode>
      <longitude>-84.2741601</longitude>
      <latitude>34.0704325</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/919/EventSponsor_14093.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2351</importID>
      <name>Insight Digital Innovation</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.insight.com/en_US/solve/digital-innovation.html</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/919/EventSponsor_14010.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2457</importID>
      <name>Google</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.google.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/919/EventSponsor_14158.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1911</importID>
      <name>Data Advantage Group, Inc.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dag.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/919/EventSponsor_14041.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>89</importID>
      <name>Profisee</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.profisee.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/919/EventSponsor_14186.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2354</importID>
      <name>Improving-Atlanta</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://improving.com/location/atlanta</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/919/EventSponsor_13975.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/919/EventSponsor_13950.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96831</importID>
      <name>Shabnam Watson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Shabnam Watson is a Business Intelligence architect with 20 years of experience developing data warehouse and business intelligence solutions. Her work focus within the Microsoft BI Stack has been on Analysis Services and Power BI.

She is an active member of PASS community and has spoken at PASS Summit, SQL Saturdays, PASS Business Analytics and Women in Technology virtual chapters, and many other local user groups and conferences. She is one of the organizers of SQL Saturday Atlanta BI Edition.

She holds a master's degree in computer science, a bachelor’s degree in Computer Engineering, and a Certified Business Intelligence Professional (CBIP) certification by The Data Warehouse Institute (TDWI).</description>
      <twitter>ShbWatson</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/shabnamwatson</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://shabnamwatson.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ShbWatson</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98006</importID>
      <name>Reza Rad</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reza Rad is a Microsoft Regional Director, MVP, author, trainer, speaker and consultant. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for nine years from 2011.
Reza wrote many books on Power BI subjects including the Power BI from Rookie to Rock Star, and Pro Power BI Architecture.
Reza is the invited speaker at the world's well-known conferences such as Microsoft Ignite, Microsoft Business Applications Summit, Ignite Tour, PASS Summit, and many other conferences.
Reza is an active blogger and writes regularly about Power BI at https://radacad.com.</description>
      <twitter>Rad_Reza</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/in/rezarad/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://radacad.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rad_Reza</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96580</importID>
      <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Over 30 years in the computing field as a developer and system integrator; over 20 years working with SQL Server since version 6; cross platform experience with Oracle and IBM SQL/DS and DB2; Microsoft Certified Trainer for over 20 years.</description>
      <twitter>arlacerda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armando-lacerda</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arlacerda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96852</importID>
      <name>James McAuliffe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>James McAuliffe is a Cloud Solution Architect with CCG Analytics, a Microsoft Gold Partner.  He is also a Microsoft Preferred Partner Solutions expert and has been worked with clients of all sizes, from local businesses to Fortune 500 companies.  Today’s mix of Big Data and cloud offerings make yesterday’s dream today’s possibility.  Let’s talk about it!</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=11710667amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98007</importID>
      <name>Reza Rad</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reza Rad is a Microsoft Regional Director, MVP, author, trainer, speaker and consultant. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for nine years from 2011.
Reza wrote many books on Power BI subjects including the Power BI from Rookie to Rock Star, and Pro Power BI Architecture.
Reza is the invited speaker at the world's well-known conferences such as Microsoft Ignite, Microsoft Business Applications Summit, Ignite Tour, PASS Summit, and many other conferences.
Reza is an active blogger and writes regularly about Power BI at https://radacad.com.</description>
      <twitter>Rad_Reza</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/in/rezarad/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://radacad.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rad_Reza</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96313</importID>
      <name>Russel Loski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Russ Loski is a SQL Server BI Developer based in Dallas-Fort Worth.  He current works as a Data Analytics Engineer for Navisite, a remote managed IT services company.   Twenty years ago, he began working with SQL Server 6.5. He has since continued to develop applications connected to all of the versions of SQL Server. He has worked with clients in industries from insurance to healthcare, from movie theaters to American football.  Russ is a regular speaker at SQLSaturday events, as well as the SQL Server Users Groups in the North Texas region. Russ likes working with data in various shapes.</description>
      <twitter>sqlmovers</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/russloski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmovers.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmovers</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96584</importID>
      <name>Hilary Wilkie</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hilary Wilkie has worked with prominent companies like Home Depot and small solo entrepreneurs. She is a Business Analyst with a Six Sigma Black Belt and currently working at AutoVIN, a division of KAR Auction Services. Hilary has worked with professionals at all levels of business including C-level, managers, and even the warehouse person! She believes behind all good processes and software are great people; often we get so passionate about the technology we forget about the people.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/hilary-wilkie-a795209/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>97967</importID>
      <name>Lucas Feiock</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lucas Feiock is a Senior Business Intelligence Consultant with KiZAN Technologies. He has four years of experience with the Microsoft BI Stack. In addition to data warehousing, data integration and data visualization, Lucas is also involved with machine learning and advanced analytics. He has experience working in multiple industries including manufacturing, sales, gas and electric utilities, and health care.</description>
      <twitter>@LucasFeiock</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucas-feiock</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sql-stack.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@LucasFeiock</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98225</importID>
      <name>Patrick LeBlanc</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick LeBlanc is a currently a Principal Program Manager at Microsoft and a contributing partner to Guy in a Cube. Along with his 15+ years’ experience in IT he holds a Masters of Science degree from Louisiana State University. He is the author and co-author of five SQL Server books. Prior to joining Microsoft he was awarded Microsoft MVP award for his contributions to the community.  Patrick is a regular speaker at many SQL Server Conferences and Community events.</description>
      <twitter>patrickdba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrickdleblanc</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://patrickdleblanc.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=patrickdba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95612</importID>
      <name>Brad Llewellyn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brad Llewellyn is a Service Engineer on Microsoft's FastTrack for Azure Team in Charlotte, NC. Brad helps individuals and organizations leverage Analytics and Azure to revolutionize themselves and their industries. He has an M.S. in Statistics from the University of South Carolina, MCSE Certification in Data Management and Analytics, MCSE Certification in Cloud Platform and Infrastructure, and various MCSA Certifications in Business Intelligence and Advanced Analytics. Brad is an active blogger at breaking-bi.blogspot.com. He is also an organizer for the Charlotte BI Group, a local PASS chapter in Charlotte, NC. You can connect with him on LinkedIn at https://www.linkedin.com/in/bradllewellyn and on Twitter @BreakingBI.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BreakingBI</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bradllewellyn/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://breaking-bi.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BreakingBI</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98224</importID>
      <name>Patrick LeBlanc</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick LeBlanc is a currently a Principal Program Manager at Microsoft and a contributing partner to Guy in a Cube. Along with his 15+ years’ experience in IT he holds a Masters of Science degree from Louisiana State University. He is the author and co-author of five SQL Server books. Prior to joining Microsoft he was awarded Microsoft MVP award for his contributions to the community.  Patrick is a regular speaker at many SQL Server Conferences and Community events.</description>
      <twitter>patrickdba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrickdleblanc</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://patrickdleblanc.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=patrickdba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95601</importID>
      <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>José Manuel Jurado currently works as SQL Escalation Engineer and Subject Matter Expert in Azure SQL Database at Microsoft Spain. With over 20+ years of experience in SQL Server environments (administration and database development), he is a speaker for internal events at Microsoft and for public events such as SQLSaturday, SQL Nexus, SQLBits, Pass Summit, SQL Server Konferenze, TechReady, DotNetConference, and Azure BootCamp. In the past, he worked as Project Manager for large global retail company for more than 10 years developing projects using different Microsoft Technologies.</description>
      <twitter>jmjuradodiaz</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-manuel-jurado-diaz-5a586014/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jmjuradodiaz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98010</importID>
      <name>Leila Etaati</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leila Etaati is the First Microsoft AI MVP in New Zealand and Australia, as well as a Data Platform MVP. She has a Ph.D. from the University of Auckland and is the co-director and data scientist in RADACAD company with many clients around the world. Additionally, she is the co-organizer of Microsoft Business Intelligence and Power BI Use group in Auckland with more than 1300 members. Leila has also co-organized 3 main conferences in Auckland: SQL Saturday Auckland (from 2015), Difinity (from 2017) and Global AI Bootcamp. She is a data scientist, BI consultant, trainer, and speaker. She is a well-known International speaker to many conferences such as MS Ignite, SQL PASS, Data Platform Summit, SQL Saturday, Power BI World Tour and in Europe, USA, Asia, Australia, and NZ. She has over 10 years’ experience with databases and software systems. Leila is an active Technical Microsoft AI blogger in RADACAD.</description>
      <twitter>@leila_etaati</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/pub/leila-etaati/36/46/b03</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.radacad.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@leila_etaati</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95764</importID>
      <name>Andy Leonard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andy Leonard is founder and Chief Data Engineer at Enterprise Data  Analytics, Microsoft Data Platform MVP, creator of the DILM (Data Integration Lifecycle Management) Suite, an SSIS trainer, consultant, developer, Business Intelligence Markup Language (Biml) developer and BimlHero, SQL Server database and data warehouse developer, community mentor, engineer, and farmer. He is a co-author of "The Biml Book and SQL Server Integration Services Design Patterns" and author of "Managing Geeks - A Journey of Leading by Doing", "Data Integration Lifecycle Management with SSIS", "Building Custom Tasks for SSIS", and the "Stairway to Integration Services". Andy blogs at andyleonard.blog where you can learn more on the About Andy page.</description>
      <twitter>AndyLeonard</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/AndyLeonard</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://andyleonard.blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyLeonard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99225</importID>
      <name>Paco Gonzalez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paco Gonzalez is the CEO of SolidQ North America, and a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Focused on Business Analytics and Artificial Intelligence, he specializes in helping organizations become data driven  from a strategic and technical perspective. Paco is a speaker at small and large conferences such as PASS Summit, Ignite, and Business Applications Summit, and he has published several books and whitepapers. He is based in Atlanta, GA.</description>
      <twitter>@pacosql</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pacosql/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@pacosql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98045</importID>
      <name>Daniel McConnell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Daniel is an IT professional with over 10 years of experience developing and implementing custom software and business intelligence solutions for clients in Government, Energy Distribution, Print and Digital Marketing, and eCommerce sectors.  Daniel has led teams of more than 15 ASP.Net developers, business intelligence developers and business analysts through a variety of different projects from data driven enterprise application integrations to in-house CRM and work force management applications, ensuring high quality delivery every step of the way.  Most recently, Daniel has focused on designing and building high performing and scale-able, cloud-based solutions.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95595</importID>
      <name>Bill Anton</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bill Anton is an expert in Analysis Services and an experienced data warehouse practitioner. In 2013, he founded Opifex Solutions, a consulting firm with deep expertise in enterprise-scale architecture, design, and performance optimization of Analysis Services and Power BI solutions. He loves eating and spends most of his free time convincing his beloved wife to adopt more golden retrievers.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLbyoBI</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/bill-anton/12/526/4bb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://byobi.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLbyoBI</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96795</importID>
      <name>Warren Sifre</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warren Sifre has been in the IT community since 1998 and has worked in a variety of industries deploying solutions utilizing MS SQL Server in one capacity or another. In 2003, he decided to make SQL Server his mastery and has since developed skills in most defined disciplines of MS SQL.  Currently he is a Principal Consultant and Technology Leader with Moser Consulting.  He is responsible for BI Solution Architecture and the mentorship of team members.  He has been a SQL Saturday Speaker since 2012, Azure Global Bootcamp, and many user groups in 2015 alone.  He has a passion for knowledge transfer and solutions architecture, with a keen interested in Info Security.</description>
      <twitter>WAS_SQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/wsifre</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.broadstrokeconsulting.com/blog/, http://www.allegient.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=WAS_SQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98081</importID>
      <name>Preston Mesarvey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a Senior Data Services Consultant with Improving based in Atlanta GA. I work primarily with Microsoft SQL Server and the accompanying Business Intelligence tools. In the last 15 years I have worked with data in the financial, medical, real estate, insurance, government, media, and industrial industries. My data interests include design, integration, and visualization. My hobbies outside the world of data include reading, trivia, baseball, music, beach road trips, and spending time with the family.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/prestonm</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/prestonm/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.engageddata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/prestonm</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96378</importID>
      <name>Samara Soucy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Samara holds a Bachelor of Arts degree in Mathematics from the University of Wisconsin - Whitewater. Since her college days, she's developed a passion for software development and specializes in C#, JavaScript, and SQL. She makes use of her ability to learn quickly and think creatively to find solutions that fit her client's needs. Samara has experience working on both small and large-scale development projects and takes great pride in working side by side with clients to ensure that the final product is a success. Samara currently resides in Buckhead.​</description>
      <twitter>@OneAngryPenguin</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@OneAngryPenguin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98014</importID>
      <name>Ganesh Lohani</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ganesh Lohani has 10 years of experience working with Business Intelligence platform and Data Analytics, with over 8 years of experience with MS BI tools and Business Intelligence processes. He is currently working for Stericycle as a senior Business Intelligence Developer. He also enjoy his evening and weekend time in providing online training, coaching and mentoring individuals who want to learn MSBI (T – SQL,  SSIS, SSRS, SSAS, and Power BI ) products. He holds MSIS degree from University of Texas at Arlington.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ganesh-lohani-6275a716</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98524</importID>
      <name>Daniel Glenn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Daniel is a Microsoft MVP with 15 years' experience building technology solutions, intranets and extranets. As Practice Leader for the Nashville-based InfoWorks Inc., Daniel helps organizations of all sizes solve complex data challenges by implementing Office 365 and SharePoint without the need of customization and costly investments.

Daniel is passionate about giving back and building the Microsoft technical community. Daniel holds leadership roles in various local user groups, serves as an organizer for Microsoft 365 Nashville, and is a co-host for the popular podcast 365 Message Center Show on https://MessageCenter.Show. You can follow Daniel online at https://DanielGlenn.com and @DanielGlenn on Twitter.</description>
      <twitter>DanielGlenn</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielglenn</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://DanielGlenn.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DanielGlenn</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96118</importID>
      <name>Cornell Emile</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>For nearly two decades, Cornell A. Emile has designed, developed, and maintained data-centric solutions within multiple industries such as Finance, Digital Marketing, Non-Profit, Retail, Manufacturing State and Federal Government using Microsoft#39;s business and data products. His main interests include architecting data solutions, Business Intelligence and NoSQL databases.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/CornellEmile</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/CornellEmile</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98606</importID>
      <name>Javier Guillen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Javier Guillen is a Solutions Architect for BlueGranite. 

An active blogger, speaker, and Microsoft community contributor, Javier has more than 10 years developing SQL Server solutions and is very interested in SQL Server Analysis Services  and the practical application of MDX and DAX patterns.

Javier is also a Power BI Workshop instructor, delivering classes in private and public settings, an adjunct BI instructor for Central Piedmont Community College in Charlotte, NC and an adjunct lecturer for the City University of New York (CUNY) School of Professional Studies undergraduate and bridge graduate courses in Business Analytics.   He is also the co-founder and co-organizer of the Charlotte Business Intelligence User Group (CBIG).</description>
      <twitter>@javiguillen</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/javierguillen/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://javierguillen.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@javiguillen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98826</importID>
      <name>Tyler Graham</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With over 20 years experience in Data Management
6 Years at Microsoft
One of the Original Designers of SQL Server Master Data Services
Author - Master Data Services -SQL Server 2008R2 and 2012
6 Years at Profisee developing Industry Solutions</description>
      <twitter>@codeswim</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-d-graham-095b946</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@codeswim</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96245</importID>
      <name>Ryan Wade</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ryan is an experienced data analytics professional. His education and work experience enables him to understand things from a technical, analytical, and business viewpoint. He has the ability to present complex data in an intuitive way using sound analytical and visualization methods.

He has an advanced analytical and technical skill-set which includes Power BI, T-SQL, R, Python, Azure Machine Learning Services, Azure Databricks, SQL Server Machine Learning Services, Advanced Modern Excel, SSIS,  SSAS Tabular.

He is a data analytics enthusiast that has spoken at a variety of database and data science conferences about various topics dealing with data analytics.</description>
      <twitter>MrDataGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanwade44</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MrDataGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95597</importID>
      <name>Jared Rhodes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>As a Microsoft MVP for Azure and Pluralsight Author, I focus on IoT, Mobile, and Cloud; trying to find the subsection of those and make them work together. Lately, I have working with AI and Edge computing as the they evolve together. I enjoy public speaking, walks on the beach, and no linker errors.</description>
      <twitter>qimata</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/qimata/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://jaredrhodes.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=qimata</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99067</importID>
      <name>Geoffrey Rayner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Geoff Rayner is the CEO of Data Advantage Group.   He has been involved in the design and implementation of metadata management and data governance solutions for 17 years.   Geoff has a BS in Engineering from Brown University.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98276</importID>
      <name>Jason Russell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jason is a Principal Consultant at Improving-Atlanta, where he has worked for the past 4 years. He focuses on Client Relationships and Power BI reports. He graduated from the University of Georgia many years ago. He is happily married with 2 mostly great kids. A self-proclaimed "nerd", he loves Star Wars, Lord of the Rings and most Science Fiction/Fantasy novels.</description>
      <twitter>jruss_17</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jrussell17</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jruss_17</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96128</importID>
      <name>Lance England</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lance England is a data professional focused on data, analysis, integration, and automation using SQL Server, Power BI, DAX, SQL Server Analysis Server, BizTalk, PowerShell, C#, and more. He has industry experience in health care, manufacturing, property rental, and non-profit sectors.</description>
      <twitter>lanceengland</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lanceengland</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://lance-england.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=lanceengland</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96582</importID>
      <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Over 30 years in the computing field as a developer and system integrator; over 20 years working with SQL Server since version 6; cross platform experience with Oracle and IBM SQL/DS and DB2; Microsoft Certified Trainer for over 20 years.</description>
      <twitter>arlacerda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armando-lacerda</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arlacerda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>97965</importID>
      <name>Lucas Feiock</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lucas Feiock is a Senior Business Intelligence Consultant with KiZAN Technologies. He has four years of experience with the Microsoft BI Stack. In addition to data warehousing, data integration and data visualization, Lucas is also involved with machine learning and advanced analytics. He has experience working in multiple industries including manufacturing, sales, gas and electric utilities, and health care.</description>
      <twitter>@LucasFeiock</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucas-feiock</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sql-stack.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@LucasFeiock</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98009</importID>
      <name>Leila Etaati</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leila Etaati is the First Microsoft AI MVP in New Zealand and Australia, as well as a Data Platform MVP. She has a Ph.D. from the University of Auckland and is the co-director and data scientist in RADACAD company with many clients around the world. Additionally, she is the co-organizer of Microsoft Business Intelligence and Power BI Use group in Auckland with more than 1300 members. Leila has also co-organized 3 main conferences in Auckland: SQL Saturday Auckland (from 2015), Difinity (from 2017) and Global AI Bootcamp. She is a data scientist, BI consultant, trainer, and speaker. She is a well-known International speaker to many conferences such as MS Ignite, SQL PASS, Data Platform Summit, SQL Saturday, Power BI World Tour and in Europe, USA, Asia, Australia, and NZ. She has over 10 years’ experience with databases and software systems. Leila is an active Technical Microsoft AI blogger in RADACAD.</description>
      <twitter>@leila_etaati</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/pub/leila-etaati/36/46/b03</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.radacad.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@leila_etaati</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96397</importID>
      <name>Chad Buher</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chad Buher is the lead Business Intelligence Architect for 1-Answer Corp, a consulting organization that provides BI guidance, support and a suite of software tools that reduces BI development time by 75%.  In roles such as Data Architect Consultant for Pragmatic Works, BI Developer for Dignity Health, Sr. Information Architect for Adventist Health System, and other BI roles over the last 18 years, Chad has seen a wide range of solutions and always seeks to listen and learn from everyone around him. Chad lives with his wife just outside of Orlando, FL where his once neat and quiet home has turned into an exhilarating daily adventure parenting three amazing kids adopted from foster care.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/chadbuher/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98044</importID>
      <name>Paul Waters</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul has over 20 years of experience working in IT-related fields. Over the past 15 years, he has focused on Business Intelligence. Paul was the Technical Editor for the book quot;Microsoft SQL Server 2008 Integration Services Problem-Design-Solutionquot; and contributed to the Wrox book quot;Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services Recipes: for Designing Expert Reports.quot;</description>
      <twitter>@pswaters</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pswaters</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@pswaters</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98542</importID>
      <name>Teo Lachev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Teo Lachev is an internationally-recognized authority on Data Analytics. Through his Atlanta-based company Prologika, a Microsoft Gold Partner in Data Analytics, he helps organizations make sense of their most valuable asset: their data. His strategy formulation, trusted advisory and mentoring, design and implementation services empower clients to apply effectively data analytics in order to understand, improve, and transform their business processes.

Teo has authored and co-authored several bestselling books on organizational and self-service data analytics, and he has been leading the Atlanta Microsoft BI and Power BI group since he founded it in 2010. Teo has been a Microsoft Most Valued Professional (MVP) Data Platform since 2010.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/tlachev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/tlachev</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://prologika.com/cs/blogs</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/tlachev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95615</importID>
      <name>Brad Llewellyn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brad Llewellyn is a Service Engineer on Microsoft's FastTrack for Azure Team in Charlotte, NC. Brad helps individuals and organizations leverage Analytics and Azure to revolutionize themselves and their industries. He has an M.S. in Statistics from the University of South Carolina, MCSE Certification in Data Management and Analytics, MCSE Certification in Cloud Platform and Infrastructure, and various MCSA Certifications in Business Intelligence and Advanced Analytics. Brad is an active blogger at breaking-bi.blogspot.com. He is also an organizer for the Charlotte BI Group, a local PASS chapter in Charlotte, NC. You can connect with him on LinkedIn at https://www.linkedin.com/in/bradllewellyn and on Twitter @BreakingBI.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BreakingBI</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bradllewellyn/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://breaking-bi.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BreakingBI</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96042</importID>
      <name>Ed Watson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ed Watson is a Principal Data Platform Consultant for Improving Enterprises, a full-stack Microsoft consulting firm in Atlanta.  Ed is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP since 2014 and like most children, Ed was born at an early age. Today, Ed specializes in the Business Intelligence stack and enjoys specializing in Power BI immensely.  He currently lives in Atlanta and is active with the Atlanta MDF and Atlanta BI user groups and is an organizer for SQL Saturday Atlanta, Atlanta BI, and Pensacola.</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/SQLGator</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/watsoned</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlgator.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/SQLGator</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98278</importID>
      <name>Jay Rajendran</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Focused on solving customer challenges through innovative technology solutions on Google Cloud Platform.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95884</importID>
      <name>Julie Smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Smith is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a BI consultant for Innovative Architects in Atlanta, GA. She#39;s implemented increasingly complex Business Intelligence solutions for over a decade at various organizations. She#39;s also worn many other database “hats” in her career – production DBA and database developer--but data integration and BI are her true passions. Julie holds a BA from the University of South Carolina. She and Audrey Hammonds co-created The Datachix.com blog.</description>
      <twitter>@juliechix</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliesmith0503/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datachix.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@juliechix</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96135</importID>
      <name>Belinda Allen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Belinda Allen is a (Power BI) Data Platform Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP).
Belinda has just completed her second book, Building Dashboards with Microsoft Dynamics GP 2016 -  Second Edition.
Belinda is also an inaugural member of the Board of Advisors for PBIUG (Power BI User Group.)  
Belinda is also well known for her blog, www.BelindaTheGPcsi.com. On her blog, she shares really useful information about the product quickly and succinctly. With followers from all over the globe, she can share knowledge and achieve her mission: “To improve the lives and business success of my followers.”</description>
      <twitter>MsBelindaAllen</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/msbelindaallen/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.BIBelinda.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MsBelindaAllen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>95595</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95595</id>
          <name>Bill Anton</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Grant Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>Level Up: Data Modeling for the Power BI Rockstar</title>
      <description>In the world of Power BI, data modeling is what separates the Rockstars from the Rookies. Join me to learn how dimensional modeling - a concept developed 20+ years ago - continues to be the best approach for delivering self-service BI to the masses.

Not only will good data modeling result in better Power BI solutions that support a wider range of reporting requirements, but they will also be easier for the business users to understand and work with. 

In this session, you'll learn how to create flexible data models that can be expanded upon over time, unlock the power of the date table, and a variety of DAX patterns supporting common but complex business logic.
 
If your Power BI solutions typically contain a single table, if you're frequently banging your head against the wall trying to figure out how to write a DAX calculation, or if you've never heard the term "dimensional model" or "star-schema", this session is for you.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96313</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96313</id>
          <name>Russel Loski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Palisades</name>
      </location>
      <title>Managing ETL Change Using BIMLScript</title>
      <description>Change is constant, especially with source files. Health care claims data files change at least yearly. You develop an SSIS package to load the source file. You meticulously identify each of the columns and map them to the targets. Your package runs fine for months. Then the file format changes. Again, you tediously select each column, etc. Wouldn't it be nice to simply document the structure of the file, the file's metadata, and generate the SSIS from that metadata? Your users demand the documentation anyway. If the file changes, you simply change the metadata. 

To demonstrate such an approach, I import some US census data. I create the SSIS package using BIMLScript and metadata. When the format changes, I change the metadata and generate a whole new package. And if your whole ETL approach changes to say Azure Data Factory? I will demonstrate how to generate an Azure Data Factory pipeline from the same metadata.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96245</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96245</id>
          <name>Ryan Wade</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Piedmont Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>AI for the Masses: The Democratization of Artificial Intelligence in the Microsoft Ecosystem</title>
      <description>Data is the new gold and companies are producing it in massive amounts. Historically it has been tough for companies to mine the data because of the amount of technical resources and human capital it takes to mine it. Fortunately, Microsoft has added tools and services in its data platform that addresses this problem. 
 
In this session we will take a tour of the Microsoft ecosystem and explore some of these tools and services. We will explore:
 
-  How AI models are easily productionized in the cloud using Azure Machine Learning Services and Azure Databricks
-  How Microsoft brought data science to the database via SQL Server Machine Learning Services
-  How AI can be used to enhance Power BI data models

Come to this information packed session, and you will walk away with ideas of how you can help your company leverage the gold mine of data it is sitting on to gain a competitive advantage.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96852</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96852</id>
          <name>James McAuliffe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Big Creek</name>
      </location>
      <title>Changing Data Is Easy, Managing Data Change is Hard!</title>
      <description>Databases are growing.  The way we use data is changing and growing.  When you have a lot of change, it has to be managed, or bad things happen to your data and your job!  A common problem with database change management is... database change management.  This session walks the user through the concepts of database change management, why it's important, and how SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT) makes this process easy.  There are a lot of great features in this frequently overlooked product, and if you are not using it, your job is a lot harder than it needs to be.  Some things we will discuss: schema compare, database versions in source control, renaming objects, and how your job is pushing the button to deliver it the EASY way with SSDT.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98044</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98044</id>
          <name>Paul Waters</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Big Creek</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT) = Awesome</title>
      <description>Visual Studio SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT) is awesome! Here are a few reasons why.

- Create and organize database objects more easily with the Database project template.
- Write SQL code faster with IntelliSense.
- Checks for errors in real-time to identify mistakes quickly. 
- Makes refactoring database objects seem like magic.
- Includes powerful tools for comparing database schemas and data.
- Integrates with source control systems including GIT.
- Helps make team development easier and safer.
- Enables continuous integration and deployment for modern end-to-end application lifecycle (ALM) practices.

Best of all… It’s free! Also, it works with all versions of Visual Studio – including the free community edition.
In this presentation, I will show you how to get started with SSDT, get some quick wins, and touch on some of the advanced features. By the end of the presentation, I hope to make you as excited about SSDT as I am.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98007</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98007</id>
          <name>Reza Rad</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Piedmont Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>Unleash Row Level Security Patterns in Power BI</title>
      <description>Security is different from Sharing; Sharing is about sharing the entire content with others, security is about authorizing different views of the content to others. In this session we go through many different Row Level Security patterns; Static Row Level Security, Dynamic Row Level Security, and many variations of the dynamic RLS, such as giving manager access as well as employee access, you will learn about user profile security scenarios, and hierarchical access levels. This session shows you how DAX and Power BI security comes together to play an important part in a Power BI project lifecycle: Row Level Security.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98225</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98225</id>
          <name>Patrick LeBlanc</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Grant Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Modeling and DAX Tips for Power BI</title>
      <description>One of the biggest problems I come across lately is poor performing Power BI reports due to bad data model designs.  Since the data model is the foundation to all the reports, if you get it right the first time everything else tends fall inline.  Join this session to learn the key steps and best practices you need to take to ensure a good data model.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96378</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96378</id>
          <name>Samara Soucy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Bellwood Quarry</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Embedded for Fun and Profit</title>
      <description>You COULD hire a front end developer to build data visualizations for your app. You COULD use "Publish to Web" to expose your sensitive data to anyone who gets a hold of the link. You COULD even force your users to leave what they were working on and tab over to the Power BI service to look at the data relevant to their current task.

None of that is fun, and it certainly isn't the most efficient use of time or funds. Fortunately, Power BI embedded is coming to your rescue. You can use the visualizations you've already built, keep the security you've already put in place, and allow your users to view contextual data in your applications-- right where they need it. You'll learn how embedding works within the Power BI service and how to create a successful embedded deployment.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96135</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96135</id>
          <name>Belinda Allen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Centennial</name>
      </location>
      <title>DAX 101 and 102</title>
      <description>In this breakout session, you'll learn the basics of the DAX language, Power BI’s modeling language. Belinda will introduce you to the concept of calculated columns, measures, and basic data modeling, with some practical examples. This introduction will cover basic calculations and an overview of scalar and table functions. This session has practical examples of business analytics and users.  To the Developer, DAX feels like a programming language; to the user, DAX feels like Excel formulas.  
1.	Define DAX and understand where it fits and why it is important
2.	Perform and Review some basic DAX commands
3.	Differentiate modeling with DAX versus the Power BI Query Editor
4.	Build a Date Table to allow for the use of Time Intelligence DAX calculations
5.	Overview of CALCULATE in DAX functions.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98006</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98006</id>
          <name>Reza Rad</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Grant Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>Architecture Blueprints for Power BI Implementation</title>
      <description>Implementing a Power BI solution is not just about the report development, dashboard design, and DAX queries. Designing the right architecture is an essential part of a Power BI implementation.

There are many areas to consider when you are designing a Power BI architecture. From sharing reports and security, to the type of connection and usage of other components such as dataflow.

Come to this session to learn about important things you need to know about the architecture of a Power BI solution. You will learn some blueprints of what are key things to consider and how to design the architecture for your solution.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98224</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98224</id>
          <name>Patrick LeBlanc</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Grant Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Performance in 6 Demos</title>
      <description>We will explore some practical and common performance problems that customers encounter when using Power BI. From report design to your data, we will cover different aspects of Power BI to get you thinking about how to use the service within your organization.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96397</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96397</id>
          <name>Chad Buher</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Bellwood Quarry</name>
      </location>
      <title>Replace Hundreds of Fragmented SSRS Reports with Integrated Dashboards in Weeks</title>
      <description>Has your organization accumulated a ton of reports that are crucial, yet fragmented and difficult to maintain? This session deals with the challenge of documenting those disconnected reports and replacing them with integrated dashboards. We will also discuss the trade offs of different data integration architecture options such as data lakes, dimensional models, real time solutions like data virtualization, and cloud based solutions. 

In this session, we will explore:
- Different industry solutions to document your existing SSRS reports and SSAS cubes to identify all the columns used in source tables/objects.
- Interrogating the database objects (views, stored  procedures, etc.) to decipher the ETL mappings and transformations and present this in a human readable format of data lineage with business rules applied to the source system.
- Grouping these reports into sets to be consolidated in a few dashboard
- Different solutions to accommodate the desired data integration architecture</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96582</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96582</id>
          <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Palisades</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Dataset Tuning</title>
      <description>Most Power BI reports rely on a small dataset. And due to a lighting fast data engine most data model mistakes are shadowed by the speed of the service. When the dataset gets bigger then best data modeling practices are required. The trick here is Power BI data engine is not relational and therefore most data modeling techniques either don’t apply or don’t deliver. In this session we will go over how to model and measure performance for larger Power BI datasets.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98014</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98014</id>
          <name>Ganesh Lohani</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Palisades</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Science 101: An Introduction to Data Science Using Python</title>
      <description>Data is everywhere and Data Science is a very popular topic among data analysts and BI professionals. In this session, I will cover the basic data science principles and methodologies using the Python programming language. I will also present some real-world data analysis case studies using the Python libraries, such as NumPy, pandas, Matplotlib, and SciPy.  This session will benefit to anyone who is looking to get started in the data science/ Data Analytics field.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98826</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98826</id>
          <name>Tyler Graham</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Piedmont Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dimension Management for Power BI</title>
      <description>No matter the complexity of your BI application, dimension management can provide your organization the tools needed to conform, manage and simplify your dimensions. Attend this session and learn how to unlock more value from your analytics.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95612</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95612</id>
          <name>Brad Llewellyn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Powers Island</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning Studio: Making Data Science Easy(er)</title>
      <description>There's so much buzz around Data Science right now.  What is it?  What can I do with it?  Do I need a Ph.D. and a team of super nerds?  In this introductory session, we'll see that Azure Machine Learning Studio's intuitive interface and selection of built-in modules brings the power of Data Science to the people....no advanced degrees necessary.  Bring your data hats and sense of adventure, because the world of data science just got a lot more inviting!</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99067</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99067</id>
          <name>Geoffrey Rayner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Centennial</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Governance Implications of the California Consumer Protectio</title>
      <description>The California Consumer Protection Act (CCPA) has substantial implications on the data governance and data management practices of all companies that have customers in California.   The CCPA will come into effect in 2020 and has substantial potentially large monetary penalties for non-compliance.   Are you ready?   We will discuss what the CCPA is and who is required to comply with the law.   A presentation of MetaCenter, an enterprise metadata management and data governance solution,  will be given to show how a tool can be used to help you comply with the data inventory and data lineage requirements of the CCPA.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96795</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96795</id>
          <name>Warren Sifre</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Palisades</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Streaming Analytics</title>
      <description>This session will cover what is Streaming Analytics and the various use cases. We will demonstrate the creation of a Streaming Analytics process which will output the data to a dashboard for review. The intention is to provide insights in how this technology can potentially be leveraged by the SQL community.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98081</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98081</id>
          <name>Preston Mesarvey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Grant Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>Evolving Your BI Environment From SSRS To Power BI</title>
      <description>With Power BI becoming a leading BI tool over the last few years, a question arises… What does this mean for the existing SSRS environment? This session will explore an analysis plan on your existing reporting landscape to provide you options and considerations to be able to make an informed decision about how Power BI could best be used in your environment. You will learn how to get valuable SSRS usage metrics. You will understand the benefits and limitations between the two BI tools and what questions to ask your users. By Monday morning you will be able to provide an analysis plan on what is involved to introduce Power BI into the enterprise.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95884</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95884</id>
          <name>Julie Smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Science</track>
      <location>
        <name>Piedmont Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Python In Power BI</title>
      <description>Python is a powerful general purpose programming language that has emerged as one of the main tools of data scientists. Python was added to Power BI in June of 2018. This session will demonstrate the two areas python can be used inside the Power BI desktop-- how to leverage python scripts inside the Power BI query editor and how to use python visuals in Power BI reports.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98278</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98278</id>
          <name>Jay Rajendran</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Grant Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>Running Windows and SQL Workloads on Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <description>Google Cloud Platform enables you to exit non-differentiating, capital intensive activities like hardware procurement and maintenance. Retire hardware, improve server utilization and deploy your Windows and SQL Workloads in an open cloud environment.  Google enables extending your SQL database with advanced Server-less Analytics and AI/ML offerings. Deliver a complete platform without the burden of provisioning, scaling and upgrading infrastructure. This session will provide a walk-through of Google's approach to running Windows/SQL workloads in the Cloud and architectural patterns to address your needs.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98542</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98542</id>
          <name>Teo Lachev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Centennial</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Pro, or Premium: that is the question</title>
      <description>One question that always pops us during my Power BI assessments for companies planning to adopt Power BI is which SKU to buy. The choice might seem obvious to your organization, but there is much more below the surface. Join this session and learn important considerations that might influence your decision, including:
•	Licensing cost
•	Hosting organizational semantic layers
•	External reporting
•	Features
•	On-premises reporting</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96118</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96118</id>
          <name>Cornell Emile</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Big Creek</name>
      </location>
      <title>Keeping Your Data Secure In Azure While Automatically Refreshing Power BI Datasets</title>
      <description>Your company has completed its data migration to Azure and now various teams are wanting to build, share and view Power BI reports and dashboards using the data.  Additionally, the access to the data has been limited to a specific list of applications and users but not to Power BI.

So how do you support the automatic data refresh of the data within Power BI and still ensure that the security of your company's data is not compromised?

This advanced Power BI session presents several techniques that can be used to maintain (and sometimes enhance) the security of your company's data while ensuring that Power BI datasets are regularly refreshed.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98045</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98045</id>
          <name>Daniel McConnell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Powers Island</name>
      </location>
      <title>Cool Things You Can Do With Azure Data Factory</title>
      <description>In this session, Daniel  Chadwick will demonstrate why ADF can be a powerful new tool in your ETL toolbelt.  They will show what the on-ramp looks like for an ETL Developer jumping into this brave new world of cloud ETL.  The basics of the tool will be covered, plus some cool things from real-world projects that demonstrate the power of the new platform.  Topics include:
 
What is it and why do I care?
How do I translate my ETL skills into a new product?
Real-world examples (cool things!)
What does it cost really?</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98009</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98009</id>
          <name>Leila Etaati</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Science</track>
      <location>
        <name>Bellwood Quarry</name>
      </location>
      <title>AI Builder: AI in Power Apps and Microsoft Flow</title>
      <description>This session is about the new possibility of doing AI inside Power Apps and Microsoft Flow.  the audience will get familiar with the new update announced in Business Application Summit on AI Builder that provides the facility to run easy AI inside Power Apps and Flow. a demo of how to create a form processing application using AI builder, Flow and Apps will be demonstrated</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95764</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95764</id>
          <name>Andy Leonard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Centennial</name>
      </location>
      <title>Moving Data with Azure Data Factory</title>
      <description>Azure Data Factory - ADF - is a cloud data engineering solution. ADF version 2 sports a snappy web GUI (graphical user interface) and supports the SSIS Integration Runtime (IR) - or "SSIS in the Cloud."

Attend this session to learn: 
 - How to build a "native ADF" pipeline;
 - How to lift and shift SSIS to the Azure Data Factory integration Runtime; and
 - ADF Design Patterns to execute and monitor pipelines and packages.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99225</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99225</id>
          <name>Paco Gonzalez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Big Creek</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Architecture</title>
      <description>Having the right architecture is key to the adoption of Power BI, and to make the most of your business intelligence solution. This session guides you through different Power BI architectures, such as Direct Query, Import, Connect Live, Composite Models, and Embedded. We will analyze different techniques in data refresh, incremental extraction, integration and collaboration to provide a quick overview of the different approaches available.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95597</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95597</id>
          <name>Jared Rhodes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Palisades</name>
      </location>
      <title>AI on the Edge</title>
      <description>The next evolution in cloud computing is a smarter application not in the cloud. As the cloud has continued to evolve, the applications that utilize it have had more and more capabilities of the cloud. This presentation will show how to push logic and machine learning from the cloud to an edge application. Afterward, creating edge applications which utilize the intelligence of the cloud should become effortless.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96128</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96128</id>
          <name>Lance England</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Centennial</name>
      </location>
      <title>DAX Fundamentals</title>
      <description>The Microsoft Tabular model is a core technology in Microsoft's business intelligence offerings, found in Power BI, Azure Analysis Services, and Excel PowerPivot. Understanding DAX (Data Analysis Expressions) is the key to unlocking the power of the Tabular model. This session will cover some fundamental concepts and common pitfalls encountered while learning DAX. 

Topics include:
* Row and filter context
* Context transition
* Filter vs filter
* Active relationships
* Automatic table to scalar conversion
* Variables
* Basics of time intelligence</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98010</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98010</id>
          <name>Leila Etaati</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Science</track>
      <location>
        <name>Big Creek</name>
      </location>
      <title>Microsoft AutoML the Next Generation of Machine Learning</title>
      <description>Automated machine learning simplifies the traditional machine learning process () by creating models with applying hyperparameter settings, and different algorithms. Also, choosing the best models among them based on the performance of each algorithm. Moreover, it provides more detail about the experiment and how much time has been spent to run each iteration and so forth. In this one hour session, an overview of what is Automated Azure ML will be provided, the latest updates of this products will be shown and the audience will learn how to set up the environment and how to use the mode in Power BI services and SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96831</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96831</id>
          <name>Shabnam Watson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Centennial</name>
      </location>
      <title>Aggregations in Power BI</title>
      <description>Aggregations are now generally available in Power BI and are one of the most important optimization methods for managing large datasets. Combined with Direct Query storage mode, they allow big datasets to be analyzed efficiently by answering high level analytical queries quickly from memory while sending more detailed queries back to the source database.

In this session, you will learn about aggregations, different table storage modes, how to set up aggregation tables and configure them to improve query performance.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95615</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95615</id>
          <name>Brad Llewellyn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Powers Island</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Power of Electric Snakes! An Introduction to PySpark for Big Data Analytics</title>
      <description>Big Data Analytics is becoming a major priority for more organizations every day.  However, traditional Hadoop skills are still difficult to find, expensive to hire and time-consuming to train.  In this introductory session, we'll see how it is easy to get started with Big Data Analytics using Spark and Python.  We'll learn how to perform standard analytical tasks, like creating RDDs and Data Frames, transforming columns and creating aggregations.  Be sure to bring your rubber suits, because we'll be playing with lightning...snakes.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98606</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98606</id>
          <name>Javier Guillen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Bellwood Quarry</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI for Data Scientists</title>
      <description>Data Scientists often use a variety of tools to perform engineering and predictive modeling activities in their quest to squeeze as much value from data as possible. Although Power BI is sometimes seen as “just” a front-end visualization tool, its capabilities for data manipulation along with its interoperability with popular data science platforms make it a good choice for data experimentation on a broad set of scenarios.

This session will provide an overview of typical use cases that benefit from Power BI’s rich exploration capabilities in support of data science efforts. Attendees will learn about integration points between Power BI and data science platforms that can help uncover valuable business insights.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96584</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96584</id>
          <name>Hilary Wilkie</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Piedmont Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>User Experience Brilliance in Power BI Dashboards</title>
      <description>User Experience (UX) and Design Thinking are common buzz words around the office. What do these words have to do with BI and Dashboards, anyway? 
Sure, Power BI itself is intuitive and user friendly, but are YOU building dashboards that give the best user experience? 
In this session, we will explore how to start using UX and the psychology behind it to empower you with Intel that will make YOUR dashboards Kick Booty!</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98276</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98276</id>
          <name>Jason Russell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Powers Island</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to Power BI (or "How Power BI changed my Marriage")</title>
      <description>Power BI introductory course with data from Amazon account to show purchases. Connections, importing/transforming data and visualizations will be covered.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98524</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98524</id>
          <name>Daniel Glenn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Bellwood Quarry</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Your On-prem Data in a Cloud World</title>
      <description>Microsoft Power BI, Flow, and PowerApps are powerful cloud tools that can take your on-premises data to new heights. Using your data where it is now gives you the ability to invest in improving processes, instead of focusing on a data migration strategy.

In this session, we will discover the benefits of using the cloud tools, how those benefits translate to being on-prem, and how we can use the data in Office 365 as well. We will setup a data gateway, connect to on-prem data sources, and use that data in Office 365 and SharePoint Server.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>97967</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>97967</id>
          <name>Lucas Feiock</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Powers Island</name>
      </location>
      <title>Speed up your data models using Azure Analysis Services</title>
      <description>Azure Analysis Services is a platform as a service (PaaS) offering that hosts Tabular Models in the cloud. The same capabilities with on-premise SSAS Tabular Models are applied to this new version. Benefits to running Azure AS is the ability to scale up\down, pause, and resume on demand. In this session we will build a semantic data model, migrate to Azure, and visualize using Power BI. If you are running Tabular Models that are compatibility level 1200 and higher this session will show you how quick and easy it is to migrate to Azure.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96042</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96042</id>
          <name>Ed Watson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Piedmont Park</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Psychology of Better Power BI Reporting</title>
      <description>In this course we identify some common mistakes that we see in the business world using Power BI.  We will identify the psychology behind the reporting techniques needed to create powerful and effective reports.  The attendee will leave the class ready to write better reports using Power BI in the real world.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>