<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #862 - Cork 2019</name>
    <startDate>6/29/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT) Greenwich Mean Time : Dublin, Edinburgh, Lisbon, London</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSATCORK</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>University College Cork</name>
      <street>Western Gateway, Western Road, Cork</street>
      <city>Cork</city>
      <state>County Cork, Ireland</state>
      <zipcode>T12 XF62</zipcode>
      <longitude>-8.50041999999996</longitude>
      <latitude>51.8931064</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/972/EventSponsor_14605.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2389</importID>
      <name>Client Solutions</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.clientsolutions.ie/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.clientsolutions.ie/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cs-logo-final-2.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1073</importID>
      <name>Spanish Point Technologies Ltd</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.spanishpoint.ie</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/862/EventSponsor_13576.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2123</importID>
      <name>Quest (Cork)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/898/EventSponsor_14051.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>966</importID>
      <name>Prodata</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.prodata.ie</url>
      <imageURL>http://www.prodata.ie/images/Prodata_Logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2124</importID>
      <name>SentryOne (Cork)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/0/adam/Content/qVRyiy7DOUKHVfZSG3OSow/Logo/download.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91287</importID>
      <name>Kaijisse Waaijer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>“Kaijisse Waaijer is an experienced technologist, specializing in Data Platforms, Machine learning and IoT. 
She is an Erasmus University graduate and currently undergoing her Master’s degree in the field of Health Economics with Econometric context at Erasmus University combined with previous attendance at Tilburg University. 
Kaijisse currently works for Microsoft EMEA as a Data Platform Consultant, specializing in Data Science, Machine learning and Big Data. 
She constantly works with customers across multiple industries as their trusted tech advisor, helping them optimize their organizational data creating better outcomes and business insights that drives value, using Microsoft technologies.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89594</importID>
      <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data Philosopher. Since 2006 invariably awarded Microsoft Most Valuable Professional title in the Data Platform category. A speaker at numerous conferences across Europe, as well as at user groups meetings. The author of many books and articles devoted to Microsoft Data Platform. An independent consultant, database-centric application practitioner and architect totally focused on SQL Server and Azure. Huge fan of Data Science and Machine Learning.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/marcinszeliga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89526</importID>
      <name>Vitor Fava</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I'm a DBA with extensive experience in the areas of Database and Information Technology, working on planning, implementation, and maintenance of large corporate database servers. 
I have several professional certifications and good experience in development activities and management of entrepreneurial environments using SQL SERVER. 
I'm a speaker at various technology events such as SQL Saturday, The Developers Conference, InteropMix and also in various discussion groups focused on database technology.
I teach advanced training in SQL Server and Azure SQL Database and also acting as MCT in Microsoft official training.
I'm the Chapter Leader of SQLManiacs PASS chapter.</description>
      <twitter>sqlservermaniacs</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://br.linkedin.com/in/vitorfava</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.vitorfava.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlservermaniacs</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93148</importID>
      <name>Douglas McDowell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Douglas McDowell is Chief Strategy Officer for SentryOne. He is a 10-year recipient of Microsoft's MVP award for Data Platform (and SQL Server), has served as a PASS volunteer (Chapter Leader, Regional Mentor, Board member) since 2001 and a member of the Microsoft Partner Advisory Council for Business Data Platform and Business Analytics (DPBA PAC) since 2005. He has lots of degrees and constantly applies his dry, cutting self-deprecating humor to most situations,</description>
      <twitter>@douglasmcdowell</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dmcdowell</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@douglasmcdowell</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89725</importID>
      <name>Shehab El-Najjar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Shehab El-Najjar was the ONLY Microsoft SQL Server MVP in Gulf for the past 6 years and the 2nd one all over the Middle East  , he is the founder of SQL Gulf events series (SQL Gulf #1 , #2 and #3 ) where he spent so much time and efforts  to broadcast Microsoft SQL Server technologies all over the Gulf such as  KSA and Emirates and other Gulf cities ahead ..) 

	He is now Professional Services Manager at Saudi  Emircom 

	He was previously COO and business leader in KSA market through his startup WAJA IT for  3 years

	He is an influencing Database community leader all over the region  	
	A senior Database Consultant (SQL Server MVP for 6 years in row) -The 2nd MVP awardee SQL Server all over Middle East and Arabic region</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/MSQLPerformance</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=126446983amp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlserver-performance-tuning.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/MSQLPerformance</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92048</importID>
      <name>Rob Sewell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob was once a production SQL Server DBA, but is now generally found automating the Data Platform and providing training for clients. He has a passion for PowerShell, Data, and DevOps. He is an MVP, an officer for the DevOps PowerShell VG, and has spoken and volunteered at many PowerShell and Data events. He is a member of the committee that organises Data In Devon and the European PowerShell Conference. He is a proud supporter of the Data and PowerShell communities. 
 
He relishes sharing and learning and can be found doing both via Twitter @sqldbawithbeard and his blog sqldbawithabeard.com. He spends most of his time looking at a screen and loves to solve problems.</description>
      <twitter>sqldbawithbeard</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/robsewellsqldba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldbawithabeard.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqldbawithbeard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91354</importID>
      <name>Craig Porteous</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Craig is a Data Platform MVP working with Incremental Group as a Data Engineer. He has more than 10 years working with the Microsoft Data Platform and related technologies, supporting global BI Environments, automating processes with PowerShell and implementing BI Solutions. Craig is actively involved in the SQL community as a co-leader of the Glasgow SQL User group  creator of the DATA:Scotland Conference in Scotland.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/CPorteous</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/craigporteous/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://craigporteous.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/CPorteous</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89599</importID>
      <name>Peter Willmot</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter has been writing software (and teaching folk how to write software) for over 30 years. He has worked with SQL Server as an architect and developer for more than 20 years (since SQL 4.2) and has also worked extensively with the .Net and various other development platforms.

Peter is a past MSDN Regional Director and was also an MVP (SQL Server and Architecture) for many years. He is a passionate and regular speaker and various industry events around the world.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90112</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91043</importID>
      <name>Angela Ross Innes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I'm a SQL Server DBA, previously a SQL Developer with over 13 years experience, currently working for Verizon Connect in Dublin</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/AngelaRossInnes</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/angela-ross-innes-a108752a/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/AngelaRossInnes</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91614</importID>
      <name>Mark Hayes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Hayes (Certified Business Intelligence Professional (CBIP), MPP - Data Science, MPP - Big Data) is a freelance Microsoft Data Platform consultant and has worked with Microsoft data technologies since 2000 with a wide range of national and international companies. He is a regular speaker on Microsoft Data Platform topics and co-leader of the Cork SQL User Group and the Cork SQL Saturday.</description>
      <twitter>MarkDataGuy</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markhayes/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MarkDataGuy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93227</importID>
      <name>Mary Fealty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mary Fealty - Power BI Evangelist
Mary is an old gamer who replaced her enjoyment of gaming with working with data. That’s how satisfying working with data is to her. She has been a massive fan of Power BI from its infancy to now. She makes her living from Power BI, as owner of Broadtree Solutions. Broadtree Solutions develop business intelligence, consult  also provide training on Power BI. Based in Belfast, covering the UK  Ireland. She can also be spotted on Game of Thrones, as a Wildling.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/Br0adtree</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/maryfealty/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/Br0adtree</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89528</importID>
      <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server DBA with over 10 year's experience. Originally from Wales but now living in Ireland</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewpruski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbafromthecold.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89542</importID>
      <name>Magnus Ahlkvist</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Independent database consultant and certified trainer with a passion for chasing that extra millisecond.
20 years of database development and administration but trying to be humble enough to understand that I'm still learning.</description>
      <twitter>Transmokopter</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://se.linkedin.com/in/magnusahlkvist</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tsql.nu</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Transmokopter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94932</importID>
      <name>Daire Cunningham</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Daire Cunningham is the Business Intelligence Practice Lead in Spanish Point Technologies, an award winning software company working with Microsoft technologies to provide business systems which remove complexity, increase productivity and connect users to critical business information. 
He has over twenty years’ experience working with Microsoft technologies including working with some of the earliest Microsoft BI products. Recent projects have included analysis and reporting on National Patient Waiting list data for the NTPF and order payment and fulfilment data-processing for eShopWorld</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dairecunningham</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95333</importID>
      <name>Mark Hayes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Hayes (Certified Business Intelligence Professional (CBIP), MPP - Data Science, MPP - Big Data) is a freelance Microsoft Data Platform consultant and has worked with Microsoft data technologies since 2000 with a wide range of national and international companies. He is a regular speaker on Microsoft Data Platform topics and co-leader of the Cork SQL User Group and the Cork SQL Saturday.</description>
      <twitter>MarkDataGuy</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markhayes/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MarkDataGuy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91630</importID>
      <name>Geovanny Hernandez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Geovanny Hernandez is a Database Engineer and Microsoft Certified Trainer with more than twelve years of experience in software development, passionate for performance tuning in MS SQL Server, Unit Testing and Python.

In addition, Geovanny collaborates with MS SQL Server community as a speaker on different sessions for PASS Malaga (Spain chapter) and virtual events for students and professionals in Universities from Nicaragua (Central America) as well in PASS Marathon and international events as SQLBits and SQLSaturday.

He is passionate about Databases and teaching, who is Microsoft Certified Solution Associate in SQL Server professional and Microsoft Certified Trainer.</description>
      <twitter>@datawithgeo</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/geovannyhernandez</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://geohernandez.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@datawithgeo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93247</importID>
      <name>Dan Galavan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dan has been working with databases for 20 years. He has delivered data platform solutions in Ireland and Germany in a variety of industries including Retail, Corporate and Investment Banking, Aerospace, CRM, Social Protection, Telecoms, and Health Product Regulation. 
Specializes in database design  development, data migration, analytics, master data management, enterprise data warehousing, data  solution architecture, and the data life-cycle in general. 
Regular contributor to SQL Server User Group community. Data Vault 2.0 certified practitioner.
Member of the Munich Colmcilles European Gaelic Football League winning team...a long time ago!</description>
      <twitter>@dangalavan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/dan-galavan/3/104/3b7</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://galavan.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dangalavan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93263</importID>
      <name>Bob Duffy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Duffy is a SQL Server MVP from Dublin, Ireland who is MCA, MCM. and Analysis Services Maestro certified. 

Bob works as a Database Architect at the Prodata SQL Centre of Excellence where he specializes in business intelligence and performance tuning.</description>
      <twitter>@bob_duffy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=8301243amp;authType=NAME_SEARCHamp;authToken=MWkaamp;locale=en_USamp;srchid=83012431382480825815amp;srchindex=1amp;srchtotal=767amp;trk=vsrp_people_res_nameamp;trkInfo=VSRPsearchId%3A83012431382480825815%2CVSRPtargetId%3A8301243%2CVSRPcmpt%3Aprimary</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.prodata.ie/author/bob.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@bob_duffy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92137</importID>
      <name>Kevin Chant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior Database Architect originally from the UK and now living in the Netherlands. Data Platform MVP and MCT.

Over 23 years experience in the IT sector, and has supported databases for companies in the top 10 of the fortune 500 list.

In addition to a lot of SQL Server experience also has a fair few Microsoft Certifications. In addition, was probably the last ever person in the world to gain the MCSD Azure Architect certification and has gained the latest Microsoft DevOps Engineer Expert certification. 

Has real life experience with SQL Server and Azure Devops. Currently SQL Server Product Owner of around 1,900 instances. 

In addition, done various things over the years for the Data Platform Community.</description>
      <twitter>kevchant</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-chant/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.KevinRChant.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kevchant</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92887</importID>
      <name>Brynn Borton</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brynn is a Azure Data Platform Architect and Principal Consultant with over 20 years’ experience working for various Microsoft gold partners. After initially starting his career building enterprise .NET solutions Brynn decided to focus on building Microsoft data focused solutions around 10 years ago. Brynn consults for Altius Ltd and currently works with a number of clients in the Hospitality and Retail Sector. Being very early adopters in helping clients move their data to the Azure cloud, Brynn has over 5 years hands on experience implementing what we would describe as the Azure Modern Data Platform.</description>
      <twitter>@brynnborton</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/brynn-borton-a114bb2/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@brynnborton</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89616</importID>
      <name>Steve Simon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Simon is a Database Solutions Architect with Business Knowledge Services Inc. He has been involved with database design and analysis for over 35 years. Steve has presented papers at numerous PASS Summits and PASS SQL Rallies. He is also regular presenter on the SQL Saturday circuit and he is a contributor on SQLShack.com</description>
      <twitter>SQLServerBoffin</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stephenrsimon/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/simon_says/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLServerBoffin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92036</importID>
      <name>Simon Whiteley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Simon Whiteley is the Director of Engineering for Advancing Analytics Ltd and a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Simon is a seasoned solution architect and technical lead with well over a decade of Microsoft Analytics experience. A deep techie with a focus on emerging cloud technologies and applying "big data" thinking to traditional analytics problems, Simon also has a passion for bringing it back to the high level and making sense of the bigger picture. When not tinkering with tech, Simon is a death-dodging London cyclist, a sampler of craft beers, an avid chef, and a generally nerdy person.</description>
      <twitter>MrSiWhiteley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/pub/simon-whiteley/32/994/aa8</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.adatis.co.uk/blogs/simonwhiteley/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MrSiWhiteley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90095</importID>
      <name>Marcelo Fernandes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marcelo Fernandes is SQL Server MVP and has 12+ years experience with databases, specialized in High Availability, critical missions and very large databases. He holds the MCP / MCDBA / MCSA / MCTS / MCITP and MCT certifications, he lives and works in Berlin for an American e-commerce company that sells home goods. He share their knowledge through webcasts, presentations and articles on Microsoft technologies and can be cantacted by email fernandes_dba@hotmail.com or twitter @ marcelodba</description>
      <twitter>marcelodba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://br.linkedin.com/in/marcelodba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://marcelodba.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=marcelodba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90016</importID>
      <name>Lord Richard Douglas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lord Richard Douglas is a Principal Solutions Engineer at SentryOne, where he specialises in the SQL Server product range. He has worked with SQL Server since version 7.0 in various developer and DBA roles and holds a number of Microsoft certifications. Richard is a keen member of the SQL Server community, having run a PASS Chapter in the UK and having served on the organizing committee for SQLRelay.
Richard is on Twitter as @SQLRich.</description>
      <twitter>SQLRich</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/richardpdouglas</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SQL.RichardDouglas.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLRich</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92501</importID>
      <name>Dmitri Korotkevitch</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dmitri Korotkevitch is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and Microsoft Certified Master, author of Pro SQL Server Internals and other books with years of experience working with SQL Server as an Application and Database Developer, Database Administrator, and Database Architect. 

Dmitri specializes in the design, development, and performance tuning of complex OLTP systems that handle thousands of transactions per second around the clock. He blogs at: http://aboutsqlserver.com.</description>
      <twitter>aboutsqlserver</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/dmitri-korotkevitch/5/980/b7</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aboutsqlserver.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=aboutsqlserver</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90487</importID>
      <name>Christoph Seck</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Christoph works as a BI Architect for KI Performance.  With SQL Server and its BI Stack he is dealing for more than 15 years.
He is cofounder and chapter leader of the German PASS chapter of Hannover, Visiting Lecturer at the University of Hildesheim and regular speaker at conferences and German PASS events on DWH topics and agile project management.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90876</importID>
      <name>Paul Andrew</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul Andrew is a principal consultant and architect, specializing in big data solutions on the Microsoft Azure cloud platform.
Paul's data engineering competencies include Azure Data Factory, Data Lake, Databricks, Stream Analytics, Event Hub, IoT Hub, Functions, Automation, Logic Apps, and of course the complete SQL Server Business Intelligence stack. 

He has many years’ experience working within healthcare, retail, and gaming verticals, delivering analytics using industry leading methods and technical design patterns.

Paul is a STEM ambassador and a very active member of the data platform community delivering training and technical sessions at conferences both nationally and internationally.

He is a father, husband, swimmer, cyclist, r</description>
      <twitter>mrpaulandrew</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrpaulandrew</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mrpaulandrew.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mrpaulandrew</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92274</importID>
      <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Broadbent is a Data Platform MVP and SQL Server MCM with more than 20 years of experience working with SQL Server and principal of SQLCloud, a consultancy specializing in concurrency control and highly available solutions. He is the founder of the UK's SQLSaturday Cambridge (its first and largest), SharePoint Saturday Cambridge, the Hybrid Virtual Chapter and the East Anglia SQL User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@retracement</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/retracement</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tenbulls.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@retracement</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>89616</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89616</id>
          <name>Steve Simon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>An introduction to Data Mining  with SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>With the vast amount of changes that occur in our daily business environments, it becomes more and more difficult to achieve our corporate goals without some ‘lighthouse’ to guide our way. Data mining, (while not a panacea to resolve or ‘control’ the effects of these changes), can provide us with statistical trends by analyzing our data and highlighting probable outcomes.

In this hands on BEGINNERS presentation we shall be looking at Microsoft SQL Server’s Data Mining capabilities and we shall be discussing:

1)  Defining what questions we want answered and how to go about this in an effective and efficient manner.

2)  Creating the data model.

3)  How to gather the necessary data, discussing the training and testing aspect.

4)  Processing the model.

5)  Extracting information from our finished model, discussing the implications of this information.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91630</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91630</id>
          <name>Geovanny Hernandez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Keeping your SQL Code safe – An introduction to GIT and SSDT for DB professionals</title>
      <description>Imagine that you have been hard working in that amazing project, your SQL code has been tuned and contains new features and followed the standard that will be crucial for the success of this project. The deploy date has arrived and you have deployed early in the morning but some minutes after the deploy, the users started to call for reporting several issues in the different systems which are using the Databases that were part of your deployment, after stressful minutes, you realized some SQL code deployed were not the same that were tested and you must rollback your code. 

In this session, I'm going to show you how to avoid problems derived of mistakes during the development process through the proper use of source control code strategy which can combine the potential of GIT and SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT) for managing latest version, detecting changes, code review and deploying through environment without stress.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89725</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89725</id>
          <name>Shehab El-Najjar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance Dreams started at SQL Server 2014 and came true now at SQL Server 2016,2017</title>
      <description>“Performance Dreams started at SQL Server 2014 and came true now at SQL Server 2016,2017 “, it is just like this because you there are unbelievable performance reads and substantial improvements that can drive your DB environment to a distinct level of stability and Performance to be a leading environment in a very short time ..! It looks like apparently a myth or legend to see those new SQL Server 2016 features how they could flipped up SQL Server Powers from the old generation to the new generation of in-advanced analytics using In-memory and CCI (Colmnstore indexes) where no longer need for any DWH solutions at all but just reading data directly from production DBs with ZERO performance impacts on end users  ..! come in here to my session and you will know more about many new features and rich powers of SQL Server 2014  2016 regarding performance particularly like  Microsoft project “Hekaton” for In-memory built in for OLTP , CCI( columnstore index) ,Resource Governor for IO</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90487</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90487</id>
          <name>Christoph Seck</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Connecting SQL and Blockchain: The Azure Blockchain Workbench [EN]</title>
      <description>Hype as it is, a valid business case currently is the most critical point for a Blockchain project. So better check it out with a PoC and best with a fast PoC before you start burning money. But getting even a simple PoC for a Blockchain project running still is hard. Connecting Blockchain data to classical databases, making them available to analytics or standard applications is worse (ever queried LevelDB?). Microsofts new "Azure Blockchain Workbench" let you do this in hours, not months. So (besides wondering why one needs this hype stuff at all) we will see how to

- Deploy a Blockchain on Azure in a breeze
- Start coding with Solidity
- Generate templates for smart contracts
- Connect them to IoT devices
- Get a PoC Web UI for free
- Push all the data into a "real" database automatically

Last but not least, we can look at some real world projects.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92274</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92274</id>
          <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room4</name>
      </location>
      <title>2 Fast 2 Furious - designing for speed, concurrency, and correctness</title>
      <description>With the multitude of isolation levels, concurrency models, and specialist technologies available in SQL Server, it is no surprise that transaction throughput and correctness can be directly correlated to the ability and knowledge of the person that wrote the code.

In this session, we will reveal how SQL Server concurrency and correctness often goes wrong, how we can avoid this, and how we can use our knowledge to design and develop for optimal server throughput for our applications and processes using tips and tricks gained from real-world scenarios.

We will cover SQL Server’s traditional locking model, In-Memory OLTP, Columnstore, Delayed Durability, and many other technologies and techniques you can use to make your transactions more robust.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89528</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89528</id>
          <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room4</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server  Kubernetes</title>
      <description>Running SQL Server in containers has huge benefits for Data Platform professionals but there are challenges to running SQL Server in stand alone containers. Orchestrators provide a platform and the tools to overcome these challenges.

This session will provide an overview of running SQL Server in Kubernetes, which is the leading orchestrator.

Topics covered will be: -
An overview of Kubernetes.
Definition of deployments, pods, and services.
Deploying SQL Server containers to Kubernetes.
Persisting data for SQL Server in Kubernetes.

This session is aimed at SQL Server DBAs and Developers who want to learn the what, the why, and the how to run SQL Server in Kubernetes.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90016</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90016</id>
          <name>Lord Richard Douglas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding the Transaction Log For Faster Throughput</title>
      <description>Does your application suffer from performance problems even though you followed best practices on schema design? Have you looked at your transaction log? 
There's no doubt about it, the transaction log is treated like a poor cousin. The poor thing does not receive much love. The transaction log, however, is a very essential and misunderstood part of your database. There will be a team of developers creating an absolutely awesome elegant design the likes of which have never been seen before, but the leave the transaction log using default settings. It's as if it doesn't matter, an afterthought, a relic of the platform architecture.
In this session, you will learn to appreciate how the transaction log works and how you can improve the performance of your applications by making the right architectural choices. From understanding the internals we can design for faster recovery and batch processes and ironically a smaller transaction log!</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90876</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90876</id>
          <name>Paul Andrew</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Complex Azure Orchestration with Dynamic Data Factory Pipelines</title>
      <description>If you have already mastered the basics of Azure Data Factory (ADF) and are now looking to advance your knowledge of the tool this is the session for you. Yes, Data Factory can handle the orchestration of our ETL pipelines. But what about our wider Azure environment? In this session we’ll go beyond the basics looking at how we build custom activities, metadata driven dynamic design patterns for Data Factory. Plus, considerations for optimising compute costs by controlling other service scaling as part of normal data processing. Once we can hit a REST API with an ADF web activity anything is possible, extending our Data Factory and orchestrating everything.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91287</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91287</id>
          <name>Kaijisse Waaijer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Training a large-scale recommendation engine on SQL server 2019</title>
      <description>In this session, we will show how to train a recommendation engine on SQL Server 2019 Big Data clusters (BDC) on Azure Kubernetes Services (AKS) using Python, Spark, and SQL. SQL Server 2019 is the first version that tightly integrates HDFS and Apache Spark with a SQL Server engine.
We will start with an overview of the SQL Server 2019 architecture for Big Data clusters. After a brief introduction to Recommender Systems, we will load product ratings to HDFS and link them to the customer and product data in SQL using Polybase. Then we will explore the dataset using Spark, Python and Data Studio and ultimately create a Training and Validation split. In the next step, we will train the Recommendation engine in Spark and persist the model to HDFS. Every step will be performed within the same SQL Server 2019 BDC cluster showcasing the incredible capabilities of SQL 2019.
On-top, by building on SQL Server 2019 BDC and Kubernetes you can run your cluster locally, on premises, or in the cloud.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92036</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92036</id>
          <name>Simon Whiteley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Modern Data Warehousing - The Lambda Approach to Azure BI</title>
      <description>Technology changes quickly - patterns and approaches less so. As we move towards distributed cloud architectures we will employ a range of disparate tools, the patterns that were designed for single box solutions may not be appropriate any more.
 
We will first review the patterns and processes that underpin the Lambda architecture, providing advice and guidance on the tool sets and integration points between them.

This intense, demo-packed session implements real-time reporting using the Lambda Architecture in Azure, demonstrating Azure Data Lake Store, Azure Databricks, Data Factory, SQL Datawarehouse and Stream Analytics. Time permitting, we will compare and contrast against an alternative pattern using Cosmos DB  Spark Structured Streaming.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92887</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92887</id>
          <name>Brynn Borton</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Azure Cosmos DB and DataBricks to provide Realtime Customer Matching</title>
      <description>Find out how a major UK hotel chain unified their wildly different sources of customer data to build a supercharged automated customer communication engine. 

Cosmos DB and Databricks where used to process and match customer data in real-time, helping them get to know their customers, how best to retain them, and how best to keep them happy, all while ensuring GDPR compliance. 

Learn how downstream systems received customer identifiers allowing tailored content to be produced in near real time, and how business users consumed the insights via Power BI

Learn how scale up and scale down allowed us to meet challenges around massive initial data loads, without blowing the project budget. 

Find out what lessons were learned and what best practices helped ensure that the Cosmos DB, Azure Functions, Event Hubs and Azure Databricks instances all played harmoniously together. Hear how we used partitioning, indexing, scaling and other cloud design patterns to deliver incredible performance.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93247</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93247</id>
          <name>Dan Galavan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Vault data warehousing - an introduction</title>
      <description>In addition to the Data Vault approach being touted as the next generation data warehouse modelling technique, with the arrival of Data Vault 2.0 comes a complete data modelling, methodology and architectural offering. 
This talk will introduce you to the core Data Vault concepts including support for an agile data warehouse, how it can contribute to faster sprints, how it lends itself to automated data model creation, how the Hub, Link and Satellite design is a perfect fit for massively parallel data load and how to virtualize a Data Mart over a Data Vault. It will also cover how a single version of the facts edges out a single version of the truth. 
Demo: Using a SQL 2017 data source, we will orchestrate the extraction, transformation and load to a Data Vault data warehouse including an example virtualized Data Mart layer. The orchestration will take place using Azure Data Factory v2.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91614</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91614</id>
          <name>Mark Hayes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Many roads to reporting with Microsoft BI technologies</title>
      <description>This session looks at the reporting technologies that are available from Microsoft for BI reporting. We will look at how Microsoft BI technologies can be used to meet a wide range of user needs, from personal BI to Enterprise-wide reporting. We will demo of various technologies can be used to meet your reporting needs and the similarities and differences between them.

Topics: Excel, Power BI, SQL Reporting Services 2017, Power BI Server, Data Models, Self Service Reporting

In this session we will see cover;
- Organisational Information Needs
- Data Modeling
- Microsoft Reporting technologies overview
- Demo on Key Reporting Technologies</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94932</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94932</id>
          <name>Daire Cunningham</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure / Cloud</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>ADF Data Flows: Build scalable, cloud-based ETL without code</title>
      <description>- SSIS gave you a graphical user interface for building your Extract, Transform and Load processes hosted in SQL Server
- Azure Data Factory v1 gave you a UI for more scalable Extracting and Loading of data, but the Transformation plug-in was left up to you
- Azure Data Factory v2 gave you more control over how your processes were triggered and the path through your steps (like the Control Flow in SSIS)
- Now coming to ADF is Mapping Data Flows, a UI for building in Transformations into your ETLs, still taking full advantage of scalability in the cloud</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93227</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93227</id>
          <name>Mary Fealty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>PowerBI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI KISS, make it beautiful</title>
      <description>In this session Mary will demo building a Power BI solution using Low-Code/No-Code while using the principle of Keep it Simple Stupid. This will allow attendees to see how quickly you can build out an simple but effective solution with relative ease. 
She will also share some of her technics for creating a unique look and feel to the report that makes for a positive user experience, by using PowerPoint, Power BI Bookmarks  the new Filter Pane.
This session is for folks who are new to Power BI but should be of interest to fellow Power BI Pros.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91354</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91354</id>
          <name>Craig Porteous</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>PowerBI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI and PowerShell - A Match Made in Heaven</title>
      <description>Power BI is the shiny new tech for processing and visualizing data in the Microsoft Data Platform. However, the plumbing in the background does need managing (even if it is cloud-based and supposedly automagic).

In this session we will take a look at how to manage your datasets, security, monitor licensing and more, all through the ultimate administration interface: PowerShell!

You'll leave the session with an overview of the management capabilities of Power BI and couple that knowledge with the awesome power (and automation possibilities) of PowerShell</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93148</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93148</id>
          <name>Douglas McDowell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Rock Your Session - Best Practices for Presentations</title>
      <description>Just because you’re a technical rock star doesn’t mean your technical presentation is going to rock. And even if you own the room for technical presentations, you may find that your business presentations often fall short. This session is for veteran presenters as well as first-timers, offering prescriptive guidance and best practices for structuring, building, and delivering a compelling presentation every time—whether technical or non-technical. Effective and persuasive presentation skills are critical for survival and success in the workplace—this is a session worth checking out.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89542</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89542</id>
          <name>Magnus Ahlkvist</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Eight hours of work in 20 minutes</title>
      <description>A case study of how a monthly data load has evolved, from just loading data into a table, through some indexes being disabled before loading and enabled after data is loaded, to partitioning the table and loading into a staging table. The last Changes to the solution has taken loading time from eight hours down to 20 minutes, saving a whole day of work for the staff checking and refining the data.
The presentation also includes some reflections on how partitioning the table has changed how both T-SQL and Entity Framework code is being written, to take advantage of partition elimination.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93263</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93263</id>
          <name>Bob Duffy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Secrets of Azure storage and SQL</title>
      <description>SQL disk configuration and planning can really hurt you if you get it wrong in azure. There is a lot more to getting SQL right on Azure VMs than next-next-next. 

Come along and chat to SQL Certified Architect, Bob Duffy, as we dive deeper into azure storage for SQL. Topics covered include:
-	SQL storage Capacity Planning concepts
-	Understanding Storage Accounts, VM limits, and disk types
-	Understanding and planning around throttling.
-	Benchmarking
-	Optimising SQL configuration to match Azure disk layout:
-	Hitting “max” disk throughput</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92137</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92137</id>
          <name>Kevin Chant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Adventure</title>
      <description>Aimed mostly at administration and based on real life scenarios, in this audience interactive session we will go through some scenarios DBA's might encounter whilst dealing with SQL Server databases and you will be provided with some options about what to do. Members of the audience will then select from these options what to do and we will follow that path and see what the outcome is from there.

Each selection will have a different outcome, and along the way you will probably learn some new things.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90095</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90095</id>
          <name>Marcelo Fernandes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Architecting SQL Server environments for Mission Critical and High Performance</title>
      <description>Mission critical SQL Servers require right architecture to satisfy SLAs, high availability, and disaster recovery requirements for your critical IT operational data environment. The ability to scale up these environments, to provide the level of performance required by OLTP and provide adequate resources is a significant operational challenge.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95333</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95333</id>
          <name>Mark Hayes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure / Cloud</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Lightning Talks</title>
      <description>Short (5-10 mins.) talks on a variety of technical topics. 

All welcome - feel free to turn up and speak on the day!</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91043</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91043</id>
          <name>Angela Ross Innes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Continuous Integration and Delivery (CI/CD) using Visual Studio and DACFx for SQL Server</title>
      <description>Implementing CI/CD on a database platform is never going to be straightforward! During this session, I will provide a high level overview of our pipeline, the tools we use, and some of the lessons we've learned along the way.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90112</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90112</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Launching A Data Science Project:  Cleaning Is Half The Battle</title>
      <description>There's an old adage in software development: Garbage In, Garbage Out. This adage certainly applies to data science projects: if you simply throw raw data at models, you will end up with garbage results. In this session, we will build an understanding of just what it takes to implement a data science project whose results are not garbage. We will use the Microsoft Team Data Science Process as our model for project implementation, learning what each step of the process entails. To motivate this walkthrough, we will see what we can learn from a survey of data professionals' salaries.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92048</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92048</id>
          <name>Rob Sewell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room4</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Notebooks in Azure Data Studio for the DBA</title>
      <description>An Azure Data Studio recent release introduced SQL Notebooks as a capability.

While you might have read about notebooks being used for Data Science, this session is for DBAs. You will see how you can use SQL Notebooks to simplify your work.

You will learn about SQL Notebooks from installing them in Azure Data Studio to creating a Notebook for Glenn Berry's Diagnostic queries as well as numerous use cases for you to use in your daily workload</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92501</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92501</id>
          <name>Dmitri Korotkevitch</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro Into Index Analysis</title>
      <description>Indexing in SQL Server is both - art and science. It is also never-ending process. Database schema, queries and workload change overtime, making old indexing strategy obsolete and leaving you with inefficient or unused indexes.  

In this session, Dmitri demonstrates several techniques that help you to perform index analysis in the system. You would learn how to detect unused and inefficient indexes, identify incorrect clustered indexes and choose the right candidates for consolidation and further index refactoring.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89526</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89526</id>
          <name>Vitor Fava</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Implementing AI solutions using the cognitive services in Azure</title>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence (AI) is bringing big changes in the way people and businesses relate to technology.
As well as the arrival of the personal computer, the cloud computing and smartphones, the AI is the artificial technology that takes you to where you're going so much faster, intuitive and smart.
In this session we will discuss the basics of IA and how we can apply it in our business using the Azure Cognitive Services.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89599</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89599</id>
          <name>Peter Willmot</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Working with SQL Managed Data Types</title>
      <description>The Geospatial and Hierarchical managed data types were introduced with SQL 2005 but are sadly seldom used (or understood) by most developers more than a decade later. In this session Peter Willmot will take you on a guided tour of these data types (along with the basics of SQL CLR integration with C#) and help you to understand the pros and cons of their inclusion in your database/application design.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89594</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89594</id>
          <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room4</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to win Kaggle competition and get familiar with machine learning ?</title>
      <description>Have you heard that knowing machine learning is the easiest way to get rich quickly? Let’s test this statement. Kaggle is the place to do data science projects, why not to start there?
During this session we will solve simple Kaggle competition. Actually, we will submit two solutions. The first made with super-duper deep neural network (black-box approach). Then we will follow proven ML methodologies and solve the problem methodically. All that using SQL Server Machine Learning Services.
Minimum slides and maximum fun guaranteed.</description>
      <startTime>6/29/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/29/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>