<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #832 - Croatia 2019</name>
    <startDate>4/6/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>100</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Belgrade, Bratislava, Budapest, Ljubljana, Prague</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatCroatia</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>University of Zagreb, Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing</name>
      <street>Unska 3</street>
      <city>Zagreb</city>
      <state>, Croatia</state>
      <zipcode>10000 Zagreb</zipcode>
      <longitude>15.9708592079346</longitude>
      <latitude>45.8013121266254</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/972/EventSponsor_14605.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2369</importID>
      <name>MOBILNA INFORMATIKA D.O.O.</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.repsly.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/832/EventSponsor_13341.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2373</importID>
      <name>Data Sense d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.datasense.hr</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/832/EventSponsor_13363.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2410</importID>
      <name>Franck</name>
      <label>Custom</label>
      <url>https://www.franck.eu/en/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/832/EventSponsor_13519.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2387</importID>
      <name>PET MINUTA d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Custom</label>
      <url>https://five.agency/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/832/EventSponsor_13396.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2330</importID>
      <name>University of Zagreb, Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing</name>
      <label>Custom</label>
      <url>https://www.fer.unizg.hr</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/832/EventSponsor_13024.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>562</importID>
      <name>Devart</name>
      <label>Custom</label>
      <url>http://www.devart.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/832/EventSponsor_13132.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2325</importID>
      <name>RevDeBug</name>
      <label>Custom</label>
      <url>https://revdebug.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/832/EventSponsor_13125.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2377</importID>
      <name>TuneIT</name>
      <label>Custom</label>
      <url>http://www.tuneit.hr/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/832/EventSponsor_13373.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2349</importID>
      <name>Tech Resources d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Custom</label>
      <url>http://www.techresources.hr</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/832/EventSponsor_13252.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2368</importID>
      <name>SPAN d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Custom</label>
      <url>https://span.eu/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/832/EventSponsor_13340.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89836</importID>
      <name>Slaven Šola</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Slaven je SQL Server konzultant sa 10+ godina iskustva . Najveći dio svoga vremena provodi u radu na kompleksnim transakcijskim sustavima sa posebnim fokusom na "performance tuning". Redovni je predavač na raznim konferencijama gdje prenosi znanje izgrađeno svakodnevna iskustva iz prakse. Od 2012. godine je osnivač TuneIT kompanije specijalizirane za upravljanje podacima na Microsoft tehnologiji.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88274</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo Kornelis is an established SQL Server community expert who spends a lot of time at various conferences. He is author of "the Execution Plan Reference" (sqlserverfast.com/epr), blogger, technical editor of Grant Fritchey's "SQL Server Execution Plans, 3rd edition" and some other books, and Pluralsight author. He was awarded SQL Server MVP and Data Platform MVP 12 times (2006 - 2016, and 2019-present).

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.</description>
      <twitter>Hugo_Kornelis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/hugokornelis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Hugo_Kornelis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87662</importID>
      <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Miloš Radivojević is a database consultant located in Vienna, Austria. He is Data Platform MVP and specializes in SQL Server for application developers and performance and query tuning. Currently, he works as a principal database consultant in bwin GVC (the largest regulated online gaming company in the world). He is co-founder of the SQL Pass Austria and speaks regularly at local and international database conferences. He is also co-author of the books SQL Server 2016 Developer's Guide, SQL Server 2017 Developer's Guide and Mastering SQL Server 2017.</description>
      <twitter>MilosSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://at.linkedin.com/pub/milos-radivojevic/1b/7bb/290/de</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://milossql.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MilosSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88454</importID>
      <name>Kevin Boles</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Boles is a SQL Server expert, working exclusively with the product since v6.5. With over 25 years of database experience and over 45,000 man hours of SQL Server engine experience, he holds many related certifications, is an MCT and was a SQL Server MVP from 2007 to 2012. Kevin has been a very successful independent consultant for over 20 years. His passion is the relational engine, especially designing, building, analyzing and tuning high-performance database applications.</description>
      <twitter>@TheSQLGuru</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/thesqlguru</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TheSQLGuru</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87683</importID>
      <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dejan Sarka, MCT and Data Platform MVP, is an independent trainer and consultant that focuses on development of database and business intelligence applications. Besides projects, he spends about half of his time on training and mentoring. He is the founder of the Slovenian SQL Server and .NET Users Group. Dejan Sarka is the main author or co-author of eighteen books about databases and SQL Server. Dejan Sarka has also developed many courses and seminars for Microsoft, Radacad, SolidQ, and Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>DejanSarka</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/dsarka/Home.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DejanSarka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89778</importID>
      <name>Marcelo Fernandes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marcelo Fernandes is SQL Server MVP and has 12+ years experience with databases, specialized in High Availability, critical missions and very large databases. He holds the MCP / MCDBA / MCSA / MCTS / MCITP and MCT certifications, he lives and works in Berlin for an American e-commerce company that sells home goods. He share their knowledge through webcasts, presentations and articles on Microsoft technologies and can be cantacted by email fernandes_dba@hotmail.com or twitter @ marcelodba</description>
      <twitter>marcelodba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://br.linkedin.com/in/marcelodba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://marcelodba.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=marcelodba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87666</importID>
      <name>Aleksandar Talev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Aleksandar Talev is Chief Development Officer in Semos  - Microsoft Gold Partner. He is professionally oriented to development of IT projects based on Microsoft technologies, primary SQL Server, Microsoft Power BI and Microsoft Azure. He has been working with SQL Server 6.5 since 1996. As a Microsoft trainer he is holding a Microsoft Curriculum courses focused on SQL Server as well as Power BI. As one of the founders of SQL Server User Group (PASS) Macedonia his free time he is engaged in developing the SQL Server community in Macedonia. He is a regular speaker on Microsoft conferences as well as local and global community events. In 2005 Microsoft awarded him with SQL Server MVP award.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/aleksandar-talev-95159187</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://Www.sqlpass.org.mk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87837</importID>
      <name>Tomaž Kaštrun</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tomaž Kaštrun is BI developer and data analyst. His main focus are data mining, T-SQL development, programming and query optimization. He has been working with SQL server since version 2000. He is Microsoft Certified Professional, Microsoft MVP for data platform and Microsoft trainer.</description>
      <twitter>@tomaz_tsql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/tomaz.kastrun</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tomaztsql.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tomaz_tsql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87682</importID>
      <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Uwe Ricken is working with IT systems since the 90’s. The primary passion for developments with Microsoft SQL Server expanded in 2007 with his engagement as a DBA for Deutsche Bank AG in Frankfurt am Main. After 6 years of operational experiences as a DBA and over 14 years as a developer of complex database models he achieved the “Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008” certification which “was” the highest technical certification. In the same year he earned his first award as a Data Platform MVP for his support to the Microsoft SQL Server community in Germany and Europe. Uwe Ricken is a speaker on many international conferences and events and preferred topics are “Database Internals”, “Indexing” and “Development”.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dbBerater</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=270775013amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmaster.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dbBerater</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88337</importID>
      <name>Mladen Prajdić</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mladen Prajdić is a Data Platform MVP from Slovenia. He's been programming for 20 years, developing diﬀerent types of applications in .Net (C#) and SQL Server, ranging from standard line-of-business, image-processing applications to high performace and IoT applications. He's a regular speaker at various conferences and usergroup meetings, really likes to optimize slow SQL statements, analyze performance, and find unconventional solutions to difficult SQL Server problems. In his free time, he also develops a very popular add-in for SSMS, called the SSMS Tools Pack (www.ssmstoolspack.com).</description>
      <twitter>@MladenPrajdic</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mladenprajdic</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/mladenp</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MladenPrajdic</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88420</importID>
      <name>Gianluca Sartori</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gianluca Sartori is a Data Platform MVP, independent consultant and performance tuning specialist. He has been working in the software industry since 1999 and has been working with SQL Server ever since. He also works as a SQL Server trainer and in his spare time he writes technical articles and participates the SQL Server forums. Gianluca enjoys presenting SQL Server topics at conferences in Europe and in Italy in particular. He is currently working as lead DBA at a famous Formula 1 team.</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/#!/spaghettidba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://it.linkedin.com/pub/gianluca-sartori/23/50b/a12</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://spaghettidba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/#!/spaghettidba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>87837</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87837</id>
          <name>Tomaž Kaštrun</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>B2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Common Data Science Mistakes</title>
      <description>In the middle of deploying the model, team of data scientists realize that the predictions are "somewhat-off". Troubleshooting on the horizon and what to do. Session will guide you through most common mistakes data scientists and statisticians are making when preparing and engineering the data using T-SQL or any other database system. Further more, we will explore common statistical and data science mistakes when modeling data, extracting know-how from the data, finding the hidden patterns and running different test against the structural models using mainly R, Python, or Spark. What not-to-do will be replaced with what to-do explanations using sample datasets and sample codes. Some statistical knowledge or background is a plus!</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87682</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87682</id>
          <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>B1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mastering DML Operations like a master</title>
      <description>DML operations mean lot of work for the database engine of Microsoft SQL Server. Understanding the details of a DML transaction may give you great benefits when planning workloads for INSERT, UPDATE and DELETE operations.

Come and learn the differences of space allocation/deallocation between Clustered Indexes and Heaps in this demo oriented session. It will answer these questions:

What is the difference of data page allocation for heaps and clustered indexes?
What is the amount of transaction log when you update data in a heap and/or in a clustered index?
What are the differences when data are delete from a heap and clustered index?
Can ETL processes be improved by usage of the right strategy for INSERTS and DELETES?
What performance drawbacks will Page Splits and Forwarded Records have for my application design?</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87662</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87662</id>
          <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>B1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Cardinality Estimation Issues with Large Tables</title>
      <description>In this session, you will see a simple query with two large tables that runs loo long with high memory grants and a very bad execution plan although preconditions for an optimal execution are fulfilled: indexes on JOIN columns exist, statistics are up-to-date, all new features and improvements are enabled (SQL Server 2017 CU 10 or SQL Server 2019 CTP2).

You’ll see how developer usually workaround this issue, when this is a good idea and when it’s not, and we’ll consider which technical and logical mistakes are made in the process of solving this issue.

Of course, you’ll see why this happens only when working with large tables, what is different in the world of large tables, and how to solve this issue by identifying and eliminating the root cause and not dealing with consequences only.

Attendees should be familiar with the process and components involved in the generation of an execution plan in SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87666</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87666</id>
          <name>Aleksandar Talev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>B2</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to choose the right data model: SQL Server or Azure Cosmos DB. Which, When and Where ?</title>
      <description>When it comes to choosing a database, always there are considerations about picking a relational (SQL) or non-relational (NoSQL) data structure. While both are viable options, there are certain key differences between these two options that users must keep in mind.This session will cover the most important distinctions and will make a difference between two of a key players in the Microsoft database world: SQL Server and Azure Cosmos DB.  The session will also illustrate some of the fundamental differences between these databases - the language, scalability and structure which cause this distinctions to have  implications for the right choice.So which database is right for your business the attendance will take informations in this session.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87683</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87683</id>
          <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>B1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Temporal Data in SQL Server</title>
      <description>Databases that serve business applications should often support temporal data. For example, suppose a contract with a supplier is valid for a limited time only. It can be valid from a specific point in time onward, or it can be valid for a specific time interval—from a starting time point to an ending time point. In addition, many times you need to audit all changes in one or more tables. You might also need to be able to show the state in a specific point in time, or all changes made to a table in a specific period of time. From the data integrity perspective, you might need to implement many additional temporal specific constraints.
This session introduces the temporal problems, deals with solutions that go beyond SQL Server 2016 and 2017 support, and shows out-of-the-box solution in SQL Server 2016 and 2017, including:
•	Defining temporal data
•	Application versioned tables
•	System versioned tables
•	What kind of temporal support is still missing</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88274</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88274</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>B1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Execution plans ... where do I start?</title>
      <description>SQL (the language) is not a third generation language, where the developer tells the computer every step it needs to take. It is a declarative language that specifies the required results. SQL Server itself will figure out what steps it takes to get to those results. Most of the time, that works very well.

But sometimes it doesn't. Sometimes a query takes too much time. You need to find out why, so you can fix it. That's where the execution plan comes in. In the execution plan, SQL Server exposes exactly which steps it took for your query, so you can see why it's slow.

However, execution plans can be daunting to the uninitiated. Especially for complex queries. Where do you even start?

In this session you will learn how to obtain execution plans. and how to start reading and understanding them.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88420</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88420</id>
          <name>Gianluca Sartori</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>B2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Infernals - A Beginner’s Guide to Worst Practices</title>
      <description>Are you faced with complaints from users, poor performing code from developers, and regular requests to build reports? Do you uncover installation and configuration issues on your SQL Server instances? Have you ever thought that in dire times avoiding Worst Practices could be a good starting point? If the answer is “yes”, then this session is for you: together we will discover how not to torture a SQL Server instance and we will see how to avoid making choices that turn out to be not so smart in the long run.

You are probably thinking: “Hey, wait, what about Best Practices?”. Sometimes Best Practices are not enough, especially for beginners, and it is not always clear what happens if we fail to follow them. Worst Practices can show the mistakes to avoid. I have made lots of mistakes throughout my career: come and learn from my mistakes!</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88337</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88337</id>
          <name>Mladen Prajdić</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>B2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting To Know SQL Server Encryption Capabilities</title>
      <description>With stricter EU privacy laws like GDPR, the need to encrypt data is greater than ever.
In this session we'll look at what SQL Server offers in this area:
1) symmetric and asymmetric server encryption which lets the server encrypt table data and control the keys, 
2) Always Encrypted (AE) which works similarly to server encryption but the client control the keys meaning server can't decrypt the data
3) Transparent Data Encryption (TDE) which encrypts your data at rest making getting data from stolen drives useless
4) creating secure SSL/TLS communication channels between your apps and the server to prevent clear text network traffic which can be observed</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89778</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89778</id>
          <name>Marcelo Fernandes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>B2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Architecting SQL Server environments for Mission Critical and High Performance</title>
      <description>Mission critical SQL Servers require right architecture to satisfy SLAs, high availability, and disaster recovery requirements for your critical IT operational data environment. The ability to scale up these environments, to provide the level of performance required by OLTP and provide adequate resources is a significant operational challenge.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88454</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88454</id>
          <name>Kevin Boles</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>B2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Common TSQL Mistakes</title>
      <description>We are going to examine a variety of oopsies MANY developers fall prey too - some obvious, some pretty subtle and some down right sneaky! Lots of code examples with the bad AND good code presented. I GUARANTEE that you will find things here that will either prevent you from getting bad data, throwing unwanted errors or vastly improving your database application's performance.  I have given this talk over 100 times now and it is always very highly rated!</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89836</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89836</id>
          <name>Slaven Šola</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>B1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server - automatska optimizacija upita</title>
      <description>Jedna od ključnih dužnosti svakog administratora baza podataka je održavati performanse sustava na optimalnom nivou. U tu svrhu Microsoft je sa SQL Server 2017 verzijom donio novost koja puno obećava, a predstavljena je kao "automatska optimizacija upita bazirana na umjetnoj inteligenciji". 

Cilj ovoga predavanja je odgovoriti na pitanje koliko nam umjetna inteligencija može olakšati svakodnevne izazove vezane za održavanje performansi sustava na optimalnom nivou. 
Kroz primjere ćemo pokušati odgovoriti i na pitanje koliko je realno očekivati da umjetna inteligencija u potpunosti preuzme brigu o performansama sustava.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>