<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #473 - Cleveland 2016</name>
    <startDate>2/6/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat473</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Hyland Software</name>
      <street>28500 Clemens Rd.</street>
      <city>Cleveland</city>
      <state>Ohio</state>
      <zipcode>44145</zipcode>
      <longitude>-81.934394</longitude>
      <latitude>41.471447</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>917</importID>
      <name>Hyland, creator of OnBase</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.onbase.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/files/b825b999-387b-4041-88ae-4fd6e8aa2367.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>84</importID>
      <name>Pure Storage</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.purestorage.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/945/EventSponsor_14396.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>607</importID>
      <name>DELL EMC</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.dellemc.com/en-us/index.htm</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/913/EventSponsor_14262.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1115</importID>
      <name>SQL Sentry</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlsentry.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sentryone.com/Images/logos/sentryone-black.svg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1617</importID>
      <name>VMWare</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.vmware.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://bobpusateri.blob.core.windows.net/shared/ChiSQL/vmware.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1203</importID>
      <name>TMW Systems</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.tmwsystems.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/930/EventSponsor_14343.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>85</importID>
      <name>Pyramid Analytics</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.PyramidAnalytics.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://pages.pyramidanalytics.com/rs/pyramidanalytics/images/logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1318</importID>
      <name>UpSearch</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://upsearch.com/microsoft-sql-server-dba-services/</url>
      <imageURL>https://upsearch.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/sqlSat_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>535</importID>
      <name>Cynergies Solutions Group</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.cynergies.net</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.cynergies.net/images/cynergies_logo_left.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1595</importID>
      <name>New Horizons Computer Learning Centers of Cleveland</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://nhls.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://nhlearningsolutions.com/Portals/0/Logos/New-Horizons-site-logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>995</importID>
      <name>RDX</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.navisite.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/951/EventSponsor_14600.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14586.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42109</importID>
      <name>Konstantin Melamud</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Konstantin has over 15 years of SQL Server experience and demonstrates his expertise and commitment to helping SQL Server DBAs succeed through his position as Director of Service Delivery at RDX.  In his role, Konstantin is responsible for designing and implementing RDX’s service delivery strategies, including those for SQL Server. Since joining RDX in 2009, Konstantin has proven to be a strong leader and expert in SQL Server database administration, architecture, performance tuning, and business intelligence. He is also a very active member of the SQL Server community and frequently presents at SQL Saturdays and user groups throughout the year. In addition, Konstantin presented during 24 Hours of PASS  and at the PASS Summits.</description>
      <twitter>@kmelamud</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@kmelamud</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42954</importID>
      <name>Colleen Morrow</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Colleen Morrow is a database professional living in Cleveland, OH who has been working with database systems since 1996. For more than 12 years, she was a Database Administrator at a large law firm where she developed an appreciation for auditing, automation, and performance tuning.  Since that time she has worked with clients in the healthcare, manufacturing, software, and distribution/freight delivery industries.  Colleen is currently a Senior Consultant at Fortified Data. She is an active member of the Ohio North SQL Server User Group and has presented at many SQLSaturday events as well as PASS Summit 2014 and 2015.</description>
      <twitter>@ClevelandDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/colleen-morrow/2a/95a/651/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://colleenmorrow.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ClevelandDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45233</importID>
      <name>Jeff Moden</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With more than 51,000 posts and 39 mostly 5 star articles, Jeff Moden is a strong contributor on SQLServerCentral.com where he coined the term “RBAR” (Row By Agonizing Row) and helped make the "Tally Table" a household name.  Jeff has more than 2 decades of experience with SQL Server and is mostly self-trained in what he calls the “Black Arts” of T-SQL.  He’s known worldwide for his informative articles, high performance T-SQL coding methods, and methods of mentoring.  His dedication to helping others earned him the MS SQL Server MVP award for nine years and the RedGate Exceptional DBA Award in 2011.  His mantra is "Performance is in the code".</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40348</importID>
      <name>Mindy Curnutt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mindy Curnutt is a 5X Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Business Owner and Entrepreneur. Her specialties include SQL Server hardware, configuration, migrations, scalability, performance tuning.  She has been actively involved in the SQL Server Community for over two decades and has become a well known speaker within the SQL and Transportation Management communities. She is a two-time PASS Volunteer of the Month, has presented at 6 SQLPASS Summits, Live360, DevConnections, MVPMix and too many SQL Saturdays to count. She is currently the President of the North Texas SQL Server User Group out of Dallas/Fort Worth, TX.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mindycurnutt</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mindycurnutt.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42964</importID>
      <name>Evelyn Maxwell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Evelyn Maxwell is a 10th grade student at Gahanna Lincoln Highschool, and an attendee and presenter at local SQL Saturdays. Since 4th grade,  (age 10) Evelyn has been working with presentation software and has given multiple school presentations was well as three SQL Saturday presentation, and a webinar for WIT. She currently has 0 years of IT experience.</description>
      <twitter>@GeoCache_11</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://geocache11blog.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@GeoCache_11</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>43043</importID>
      <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adam Belebczuk is the Owner amp; Principal Consultant at Belebczuk Consulting Services, LLC and has more than 10 years of experience in IT, ranging from customer service to server/network administration to software and database development and administration. Adam is the Chapter Leader for the Ohio North SQL Server Users Group, a frequent speaker and volunteer at PASS events, and specializes in SQL Server development, performance tuning, high availability, and disaster recovery.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLDiablo</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/itacb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqldiablo.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLDiablo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42303</importID>
      <name>Wendy Pastrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wendy Pastrick is from Chicago, IL, and for the past 15 years has served as a Database Administrator supporting both development and production environments. Her many years of involvement with PASS include WIT Virtual Chapter and the Chicago Suburban User Group, serving as Regional Mentor, and as a PASS Board member since 2013. Wendy has organized several highly successful SQLSaturday events in Chicago.</description>
      <twitter>@wendy_dance</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://wendyverse.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@wendy_dance</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41668</importID>
      <name>Deji Akomolafe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Deji Akomolafe (a member of the Office of the CTO Ambassador Program and Staff Solutions Architect within VMware#39;s Global Field and Partners Readiness Group) specializes in the virtualization of Microsoft Business Critical Applications on VMware#39;s vSphere platform. Deji is a regular speaker at VMworld, Partners Exchange Conference, VMUG, SQL Saturday and EMCWorld, presenting technical subject matters related to Microsoft Applications virtualization and providing technical guidance to help clients enhance their expertise and ability to optimally virtualize and operate their critical applications.</description>
      <twitter>@dejify</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.vmware.com/apps</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dejify</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42965</importID>
      <name>Paul Hiles</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul has over 20 years of experience in the IT field which includes: programmer, system administrator, technical manger and both an operational and application DBA. He has been working with SQL Server since 2000 starting with version 7.0. He is currently a Data Architect where he specializes in SSIS, SSRS and database design and performance tuning.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42378</importID>
      <name>Ben Miller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben has been a member of the SQL Server Community since 2000. He loves a challenge and has fixed many SQL Servers and helped hundreds of people get more out of their DBA jobs.  He is a Data Platform MVP a SQL Server Certified Master (MCM). He has worked at various companies throughout the USA, as well as at Microsoft for 7 years. He is passionate about SQL Server Infrastructure, High Availability, Automation and Integration using SMO and PowerShell. He teaches DBAs how to use PowerShell to do their job and teaches SQL Server Internals. He is @DBAduck all around the web (Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, Blog) so let's catch up.</description>
      <twitter>DBAduck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dbaduck/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbaduck.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAduck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41835</importID>
      <name>Frank Gill</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Frank Gill is a Senior Data Engineer at Concurrency   With 21 years of IT experience, the first 8 as a mainframe programmer, he has developed a love of all things internal. Over the past several years, he has worked extensively with SQL Server solution in Azure, including Managed Instance.  When not administering databases or geeking out on internals, Frank volunteers at the Art Institute of Chicago and reads voraciously.</description>
      <twitter>skreebydba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=22766305amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://skreebydba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=skreebydba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42973</importID>
      <name>Justin Randall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Justin Randall is a Senior Consultant at SQL Sentry, LLC. He has over 30 years of data management experience in a variety of roles from Enterprise Data Modeler to DBA, supporting development in DB2, Sybase, and SQL Server. Justin frequently speaks at SQL Server User Group meetings and SQL Saturdays, and has presented at several SQLintersection conferences. His current professional interests are SQL Server performance monitoring and tuning, and career development.</description>
      <twitter>jh_randall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/public-profile-settings?trk=prof-edit-edit-public_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.sqlsentry.com/justinrandall</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jh_randall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39714</importID>
      <name>Pat Phelan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pat Phelan first joined a computer user group (DECUS) in High School, and has joined many more since then. Pat worked many jobs in high school and college, and over twenty years for a major accounting firm. Pat started working for Involta in 2007 and is now the database mentor and a member of the Engineering team. Involta builds, owns and operates world class colocation datacenters and also provides managed services and support staff to clients.</description>
      <twitter>@YetAnotherSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/phelanp</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@YetAnotherSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41560</importID>
      <name>Cassandra Faris</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cassandra Faris is passionate about the human side of technology. Her career has focused on supporting tech professionals through community outreach, hiring, mentoring, and employee engagement. She is an international speaker who specializes in teaching people how to be more effective team members and advance their careers.  She is also the President of the Microsoft and open source conference, DogFoodCon, and a Per Scholas Advisory Board member. She has an MBA in Organizational Leadership. When she's not busy with the tech community, she is avid tabletop gamer, runner, and soccer fan who travels as much as possible.</description>
      <twitter>cassandrafaris</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cassandrafaris</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=cassandrafaris</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42662</importID>
      <name>Steve Hood</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I#39;m a DBA who has gone through most of my career with few people to learn and unsure of where to find great help until I found a real mentor.  When I started at a company with a great, knowledgeable manager and learned to find others speaking about SQL Server online my skills boomed.  This is especially true in my most passionate area, SQL Server performance.  

Knowing that my knowledge came from others, I now have a second passion of sharing my knowledge with others.</description>
      <twitter>@SteveHoodSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stevehoodsql</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://simplesqlserver.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SteveHoodSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41224</importID>
      <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wayne Sheffield, a Microsoft Certified Master in SQL Server and Microsoft Most Valuable Professional, started working with xBase databases in the late 80’s. With over 25 years in IT, he has worked with SQL Server (since 6.5 in the late 90’s) in various dev/admin roles, with an emphasis in performance tuning. He is the author of several articles at www.sqlservercentral.com, a co-author of “SQL Server T-SQL Recipes”, and enjoys sharing his knowledge by presenting at SQL events worldwide and blogging at http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</description>
      <twitter>@DBAWayne</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/WayneSheffield</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DBAWayne</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42958</importID>
      <name>Julie Smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Smith is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a BI consultant for Innovative Architects in Atlanta, GA. She#39;s implemented increasingly complex Business Intelligence solutions for over a decade at various organizations. She#39;s also worn many other database “hats” in her career – production DBA and database developer--but data integration and BI are her true passions. Julie holds a BA from the University of South Carolina. She and Audrey Hammonds co-created The Datachix.com blog.</description>
      <twitter>@juliechix</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliesmith0503/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datachix.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@juliechix</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42994</importID>
      <name>Jim Arko</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jim Arko is a Database Administrator working in a global SaaS environment. He is a SQL Server MCSA with experience supporting systems of all sizes across a variety of industries. His favorite areas of SQL Server include performance tuning and HA/DR. </description>
      <twitter>@jimarko</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jimarko</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.jimarko.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@jimarko</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42843</importID>
      <name>Peter Shore</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Shore is a seasoned IT professional with over 25 years of experience. He took the accidentally intentional DBA plunge in 2013 and has discovered that he loves to find the stories the data has to tell. Peter is comfortable working with both physical and virtual servers, where he tries to apply best practices to attain performance improvements. He is also adept at bridging the gap between technical and business language in order to bring technology solutions to business needs.</description>
      <twitter>pshore73</twitter>
      <linkedin>Public Profile         https://www.linkedin.com/in/petershore</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pshore73</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42988</importID>
      <name>Andy Yun</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andy Yun is a SentryOne Principal Solutions Engineer and a former Microsoft MVP. He has been working with SQL Server for nearly 20 years as both a Database Developer and Administrator. Leveraging knowledge of SQL Server Internals and extensive experience in highly transactional environments, he strives to make T-SQL leaner and meaner. Andy is extremely passionate about passing knowledge onto others, regularly speaking at User Groups, SQL Saturdays, and PASS Summit. Andy is a co-founder of the Chicago SQL Association, co-Chapter Leader of the Chicago Suburban User Group, and part of the Chicago SQL Saturday Organizing Committee.</description>
      <twitter>SQLBek</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlbek</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlbek.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLBek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39988</importID>
      <name>Eugene Meidinger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eugene Meidinger works as a BI consultant and full time Pluralsight author. He currently focuses on content on Power BI and related products. He also leads the Pittsburgh Power BI User Group. He is certified in querying and administering SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlgene</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlgene.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlgene</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41294</importID>
      <name>Dave Mattingly</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave Mattingly has spent thirty years of designing, developing, databasing, documenting, and directing a variety of projects in many industries. In the past, he’s worked on space travel, fraud prevention, data accuracy, and virtual reality for industries such as games, ecology, health, religion, and money. He also writes, publishes, orates, teaches, and preaches.</description>
      <twitter>@dave_mattingly</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/blackwyrm</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.davemattingly.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dave_mattingly</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42977</importID>
      <name>Michael J Swart</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael J Swart is a passionate database professional and blogger. Working in Kitchener, Ontario, he has developed software for the past 20 years and has focused on database development and software architecture for the past 10 years.

He enjoys speaking about anything data related, contributing to community projects, and has been awarded Microsoft's MVP since 2011.</description>
      <twitter>@MJSwart</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://MichaelJSwart.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MJSwart</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39864</importID>
      <name>David Maxwell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Maxwell has almost 20 years of experience with SQL Server, with a keen interest in performance tuning, monitoring, and troubleshooting. He has experience in environments as diverse as health care institutions, auto manufacturers, and insurance companies. David has been a frequent presenter at SQLSaturday events around the United States since 2012, as well as a presenter for the DBA Fundamentals Virtual Group, the Performance Virtual Group, 24 Hours of PASS, and the annual PASS Summit. David participates in his local Columbus Ohio PASS Local Group, where he serves on the board of directors as SQLSaturday coordinator.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dmmaxwell</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidmmaxwell</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dmmaxwell.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dmmaxwell</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46154</importID>
      <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adam Belebczuk is the Owner amp; Principal Consultant at Belebczuk Consulting Services, LLC and has more than 10 years of experience in IT, ranging from customer service to server/network administration to software and database development and administration. Adam is the Chapter Leader for the Ohio North SQL Server Users Group, a frequent speaker and volunteer at PASS events, and specializes in SQL Server development, performance tuning, high availability, and disaster recovery.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLDiablo</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/itacb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqldiablo.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLDiablo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45055</importID>
      <name>Jonathan Kehayias</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jonathan Kehayias is a Principal Consultant and trainer with SQLskills, and has been recognized as a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for over 10 years, and was the youngest person ever to achieve the Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server certification. He has presented at numerous conferences including PASS Summit and SQL Rally, SQLBits, VMware Open Forum, SQLintersection, and multiple SQLSaturdays around the world. As a performance tuning and high availability expert for SQL Server, Jonathan has architected and implemented complex systems and solutions for some of the worlds most challenging workloads.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLPoolBoy</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlskills.com/blogs/jonathan</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLPoolBoy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42689</importID>
      <name>Chris Bell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Bell offers a unique view of how we live and work with data, both now and as we head into the future. Having braved many roles, lifecycles, and battles in the IT world, he has honed his DBA (Database Administration or Do 'Bout Anything) skills in Information Systems and development, focusing on SQL Server. Currently, he serves as the lead DBA at The Motley Fool. You can keep up with Chris' thoughts and technical community activities at WaterOxConsulting.com.</description>
      <twitter>@cbelldba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/christopher-bell/19/a08/93/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.wateroxconsulting.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cbelldba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46156</importID>
      <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adam Belebczuk is the Owner amp; Principal Consultant at Belebczuk Consulting Services, LLC and has more than 10 years of experience in IT, ranging from customer service to server/network administration to software and database development and administration. Adam is the Chapter Leader for the Ohio North SQL Server Users Group, a frequent speaker and volunteer at PASS events, and specializes in SQL Server development, performance tuning, high availability, and disaster recovery.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLDiablo</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/itacb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqldiablo.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLDiablo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42253</importID>
      <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joseph D'Antoni is a Senior Consultant and Microsoft Data Platform MVP with over 20 years of experience working in both Fortune 500 and smaller firms. He is a Principal Consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates and lives in Malvern, PA. He is a frequent speaker at major tech events like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and Enterprise Data World. He blogs about all topics technology at joeydantoni.com. He believes that no single platform is the answer to all technology problems. Joseph holds a BS in Computer Information Systems from Louisiana Tech University and an MBA from North Carolina State University, and is the co-author of the Microsoft book "Introducing SQL Server 2016”.</description>
      <twitter>jdanton</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=3997984amp;trk=hb_tab_pro_top</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://joeydantoni.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jdanton</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41306</importID>
      <name>Delora Bradish</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Delora Bradish comes to  SQL Saturday by way of Pragmatic Works.  She has worked with SQL Server from 1999 with a primary career focus in MS BI since 2005.  Delora has assisted companies of every size to implement SSIS, SSRS, SSAS and Sharepoint solutions.  Some of her clients have included Hewlett-Packard, NASCAR, and General Motors, as well as state governments and prominent medical agencies.  Delora is a MCSE in BI and Data Platform, and holds her MCSA in SQL 2012.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlsme</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/delora-bradish/1b/a16/698</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.delorabradish.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlsme</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42962</importID>
      <name>Michael John</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With 20 years experience in all aspects of development and administration of SQL Server, from version 6.5 to 2016, I have seen, broken, and fixed just about everything in SQL Server!</description>
      <twitter>#Progeek11</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-john-3403b45/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=#Progeek11</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42996</importID>
      <name>Amy Herold</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Amy Herold is currently a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft, specializing in APS. Prior to this, she was a Sr. Database Administrator, focusing on PowerShell and automation. She is also currently the Director of Programs for the North Texas SQL Server User Group (NTSSUG). She frequently speaks at SQL Saturday and user group events across the United States and has also participated in numerous Women in Technology sessions as a panelist. Amy currently blogs at sqlkitten.com.</description>
      <twitter>@texasamy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aherold</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlkitten.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@texasamy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42285</importID>
      <name>David Eldersveld</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Consultant with BlueGranite, proud dad, and developer focused on business intelligence and advanced analytics. David has worked with SQL Server for over ten years and has been a consultant in Microsoft BI for the past five. David blogs occasionally at blog.dataveld.com and www.blue-granite.com/blog/author/david-eldersveld.</description>
      <twitter>twitter.com/dr_eldersveld</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/davideldersveld</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.blue-granite.com/blog/author/david-eldersveld</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=twitter.com/dr_eldersveld</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41542</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42912</importID>
      <name>Allen White</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Allen White is a Data Platform consultant. He has been both a developer and an administrator, so he understands both perspectives towards database technology. He loves sharing his experiences and helping people learn how to use SQL Server. Allen has spent over 40 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1992, and has been awarded Microsoft’s MVP Award for the last 13 years. Allen was a PASS Director from 2016 - 2018.</description>
      <twitter>SQLRunr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/allen-white-sql-server-mvp/5/784/b08/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataperfpro.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLRunr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42981</importID>
      <name>Erin Stellato</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erin Stellato is a Data Platform MVP and lives outside Cleveland, OH. She has almost 20 years of technology experience and has worked with SQL Server since 2003. Her areas of interest include performance tuning, Query Store, Extended Events, and helping accidental/involuntary DBAs understand how SQL Server works. Erin is an active member of the SQL Server community, has volunteered for PASS at the local and national level, and is a regular speaker at conferences including the PASS Summit, SQLIntersection, and SQLBits. Outside of time with family and friends, she enjoys running, spinning, movies, and all things chocolate.</description>
      <twitter>erinstellato</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/erinstellato</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlskills.com/blogs/erin</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=erinstellato</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39978</importID>
      <name>Aaron Cutshall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Aaron N. Cutshall is an Enterprise Data Architect with 20 years of experience in analysis, design and development for applications and databases in manufacturing and warehousing plus over 15 years in the Healthcare Informatics field.  His primary focus is in designing and developing solutions for extremely large data sets that perform quite well in SQL Server.  He is active in the SQL Server community and speaks at SQL Saturday sessions across the country.</description>
      <twitter>sqlrv</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlrv</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlrv.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlrv</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40088</importID>
      <name>Warren Sifre</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warren Sifre has been in the IT community since 1998 and has worked in a variety of industries deploying solutions utilizing MS SQL Server in one capacity or another. In 2003, he decided to make SQL Server his mastery and has since developed skills in most defined disciplines of MS SQL.  Currently he is a Principal Consultant and Technology Leader with Moser Consulting.  He is responsible for BI Solution Architecture and the mentorship of team members.  He has been a SQL Saturday Speaker since 2012, Azure Global Bootcamp, and many user groups in 2015 alone.  He has a passion for knowledge transfer and solutions architecture, with a keen interested in Info Security.</description>
      <twitter>WAS_SQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/wsifre</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.broadstrokeconsulting.com/blog/, http://www.allegient.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=WAS_SQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46158</importID>
      <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adam Belebczuk is the Owner amp; Principal Consultant at Belebczuk Consulting Services, LLC and has more than 10 years of experience in IT, ranging from customer service to server/network administration to software and database development and administration. Adam is the Chapter Leader for the Ohio North SQL Server Users Group, a frequent speaker and volunteer at PASS events, and specializes in SQL Server development, performance tuning, high availability, and disaster recovery.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLDiablo</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/itacb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqldiablo.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLDiablo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46157</importID>
      <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adam Belebczuk is the Owner amp; Principal Consultant at Belebczuk Consulting Services, LLC and has more than 10 years of experience in IT, ranging from customer service to server/network administration to software and database development and administration. Adam is the Chapter Leader for the Ohio North SQL Server Users Group, a frequent speaker and volunteer at PASS events, and specializes in SQL Server development, performance tuning, high availability, and disaster recovery.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLDiablo</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/itacb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqldiablo.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLDiablo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41284</importID>
      <name>Matt Nelson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt Nelson is a Database Administrator and Business Intelligence developer for RDX (Remote DBA Experts) in Pittsburgh, PA. With over 10 years of experience, He works with more than 200 clients on general database administration needs and BI projects. Matt is also the Chapter Leader of the Pittsburgh SQL Server Users Group, and an organizer of Pittsburgh SQL Saturday. He occasionally blogs at www.nelsonsweb.net and http://www.rdx.com/Blog/</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/mattpgh</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mattpgh</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://wwww.nelsonsweb.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/mattpgh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46155</importID>
      <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adam Belebczuk is the Owner amp; Principal Consultant at Belebczuk Consulting Services, LLC and has more than 10 years of experience in IT, ranging from customer service to server/network administration to software and database development and administration. Adam is the Chapter Leader for the Ohio North SQL Server Users Group, a frequent speaker and volunteer at PASS events, and specializes in SQL Server development, performance tuning, high availability, and disaster recovery.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLDiablo</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/itacb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqldiablo.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLDiablo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>41668</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41668</id>
          <name>Deji Akomolafe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Successfully Virtualizing SQL Server on vSphere - Straight from t</title>
      <description>Over the years, virtualization has matured from the exotic black magic realm to become a mainstream standard IT practice. "Virtualize First" is now a well-accepted default practice in most enterprises and any deviation is now considered an anomaly. In spite of this trend, many IT administrators and architects still have some reservations about virtualizing SQL Server workloads. They consider SQL too "critical" to be virtualized; they wonder and worry about scale about performance; they are looking for guidance and reassurance. If this is where you (or your clients) are today, be sure to attend this session. You will gain valuable insights from what others have done to successfully undertake similar tasks in their environments. We will talk about configuration pitfalls to avoid and also review the configuration and current performance data for some of the most demanding applications in customers environments. Got an SQL virtualization or performance question? Bring it!</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42253</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42253</id>
          <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Flying Through the Clouds--Performance Tuning in Azure</title>
      <description>So between your management and Microsoft, it’s been decided that you are moving your SQL Server workloads to the cloud. Whether it’s Microsoft Azure SQL Database or running SQL Server in a VM, there are unique performance tuning challenges that are different in a cloud environment. Just like when you moved your SQL Servers from physical to virtual environments, you will learn new techniques for tuning workloads. In this session you will learn about:

•	Optimizing TempDB in an Azure VM
•	Reducing latency between application VMs and database VMs
•	Right sizing Azure VMs for performance and cost
•	Striping I/O across devices in Azure VMs
•	Performance Tuning in Azure DB

You will learn about techniques that will not just improve your system performance, but save you company money, which can be easily quantified just in time for your performance review. 
</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42962</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42962</id>
          <name>Michael John</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Top Development and Design Mistakes</title>
      <description>There are many mistakes made repeadedly that are never caught in the database design and subsequent development efforts that affect performance, logic, and casue pain for the DBA. 
This session will point these issues out, and help you prevent and identify these issues.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42996</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42996</id>
          <name>Amy Herold</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deadlock, Block  Two Smoking Barrels: Breaking Down Blocking and Deadlocks</title>
      <description>While blocking and deadlocks are part of the territory for a DBA, dealing with them can be another story. In this session we will break down locking types, capturing and identifying deadlocks and the code behind them, and things you can do to resolve and prevent blocking and deadlocks. If you are frequently dealing with deadlocks in your databases this session is for you.
</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42965</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42965</id>
          <name>Paul Hiles</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>The SSIS Catalog - What is it and Why should I use it.</title>
      <description>The SSIS Catalog was introduced in SQL Server 2012.  This session is going to explore what the catalog is and how it can improve the scheduling and tracking package executions.  One of the biggest advantages to the SSIS Catalog is that it allows a single package to be ran with multiple environments without having to make any changes to the package.  First, we will review some bonus material with SSIS project parameters.  Then review their use with the catalog's environments.  Next, the fun will begin with examining the catalog and using it to execute packages in different environments.  Finally,  we will take a look that the catalog's logging and database to monitor and review the packages executions.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42958</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42958</id>
          <name>Julie Smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Factory: My Data Wandered Lonely as a CLOUD.</title>
      <description>Azure Data Factory is a json based data integration tool. It is not SSIS in the cloud, but like SSIS, its main purpose is moving data. This is an absolute beginner session on Azure Data Factory. I will cover basic terms and operations and show how to move your data the Azure way. </description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42994</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42994</id>
          <name>Jim Arko</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Troubleshooting SQL Server Performance Using Wait Stats</title>
      <description>Sometimes the hardest part of diagnosing performance issues is determining where to start. Wouldn’t it be nice if you could just ask SQL Server what’s slowing it down? Good news: you can! Every single time SQL Server has to wait on a resource it keeps track of it in its Wait Stats. That valuable data can be used to narrow down your troubleshooting efforts and help you get to the root cause quicker. This session will provide an introduction to Wait Stats and explain how they can be leveraged to improve your performance tuning skills.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42689</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42689</id>
          <name>Chris Bell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hacking Expos#233; - Using SSL to Secure SQL Server Connections</title>
      <description>You know all the ways to protect your database when it is at rest, but what about when someone connects and starts running some queries? What if they connect and don't do anything? Just how exposed is that data? 
We will assume the role of a hacker and, by using a simple technique, we will sniff packets on a network to reveal what data is being sent. You may be shocked! 
We will then secure our database connections with a simple self-signed SSL certificate. 
Once secured, we will resume the role of the hacker and look inside the packets to see what has changed. 
*Warning - Do not try these demos at work without proper permissions as actual hacking techniques are used. 
</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41224</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41224</id>
          <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSMS Tips and Tricks</title>
      <description>Almost everyone uses SSMS to write queries and to browse around on the server - but do you use all of the features that SSMS offers to increase your productivity? Most people use few of these, and probably don't even know that many of these features even exist. Come to this session, consisting almost entirely of demos in SSMS, to see features built in to SSMS that will improve your experience and productivity. Time permitting; we'll also go into some 3rd party products that also increase your productivity in SSMS.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42977</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42977</id>
          <name>Michael J Swart</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Something Stinks: Avoiding Parameter Sniffing Issues</title>
      <description>Some of the most painful database problems involve queries that have inconsistent performance. These queries can run fast on your dev box, but not in QA. These queries can be fast in the morning, but not in the afternoon. I take an in-depth look at the causes of this variable performance. How to recognize such queries at development time and what you can do about it. When we're done, developers who write SQL will have a solid set of tools to help write consistent, predictably fast SQL.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42843</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42843</id>
          <name>Peter Shore</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>DBA 102: Now What</title>
      <description>Things happened, you got a knock on the head and when you awoke your boss said “congratulations” you are our new DBA, perhaps you came to the role in a more intentional manner or are just DBA curious.  Your environment is running but you are wondering “now what” or “what’s next”.  In this session we will give an overview of a few things that could, perhaps even should be next and give some recommendations as to where you can find more resources on-line and maybe even suggest a few sessions to attend at this very SQL Saturday.  So, what will be covered, recovery strategy (you think I mean backups, I don’t, you’ll see why), a touch on performance tuning with a hint of indexing thrown in, add a pinch of high availability and a smattering of security all of which will give you some idea how to answer “now what”.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45055</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45055</id>
          <name>Jonathan Kehayias</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Diagnosing SQL Amnesia: Where is Your Memory Going?</title>
      <description>Memory problems in humans can be caused by injuries, traumatic events, or physical deficiencies. Interestingly enough, the same holds true for SQL Server. In this session, learn about common patterns and problems that affect SQL Server memory usage and how to solve them, based on real-world scenarios. We start with an overview of the SQLOS memory manager and the internals behind the memory components that are necessary to troubleshoot problems. We then move straight into sample scenarios. From incorrectly sized hardware for a specific workload to code and schema design challenges that tax SQL Server memory usage, this session gives you the practical tools necessary to tackle even the most challenging memory problems.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42912</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42912</id>
          <name>Allen White</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Maintain SQL Server Performance Baseline w/PowerShell</title>
      <description>Maintaining a solid set of information about our servers and their performance is critical when issues arise, and often help us see a problem before it occurs.  Building a baseline of performance metrics allows us to know when something is wrong and help us to track it down and fix the problem.  This session will walk you through a series of PowerShell scripts you can schedule which will capture the most important data and a set of reports to show you how to use that data to keep your server running smoothly.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42981</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42981</id>
          <name>Erin Stellato</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Answering the question, "What happened?" with Query Store</title>
      <description>One of the most highly anticipated new features in the SQL Server 2016 release is Query Store.  It's been referred to as the "flight recorder" for SQL Server because it tracks query information, namely plans and runtime statistics.  If you've ever had to drop everything and try to troubleshoot a sudden drop in performance, then you've probably already realized the value of this feature.  In this session we'll explore the Query Store feature using the latest CTP of SQL Server 2016.  We'll review the different options for Query Store, look at examples of what gets collected, dig through the included reports, and see how you can force SQL Server to use a specific plan for a query.  </description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42964</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42964</id>
          <name>Evelyn Maxwell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Improving Your PowerPoint Skills</title>
      <description>PowerPoint can enhance the presentation of any speaker or business professional, but using it effectively in your sessions or presentations can be difficult without practice. In this session, you will learn how to take your PowerPoint skills to the next level, using more advanced transitions, animations, and media forms in your presentations. This will help you engage your audience and communicate visually instead of just verbally, making your presentations more effective. After attending this session, you can feel confident that your PowerPoint skills have improved.   </description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>43043</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>43043</id>
          <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Career Opportunities at Hyland</title>
      <description>Join several Hylanders for an overview and discussion of available database-related positions within the company.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45233</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45233</id>
          <name>Jeff Moden</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Secret to High Performance Code...The Devil’s in the Data</title>
      <description>You found code you need in a “Holy Grail” article complete with test data and tests across several methods “clearly” identifying the best one to use.  Excited at your good fortune, you quickly download the code, rerun the tests on your Dev box . It “passes” with flying colors.  You promote the code to production and go home on time for a change.

The next day, your boss and the DBA are waiting for you in your cube and, look, the DBA has a bat with your name on it because your code brought the server to its knees and the code failed.

How is that possible?  The answer is, “The Devil’s in the Data”.

Whether you’re an SQL “Newbie” or seasoned veteran, this “Black Arts” session will teach you most of what you need to know to build large quantities of just about any test data you might imagine and more quickly than you ever dreamed.  It’ll also show you how to avoid the pitfalls that lead to the DBA with the bat. ;-)</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42973</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42973</id>
          <name>Justin Randall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building Your Yellow Brick Road: Directing Your Path to a Successful Career</title>
      <description>For most of us, our career in technology was and is the result of our combined education, experience, opportunities, and luck. In this presentation we will explore approaches to creating the career we want instead of the one we stumble into.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46155</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46155</id>
          <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Pyramid Analytics - Power BI On Prem</title>
      <description>Have you heard about the recent Power BI on-prem Server?   Have you heard about the recent Strategic Alliance between Microsoft and Pyramid Analytics?  Come and learn from Michael Ford about the recent Strategic Alliance formed between Pyramid Analytics  Microsoft, and learn about the power of BI Office.  Do you like Power BI – but your company is not ready to move to the CLOUD?  Do you want to allow your business users to build Tabular models on the fly and visualize them immediately?    You can do all of this and more with Pyramid Analytics’ BI Office suite.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42954</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42954</id>
          <name>Colleen Morrow</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Inside the Black Box - Making Sense of Service Broker</title>
      <description>SQL Server Service Broker is often seen as a black box. Messages go in, and hopefully they come out on the other side.  But when they don't, DBAs typically don’t know where to look. Trying to figure out what’s wrong quickly turns into a guessing game.
It’s not that complicated once you understand how it all works. 
Service Broker is an asynchronous messaging technology built into SQL Server that allows you to scale out your application, replicate data or perform ETL, all while guaranteeing messages are delivered and processed in the right order.   In this session, we'll discuss the basics of the Service Broker architecture, its components, and deployment options.  We will discuss troubleshooting tips and performance best practices to help you deploy a Service Broker solution in your own environment.
</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42988</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42988</id>
          <name>Andy Yun</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Every Byte Counts: Why Your Data Type Choices Matter</title>
      <description>Ever encounter a table consisting only of BIGINT, CHAR(255), and NVARCHAR(MAX) columns? Did your gut tell you that this is bad, but you had difficulty explaining why? Did you know that these data type choices can be a real performance killer? 

Attend this session to learn how database records are stored within SQL Server, and why all data types are not created equal. Armed with that knowledge, we will then explore several performance scenarios that may be impacting your systems right now! 

When you leave, you will be able to explain to your colleagues why data type choices matter, assess your own systems, and implement some best practices to mitigate these performance killers.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41284</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41284</id>
          <name>Matt Nelson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building dynamic SSIS packages for more flexibility</title>
      <description>After building a handful of SSIS packages, you probably want to have more flexibility to make the package execution more dynamic.  In this session, we will learn how to use  variables, expressions, and loops to do things like: extract data to a file with *today's* date in the file name, load all files in a directory at the same time, and loop through a set of servers to gather data.  For this session, you should already be familiar with how to create SSIS packages to load data from flat files and extract data to flat files.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>39978</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39978</id>
          <name>Aaron Cutshall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Lost Science of Set Theory</title>
      <description>Many database developers today do not have a Computer Science degree and may also have begun their career developing software using procedural programming languages (Java, C#, etc.). As a result, they may not have the background needed to conceptualize solutions in terms of sets of data and therefore may not be able to develop efficient set-based queries. In this session, we will review the basics of set theory and how it applies to database development to enable you to turn cursors, loops, and other procedural programming practices into efficient set-based operations that make the most use of a relational database engine.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46156</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46156</id>
          <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Pure Storage</title>
      <description>Join Pure Storage for their sponsor lunch session</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42285</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42285</id>
          <name>David Eldersveld</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Exploring R Services and Advanced Analytics in SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>2016 welcomes the new R Services, which brings advanced analytics capabilities to SQL Server. You will learn how SQL Server R Services can enhance the work of a BI developer or analyst as well as impact a DBA. You will witness a few scenarios covering how to leverage R scripts in-database using T-SQL as well as how to use R in Reporting Services and Power BI. Finally, you will experience a gentle introduction to the installation and configuration of R Services. This session is targeted toward SQL professionals who have never used the R language.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46158</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46158</id>
          <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>EMC - Transform Database Agility with XtremeIO</title>
      <description>All-Flash Arrays deliver IOPS in abundance. XtremIO goes further to provide predictable, consistent sub-millisecond latency and unleash agility for your SQL Server databases. Our unique XtremIO Virtual Copies (XVC) capabilities allow for fully writable copies for production, test/dev, reporting/analytics workloads on our market leading consolidation platform. This allows for consolidation of your SQL Server based environments onto a single array to maximize efficiency.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42378</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42378</id>
          <name>Ben Miller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Database Encryption</title>
      <description>Have you ever wanted to know how Transparent Database Encryption (TDE) works or how you set it up? This session will go over all the steps and caveats that go with this technology. This is a topic that is an Enterprise Feature, but allows you to have your database encrypted on disk.  We will discuss the Encryption Hierarchy which is used for encryption in SQL Server. Become a SQL Server Encryption Master when you are done with this session. You will also learn how to set up the Encryption for Database Backups.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41560</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41560</id>
          <name>Cassandra Faris</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>It's OK to Talk to Strangers</title>
      <description>Tired of job boards and recruiter spam? There’s a better way to manage your career growth. Networking is something that doesn’t come naturally to many people, but it’s a tool that every tech professional should have in their tool belt. In this talk, you’ll learn tips for growing your professional network online and offline. You’ll also learn strategies for intentionally fostering relationships. A good network means fewer strangers, more free lunches, and a better path to finding your next opportunity.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42662</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42662</id>
          <name>Steve Hood</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Indexing Strategy</title>
      <description>Index for your entire server's performance instead of indexing for a single query, mostly by ensuring indexes are reusable by as many queries as reasonable.  Make the most of every index while limiting overhead of memory usage, I/O, disk, data modifications, and index maintenance.  Also look into tuning or rescheduling the queries that fall outside of typical data access patterns to keep index usage as efficient as possible.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>39864</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39864</id>
          <name>David Maxwell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Turbo-Charged Transaction Logs</title>
      <description>The transaction log is one of the most critical, yet often misunderstood components of SQL Server. From out of control log growth to very long start-up times, problems with the transaction log can cause a lot of pain. In this session, we'll look at how the transaction log works and how to optimize its performance. You'll learn how to determine the right settings for maximum throughput, and what to do when things get out of control.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41294</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41294</id>
          <name>Dave Mattingly</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Next Dimension of Data</title>
      <description>Send your data on a journey through space and time, while engaging your audience’s senses to tell its story.
SQL Server’s geospatial datatype offers pinpoint accuracy and many advanced location-aware capabilities, such as shapes, overlaps, distances, and direction. The Power Map feature can turn your addresses and supporting figures into a movie.
Turn your facts and figures into a compelling story by entering geospace: the final frontier.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>39988</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39988</id>
          <name>Eugene Meidinger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Execution Plans 101</title>
      <description>Do you have a query that you want to tune, but don't know where to start? Execution plans can be a great starting point for understanding what your query is doing under the hood. This course covers the bare bones basics: what an execution plan is, how to run them, how to read them, and additional features.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41835</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41835</id>
          <name>Frank Gill</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Determine What Data Is Corrupt</title>
      <description>There are two kinds of DBAs in the world -- those who have experienced corruption, and those who will.  Join me for this session to learn what corruption is, how it can occur, and how to check if your data is corrupt.  And if you do find corruption, I will show you how to identify what data is affected using DBCC CHECKDB and DBCC PAGE.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41306</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41306</id>
          <name>Delora Bradish</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Your BI Blueprint Does Matter: Modeling for MS BI</title>
      <description>The topic for this hour will be modeling for MS BI with a focus on multidimensional modeling. We’ll talk about a recommended blueprint for MS BI projects, the best option for effectively handing deleted rows, denormalization, degenerate dimensions, slowly changing dimensions, many-to-many relationships, considerations for predictive analytics, and tips for migrating from other platforms. Given time considerations, we’ll also be covering how agile methodologies and ABC (audit, balance and control) impact our modeling decisions. Come join us for an information packed hour!</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41542</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41542</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Peanut Butter  Chocolate:  Integrating Hadoop with SQL Server</title>
      <description>So you jumped on the bandwagon and set up a Hadoop cluster…but now what?  Your database developers and app developers know how to integrate with and develop against SQL Server, but the Hadoop world can be a completely different experience.  This talk will help bridge the gap between SQL Server and Hadoop, using tools such as SQL Server Integration Services and Sqoop to migrate data between a Hadoop cluster and a SQL Server instance, as well as PolyBase to integrate the two like never before.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46154</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46154</id>
          <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Sentry / UpSearch - A case study in SQL monitoring and perfor</title>
      <description>Join SQL Sentry  UpSearch for a case study in SQL Server monitoring and performance tuning</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40088</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40088</id>
          <name>Warren Sifre</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <description>We will discuss what is Azure Machine Learning, how it works, what it can do, and why would you use it.  This session includes demonstration and use case scenarios.  The goal of this session it to provide an understand of what Azure ML can do and how it may apply to business use cases.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46157</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46157</id>
          <name>Adam Belebczuk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>TMW Systems - TMW Awakens</title>
      <description>Join TMW for their sponsor lunch session</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42303</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42303</id>
          <name>Wendy Pastrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Demystifying AlwaysOn</title>
      <description>Microsoft rebranded and upgraded the high availability options for SQL Server 2012. This has caused a flurry of confusion around what features are used in what scenarios. Learn what the prerequisites are for running a Failover Cluster Instance or an Availability Group using AlwaysOn. We will also cover setting up an Availability Group then demonstrate both an automated and manual failover process. Finally, we wrap up with a discussion about using the Listener service and how that needs to be configured for your applications to continue to function on failover.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42109</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42109</id>
          <name>Konstantin Melamud</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing your data warehouse for OLAP Processing</title>
      <description>Analysis Services have become a major part of upper management daily decision making activities.  However, with our DW sizes reaching multiple terabytes minimizing time required to process our data has become our top priority. In this session, we will cover the options we have as DBA’s to improve the performance of our DW processing time. We will look at features and general best practices available to us within SSAS as well as enterprise level features within the database engine itself and how aligning them to work side by side would yield us at least 200% improvement in our processing time.</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40348</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40348</id>
          <name>Mindy Curnutt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>TSQL Coding Techniques - Are You Playing with Fire?</title>
      <description>The good news? T-SQL is one of the easiest coding languages to learn.  The bad news? Writing scalable T-SQL that performs optimally is an art that takes years to master. In this session, learn about some common T-SQL Troublemakers - Looping, Scalar Functions, Implicit Conversions, Non-Parameterized SQL and Parameter Sniffing.  Through examples and demos in this session you will witness the situational pitfalls of the techniques above.  With each demo, you will be given an alternate T-SQL solution that solves the same problem in an efficient and scalable manner.  Let's get things moving!</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>39714</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39714</id>
          <name>Pat Phelan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Architecture 101</title>
      <description>This presentation is a quick introduction for the DBA or developer who was just told that their boss promised a major new customer a scalable, well designed database. The customer will pay a lot of cash and years of ongoing business using this database… If you deliver it this week!

You’ll get a big bonus if you build this right, but you also remember what your co-workers did to the person who bungled the last database design… and wonder if that designer ever recovered! This session will introduce you to the fundamentals of Datatypes, Relational Algebra, and Normalization to help you avoid the major pitfalls and maybe get some sleep too!
</description>
      <startTime>2/6/2016 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/6/2016 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>