<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #702 - Malaysia 2018</name>
    <startDate>1/13/2018 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+08:00) Irkutsk, Ulaan Bataar</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatMalaysia</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Malaysia</name>
      <street>Level 26, Menara 3 Petronas, Persiaran KLCC, Kuala Lumpur City Centre</street>
      <city>Kuala Lumpur</city>
      <state>Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia</state>
      <zipcode>50088</zipcode>
      <longitude>101.692001342773</longitude>
      <latitude>3.10476994514465</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70302</importID>
      <name>Darien Nagle</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Darien has over 30 years of IT experience including former positions at TIBCO and Microsoft. Darien has worked across Australia and Southeast Asia including as Specialist Director at Microsoft Malaysia. An accomplished Cloud Computing seller and recognised best-practices global speaker, Darien is a believer in a future of Platform-as-a-Service-based cloud applications. His expertise includes establishing and embracing a customer's cloud journey and jointly developing a cloud technology roadmap incorporating some quick value-based wins up front. His current technologies and solutions expertise are too broad to mention here but include Linux and Windows virtual machines in the cloud, SAP on Microsoft Azure, SQL Server and BI, and many more.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69733</importID>
      <name>Hansamali Gamage</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hansamali Gamage is an experienced professional and Microsoft MVP in Visual Studio and Technologies from Sri Lanka. She possesses 5+ years of experience in. NET stack and Azure related services. She is a frequent speaker in SL .NET Forum, SL Data community and global SQLSaturday events and Data camps. She is a tech enthusiasts and an award winning writer on Microsoft Tech Net forum.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/HansamaliGamage</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/hansamali-gamage-37777a50/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://hansamaligamage.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/HansamaliGamage</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70268</importID>
      <name>Nagaraj Venkatesan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nagaraj Venkatesan is a Data Platform MVP from Singapore and the leader of Singapore SQL PASS Chapter. As a SQL Server enthusiast, Nagaraj is a regular speaker in Asia Pacific region at Data Platform events like SQL Saturdays, SQL Server Geeks Summit, User group meetups etc.  Nagaraj shares his technical expertise at strictlysql.blogspot.com. Nagaraj also runs a YouTube channel called "DataChannel", which contains technical interviews with top Microsoft Data Platform experts in the world.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/arrnagaraj</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://in.linkedin.com/in/nagaraj-venkatesan-b6958b6</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://strictlysql.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/arrnagaraj</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69727</importID>
      <name>Dinesh Priyankara</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dinesh is an experienced professional and database enthusiast with skills in database management systems and business intelligence. Possessing over 18 years of experience on data related technologies, he does training, consulting, and is a top contributor to the local SQL Server community. In recognition of his contributions and expertise he has demonstrated, he was awarded the Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) award for SQL Server for 13 consecutive years since 2006.
He is a Subject Matter Expert on SQL Server exams and has contributed for SQL Server 2012, 2016, 2017 and Azure Data Engineering exam development and Job Task Analysis (JTA).
Dinesh is the Founder/Principal Architect of dinesQL (Pvt) Ltd (http://dinesql.com). In his</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/dinesh_priya</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://lk.linkedin.com/in/dineshpriyankara/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dinesql.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/dinesh_priya</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71964</importID>
      <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Flynn is a Senior Database Administrator with 10 years experience in large 24 x 7 enterprise environments. He is a certified master for SQL Server and a regular attendee of the PASS Summit.

Has presented at SQLSaturday events in Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane and Auckland, Edmonton and Calgary, Oslo and Cambridge</description>
      <twitter>sqllensman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqllensman.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllensman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70267</importID>
      <name>Nagaraj Venkatesan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nagaraj Venkatesan is a Data Platform MVP from Singapore and the leader of Singapore SQL PASS Chapter. As a SQL Server enthusiast, Nagaraj is a regular speaker in Asia Pacific region at Data Platform events like SQL Saturdays, SQL Server Geeks Summit, User group meetups etc.  Nagaraj shares his technical expertise at strictlysql.blogspot.com. Nagaraj also runs a YouTube channel called "DataChannel", which contains technical interviews with top Microsoft Data Platform experts in the world.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/arrnagaraj</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://in.linkedin.com/in/nagaraj-venkatesan-b6958b6</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://strictlysql.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/arrnagaraj</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71963</importID>
      <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Flynn is a Senior Database Administrator with 10 years experience in large 24 x 7 enterprise environments. He is a certified master for SQL Server and a regular attendee of the PASS Summit.

Has presented at SQLSaturday events in Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane and Auckland, Edmonton and Calgary, Oslo and Cambridge</description>
      <twitter>sqllensman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqllensman.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllensman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72273</importID>
      <name>Gogula Aryalingam</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gogula is a data analytics professional from Sri Lanka, with 14+ years on the Microsoft data platform. He has worked with many aspects of data analytics and BI solutions from architecting, designing, developing and consulting across various industries and verticals. He is Regional Mentor for PASS South Asia, Data Platform MVP, MCSE, former MCT, and MSc in IT. Gogula's passion revolves data analytics and BI; hence enjoys writing, teaching and speaking about the things he works with. He was also involved as an SME for Microsoft certification development. He currently juggles his full time job as Lead Architect while speaking at local and foreign events, along with regular stints at the Sri Lankan Data Community which he co-founded.</description>
      <twitter>http://www.twitter.com/gogula</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/gogula</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datamaul.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://www.twitter.com/gogula</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71965</importID>
      <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Flynn is a Senior Database Administrator with 10 years experience in large 24 x 7 enterprise environments. He is a certified master for SQL Server and a regular attendee of the PASS Summit.

Has presented at SQLSaturday events in Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane and Auckland, Edmonton and Calgary, Oslo and Cambridge</description>
      <twitter>sqllensman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqllensman.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllensman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72104</importID>
      <name>Danaraj Ram Kumar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Danaraj works on modern BI delivery activities that includes corporate BI data models development and data integration in the cloud.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkd.in/1BH7dv4</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71966</importID>
      <name>Hamid J. Fard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am SQL Server Data BI Platform Expert with more than 9 years’ of professional experience, I am currently Microsoft Certified Master: SQL Server 2008, Microsoft Certified Solutions Master: Charter-Data Platform, Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CIW Database Design Specialist. After a few years of being a production database administrator I jumped into the role of Data Platform Expert. Being a consultant allows me to work directly with customers to help solve questions regarding database issues for SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://my.linkedin.com/in/hamidjfard</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69599</importID>
      <name>Adnan Hendricks</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adnan is co-founder www.AzurePlatformExperts.com and one of the world’s leading infrastructure experts a Microsoft MVP ,MCT (Regional Lead in NL 2014-2017)Member Microsoft Onedrive Experts Program (MODE), Microsoft Windows Technical Experts Program
Follow him on twitter @Microspecialist</description>
      <twitter>@Microspecialist</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nl.linkedin.com/in/ahendricks</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Microspecialist</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72927</importID>
      <name>Sina Manavi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sina is an Senior Mananger working in Financial and Banking industry as Regional IT Security in an Malaysian Bank, reporting directly to the CISO and C-Suite. He is responsible to design, develop and implement IT Security Blueprint, Strategy and Planning, Cyber Threat Inteligence, Threat Assessment and Advisory, and Risk Management and Compliance. 
He is a regulator speaker in Malaysia. He has trained over 500 Industry professionals in Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing, User Awareness and also designed and conducting Capture The Flag (CTF) hacking competition for different universities and organizations. He has developed three books under the company’s copyright in Mobile, Web and Network Penetration Testing. He has been co-</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sinamanavi?lang=en</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sinamanavi/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sinamanavi.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sinamanavi?lang=en</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>69727</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69727</id>
          <name>Dinesh Priyankara</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Cloud Data Warehousing: Azure SQL Data Warehouse</title>
      <description>The heart of almost all Business Intelligence solutions; Relational Data Warehouse, has been servicing us for decades making the implementation is complete and success. It was always an On-Premises database, but now it is available as a Database-as-a-Service with Microsoft Azure, called Azure SQL Data Warehouse. It is a MPP cloud-based, scale-out relational database that supports workloads from few hundred gigabytes to petabytes of data and it addresses all modern requirements in data warehousing. Let’s talk about traditional On-Premises data warehouse little bit and then discuss about Azure SQL Data Warehouse and implementation of it.</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 10:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 11:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70302</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70302</id>
          <name>Darien Nagle</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Consolidation with Azure SQL Database: an IT Pro  DBA's view.</title>
      <description>Azure SQL Database has come a long way, and for MS SQL, it's ahead of its other public Cloud competitors by miles. This session will look at the practical benefits of using a fully managed SQL Server database as a platform for traditional DBA-managed SQL consolidation. We'll take a look at the benefits in terms of technology and cost models, as well as a direct comparison with SQL Server on-premise and comparisons with other public Cloud providers. We'll also take a look at the most significant features that have been added in the last year that'll make you change your mind about adopting this as your next Database.</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>72273</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>72273</id>
          <name>Gogula Aryalingam</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Lake Analytics: Leveraging the Modern Data Warehouse</title>
      <description>What you feared has come upon you: You’ve been happily building business intelligence solutions the traditional way for years; Finally, the big data curse has caught up with you. Your organization wants to exploit their big data along with their day-to-day transactional data. You are now tasked with storing all this in one place and working your analytics magic on it. You start wondering how and where you would store this data, what kind of hardware you would need and and how you would learn everything from storing to processing to analysis in a short time – after all big data is a different type of beast from transactional data.
Fear not, all you need to do is look to the heavens; with Azure Data Lake and Azure Data Lake Analytics, you could get started quite fast. After an introduction to Azure Data Lake, we will dive into how you could perform simple yet power analytics using methods that are familiar with Azure Data Lake Analytics.</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>72927</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>72927</id>
          <name>Sina Manavi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Security Features - GDPR  Data Security Protection</title>
      <description>This talk will introduce the latest security controls and features introduced by Microsoft. The OWASP Top 10 Application Security Risks – 2017 will be introduce to address common SQL Server  misconfiguration sin and application security vulnerabilities to help SQL Server experts to obtain a better understanding on SQL Server Hardening and Best Practices. And Finally, We will brief GDPR and Data Security and share how SQL Server can ease the process with minimum application change.</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71964</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71964</id>
          <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing your management of SQL Server with SSMS and SQLOperationsStudio - The 2018 Edition</title>
      <description>In this session we will look at how to optimise your use of the GUI tools provided for SQL Server

We will cover 
(a) How to efficiently use the latest version of SQL Server Management Studio
(b) What is available with the New Kid in Town - SQL Server Operations Studio
(c) An introduction to some of the Third Party extensions available

Attendees will come away with an appreciation of how to maximise the use of these tools and also some useful extensions for these tools</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71965</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71965</id>
          <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Corruption - Advanced Recovery Techniques</title>
      <description>Being able to monitor, diagnose and recover from Database Corruption is  a critical skill for any SQL Server DBA. 
In this session we will walk through the techniques required to detect and repair various forms of Corruption 
Using a number of example corrupted database we will explore how to determine and fix corruption while avoiding some of the common mistakes.
Warning: Hex Editors and DBCC Page dumps will be involved!</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70268</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70268</id>
          <name>Nagaraj Venkatesan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>High Availability for Azure SQL Database</title>
      <description>Configuring high availability on Azure SQL Database comes with a few options. The following session provides an overview on concepts of Geo Replication, Elastic Pools and Azure Failover Groups and how they can be used in providing high availability for Azure SQL Database. Session would involve few demos on configuring high availability and would provide the audience a clear understanding on developing resilient applications on Azure SQL Database.</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 4:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 5:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71963</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71963</id>
          <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>DBATools! The reason to finally start learning and using Powershell</title>
      <description>Powershell has been part of Windows for &gt; 10 years and has been part of SQL Server since 2008.
In spite of this the adoption among Database Professionals for use in investigating and managing their environments has been low.

With the release of the open source DBA Tools module from DBATools.IO, with its 300+ commands, the time has arrived for Database Professionals to embrace PowerShell and upgrade their skills to support the modern Hybrid environment.

In this session we will look how to download, install and begin using the power within both this module and Powershell.

No prior experience with Powershell required!</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>72104</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>72104</id>
          <name>Danaraj Ram Kumar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Empowering Modern BI - the gap between Self-Service and Corporate BI</title>
      <description>BI is evolving fast and this track walks you through on how corporate BI and self-service BI closes the gap. Empower analytics with SQL Server Analysis Services Tabular and watch how business can rapidly derive insights from corporate models while integrating self-service BI with corporate models.</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69599</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69599</id>
          <name>Adnan Hendricks</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Working with Azure Data, BIG Data Services and Azure SQL for your Applications</title>
      <description>A Guide to Working with Data Services and Azure SQL for your Applications Although Microsoft Azure and the concept of Cloud Computing has been around for a while it is still a mystery to many.This talk takes a look at Azure Data storage – what it is, the types of storage options available and their advantages and disadvantages. 
 We’ll take a look at the different options available for your SQL applications to see how to create and manage SQL databases in the Cloud. By the end of this talk you will be ready to get straight into Azure and start taking advantage of what it has to offer</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 4:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 5:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69733</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69733</id>
          <name>Hansamali Gamage</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Let's make a complex data set simple using Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <description>Azure Cosmos DB is an evolution of Azure Document DB. 
It's the industry first globally distributed database service, allow you to scale storage and throughput across many geographical regions with promising low latency.
Cosmos DB supports for multi model database, different types of database engines like key-value, document, graph and multi API support like SQL, Azure Table Storage, Gremlin, MongoDB.
Let's see in action with a demo, how you can transfer your complex data into a simpler format with Document API and scale it in different regions with specific storage and throughput.</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71966</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71966</id>
          <name>Hamid J. Fard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2017 Availability Group Performance Internals</title>
      <description>Sometimes DBAs find that SQL Server Availability Group performs very slow REDO operation on Replica server. During this session, you will realize what is going in Availability Group internal process.</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70267</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70267</id>
          <name>Nagaraj Venkatesan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data and BI Platforms</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Adaptive Query Processing in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>Adaptive Query Processing is one of the most important enhancements to be released in SQL Server 2017. Adaptive Query Processing adds intelligence to the optimizer and improves query plan choices significantly. Following session will provide an overview on Adaptive query processing and explain the scenarios at which Adaptive Query Processing automatically provides performance gain with no change to the code.</description>
      <startTime>1/13/2018 10:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/13/2018 11:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>