<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #366 - Ottawa 2015</name>
    <startDate>4/25/2015 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>100</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatOttawa</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Ottawa</name>
      <street>100 Queen St, Suite 500</street>
      <city>Ottawa</city>
      <state>Ontario, Canada</state>
      <zipcode>K1P 1J9</zipcode>
      <longitude>-75.696934</longitude>
      <latitude>45.422181</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>978</importID>
      <name>The Pythian Group</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pythian.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://stephanefrechette.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/pythian.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>70</importID>
      <name>Tegile Systems</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.tegile.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/SQLSaturday/EventSponsors/Tegile_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>85</importID>
      <name>Pyramid Analytics</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.PyramidAnalytics.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://pages.pyramidanalytics.com/rs/pyramidanalytics/images/logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>567</importID>
      <name>DevTeach</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.devteach.com/Index.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://devteach.com/images/devteachlogo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19997</importID>
      <name>Michael DeFehr</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael DeFehr is an independent SQL Server consultant based in Winnipeg, Canada. He is focused on database administration and development using Microsoft SQL Server.
A SQL Server MVP, Professional Engineer and MCITP in both Database Development and Administration, Mike has spent the past 15 years producing and maintaining database solutions. Mike specializes in the relational and storage engines and his solutions emphasize performance and simplicity.</description>
      <twitter>@mdefehr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/mdefehr</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mikedefehr.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mdefehr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22124</importID>
      <name>Phillip Labry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Phillip Labry is a Senior BI Consultant and Trainer with over 20 years experience in SQL Server and over 30 in IT. He has been lucky enough to work on data projects spanning telecom, banking, retail, law enforcement, health care, insurance, financial services and energy sectors. As a national consultant he provides training and builds solutions utilizing the full MS BI stack. He is an active member of the Madison, WI PASS chapter and speaks at events in the USA and Canada.</description>
      <twitter>@philliplabry</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://phillip.labry.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@philliplabry</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13741</importID>
      <name>Edwin M Sarmiento</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Edwin M Sarmiento is the Managing Director of 15C, a consulting and training company that specializes in designing, implementing and supporting SQL Server infrastructures. He is a 12-year former Microsoft Data Platform MVP and Microsoft Certified Master from Ottawa, Canada (but he’s originally from the Philippines) specializing in high availability, disaster recovery and system infrastructures running on the Microsoft server technology stack. His background in Unix has taken him to the world of DevOps and Docker to containerize SQL Server. He is very passionate about technology but has interests in music, professional and organizational development, leadership and management matters when not working with databases.</description>
      <twitter>EdwinMSarmiento</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/edwinmsarmiento</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.EdwinMSarmiento.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=EdwinMSarmiento</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21686</importID>
      <name>Paresh Motiwala</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paresh Motiwala a Azure/Big Data enthusiast, Manager of Database Platform teams has led several large SQL implementations, migrations and upgrades. He has managed multi terabyte OLTP databases. He has also been a Sr. SQL DBA and a Solutions Architect in Fortune 100 companies.  He helps/organizes and speaks at many SQL Saturdays, Azure Bootcamp, Azure Datafests and User Groups(Boston BI UG, NESQL, PASS PD VG and PASS DBA VG).

He is certified in Big Data Analytics, FinTech, PMP, Public Speaking, Business Communications. He is a avid singer, cook, open networker, and stand-up comedian. 
He teaches public speaking, debating, interviewing and group discussion skills and mentors children around the globe via www.circlesofgrowth.com</description>
      <twitter>pareshmotiwala</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pareshmotiwala</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://pareshmotiwala.wordpress.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=2amp;action=editamp;message=6amp;postpost=v2</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pareshmotiwala</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11578</importID>
      <name>Christian Cote</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Christian Coté is an IT professional with more than 15 years of experience working in data warehouse and business intelligence projects.  Christian developed an expertise in data warehousing over the years and designed many ETL/BI processes using a range of tools on multiple platforms. He's been presenting at several conferences and code camps. He currently co-leads the SQL Server PASS chapter in Montreal as well as Global French SQL PASS Chapter.  He is also a Microsoft Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP).</description>
      <twitter>Christian_SQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://ca.linkedin.com/in/ccote</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://bi-blogger.typepad.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Christian_SQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27638</importID>
      <name>Warner Chaves</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warner is a SQL Server MCM, Data Platform MVP and Principal Consultant at Pythian, a global Canada-based company specialized in DBA services. A brief stint in .NET programming led to his early DBA formation working for enterprise customers in Hewlett-Packard ITO organization. From there he transitioned to his current position at Pythian, building and managing data solutions in many industry verticals while leading a highly talented team of Data Platform consultants.</description>
      <twitter>@warchav</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/warnerchaves/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlturbo.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@warchav</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21200</importID>
      <name>Murilo Miranda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Murilo Miranda is a blogger, speaker and SQL Server MVP from Portugal. Nowadays he#39;s a Cloud Operations Engineer at DataStax. Murilo’s passion for working with people coupled with his honesty have helped him establish effective, meaningful relationships with his clients. When he isn’t working, he can be found enjoying life with his family, watching football and playing Playstation.</description>
      <twitter>murilocmiranda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pt.linkedin.com/in/murilomiranda/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=murilocmiranda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14865</importID>
      <name>Michelle Kamrat Gutzait</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With greater than 25 years of IT experience, Michelle has worked exclusively with SQL Server for the past 15+ years. 
She has designed methodologies that consist of documentation, utilities, and scripts to automate architecture, design, and performance tuning initiatives for her clients. Michelle is able to see the wider vision of her clients’ business. She is passionate about solving problems quickly and providing value to her clients. 
She speaks English, Hebrew, Spanish and a lot of T-SQL!!</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.pythian.com/experts/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12146</importID>
      <name>Damir Bersinic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Damir Bersinic is a Core Infrastructure Architect at the Microsoft Technology Center in Canada. He is passionate about showing customers the benefits Microsoft's private, public, and hybrid cloud technologies to allow them to grow their ability to respond to business pressures with agility and confidence. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://about.me/damirb</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25590</importID>
      <name>Steve Simon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Simon is a Database Solutions Architect with Business Knowledge Services Inc. He has been involved with database design and analysis for over 35 years. Steve has presented papers at numerous PASS Summits and PASS SQL Rallies. He is also regular presenter on the SQL Saturday circuit and he is a contributor on SQLShack.com</description>
      <twitter>SQLServerBoffin</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stephenrsimon/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/simon_says/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLServerBoffin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>12146</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12146</id>
          <name>Damir Bersinic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1 (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Best Practices for Fabric Configuration of SQL Server Workloads in Private Cloud Environments</title>
      <description>As you migrate SQL Server workloads to a private cloud, many questions arise on how to best configure the virtualization host and virtual machines to get the best performance possible.  Further, questions around how the physical architecture impacts to the virtual environment and vice versa need to be addressed in order to ensure the organization reaps the benefits of cloud computing.  

In this session you will learn how to configure the four key fabric resources (CPU, memory, disk, and network) to enable best performance for your SQL Server workloads.  We will also cover how to avoid the little "gotchas" that could really cause you headaches.   Find out the impact of NUMA architecture on VM configuration, how to leverage storage capabilities in Windows Server 2012 R2 to enable robust performance, how SR-IOV and RDMA can help boost network performance, and much more.  You will also learn how to extend your architecture to Microsoft Azure to allow for additional capabilities.</description>
      <startTime>5/16/2015 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/16/2015 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27638</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27638</id>
          <name>Warner Chaves</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1 (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Restore Cookbook</title>
      <description>How do you restore a database that has lost a file? How do you recover from a lost transaction log? How do you get rid of corruption in the fastest time?

At some point in time, these and other destructive scenarios will happen to your databases. And people will look at you and expect you to react swiftly and confidently.

In this session we will demo these scenarios from disaster to resolution. Because if we are the guardians of our SQL Servers then we should all know these recipes.</description>
      <startTime>5/16/2015 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/16/2015 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22124</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22124</id>
          <name>Phillip Labry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2 (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Interactive Data Visualizations in Power View </title>
      <description>Power View is an interactive data exploration, reporting and presentation tool that is a pleasure for business people to use. It the one of the core building blocks of Power BI. In this session we will cover slicing, filtering, custom drill hierarchies, animated scatter plots, maps and more. You don't have to be a visualization expert to create beautiful and compelling visualizations. </description>
      <startTime>5/16/2015 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/16/2015 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21686</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21686</id>
          <name>Paresh Motiwala</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2 (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Setting up your BI Infrastructure</title>
      <description>We know BI in bits and pieces. But imagine if you had to setup the BI infrastructure from scratch. 
What do we need to consider, which players do we consider, what are the components, the HA/DR scenario for the same, what technology to use? These are the questions we will attempt to answer along the way.
What are the best practices involved in creating a BI infrastructure. We can discuss whether to outsource this project or rise above our DBA job and do it ourselves.</description>
      <startTime>5/16/2015 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/16/2015 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11578</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11578</id>
          <name>Christian Cote</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2 (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Factory concepts</title>
      <description>Azure Data Factory is a new Service offered by Microsoft on Azure that can help you to  manage your data on premise and in the clouds. This session will allow you to familiarize yourself with the different concepts and opportunities offered by the Azure Data Factory service.</description>
      <startTime>5/16/2015 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/16/2015 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19997</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19997</id>
          <name>Michael DeFehr</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1 (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Plans and Indexes in SQL Server</title>
      <description>Data access can be easy to set up in your applications with wizards and ORMs, but sometimes your queries are just not as fast as you think they should be – especially on those tables that are getting bigger and bigger. In this session, we will take a peek under the hood and see how SQL server answers the questions you ask of it. This is an introductory session, but it will be jam-packed with demos and useful tips that you will be able to use to make your applications more responsive.</description>
      <startTime>5/16/2015 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/16/2015 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13741</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13741</id>
          <name>Edwin M Sarmiento</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2 (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Configuring SharePoint 2013 as a BI Platform</title>
      <description>With SharePoint as the business collaboration platform of choice for the enterprise, it has become an important piece in the overall Microsoft BI stack. However, deploying and configuring it to support Microsoft BI solutions has become a cumbersome task for the IT professional. 

In this session, you will learn what it takes to successfully architect and design SharePoint 2013 as a BI platform. We will cover multiple configuration scenarios and the different technologies necessary to build the infrastructure. At the end of the session, you can walk away feeling confident to run Power Pivot, Power View and Reporting Services in your SharePoint 2013 farm.</description>
      <startTime>5/16/2015 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/16/2015 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14865</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14865</id>
          <name>Michelle Kamrat Gutzait</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1 (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Discover the performance hidden secrets with the Microsoft Performance Analysis of Logs (PAL) Tool</title>
      <description>Performance and tuning has always been a big and complex topic for DBAs, developers and users.
This session covers the Microsoft  PAL tool report and how to easily find performance bottlenecks in your SQL Server environment.</description>
      <startTime>5/16/2015 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/16/2015 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25590</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25590</id>
          <name>Steve Simon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2 (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>DAX and the tabular model</title>
      <description>With the advent of the tabular model in SQL Server 2012, another analytical option has opened to the BI Specialist. We shall be looking at what critical factors should be analyzed prior to opting for the model and that done,  how to extract data from a tabular model using Data Analysis Expressions (DAX).
We shall discuss many of the often used functions, discuss their 'overloads' (utilizing several practical examples) and see how to turn the extracted data into valuable information that may be used by decision makers to help the enterprise achieve its corporate goals.</description>
      <startTime>5/16/2015 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/16/2015 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21200</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21200</id>
          <name>Murilo Miranda</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1 (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>	What a DBA need to know about In-Memory OLTP?</title>
      <description>A recent capability on SQL Server world, the In-Memory OLTP (aka Hekaton) is one of the most exciting features that came on SQL Server 2014 and promises a great performance improvement. On this session we will introduce this feature and discuss few topics as its architecture, high-availability, migration and other interesting topics for DBAs who want to better understand this new "beast".</description>
      <startTime>5/16/2015 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/16/2015 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>