<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #708 - Cleveland 2018</name>
    <startDate>2/3/2018 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatCleveland</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Hyland Software</name>
      <street>28500 Clemens Rd.</street>
      <city>Cleveland</city>
      <state>Ohio</state>
      <zipcode>44145</zipcode>
      <longitude>-81.934394</longitude>
      <latitude>41.471447</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1852</importID>
      <name>Hyland</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.hyland.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/files/b825b999-387b-4041-88ae-4fd6e8aa2367.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1588</importID>
      <name>Quest</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/967/EventSponsor_14754.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2085</importID>
      <name>DataCore Software</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.datacore.com/maxparallel</url>
      <imageURL>https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-F8tuBkoFZdk/WoWRx6DFK6I/AAAAAAAABfg/OkGDR2OzZesOvgiY5D26FFuCkCdx-MhEwCLcBGAs/s1600/DClogo_Pantone_485C.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1830</importID>
      <name>Foundation Software, Inc.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.foundationsoft.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.foundationsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/FoundationSoftware_Logo_Web.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1408</importID>
      <name>TEKsystems</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.teksystems.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.teksystems.com/-/media/teksystems_com/Images/Logos/TEKsystems_logotype_RGB.png?h=35la=enw=174hash=6E1C244A79BA91199AE4E4B401EDBAA8AE9FCD55</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1203</importID>
      <name>TMW Systems</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.tmwsystems.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/930/EventSponsor_14343.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1010</importID>
      <name>Robert Half Technology</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.roberthalf.com/technology/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/870/EventSponsor_14188.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>373</importID>
      <name>Akron Canton AITP</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.akron-aitp.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.akron-aitp.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/CompTIA_AITP_new-logo_red-Tagline.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1595</importID>
      <name>New Horizons Computer Learning Centers of Cleveland</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://nhls.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://nhlearningsolutions.com/Portals/0/Logos/New-Horizons-site-logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14586.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1124</importID>
      <name>SQLskills</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlskills.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlskills.com/sqlskillslogo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70529</importID>
      <name>Wendy Pastrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wendy Pastrick is from Chicago, IL, and for the past 15 years has served as a Database Administrator supporting both development and production environments. Her many years of involvement with PASS include WIT Virtual Chapter and the Chicago Suburban User Group, serving as Regional Mentor, and as a PASS Board member since 2013. Wendy has organized several highly successful SQLSaturday events in Chicago.</description>
      <twitter>@wendy_dance</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://wendyverse.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@wendy_dance</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70040</importID>
      <name>Matt Gordon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and has worked with SQL Server since 2000. He is the leader of the Lexington, KY PASS local group and a frequent domestic and international community speaker. He's an IDERA ACE alumnus and 2020 Friend of Redgate. His original data professional role was in database development, which quickly evolved into query tuning work that further evolved into being a DBA in the healthcare realm. He has supported several critical systems utilizing SQL Server and managed dozens of 24/7/365 SQL Server implementations. Following several years as a consultant, he is now the Director of Database Management for rev.io, where he is implementing data governance, DevOps, and performance improvements enterprise-wide.</description>
      <twitter>sqlatspeed</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlatspeed</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlatspeed.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlatspeed</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70369</importID>
      <name>David Maxwell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Maxwell has almost 20 years of experience with SQL Server, with a keen interest in performance tuning, monitoring, and troubleshooting. He has experience in environments as diverse as health care institutions, auto manufacturers, and insurance companies. David has been a frequent presenter at SQLSaturday events around the United States since 2012, as well as a presenter for the DBA Fundamentals Virtual Group, the Performance Virtual Group, 24 Hours of PASS, and the annual PASS Summit. David participates in his local Columbus Ohio PASS Local Group, where he serves on the board of directors as SQLSaturday coordinator.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dmmaxwell</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidmmaxwell</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dmmaxwell.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dmmaxwell</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70169</importID>
      <name>Hasan Savran</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hasan Savran is a BI Architect at Progressive Insurance Company. He spends his days architecting cutting edge business solutions by using the latest Web and Database technologies. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer.
Hasan has spoken at many SQL Saturdays, Code Camps and User groups. He is an active member of the HTML5 and WebAssembly W3C groups. He likes to write about SQL, CosmosDB, C#, and Front End development on his blog.</description>
      <twitter>Savranweb</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/hasansavran/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://h-savran.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Savranweb</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70410</importID>
      <name>Drew Furgiuele</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Drew Furgiuele is a senior DBA that lives in Dublin, Ohio who is passionate about SQL Server and PowerShell. He's been working with SQL Server since 2002. When he’s not accidentally dropping tables in production, he likes writing automation scripts, blogging about SQL Server Replication, wiring electronics, playing board games, and spending time with his dog. He's also not embarrassed by his Spotify playlists.</description>
      <twitter>pittfurg</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pittfurg</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.port1433.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pittfurg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70037</importID>
      <name>Dave Bland</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Over 20 years of SQL Server experience that includes being a DBA,  BI development and Application development using VB.NET.  Dave currently is the Manager of the DBA team at Stericycle.  Dave is a Friend of Red-Gate for 2019. He is a frequent presenter at SQL Saturday events and user groups around the country. Has been teaching SQL Server since version 2000 and is the SQL Server instructor at Harper College in Palatine, IL. Current certifications include: • Microsoft Certified Trainer • MCTS: SQL Server 2008, Implementation and Maintenance • MCTS: SQL Server 2008, BI Development and Maintenance • MCSA: SQL Server 2008 • MCSA: SQL Server 2016 • MCSE: SQL Server 2016 - BI • MCDBA: SQL Server 2000 • MCSD  • MCSE: Data Management and Analytics</description>
      <twitter>@SQLDave29</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dave-bland-sql-server</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.davebland.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLDave29</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70068</importID>
      <name>Jim Donahoe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jim is a Premier Field Engineer for Microsoft in the Data/AI space.  He lives in Pittsburgh in a small suburb.  He loves working with all things Azure(ARM templates, DBaaS, SQL on IaaS).  He is an avid collector of retro video games! He is a member of the Idera ACE program for 2018.</description>
      <twitter>SQLFlipFlopsDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlflipflopsdba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLFlipFlopsDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72369</importID>
      <name>Bert Wagner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bert Wagner teaches data-focused developers how to use SQL Server efficiently every week on his YouTube channel “SQL with Bert.” When not filming episodes, he gains inspiration for his content through his work as a Principal Business Intelligence Developer for Progressive Insurance in Cleveland, OH.  

Starting his career as an SSIS and SSRS developer, Bert fell in love with SQL Server query writing and performance tuning.  Nowadays, he focuses on full stack web development and uses his database tuning skills to ensure that his applications run at peak performance.</description>
      <twitter>bertwagner</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bertwagner/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://bertwagner.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bertwagner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70865</importID>
      <name>Mindy Curnutt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mindy Curnutt is a 5X Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Business Owner and Entrepreneur. Her specialties include SQL Server hardware, configuration, migrations, scalability, performance tuning.  She has been actively involved in the SQL Server Community for over two decades and has become a well known speaker within the SQL and Transportation Management communities. She is a two-time PASS Volunteer of the Month, has presented at 6 SQLPASS Summits, Live360, DevConnections, MVPMix and too many SQL Saturdays to count. She is currently the President of the North Texas SQL Server User Group out of Dallas/Fort Worth, TX.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mindycurnutt</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mindycurnutt.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70070</importID>
      <name>Kevin Mackey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin a software architect with a track record of creative and effective delivery of results for organizations who want to translate data into information.

With a background as a trainer Kevin can explain complex technologies and concepts in easy to understand language. By the same token, he can take complex business problems and express them in terms technology teams can use to derive solutions.

Kevin has a focus on automation of data movement, analysis, information delivery, and of the code to accomplish this.</description>
      <twitter>@kevinjmackey</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevinjmackey/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://kjmackey.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@kevinjmackey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70884</importID>
      <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kellyn Pot’Vin-Gorman is a member of the Oak Table Network and an Idera ACE and Oracle ACE Director alumnus. She is a Data Platform Architect in Power BI with AI in the EdTech group at Microsoft. Kellyn is known for her extensive work with multi-database platforms, DevOps, cloud migrations, virtualization, visualizations, scripting, environment optimization tuning, automation, and architecture design. 

Kellyn has spoken at numerous technical conferences for Oracle, Big Data, DevOps, testing, and SQL Server. Her blog (http://dbakevlar.com) and social media activity under her handle, DBAKevlar, is well respected for her insight and content.</description>
      <twitter>DBAKevlar</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellynpotvin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dbakevlar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAKevlar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70247</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70709</importID>
      <name>Monica Rathbun</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Monica Rathbun lives in Virginia, is a Microsoft MVP for Data Platform and Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert. She has nearly two decades of experience working with a wide variety of database platforms with a focus on SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. She is a frequent speaker at IT industry conferences on topics including performance tuning and configuration management. She is the Leader of the Hampton Roads SQL Server User Group and a Mid‐Atlantic PASS Regional Mentor. She is passionate about SQL Server and the SQL Server community, doing anything she can to give back. Monica can always be found on Twitter (@sqlespresso) handing out helpful tips. You can find Monica blogging at sqlespresso.com</description>
      <twitter>SQLEspresso</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlespresso</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlespresso.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLEspresso</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70132</importID>
      <name>Julie Smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Smith is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a BI consultant for Innovative Architects in Atlanta, GA. She#39;s implemented increasingly complex Business Intelligence solutions for over a decade at various organizations. She#39;s also worn many other database “hats” in her career – production DBA and database developer--but data integration and BI are her true passions. Julie holds a BA from the University of South Carolina. She and Audrey Hammonds co-created The Datachix.com blog.</description>
      <twitter>@juliechix</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliesmith0503/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datachix.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@juliechix</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70620</importID>
      <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tracy Boggiano is a Senior Database Administrator for DocuSIgn. She has spent over 20 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1999, and is currently certified as an MCSE Data Platform. Tracy has worked on SQL Server since 6.5. She has spoken at local user groups and numerous SQLSaturdays. She is currently a co-leader of a TriPASS Local Group in Raleigh, NC.   

Tracy also tinkered with databases in middle school to keep her sports card collection organized. She blogs at databasesuperhero.com. 

Her passion outside of SQL Server is volunteering with foster children as their advocate in court through volunteerforgal.org and being a mental health advocate as part of the PAIMI NC Advisory Council.</description>
      <twitter>TracyBoggiano</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyboggiano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://databasesuperhero.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TracyBoggiano</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70292</importID>
      <name>Dave Mattingly</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave Mattingly has spent thirty years of designing, developing, databasing, documenting, and directing a variety of projects in many industries. In the past, he’s worked on space travel, fraud prevention, data accuracy, and virtual reality for industries such as games, ecology, health, religion, and money. He also writes, publishes, orates, teaches, and preaches.</description>
      <twitter>@dave_mattingly</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/blackwyrm</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.davemattingly.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dave_mattingly</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70744</importID>
      <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joseph D'Antoni is a Senior Consultant and Microsoft Data Platform MVP with over 20 years of experience working in both Fortune 500 and smaller firms. He is a Principal Consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates and lives in Malvern, PA. He is a frequent speaker at major tech events like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and Enterprise Data World. He blogs about all topics technology at joeydantoni.com. He believes that no single platform is the answer to all technology problems. Joseph holds a BS in Computer Information Systems from Louisiana Tech University and an MBA from North Carolina State University, and is the co-author of the Microsoft book "Introducing SQL Server 2016”.</description>
      <twitter>jdanton</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=3997984amp;trk=hb_tab_pro_top</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://joeydantoni.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jdanton</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70946</importID>
      <name>John Deardurff</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John has been a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) for over 20 years teaching Azure, SQL Server, Exchange Server, and Windows Server networking courses. He is currently a SQL Premier Field Engineer for Microsoft. He is an MCT Regional Lead for the Eastern United States and a former Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>SQLMCT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/JohnDeardurff</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlmct.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLMCT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71373</importID>
      <name>Peter Shore</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Shore is a seasoned IT professional with over 25 years of experience. He took the accidentally intentional DBA plunge in 2013 and has discovered that he loves to find the stories the data has to tell. Peter is comfortable working with both physical and virtual servers, where he tries to apply best practices to attain performance improvements. He is also adept at bridging the gap between technical and business language in order to bring technology solutions to business needs.</description>
      <twitter>pshore73</twitter>
      <linkedin>Public Profile         https://www.linkedin.com/in/petershore</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pshore73</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70628</importID>
      <name>Allen White</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Allen White is a Data Platform consultant. He has been both a developer and an administrator, so he understands both perspectives towards database technology. He loves sharing his experiences and helping people learn how to use SQL Server. Allen has spent over 40 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1992, and has been awarded Microsoft’s MVP Award for the last 13 years. Allen was a PASS Director from 2016 - 2018.</description>
      <twitter>SQLRunr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/allen-white-sql-server-mvp/5/784/b08/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataperfpro.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLRunr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71370</importID>
      <name>Jeff Moden</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With more than 51,000 posts and 39 mostly 5 star articles, Jeff Moden is a strong contributor on SQLServerCentral.com where he coined the term “RBAR” (Row By Agonizing Row) and helped make the "Tally Table" a household name.  Jeff has more than 2 decades of experience with SQL Server and is mostly self-trained in what he calls the “Black Arts” of T-SQL.  He’s known worldwide for his informative articles, high performance T-SQL coding methods, and methods of mentoring.  His dedication to helping others earned him the MS SQL Server MVP award for nine years and the RedGate Exceptional DBA Award in 2011.  His mantra is "Performance is in the code".</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71249</importID>
      <name>Angela Henry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Angela is a Solution Architect, living in High Point, NC and loves what she does. She's worked with all versions of SQL Server  worn all the hats that come with dealing with SQL Server throughout the years: developer, administrator, data architect and BI developer. She has her MSCE in Data and Analytics (f.k.a., Business Intelligence), is a Data Platform MVP, and a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT).  She is the former chapter leader for the PASS Triad SQL User Group in Greensboro, NC. In her spare time you can probably find her in or at the pool, she's an avid US Masters Swimmer, Coach and Instructor.</description>
      <twitter>SQLSwimmer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/angelahenrydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SQLSwimmer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLSwimmer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71495</importID>
      <name>Pat Phelan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pat Phelan first joined a computer user group (DECUS) in High School, and has joined many more since then. Pat worked many jobs in high school and college, and over twenty years for a major accounting firm. Pat started working for Involta in 2007 and is now the database mentor and a member of the Engineering team. Involta builds, owns and operates world class colocation datacenters and also provides managed services and support staff to clients.</description>
      <twitter>@YetAnotherSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/phelanp</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@YetAnotherSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70031</importID>
      <name>Eugene Meidinger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eugene Meidinger works as a BI consultant and full time Pluralsight author. He currently focuses on content on Power BI and related products. He also leads the Pittsburgh Power BI User Group. He is certified in querying and administering SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlgene</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlgene.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlgene</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70975</importID>
      <name>Carlton Ramsey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlton B Ramsey has worked for Third Federal Savings and Loan in Cleveland Ohio for two decades as an Application Developer and Database Administrator. He is an active member of the North Ohio SQL Server User Group, frequent SQL Saturday Presenter and Past-President of the Akron-Canton Chapter of CompTIA AITP (Association of Information Technology Professionals). In addition, he has a MCSA SQL 2016 Database Development.</description>
      <twitter>@eccentricDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/carltonramsey/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.eccentricDBA.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@eccentricDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71440</importID>
      <name>Kerry Tyler</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kerry Tyler is a SQL Server, Business Intelligence, and Azure consultant. His initial IT experience was in network engineering and Windows system administration before moving into the data realm. This infrastructure background builds a firm foundation for performance tuning and cloud infrastructure design and implementation. Kerry has full-time DBA experience in SQL Server since version 2000 and business intelligence architecture since SQL Server 2005. In addition to consulting work, he delivers presentations and training on SQL Server administration, business intelligence, and Azure data and infrastructure components.</description>
      <twitter>AirborneGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kerrytyler</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://airbornegeek.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AirborneGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70974</importID>
      <name>Joe Obbish</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joe Obbish has nearly a decade of experience with SQL Server and other database platforms. He works as a query tuning, columnstore, and scalability expert within Epic, a large EHR and analytics vendor in Madison, WI. In less than two years, he became one of the top contributors for SQL Server on the DBA StackExchange community. Joe blogs about advanced columnstore and query tuning topics on his blog, http://www.orderbyselectnull.com. In his spare time, Joe enjoys baking and sharing these treats with his coworkers.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://orderbyselectnull.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71437</importID>
      <name>Erin Stellato</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erin Stellato is a Data Platform MVP and lives outside Cleveland, OH. She has almost 20 years of technology experience and has worked with SQL Server since 2003. Her areas of interest include performance tuning, Query Store, Extended Events, and helping accidental/involuntary DBAs understand how SQL Server works. Erin is an active member of the SQL Server community, has volunteered for PASS at the local and national level, and is a regular speaker at conferences including the PASS Summit, SQLIntersection, and SQLBits. Outside of time with family and friends, she enjoys running, spinning, movies, and all things chocolate.</description>
      <twitter>erinstellato</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/erinstellato</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlskills.com/blogs/erin</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=erinstellato</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70108</importID>
      <name>Arthur Daniels III</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Arthur Daniels is a Premier Field Engineer (PFE) at Microsoft. He has focused on diagnosing and optimizing performance on very large databases in mission critical environments.</description>
      <twitter>ArthurDanSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.DBA-Art.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ArthurDanSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71064</importID>
      <name>Jeremy Frye</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeremy Frye is the manager of the Business Intelligence and data warehousing team at RDX. He is a Business Intelligence architect and developer with a background in database administration as well. Jeremy has over 9 years of experience in SQL Server. He has spoken on BI topics at many SQLSaturday's throughout the country, webinars, and local and remote SQL user groups. In his spare time, Jeremy often spends time trying to bridge the gap between keyboard strokes and workout reps.</description>
      <twitter>SQLBInstein</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremyilfrye</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://jeremyfrye.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLBInstein</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71244</importID>
      <name>Andy Mallon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>--</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71461</importID>
      <name>John Morehouse</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Morehouse is currently a Consultant with Denny Cherry  Associates living in Louisville, Kentucky. With over 2 decades of technical experience in various industries, John now focuses on the Microsoft Data platform and specializes in Microsoft SQL Server.  He is honored to be a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, VMWare vExpert, Friend of Red Gate, Sentry One PAC member  Community Ambassador, and 2016 Idera Ace.  John has a passion around speaking, teaching technical topics, and giving back to the technical community as much as possible.  He is a user group leader, SQL Saturday organizer, and former PASS regional mentor. He is also a blogger, avid tweeter, and a frequent speaker at SQL Saturday’s as well as other conferences.</description>
      <twitter>SQLrUs</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlrus</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlrus.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLrUs</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70131</importID>
      <name>Hope Foley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hope Foley, a former Data Platform MVP, has worked across many industries as a DBA and Business Intelligence consultant.  She joined team at Microsoft and is a Data  AI Technology Solutions Professional.  She has worked with enterprise customers but now focuses on education. Hope is an active member in the SQL Server and PASS communities speaking at events and organizing the SQLSaturday event in Indianapolis.</description>
      <twitter>hope_foley</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/hopefoley/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.hopefoley.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=hope_foley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71248</importID>
      <name>Angela Henry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Angela is a Solution Architect, living in High Point, NC and loves what she does. She's worked with all versions of SQL Server  worn all the hats that come with dealing with SQL Server throughout the years: developer, administrator, data architect and BI developer. She has her MSCE in Data and Analytics (f.k.a., Business Intelligence), is a Data Platform MVP, and a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT).  She is the former chapter leader for the PASS Triad SQL User Group in Greensboro, NC. In her spare time you can probably find her in or at the pool, she's an avid US Masters Swimmer, Coach and Instructor.</description>
      <twitter>SQLSwimmer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/angelahenrydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SQLSwimmer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLSwimmer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71492</importID>
      <name>Eric Blinn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eric has been a SQL Server DBA in the legal, software, transportation, and insurance industries for over 10 years.  Currently he is the Sr Data Architect for Squire Patton Boggs, a leading provider of legal services with 47 offices in 20 countries.  

Eric is a 2018-2019 Idera Ace and has co-authored 2 Idera Whitepapers.

He has been a presenter at PASS Summit, SQLSaturdays, the in.sight transportation conference, and the Ohio North SQL Server User's Group.</description>
      <twitter>@SQL2TheSequel</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ericblinn</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://ericblinn.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQL2TheSequel</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71389</importID>
      <name>Sam Nasr</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sam Nasr has been a software developer since 1995, focusing mostly on Microsoft technologies.  He’s a Sr. Software Engineer with NIS Technologies where he consults and teaches clients about the latest .Net technologies.  Sam has achieved multiple certifications from Microsoft (MCSA, MCAD, MCTS, MCT), and is the leader of the Cleveland C#/VB.Net User Group since 2003. In addition, he’s the leader of the .Net Study Group, an author for Visual Studio Magazine, and a Microsoft MVP since 2013.  When not coding, Sam loves spending time with his family and friends or volunteering at his local church.</description>
      <twitter>SamNasr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/samsnasr</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://samnasr.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SamNasr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>70068</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70068</id>
          <name>Jim Donahoe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting started with SQL Azure Database: What you need to know</title>
      <description>Azure SQL Database offers a way quickly spin up new databases with minimal management requirements. However, the number of differences between on-premises SQL Server and Azure SQL Database can be overwhelming. Even worse, with DBaaS it’s not clear who is responsible for what anymore.
In this session, we will cover all the basic steps of getting your first Azure SQL Database instance spun up. We’ll cover common gotchas, like firewall settings and resource locks. We’ll also dive into some more advanced options with templates, allowing you to make your processes reproducible.
By the end of this presentation, you’ll understand if Azure SQL Database is the right choice for you and your needs. You’ll understand how it can simplify management and allow you to scale easily. Finally, you’ll have the confidence to go and create your own instance with ease.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70410</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70410</id>
          <name>Drew Furgiuele</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server and PowerShell: Let's Get Serious</title>
      <description>Whether you’ve dabbled in PowerShell or wondered what all the fuss is about, make no mistake: PowerShell isn’t going away. It is definitely something worth learning to make your life as a SQL Server professional easier, and allow you to advance in your career as a DBA.

In this session, you’ll see practical, real-world examples of how you can blend SQL Server and PowerShell together. You’ll also get a look at the SQL Server PowerShell provider and how you can incorporate it into your automation scripts.

Instead of focusing on syntax, the session will plunge straight into examples and highlight various snippets of code and how they work. You can expect to see code examples on how PowerShell can do anything from comparing tables across servers, automating and centralizing your backups, and even doing in-depth security audits.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70070</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70070</id>
          <name>Kevin Mackey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Don't just code it—Generate It</title>
      <description>Code Generators are all the rage—BIML, JS frameworks, .NET scaffolding, even the humble templates provide by SSMS for views, stored procedures, functions.
Table-driven applications allow one set of code to handle changing business needs. Metadata-driven code generation takes this a giant step further. If you can describe your code with an algorithm operating against a set of data, you can get a computer to produce the code.
 - Source to Target mapping documents can be used to generate the code to effect the mapping.
 - Service Broker activation stored procedures have a clearly defined structure. They can be mass-produced.
 - Standard CRUD stored procedures can be stamped out cookie-cutter fashion.
 - Business rules can be encoded in data and the code to implement them manufactured.
Generated code has systematic errors. Fix the errors at the generator. All the code now works. If the code is so boring that a computer can produce it, why not spend your talent doing something interesting?</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70369</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70369</id>
          <name>David Maxwell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Targeting Wait Statistics with Extended Events and DMVs</title>
      <description>When troubleshooting overall server performance, wait statistics are a great place to start. But when your SQL Server hosts a complex set of workloads, it can be difficult to narrow down which queries are causing the most wait, and what types of wait they are causing. Fortunately, SQL Server provides easy ways for targeting which queries are causing you the most wait time. In this session, we’ll learn how to use both Extended Events, and Dynamic Management Views new to SQL Server 2016 for examining wait statistics at a query level, rather than at the server level. We’ll analyze poorly performing queries using a combination of methods and show how to quickly narrow down what SQL Server is waiting for, and why.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71495</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71495</id>
          <name>Pat Phelan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Relational Data Architecture 101</title>
      <description>This presentation is a quick introduction for the DBA or developer who was just told that their boss promised a major new customer a scalable, well designed database. The customer will pay a lot of cash and years of ongoing business using this database… If you deliver it this week!

You’ll get a big bonus if you build this right, but you also remember what your co-workers did to the person who bungled the last database design… and wonder if that designer ever recovered! This session will introduce you to the fundamentals of Datatypes, Relational Algebra, and Normalization to help you avoid the major pitfalls and maybe get some sleep too!

This presentation is a survey of Data Architecture for the Intermediate DBA, it is not intended for experienced Data Modelers.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70037</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70037</id>
          <name>Dave Bland</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Statistics - Why are they there and what do I do with them</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn the basics of statistics and what they are used for.  You will learn how to gather information about the statistics and how to use the information to improve performance.  It is important the statistics are maintained to work properly.  We will discuss what on going maintenance should be done on statistics.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70247</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70247</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Applying Forensic Accounting Techniques Using SQL And R</title>
      <description>Forensic accountants and fraud examiners use a range of techniques to uncover fraudulent journal entries and illegal activities. As data professionals, most of us will never unravel a Bernie Madoff scheme, but we can apply these same techniques in our own environments to uncover dirty data. This session will use a combination of SQL Server and R to apply these fraud detection techniques, which include Benford's Law, outlier analysis, time series analysis, and cohort analysis.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70865</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70865</id>
          <name>Mindy Curnutt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Parameters in SQL Server - Query Performance Makers or Breakers</title>
      <description>T-SQL programming makes wide use of parameterization in stored procedures, dynamic statements and ad-hoc queries. Many developers aren’t aware of the significant influence they have on query performance. Incorrect use or lack of parameters is a common reason for query performance issues.
Have you experienced a query that always ran fast, suddenly (and for "no reason") become slow? And with nothing changing? Yep!
* In this session we will learn about how the plan cache deals with queries that are (and are not) parameterized. 
* You'll learn about parameter sniffing, what it is, and how it's handled in the older and newest versions of SQL. 
* We will explore the problem of mismatched data types and implicit conversions - and how that ties in with ORM generated code. 
* Lastly, we'll take a peek at value list handling from applications, and how using a table valued parameter as an input instead.
If this is a new topic to you, you'll leave this session with takeaways galore.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71064</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71064</id>
          <name>Jeremy Frye</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Hoarding (Buried Alive):  Better Data Modeling and Management When Using Power BI</title>
      <description>Microsoft’s Power BI service has allowed end users and business analysts to exercise their creativity as developers.  The expansion of department resources to create elegant and visually appealing reports for themselves as well as the organization at a fast pace has taken some of the burden off developers, or has it?

Are you hoarding your environment with unorganized piles of data to feed your wonderful Power BI reports?  In this life of point and click, drag and drop reporting, we sometimes lose sight of cohesive business standards, data integration and modeling.

In this session, we will look at potential data management nightmares that include but are not limited to; overlapping data, inconsistent naming conventions, undocumented transformations, mismatch data types and varying granularity.  We will focus on the importance of having a solid data model and managing data governance using Power BI as well as traditional tools and best practices.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70744</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70744</id>
          <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Relationships Matter: Graph DB in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>Graph databases solve a lot of complex relationship challenges that relational databases struggle
to support. Relational databases are optimized for capturing data and answering
data questions.  Graph databases are highly optimized for answering questions about data relationships.  Do you, data professional, understand which data stories need which type of technology? 
- Master Data
- Networks  Infrastructure
- Trees and Hierarchies
- Connections between People 
In this session you will learn which data stories are the right fit for your relational stores, and
which are the right fit for graph databases. You will learn options for bringing this data together for more intelligent data solutions.   You will learn the basics of how this is implemented in SQL Server 2017.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70040</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70040</id>
          <name>Matt Gordon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>New Features and New Speed in SQL Server 2016 (and 2017!) Always On Availability Groups</title>
      <description>Microsoft has added new performance improvements and new features to SQL Server 2016 and 2017’s implementation of Always On Availability Groups. This session will cover improvements that range from Standard Edition support for AGs to load balanced replicas to new ways to create those replicas. We’ll kick the tires on the improved Azure support and discuss the massive performance improvements in Always On as well.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70292</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70292</id>
          <name>Dave Mattingly</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Alexa, Talk to Me</title>
      <description>Learn how to create your own skill (app) for Amazon's Echo / Dot service known as Alexa.
In this session, we'll create a simple skill from scratch, and show how to get into some of the more advanced options.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70884</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70884</id>
          <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Essential Linux for the SQL Server DBA</title>
      <description>Linux has come to Microsoft! Do you want to gain the knowledge that Oracle DBAs have been using for years to manage their databases on this valuable OS?
This session is taught by a multi-platform DBA who specializes in Oracle and SQL Server with almost two decades on Unix/Linux experience.  The goal is to give you the most valuable fundamentals and commands that are important to the DBA when managing a database in a Non-Windows environment. 
We’ll learn:
1.    Linux history and concepts.
2.    Important differences between systems
3.    Crucial commands to get around 
a.    Navigating, searching and managing
b.    Monitoring, tracing and updating
c.     Editing and scripting

You’ll leave feeling more at ease with Linux and have plenty of content and links to continue the learning after the session!</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71373</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71373</id>
          <name>Peter Shore</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Data-Professional’s Junk Drawer</title>
      <description>There is at least one in your home right now, a box, a basket, a bucket, perhaps even actually drawer; hastily organized at best but full of tools, gadgets, widgets and whatchamacallits designed for one or two specific purposes.  Realistically, we all want to use the more generic, multipurposed item found in our “well organized place for storing things”, yet deep down we know that tool/gadget/widget etc. is really what we need.  As data-professionals, we are all familiar with the largest “junk drawer” ever created, the Internet.  In this session, we will discuss some tools which are not data specific, the jobs they do well, and where to find them.  Join as us as explore Robocopy, parts of the SysInterals Suite, a connection manager or two, portables apps aplenty and more so that you can move that file more efficiently, troubleshoot that problem through a different lens, or simply know what the heck someone else is talking about.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71370</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71370</id>
          <name>Jeff Moden</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hierarchies on Steroids</title>
      <description>Hierarchical data sets are everywhere. If you haven't worked with one yet, you probably will someday.

If you're already working with them, you know they can be horribly complex, slow performing, difficult to maintain resource hogs that can really take the steam out of any GUI or batch process.

This simple but code intensive "Black Arts" session shows you how to quickly and easily get around all of that using all 3 common hierarchical structures and includes a very high performance method (100,000 nodes in less than 4 seconds and 1 Million nodes in less than a minute) for converting Adjacency Lists to Nested Sets that even a beginner can understand.  

If there's time, we'll cover a new "pre-aggregated" Hierarchical table structure that answers most of the questions you'd ask of a Hierarchy. You just have to know that a Tally Table is involved somewhere in this. ;-)

Don't let the "Intermediate" rating of this session scare you beginners away because we start at the ground floor.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71437</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71437</id>
          <name>Erin Stellato</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Store and Automatic Tuning in SQL Server 2017 and Azure SQL DB</title>
      <description>One of the most highly anticipated new features in the SQL Server 2016 release was Query Store. It's referred to as the "flight data recorder" for SQL Server because it tracks query information over time – including the text, the plan, and execution statistics. The addition of wait statistics information – tracked for each query plan – in SQL Server 2017 makes Query Store a tool that every data professional needs to know how to use, whether you're new to troubleshooting or someone who's been doing it for years. When you include the new Automatic Tuning capabilities in SQL Server 2017 and Azure SQL Database, suddenly it seems like you might spend less time fighting fires and more time enjoying a lunch break that’s not at your desk. In this session, we'll talk through these new features - and see them in action - so you can understand how you can immediately start to use them once you’ve upgraded to SQL Server 2017.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>72369</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>72369</id>
          <name>Bert Wagner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>High-Performance SSRS: Techniques For Faster Reports</title>
      <description>SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) is an easy-to-use tool for automating reports and creating highly visual dashboards. Although SSRS is easy to learn there are many tips and tricks that can improve your report building experience, not to mention make your reports run blazing fast! 
This rapid-fire session goes over my learnings from the past six years of developing high-performance SSRS reports, including topics like multivalue parameter efficiencies, how to best utilize subreports, and performing SQL CRUD operations with SSRS.
Each rapid-fire topic includes sample data and an SSRS reporting example that users will be able to try out for themselves.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71244</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71244</id>
          <name>Andy Mallon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Shortcuts from an Impatient DBA</title>
      <description>This session is about performance tuning your day. 

We spend a lot of time thinking about how to write efficient code, but we don't spend a lot of time thinking about how to be efficient with how we use our tools. In this session I will show you some lesser known keyboard shortcuts, tips, tricks, and hacks that will make your day easier. These are the tricks I've picked up over the years that help me get my work done quicker and easier. 

Even the most seasoned Database Professionals will learn a new trick that makes SSMS even easier to use.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70709</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70709</id>
          <name>Monica Rathbun</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>You're Stuck with Crappy Hardware, Now What?</title>
      <description>Many of us have to deal with hardware that doesn’t meet our standards or contributes to performance problems. This session will cover how to work around hardware issues when it isn’t in the budget for newer, faster, stronger, better hardware.  It’s time to make that existing hardware work for us. Learn tips and tricks on how to reduce IO, relieve memory pressure, and reduce blocking.  Let’s see how compression, statistics, and indexes bring new life into your existing hardware.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70031</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70031</id>
          <name>Eugene Meidinger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>An (Advanced) Introduction to Dax</title>
      <description>Coming from the Excel world, DAX can look like Excel formulas on steroids. However, to be successful with DAX and Powerpivot, you'll need a completely different mental model. In this introduction to DAX, we won't spend too much time on the basics. Instead, we'll focus the concepts that make DAX unique. This will help you avoid the stumbling blocks of working with DAX. We will cover calculated columns, measures, aggregations, filtering, and iterators.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70628</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70628</id>
          <name>Allen White</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Emergency! Are You Ready for Disaster to Strike?</title>
      <description>Most of the time pilots are learning to fly, they're actually learning how to recover from emergency conditions. While we as Database Administrators focus on taking backups, how much time do we actually spend practicing recovering with those backups? This session will focus on the kinds of situations that can dramatically affect a data center, and how to use checklists to practice recovery processes to assure business continuity.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71249</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71249</id>
          <name>Angela Henry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>What is Power BI?</title>
      <description>You’ve heard all the buzz about Power BI, but you have no idea what it is and how it works. This session explains what Power BI is, who can use it and why you would want to. It’s an introductory session that gives you the information you need to determine if Power BI is right for you and your organization.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70108</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70108</id>
          <name>Arthur Daniels III</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Reading Execution Plans Successfully</title>
      <description>If you've seen an execution plan but didn't know how to read it, this session is for you.

The goal of this session to learn how SQL Server is interpreting your query into an execution plan. We'll discuss execution plan internals, how SQL Server estimates the cost of your query, and what a graphical execution plan is displaying through its operators.

Learning to read an execution plan is a great way to begin troubleshooting performance. At the end, we will take a look at how SQL Server 2016 provides more tools for exploring execution plans.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71389</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71389</id>
          <name>Sam Nasr</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 Security Features</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 provides several new security features for developers and architects.  Features such as Dynamic Data Masking (DDM), "Always Encrypted", and Row-Level Security provide an additional level of security natively through the database server.  We'll explore the implementation of these features on the client/server for data in transmission or at rest.  In addition, we'll examine built-in features and custom implementations.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71461</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71461</id>
          <name>John Morehouse</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Databaseology: A Deep Dive Into Database Internals</title>
      <description>Have you ever taken apart a toaster or an alarm clock just to see how it worked? Ever wondered how that database actually functions at the record level, behind the scenes? SQL Server Databaseology is the study of SQL Server databases and their structures down to the very core of the records themselves. In this session, we will explore some of the deep inner workings of a SQL Server database at the record and page level.  You will walk away with a better understanding of how SQL Server stores data and that knowledge will allow you to build better, faster databases.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70132</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70132</id>
          <name>Julie Smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>H*ckin Sweet Reports with Power BI</title>
      <description>Power BI is constantly evolving; this session is an overview of the current elements of Power BI and ways to implement them, based on our experience in the field using it. Topics include the Power BI Service, Power BI Desktop, Power BI Embedded, Pricing models and some details of Power BI Premium. Sample data set used in this presentation is from @DogRates</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71492</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71492</id>
          <name>Eric Blinn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to indexing for SQL writers</title>
      <description>Are you just starting out writing SQL for applications or reports?  Did you back into a DBA role by accident?  Do you know nothing about indexes and think you should?  If you answered yes to any of those questions then this class is for you.  
This class presents indexes from the ground up and lays the foundation for solid index usage.  We'll cover what indexes are, different types of indexes, when to use them, and when not to use them.  We'll also briefly cover index maintenance.  
This class is designed for beginners and is designed to be very practical.  It won't dive deep on any one subject and won't bog down with technical minutiae.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70974</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70974</id>
          <name>Joe Obbish</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Decoding the Cardinality Estimator to Speed Up Queries</title>
      <description>The cardinality estimator in SQL Server is a massively complex piece of software that is responsible for calculating the estimated number of rows for query plans. We will derive some of the simplest and most important rules for cardinality estimation. Armed with that knowledge, we will address errors in cardinality estimates which can cause poor query performance. Demos include filtering on multiple columns, using local variables, dealing with ascending keys, and more.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70169</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70169</id>
          <name>Hasan Savran</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Multi-Purpose (AppDev, DBA, BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>What's new in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2017 has great new additions and features for everybody. If you are a developer, you want to learn about new Graph tables, new M.O.T enhancements, and new functions. If you are a BI developer, you want to learn about how to run R and Python in SQL Server. If you are a DBA, you might want to learn about new features like Resumable Online Indexes, Automatic Query Optimization and how to monitor R and Python scripts. This session will have overall information about new features of SQL Server 2017</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70975</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70975</id>
          <name>Carlton Ramsey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL Basics</title>
      <description>In this session we will go over T-SQL Basics.  We will review SELECT, INSERT, UPDATES and DELETE statements.  Discuss how to retrieve data from multiple tables.  Work with group by and other commands to retrieve data from your database.

This session is geared towards and audience that may have never worked with a SQL Server Database and is looking for a quick start for working with data stored in a database.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70620</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70620</id>
          <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tips on Managing Lots of SQL Servers</title>
      <description>When managing a single server it is easy to keep track of the configuration of that server, but what about when you have more than ten servers to manage or a hundred? How do you know they are setup correctly?  How do you maintain the databases on each server? How do you take care of patching? How do you know when your server is on fire? 

In this talk we will answer these questions and more as we discuss technologies and approaches you can use to make sure your environment is configured and performing at its best.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71248</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71248</id>
          <name>Angela Henry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to Integration Services (SSIS)</title>
      <description>This session is a very basic introduction to Integration Services (SSIS).  We’ll cover the basics; what it’s used for and the various parts and pieces to get you started creating your own projects in no time.  We’ll talk about packages, connections and project parameters and their respective tasks/properties.  We’ll also cover some basic performance tuning to make your packages run faster.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70131</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70131</id>
          <name>Hope Foley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>PaaS Your BISM: Intro to Azure Analysis Services</title>
      <description>The acronyms get out of control sometimes but the platform as a service (PaaS) offerings keep coming!  Microsoft has introduced another one in the data platform called Azure Analysis Services.  This service allows for the hosting of your BI Semantic models (BISM) in Azure.  In this session we'll get an introduction to this new service and walk through how to get started using it.  We'll also discuss the benefits and differences of this and the on premise SSAS solution.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70529</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70529</id>
          <name>Wendy Pastrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Navigating the Options for Data Redundancy</title>
      <description>SQL Server has so many options for data redundancy, how do you know when you should use replication, or log shipping or AlwaysOn, etc? We will use real world examples where data redundancy is needed and discuss which is the appropriate technology and why. This is more than just a high availability vs disaster recovery discussion. If you have ever been confused or overwhelmed by all of the options, they will be broken down and made clear in this session.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70946</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70946</id>
          <name>John Deardurff</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Vocabulary of Performance Tuning</title>
      <description>This session is for the absolute beginner to learn the terminology of performance tuning and how queries are processed. This includes how queries are Parsed, Resolved, Optimized, Compiled and Executed. We will see how this effects Batches, Transactions, and Errors. We will also briefly discuss table structures and  the differences between Heaps and Clustered Indexes. The session is led by an expert Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) and Microsoft MVP who regularly teaches the SQL Server certification courses.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71440</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71440</id>
          <name>Kerry Tyler</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Training 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Managing Your Schema with Database Projects in Visual Studio</title>
      <description>Integrating databases schema changes into a Software Development Lifecycle Management (SDLC) process can be a  daunting and often tedious proposition. Adding  the complexity of version control to the mix complicates this scenario. Fortunately, beginning with Visual Studio 2012, Database Projects add an "easy" button to this process. In this session, you will learn about the features and capabilities of VS Database Projects and how to use them to improve the lifecycle of your database structures, even if your organization does no code management.</description>
      <startTime>2/3/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/3/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>