<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #646 - Singapore 2017</name>
    <startDate>8/26/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+08:00) Irkutsk, Ulaan Bataar</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatSingapore</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Singapore Operations Pte Ltd</name>
      <street> #22-01 One Marina Boulevard</street>
      <city>Singapore</city>
      <state>Singapore, Singapore</state>
      <zipcode>018989</zipcode>
      <longitude>103.85277</longitude>
      <latitude>1.28222</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2003</importID>
      <name>Detecta</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.detecta.io</url>
      <imageURL>https://detecta.io/sites/default/files/detecta-logo_0.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Raffle</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/908/EventSponsor_14257.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64002</importID>
      <name>Robert Blaas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have over 20 years of experience in the architecture, design and delivery of Business Intelligence solutions with a focus on the data structures required to effectively deliver business information. Over this time I have consulted with large multi nationals, local government and private companies in New Zealand and overseas.

I have designed and developed enterprise data warehouses and large corporate data stores ensuring high quality data and information to business users. I enjoy working with people across a business to understand their requirements and translates these into sound technical structures. Having worked within multi-cultural environments, I am able to easily facilitate, mentor and coach business teams in meeting their inf</description>
      <twitter>rwb1912</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/rblaas</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=rwb1912</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63000</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63459</importID>
      <name>Manohar Punna</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Manohar Punna is an Data Platform Geek and Vice President of DataPlatformGeeks by passion and a Data Platform Consultant by profession. He is a speaker at various conferences like PASS Summit, SQLBits, DPS. He has authored over 150 blogs and has written a One DMV a Day series which is a longest one day series on any topic on SQL Server till date.
Manohar is a product of this community and strongly believes in giving back to the community. So, ask him anything you would like to know and he is happy to learn it with you.</description>
      <twitter>ManuSQLGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/manohar-punna/15/153/508</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservergeeks.com/author/manoharpunna/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ManuSQLGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>62915</importID>
      <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr.SubraMANI Paramasivam is a Microsoft MVP, PhD, Microsoft Certified Trainer and Head of Data  AI at DAGEOP Ltd having 21 years of DB, BI, Analytics and AI experience. Mani has also spoken in various events like MS IGNITE, PASS Summit, MS Inspire, SQLBITS, Power Platform Summit, Global AI Bootcamp, Data  BI Summit, SQLRelay,  Power BI World Tour, Data Platform Summit, INSIDESQL UK, Global AI Nights, SQLServerGeeks Summit, MCT Global Summits, Data Day Events and various user group events. Mani also believes in Empowering Every Person in the planet and spreads the awareness on Global challenges via www.EmpoweringEveryPerson.com. He is also a co-owner of 1 Global AI Meetup and 3 Power BI PUG  PASS local / user groups.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dageop</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/dageop</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.yoursqlman.com/index.php/blogs</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dageop</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69134</importID>
      <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warwick Rudd is a Data Platform MVP, Microsoft Certified Master, Founder and Principal Consultant at SQL Master Consulting. With 20+ years of experience beginning with the release of SQL Server 6.5, he has worked in both Australia and England from small start-ups to Multi-National Corporations. He hosts the PASS DBA Fundamentals Downunder Virtual Chapter, Organises the PASS SQL Saturday Brisbane event and has spoken at many SQL Server User Groups  SQL Saturday events globally. When not playing with the SQL stack, Warwick likes to get away to the cold and spend time snowboarding.</description>
      <twitter>warwick_Rudd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/pub/warwick-rudd/0/956/718</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmastersconsulting.com.au/Blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=warwick_Rudd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67972</importID>
      <name>Dharmendra Keshari</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dharmendra Keshari has strong and in-depth experience in Database Management. Currently, working as Technical Specialist for Data Platform at Microsoft in Singapore and handling one of the most critical databases support for clients.

Dharmendra is an avid, regular mentor on social media, helping several enthusiast in solving their problems related to Database management. he is co-leader and regular speaker at Singapore SQL Server Pass Chapter (User Group). He has done certification for “Microsoft SQL Server#174; 2008, Implementation” and “Maintenance amp; Administering Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Database”.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://sg.linkedin.com/in/dharmendra-keshari-a7043398</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dharmendrakeshari.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64548</importID>
      <name>Anil Maharjan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Anil Maharjan is Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Has more than 9 years of development  implementation experience in HealthCare Data Analytics, Telecommunication Industry.
•	Published article, frequent Blogger and speaker at Microsoft Ignite Singapore - 2019, Data and BI Summit 2018 -Dublin, Power Platform Australia Summit 2019, SQL Saturday , SQLServer2016 Discovery Day, SQLServerGeeks Annual Summit , SQL Server User group , Nepal Power BI User Group Meetup and other SQL Events.
•	Organizing member at Himalayan SQL Server User Group
•	User Group Leader Nepal Power BI User Group
•	Program Committee member for PASS Summit 2014 
•      Program Committee member for DATA and BI Summit 2018 and  Power Platform Australia Summit 2019 .</description>
      <twitter>Anil_Maharjan</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://np.linkedin.com/in/maharjananil</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://anilmaharjanonbi.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Anil_Maharjan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69052</importID>
      <name>Mohit Niranwal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mohit Niranwal has more than 10 years of experience and has worked with SQL Server 6.5 through SQL 2016.
He has experience in plan, build and operate  reliable, highly available, secure and scalable infrastructures for SQL Server.
He is currently based in Singapore working on design, development, and performance tuning of complex OLTP systems.
 Mohit is a MCSE Sql Server 2012 for data platform.</description>
      <twitter>@mohitniranwal</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/mohit-niranwal-590759ab</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mohitniranwal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68525</importID>
      <name>Parikshit Savjani</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Parikshit Savjani is a Senior Program Manager with Microsoft SQL Server Product Group, working on making the customers and SQL community successful on Microsoft Data platform. He has more than 9 years of experience with Microsoft and SQL Server. He started with Microsoft CSS providing support assistance to Premier customers of Microsoft and then moved on to become Premier Field Engineer (PFE), working with large enterprise customers providing best practice guidance, performance tuning, consulting, and proactive assistance to improve the overall health of SQL Server deployments. He contributes to the community via his blog, slideshare  by presenting in various SQL community events.</description>
      <twitter>@talktosavjani</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://in.linkedin.com/pub/parikshit-savjani/6/593/263</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserverfaq.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@talktosavjani</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67918</importID>
      <name>Vinod Kumar M</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vinod Kumar has worked with SQL Server extensively since joining the industry over more than 17 years back. Working on various versions from SQL Server 7.0, Oracle 7.3 and other database technologies - he now works with Microsoft Technology Center (MTC) as Technology Architect. With extensive database, BI and application background, he currently helps customers maximize on the investments on technologies to solve real world business and technology integration problems. Speaker in major conferences like TechEd India (12 yrs), TechNet, MSDN, Azure Conference etc.</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/vinodk_sql</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.ExtremeExperts.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/vinodk_sql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63316</importID>
      <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Uwe Ricken is working with IT systems since the 90’s. The primary passion for developments with Microsoft SQL Server expanded in 2007 with his engagement as a DBA for Deutsche Bank AG in Frankfurt am Main. After 6 years of operational experiences as a DBA and over 14 years as a developer of complex database models he achieved the “Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008” certification which “was” the highest technical certification. In the same year he earned his first award as a Data Platform MVP for his support to the Microsoft SQL Server community in Germany and Europe. Uwe Ricken is a speaker on many international conferences and events and preferred topics are “Database Internals”, “Indexing” and “Development”.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dbBerater</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=270775013amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmaster.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dbBerater</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64334</importID>
      <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joseph D'Antoni is a Senior Consultant and Microsoft Data Platform MVP with over 20 years of experience working in both Fortune 500 and smaller firms. He is a Principal Consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates and lives in Malvern, PA. He is a frequent speaker at major tech events like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and Enterprise Data World. He blogs about all topics technology at joeydantoni.com. He believes that no single platform is the answer to all technology problems. Joseph holds a BS in Computer Information Systems from Louisiana Tech University and an MBA from North Carolina State University, and is the co-author of the Microsoft book "Introducing SQL Server 2016”.</description>
      <twitter>jdanton</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=3997984amp;trk=hb_tab_pro_top</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://joeydantoni.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jdanton</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>62999</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66610</importID>
      <name>Tejas Shah</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tejas is a Principal Program Manager with SQL Tiger team at Microsoft. Prior to that he worked as an Escalation Engineer with SQL support team for over 13 years and has an overall industrial experience of over 19 years.</description>
      <twitter>@mr_tejs</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tejas-shah-72a62027/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mr_tejs</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69062</importID>
      <name>Prakash Sawant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Prakash has more than 16 years of experience across APAC, Middle East, USA and Singapore engaging Chief Financial Officers, CXO’s in telco, government, financial sectors, and assisting them in building business solutions in Cloud, data acquisition, data security, management and Business Insights. He has designed hybrid solutions unifying on premise and cloud offerings, helping customers to get better ROI. 
Prakash Has acknowledged hands on experience in the IT industry which facilitated him speak at international conferences, operate in presales environments and conduct actual design and delivery services.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/prakash-sawant-8b29902/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66620</importID>
      <name>Martin Catherall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin is a data consultant in Melbourne, Australia, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, and PASS Regional Mentor for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region.
Martin founded the Christchurch, New Zealand PASS Local Group and lead the group for a number of years before relocating to Melbourne.
He has been using SQL Server in various roles since 2000. In addition to anything data related, he enjoys playing the guitar and having fun with his family.</description>
      <twitter>MartyCatherall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/martincatherall</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://martincatherall.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MartyCatherall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66598</importID>
      <name>Dinesh Priyankara</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dinesh is an experienced professional and database enthusiast with skills in database management systems and business intelligence. Possessing over 18 years of experience on data related technologies, he does training, consulting, and is a top contributor to the local SQL Server community. In recognition of his contributions and expertise he has demonstrated, he was awarded the Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) award for SQL Server for 13 consecutive years since 2006.
He is a Subject Matter Expert on SQL Server exams and has contributed for SQL Server 2012, 2016, 2017 and Azure Data Engineering exam development and Job Task Analysis (JTA).
Dinesh is the Founder/Principal Architect of dinesQL (Pvt) Ltd (http://dinesql.com). In his</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/dinesh_priya</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://lk.linkedin.com/in/dineshpriyankara/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dinesql.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/dinesh_priya</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68526</importID>
      <name>Sarbjit Singh</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sarbjit brings 24 years of IT experience spanning assessments, consulting, implementation and training for a wide range of Microsoft technologies from mid 1990s to 2017.  Sarbjit has cross-functional experience serving customer environments across a wide range of industries. Financial, Public Sector, Telecommunication, Media, Energy, Transport and Healthcare sectors.

Sarbjit have had experience leading and working with culturally diverse international teams across US, Europe, Asia Pacific and ANZ regions delivering business transformation outcomes for client organizations.  Sarbjit now runs experience4live.com as a life coach and is a FIA licensed race car driver, underwater photography and videography and travels.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sarbjitgill</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarbjitsinghgill</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/PublicProfile/4040012?fullName=Sarbjit%20%20Singh</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sarbjitgill</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64235</importID>
      <name>Hamish Watson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hamish Watson is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware Expert with a passion for efficient database and application deployment using DevOps methodologies. 

He has 20+ years of IT experience in managing and deploying large scale databases on SQL Server technologies. 

He has been managing SQL Server since SQL Server 2000, and pragmatic approaches to delivering business value to clients is his career passion.

Educating and helping others learn is a driver for Hamish. He is a Director-At-Large on the PASS Board, international speaker, and a repeat guest lecturer at a local university.</description>
      <twitter>theHybridDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/in/hamishwatson8</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/the-hybrid-dbas-blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=theHybridDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64071</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denny Cherry is the owner and principal consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates Consulting and has over a decade of experience working with platforms such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Microsoft SQL Server, Hyper-V, vSphere, and Enterprise Storage solutions. Denny’s areas of technical expertise include system architecture, performance tuning, security, replication, and troubleshooting. Denny currently holds several Microsoft Certifications related to SQL Server 2000 through 2019, including being a Microsoft Certified Master, Microsoft MVP and VMware vExpert Award.</description>
      <twitter>mrdenny</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrdenny</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.dcac.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mrdenny</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65324</importID>
      <name>Karen Lopez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Karen Lopez is a Sr. Project Manager and Architect for InfoAdvisors. A frequent speaker at conferences and local user groups, she has 20+ years of experience in project and data management on large, multi-project programs. Karen is a chronic volunteer, a Data Platform MVP, and an active advocate for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education and data quality.

Karen’s presentations are known for their lively and interactive approach to learning. Her motto: “Love Your Data!”</description>
      <twitter>datachick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/karenlopez</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datamodel.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=datachick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66649</importID>
      <name>Andreas Wolter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andreas Wolter is a Program Manager for SQL Server- and Azure Security at Microsoft. In this role he is working on Security features of SQL Server, Azure SQL Database and Managed Instance. He is currently focusing on “Separation of Duties”-concepts and RBAC-Integration. He has 18 years of experience with SQL Server before joining Microsoft and is the founder of Sarpedon Quality Lab, the Germany-based company specialized on SQL Server HA, Performance and Security. He is Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) for SQL Server and Microsoft Certified Solutions Master for the Data Platform (MCSM) and was recognized as MVP for multiple years in row.</description>
      <twitter>AndreasWolter</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/andreaswolter</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.andreas-wolter.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndreasWolter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>63316</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63316</id>
          <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF12</name>
      </location>
      <title>Zombie Attack Against Clustered Indexes - Who really need them!</title>
      <description>Clustered Index zombies come out of their graves to make the peace loving Heaps to one of them in your databases. Try to attack them or find a fair way to make them living together in peaceful harmony.

If you ask experts about using a clustered index you will in most cases hear the following statements: Yes, you need a narrow and contiguous clustered index for your table for good performance. Last but not least Microsoft Azure Databases requires clustered indexes but there might be situations when workloads and queries will suffer from wrong implemented clustered indexes.

Watch the demos which show in an impressive way that clustered indexes are not always the best choice. Build your clustered indexes wise or - as the demos will show - forgo for it for a better scaling. Become aware of the pros and cons of Clustered Indexes and make a wise decision when to use clustered indexes and the correct key attributes for it.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>62999</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>62999</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>2,4,8  16 - Upgrade your journey with SQL Server</title>
      <description>2,4,8  16 - these aren't just numbers to count or calculate. These are years that how SQL Server evolved as number of years!

Why Upgrade? 
Data Platform Upgrade topic has been a popular session that I've presented in major conferences like Microsoft Tech-Ed (North America, Europe  India) and SQLbits since 2008. 

In this session, we will overview in depth end-to-end upgrade process that covers the essential phases, steps and issues involved in upgrading  SQL Server (2000 to  2012),  SQL Server 2014 (with a good overview on 2016 too) by using best practices and available resources. 

What to-do and what not-to-do?

A popular session that I have been presenting since the year 2008, in MS Tech-Ed, SQL Saturday  SQLbits UK.
We will cover the complete upgrade cycle, including the preparation tasks, upgrade tasks, and post-upgrade tasks. Real-world examples from my Consulting experience expanding on why  how such a solution.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64002</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64002</id>
          <name>Robert Blaas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF15</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Quality and the BI Life Cycle</title>
      <description>In today’s high pressured business environments the need for agile BI has forced users to produce information at an ever increasing rate. The aspect of data quality is often overlooked as the need to bring out information at a more rapid pace forces people to cut corners. More often than not, data quality plays a back seat role until serious questions are raised regarding some of the information that is being published and as a result questions are asked about the reliability of the decision making process.This session will show business users how DQS can assist their business in identifying, resolving and managing data quality issues through a couple of clear and concise examples._The session will also show how the DQS engine can integrate with SSIS backend data warehousing package to assist in automating data quality issue resolution, again through clear and concise code examples.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64548</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64548</id>
          <name>Anil Maharjan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Power Query to Tell Your Story from Your Facebook Data</title>
      <description>The session is mainly for the one who is trying to extract the story behind their Facebook data by using Power Query. By using Power Query you can extract your Facebook data easily and do analysis your own story by using your own Facebook data. Talking about Power Query: Microsoft Power Query for Excel is an Excel add-in that enhances the self- service Business Intelligence experience in Excel by simplifying data discovery, access and collaboration. Power Query can connect data across a wide variety of sources, where Facebook is one of the data source. This session helps you to learn about the Power Query, Power View, and Power BI and mainly helps you to do self-service BI by using your own Facebook data with the help of Power Query, Power View ,MS-Excel 2013 and Power BI.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65324</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65324</id>
          <name>Karen Lopez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR01</name>
      </location>
      <title>1 Database, Many Data Models: Database Designers and Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <description>Azure Cosmos DB is Microsoft's globally-distributed database as a service which supports multiple database models such as graph, key value, and document data models -- with the ability to add new models in the future.

In this hands-on session, attendees will learn about and use the features of Azure Cosmos DB, with these topics highlighted:

- Key Value Features
- Graph Features
- Document Features
- Column Family
- Scalability  Elasticity
- Global Distribution
- Tunable Consistency

It is the first cloud database to natively support a multitude of data models and popular query APIs, is built on a novel database engine capable of ingesting sustained volumes of data and provides blazing-fast queries – all without having to deal with schema or index management. And it is the first cloud database to offer five well-defined consistency models so you can choose just the right one for your app.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 9:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66620</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66620</id>
          <name>Martin Catherall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>In memory OLTP  - what can it do for me?</title>
      <description>In Memory OLTP came along in SQL Server 2014 along with several limitations.
It was still really useful – as long as your use case suited the limitations.
SQL Server 2016 removes several of these limitations and widens the use cases of in-memory OLTP.
For example, even if you are not taking advantage of in-memory tables, you can probably leverage performance improvements by replacing traditional table variables and both local and global temporary tables with in memory implementations. Now you’ll be able to say that table variable is truly in memory!
Come along to this session and learn about some of features of in memory OLTP  - or Hekaton as a lot of people refer to this -  and how you may be able to leverage these high performance features in both new and existing applications.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63459</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63459</id>
          <name>Manohar Punna</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF15</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building a Centralised Database Maintenance and Monitoring Solution</title>
      <description>Database Professional is always challenged with monitoring and maintenance across the environment. Be it 10 server or a 1000 servers, would it be easier to have a centralised solution? 
In this session I will walk you through the simple steps of building a centralised database maintenance and monitoring solution. This solution will help a database professional to query all the monitored instances, collect performance metrics, run customized scripts and any maintenance task a database professional needs to perform across the database environment. 
Talk about a easy DBA life, this is a definite simple solution you should build.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64235</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64235</id>
          <name>Hamish Watson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>DevOPs and the DBA</title>
      <description>You may have heard the word "DevOps" and wondered whether it is just another buzzword and/or what it can do for you.

In this session I will demystify the concepts of DevOps and we will look at two aspects of DevOps - Continuous Integration  Continuous Delivery.

Continuous Integration is the practice in which software developers frequently integrate their work with that of other members of the development team.It also involves automating tests around the integrated work

​Continuous Delivery is the next step after Continuous Integration in the deployment pipeline and is the process of automating the deployment of software to  test, staging, and production environments.

Database migrations/changes are an area that may not be typically automated or utilise Continuous Delivery.

Through the use of a comprehensive live demo to a running production database the audience will learn the benefits and how to implement Continuous Delivery in their database systems deployment pipelin</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66610</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66610</id>
          <name>Tejas Shah</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR01</name>
      </location>
      <title>Improve data load speed and query performance with Columnstore indexes</title>
      <description>Is data load performance into columnstore slowing you down? Should you drop nonclustered indexes before loading data? What batchsize should you choose? How should you handle large number of Updates/Deletes? Columnstore index can speed up the performance of analytics queries significantly but are you getting the best performance possible? Come to this session to learn the best practices and the techniques customers have used to load data in parallel with minimal or reduced logging into columnstore index. Specifically, we will cover data load using BCP, Bulk Insert, SSIS or MERGE command, concurrent trickle insert in IOT scenario as well as moving data from staging table. We will also talk about how to diagnose performance issues in queries accessing columnstore index and the steps you can take to troubleshoot.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66598</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66598</id>
          <name>Dinesh Priyankara</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>Cloud Data Warehousing: Azure SQL Data Warehouse</title>
      <description>The heart of almost all Business Intelligence solutions; Relational Data Warehouse, has been servicing us for decades making the implementation is complete and success. It was always an On-Premises database, but now it is available as a Database-as-a-Service with Microsoft Azure, called Azure SQL Data Warehouse. It is a MPP cloud-based, scale-out relational database that supports workloads from few hundred gigabytes to petabytes of data and it addresses all modern requirements in data warehousing. Let’s talk about traditional On-Premises data warehouse little bit and then discuss about Azure SQL Data Warehouse and implementation of it.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68526</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68526</id>
          <name>Sarbjit Singh</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF12</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Data for Digital Transformation</title>
      <description>One of the main drivers for digital transformation reported in the survey was optimizing customer experiences and engagement. More than 60 percent of executives identified delivering a superior experience for customers and creating new sources of customer value as important factors in determining an organization’s success as a digital business. These goals aren’t just pipedreams either – organizations are backing this assertion with serious budgetary investment, with half of respondents planning to invest in building applications in the next year that support the customer engagement model.  So what role does data play in achieving these goals through a successful digital transformation? I will present details of the answer to this questions. I will cover how the data a company collects can be analyzed for insights that help the company personalize its interactions with customers. Data can be used to find trends around a customer’s habits, which is typically indicative of their future</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68525</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68525</id>
          <name>Parikshit Savjani</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR01</name>
      </location>
      <title>Upgrade to SQL Server 2017: Intelligent Diagnostics Just Built-In</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 and SQL Server 2017 Just Works! But if you are a IT Professional you want to be armed with all the right diagnostics to react to a mission critical problem or tune the engine to the needs for your business. Dev-Ops also requires the right tools to build and tune queries for maximum performance. SQL Server 2016 and 2017 have all the diagnostics you need just built-in to the product. These are the foundation for great tools from vendors such as SentryOne, RedGate, SolarWinds, and Idera. We also have intelligence built-into the engine based on these diagnostics to automate, learn, and adapt. In this session we will show you the wide variety of these diagnostics with testimonies from vendors and SQL MVPs. You will learn why SQL Server diagnostics are the best in the industry, built-in, and spans all platforms across SQL Server, Azure, and Linux</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66649</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66649</id>
          <name>Andreas Wolter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR01</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2017: Better HA  DR</title>
      <description>The newest release of SQL Server brings several important bits that can make a difference for your HA and DR strategies. In this session, we will look at those improvement that concern Always On Availability Groups and other areas that help to keep your system available not just technically but also performance-wise. We will also look at the lesser known automatic seeding option that exists since SQL Server 2016 and how new DMVs help to analyze and estimate backup requirements  effects. If you are unsure if SQL Server 2017 is a distinguishing factor from former releases, and you have high demands for HA  DR, this session shall give you the answers.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64071</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64071</id>
          <name>Denny Cherry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF12</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing SQL Server Performance in a Virtual Environment</title>
      <description>In this session we'll look over some of the things which you should be looking at within your virtual environment to ensure that you are getting the performance out of it that you should be.  This will include how to look for CPU performance issues at the host level.  We will also be discussing the Memory Balloon drivers and what they actually do, and how you should be configuring them, and why.  We'll discuss some of the memory sharing technologies which are built into vSphere and Hyper-V and how they relate to SQL Server.  Then we will finish up with some storage configuration options to look at.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63000</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63000</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data with Azure: where to begin? Concepts and best practices</title>
      <description>In order to ascertain the abilities of cloud computing platform, let us overview what is available  offered on Microsoft Azure.

Microsoft Azure has the ability to move, store and analyze data within the cloud. It is essential to evaluate multiple opportunities and options with Microsoft Azure data insights. In this session let us talk about strategies on data storage, data partitioning and availability options with Azure. A tour on how best these Azure components can help you achieve success for your Big Data platform.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69134</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69134</id>
          <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF12</name>
      </location>
      <title>An Introduction to SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2017 being released brings to the table some new features and improvements in quick succession from SQL Server 2016. In this session we will look at a subset of the new /or improved features that SQL Server 2017 brings to the table.
              
              From Analytics, Availability, Configuration and Performance there is something for everyone in this session to introduce you to the latest version of SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67918</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67918</id>
          <name>Vinod Kumar M</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF12</name>
      </location>
      <title>Become a SQL Ninja: SQL Server Tools</title>
      <description>Abstract: In this session I will walk through some of the out-of-box SQL Server tools that you will need to know or never knew could be so much fun. A number of commandline utilities exist with SQL Server that we are never exposed to. In this session, I will take a tour of each of these tools and the scenario’s that real world customers used them in innovative ways.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67972</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67972</id>
          <name>Dharmendra Keshari</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 Query Store</title>
      <description>The Query Store feature is a game changer for how SQL Server professionals troubleshoot query performance. It provides the ability to natively capture baseline data within SQL Server. Using the performance metrics the Query Store records, we can decide which Execution Plan SQL Server should use when executing a specific query.
During this session we will take a thorough look at the Query Store, its architecture, the build-in reporting, DMVs and the performance impact of enabling the Query Store. No matter if you are a DBA or developer, the Query Store has information that can help you</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69052</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69052</id>
          <name>Mohit Niranwal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR01</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Unknown Mysteries: The Case of Transparent Data Encryp</title>
      <description>Basic Overview of Encryption concepts supported by SQL Server like HASHES, ASYMMETRIC KEYS, SYMMETRIC KEYS, CERTIFICATES, ENCRYPTION ALGORITHMS, Service Master Key (SMK), Database Master Key (DMK), Database Encryption Key (DEK).
Then we will work through TDE Overview, Availability, What is encrypted/not encrypted and Implementation steps and best practices.
Finally, we will explore hidden mysteries of TDE  and decryption pitfall.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69062</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69062</id>
          <name>Prakash Sawant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF15</name>
      </location>
      <title>Graph Data processing with SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2017 and Azure SQL Database now enable you to describe a Graph (a network structure) and store data in the form of nodes and edges making up the graph</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>62915</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>62915</id>
          <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF15</name>
      </location>
      <title>Beginning Data Science-From Novice to Professional</title>
      <description>Where to begin the step 1 of data science to become a Data scientist? What are these Data Scientists up to? This is an initial data science session, for a novice and learn how easily you can step in to Data Science and start to become a professional.

 How can we see and try using a data scientist statistical model in our day to day familiar tool like Microsoft SQL Server?

 Thanks to Microsoft for integrating R Revolution within SQL Server 2016. We all now have the opportunity to use R packages and see the results within SQL 2016 and also to utilize it for any applications and/or Reporting services.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64334</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64334</id>
          <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR01</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server on Linux--Linux for the SQL DBA</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn about the new release of SQL Server on Linux. You will learn about how to choose Windows versus Linux, the changes needed to make SQL Server run on Linux, and high availability and disaster recovery solutions.</description>
      <startTime>8/26/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/26/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>