<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #689 - Prague 2017</name>
    <startDate>10/21/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Amsterdam, Berlin, Bern, Rome, Stockholm, Vienna</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatPrague</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>DOX</name>
      <street>Poupětova 1</street>
      <city>Prague</city>
      <state>Hlavní Mesto Praha, Czechia</state>
      <zipcode>17000</zipcode>
      <longitude>14.44704</longitude>
      <latitude>50.10678</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1826</importID>
      <name>Avast Software s.r.o.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.avast.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/889/EventSponsor_14184.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2053</importID>
      <name>JT Banka, a.s.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.jtbank.cz/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/889/EventSponsor_13860.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1806</importID>
      <name>Joyful Craftsmen</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://joyfulcraftsmen.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/889/EventSponsor_13836.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2057</importID>
      <name>Prianto GmbH</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.quest.com/_home/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.prianto.com/fileadmin/_processed_/f/4/preview_Quest_Logo_Orange_RGB_JPEG_c98548d27e.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1736</importID>
      <name>Advantage Solutions, s. r. o.</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.origam.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.origam.com/web/public/images/logo_Orange.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68506</importID>
      <name>Dmitry Pilugin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dmitry Pilugin, is a SQL Server DB developer from Russia, Moscow. He works with SQL Server for more than ten years. Currently he works as a database developer lead, responsible for the development of production databases in the media research company. 

Dmitry holds a blog about SQL Server query processing: QueryProcessor.com, where he writes about a query optimization and execution, and also likes to share his knowledge about it speaking at various community events and tech conferences. Data Platform Microsoft MVP since 2014.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SomewereSomehow</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/pilugin-dmitry-somewheresomehow/2b/210/277</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.queryprocessor.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SomewereSomehow</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69015</importID>
      <name>Bent Pedersen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bent is a Data Platform MVP and working as Senior Business Analytics Architect at Kapacity A/S, where he have been working with enterprise customers on solutions with SSAS Tabular, SQL Server and in general Azure Data Platform services for the last years. During the past years, he concentrated on working with architecturing, devOps, Automation, testing and simplifying development processes for the Azure Data Platform.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLBent</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://dk.linkedin.com/in/bentnissenpedersen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.biblog.eu</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLBent</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68878</importID>
      <name>Oliver Frost</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am currently working as a Data Engineer, improving the company data platform and providing the necessary resources for our data consultants. I am extremely fortunate to dabble with a number of tools including those from the Microsoft BI stack and NoSQL tech like Neo4j, R and Python. My strengths lie in integrating multiple technologies for a specific business problem.

I aim to present material that BI consultants and developers can all take away something new to apply to their own work processes. I try to apply knowledge and skills from my previous life as a neuroscientist and as a blindfolded Rubik's Cube world record holder. I am of the belief that, one day, neuroscience and big data will come together in a big way.</description>
      <twitter>@ConsolidataLtd</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/olliefrost</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ConsolidataLtd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69055</importID>
      <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wolfgang Strasser creates solutions based on the Microsoft Data Platform tools in his day-to-day job as Business Intelligence consultant. Either using SQL Server Database Engine, SSIS, reporting with SSAS and SSRS, implementing Power BI solutions or cloud tools for data analysis - the data-tools-landscape is broadening every day! Based on his professional careers as a software developer he likes to work on structured development processes.
Wolfgang shares his knowledge with the community at many national and international events. For his community work, Wolfgang has been awarded with the Microsoft MVP Award for Data Platform in October 2015</description>
      <twitter>wstrasser</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/wolfgang-strasser/7b/912/22b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://workingondata.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=wstrasser</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68798</importID>
      <name>Jiří Neoral</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jiri is BI Data Architect in Dixons Carphone and Microsoft MVP Data Platform. Before joining Dixons worked as Freelance Bi consultant and MCT (since 2008). Jiri has strong passion for Business Intelligence and loves to share his knowledge. Is active blogger about BI although decided to write in Czech and focus mainly on Czech and Slovak audience. He is also active speaker on conferences and community events (mainly based in Czech Republic). Jiri is Czech PUG leader and SQL PASS Member.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/JiriNeoral</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://cz.linkedin.com/in/jiri-neoral-b2597945</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.neoral.cz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/JiriNeoral</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68863</importID>
      <name>Jan Mulkens</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jan Mulkens is a Microsoft MVP in AI, a Solution Expert at Ordina Belgium, and a Microsoft Data Platform  BI Consultant.
In his spare time, he is a speaker at conferences and user groups in Europe and he organizes two user groups and a conference in Belgium.
Power BI Days conference (www.powerbidays.com), Belgium Microsoft Advanced Analytics User Group (bit.ly/msaaug), and Flemish Power BI User Group (meetup.powerbibelgium.com).</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/JanMulkens</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/janmulkens</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.janmulkens.be</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/JanMulkens</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69048</importID>
      <name>Alex Whittles</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alex is a Data Platform MVP, and is the owner and lead consultant at Purple Frog, a SQL Server Business Intelligence consultancy in the UK. He specializes in Data Warehouse modelling, ETL, Cubes, MDX amp; DAX. He#39;s a chartered engineer amp; has an MSc in Business Intelligence.

He runs the Birmingham (UK) SQL Pass chapter amp; Azure user groups, and is on the SQLBits and SQL Relay committees in the UK. 

Alex is a regular speaker at global events including SQLBits, PASS Summit, SQL Relay, SQL Saturdays as well as numerous SQL Pass chapters around Europe</description>
      <twitter>@PurpleFrogSys</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/alexwhittles</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.PurpleFrogSystems.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@PurpleFrogSys</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67704</importID>
      <name>Jakub Müller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>...</description>
      <twitter>@tckscz</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tckscz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68784</importID>
      <name>Damian Widera</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server MVP amp; MCT
Software engineer with 18+ years of professional experience in all aspects of software development.
Damian participated in a number of projects in international environments and possesses practical knowledge of procedures and tools which are necessary for successful implementation of such projects.
Now he focuses on building solutions based on Microsoft SQL Server environment (including complex database driven systems, database tuning and optimization).</description>
      <twitter>@DamianWidera</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/damian-widera-0b56284</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://codingfamily.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DamianWidera</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69031</importID>
      <name>Ivan Donev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a Data platform MVP with more than 10 years of real-life experience with SQL Server and its stack of services. Besides the support and project work, I am also a trainer, conference speaker and user group organizer (and volunteer).</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ikdonev</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivandonev/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ikdonev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68885</importID>
      <name>Miroslav Dimitrov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Miroslav Dimitrov is a Senior Big Data and Analytics Engineer at DXC Technology, regular speaker at various events and Microsoft Certified Trainer. He is MCSE: Data Platform for SQL Server and MCITP on SQL 2008. In the last years he had worked on great variety of customers' environments and involved in complex transitions and transformation projects as well as developing private and public cloud solutions. Miroslav is also leading database courses at Sofia University.</description>
      <twitter>@miro_dd</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://bg.linkedin.com/in/dimitrovmiroslav</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlshack.com/author/miroslav-dimitrov/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@miro_dd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67749</importID>
      <name>Grzegorz Stolecki</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Business Intelligence expert with 20+ years of experience. Grzegorz worked as architect, developer and trainer. Currently he focuses on developing specialized analytical and reporting solutions using machine learning models for large and mid-size enterprises. He also works on financial planning, consolidation and budgeting applications. Grzegorz is one of the leaders of Polish Data Community (former Polish SQL Server User Group PLSSUG). You can meet him very often at community meetings, conferences and other events. He is an active speaker and ATE member. Microsoft MVP in Data Platform Area since 2010.</description>
      <twitter>gstolecki</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/grzegorzstolecki</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=gstolecki</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69005</importID>
      <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen, as the founder of Savory Data, has a long history of providing customer solutions in the areas of data engineering, data science, and Business Intelligence. He is a certified software engineer, a graduated business educator, and professor of Databases  Project Management at HTL Leonding, and is certified as an MCSE  MCT. He is a published author and writes articles for well-known journals. He co-founded PASS Austria and organizes SQLSaturdays in Austria. Markus is a founding member of Power BI Usergroup Austria. Since 2017 Markus was awarded as an Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>MEhrenmueller</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markus-ehrenmueller/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.savorydata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MEhrenmueller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67807</importID>
      <name>Michal Sadowski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior Database Platform Engineer, leader of Krakow chapter of Data Community Krakow (former Polish SQL Server User Group) - PASS Chapter. With more than 10 years of experience in Microsoft technology, helps in advisory for performance optimization on database and application levels. Active speaker on SQL Server related events like SQLSaturday, SQLDay, MCT Global Summit etc. Holds many Microsoft certificates including MCSE: Data Platform, MCSA: SQL Server 2012/2014/2016, MCSA: Windows Server 2008/2012/2016 and MCT.</description>
      <twitter>SadowskiMichal</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/pub/michal-sadowski/4/b33/717</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlplayer.net/michal-sadowski</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SadowskiMichal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69007</importID>
      <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen, as the founder of Savory Data, has a long history of providing customer solutions in the areas of data engineering, data science, and Business Intelligence. He is a certified software engineer, a graduated business educator, and professor of Databases  Project Management at HTL Leonding, and is certified as an MCSE  MCT. He is a published author and writes articles for well-known journals. He co-founded PASS Austria and organizes SQLSaturdays in Austria. Markus is a founding member of Power BI Usergroup Austria. Since 2017 Markus was awarded as an Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>MEhrenmueller</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markus-ehrenmueller/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.savorydata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MEhrenmueller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67828</importID>
      <name>Marcos Freccia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Currently working as a Microsoft SQL Server DBA at Zalando SE, Marcos has over 9 years of SQL Server experience, working from small to enterprise environments with High Availability, Disaster Recovery, Database Optimization, etc.. Holding several Microsoft certifications such as: MCITP DBA  DEV, MCSE Data Plataform and his last certification on Microsoft Azure Design and Implement Cloud Data Platform Solutions. In 2013 Marcos was awarded as a Microsoft MVP by his contributions in the Brazilian SQL Server community. Marcos is a frequent speaker in the SQL Server Community and he was the organizer of the first SQL Saturday in South Brazil.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlfreccia</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://br.linkedin.com/in/marcosfreccia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://marcosfreccia.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlfreccia</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69239</importID>
      <name>Tomas Tucek</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>More than 10 years in IT spent on custom solution(s) development, mainly for enterprises. Last several years spent in Business Intelligence product/project leading. Passionate in software craftsmenship.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ttfromjc</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.joyfulbi.com</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://joyfulcraftsmen.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ttfromjc</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68570</importID>
      <name>Marek Chmel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have started working in IT as a consultant and trainer for Microsoft server systems and from the beginning I did focus mainly on SQL Server. Few years back I have joined atamp;t, where I workin a team responsible for 24/7 operations for large SQL server environments.  Our primary focus is architecture, delpoyment, performance tuning and disaster recovery for SQL Server ranging various sizes, versions and editions. If there#39;s any free time left, you can catch me speaking at a conference or teaching a Microsoft or security class in a training center.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://cz.linkedin.com/in/mchmel</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.prosql.cz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69027</importID>
      <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Martorana Tusa is a Business Intelligence Team Manager at Würth Phoenix,  the IT and consulting company of the Würth-Group. 
He is awarded as MVP in the Data Platform category

Former BI Specialist at Widex, a Danish manufacturing company, and BI Developer in the IT department of an Italian banking group. 20+ years of experience working with data. 
He is focused on the entire BI stack: database development, data warehousing, data analysis, reporting, etc. 
Andrea is a usual speaker at many events: SQLSaturdays, conferences in Europe and PASS Summit, and for PASS Virtual Groups. 

Andrea is an author for sqlshack.com, sqlservercentral.com, and UGISS (User Group Italiano SQL Server).</description>
      <twitter>bruco441</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bruco441</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>68878</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68878</id>
          <name>Oliver Frost</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Backstage</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Science with SQL Server 2016 and R</title>
      <description>One of the most notable additions to the Microsoft BI stack is the addition of Microsoft R Server inside SQL Server 2016. The inbuilt ScaleR packages deliver scalability and multithreading capabilities that open-source R can’t easily provide, opening up a world of possibilities for data scientists interested in machine learning and predictive analytics. But what does this look like on a Microsoft platform?

Oliver Frost, a Data Science Engineer at Direct Line Group, demonstrates what tools are available to you as a data scientist inside SQL Server 2016. Discover how R adds value where traditional relational databases struggle, how to use ScaleR functions to build predictive models and efficient machine learning pipelines.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69015</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69015</id>
          <name>Bent Pedersen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Backstage</name>
      </location>
      <title>Scripting Tabular models</title>
      <description>Introducing the new scripting language for tabular models. Before SQL Server 2016 tabular models was wrapped into a multidimensional constructs. TOM is the new native library for tabular - this makes it easy to maintain, modify and deploy your model.

During this session I will go through and explain some examples and best practices on generating a SSAS tabular model by using the new TOM. I will spend some time showing and explaining a real world example on pushinga measure creation and changes to the key business stakeholders and to ensure quick time to market.

The last thing i will show is how you speed up your development free up up to 50% of the time you spend building tabular models with the simple and advanced features of Tabular Editor 2.0</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68863</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68863</id>
          <name>Jan Mulkens</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Enabling Citizen Data Science with Microsoft</title>
      <description>In times past, Data Science was only for those elite few with a rare combination of skills including advanced knowledge of statistics.
Microsoft has been making sure that everyone can participate in the data revolution by giving people access to predictive API’s, in-database advanced analytics and drag-and-drop predictive experiments. All thanks to SQL Server 2016 and the Cortana Intelligence Suite in Azure.
These advances have given people with less knowledge of statistics and programming the ability to become what Gartner calls citizen data scientists. Should we be worried about creating fools-with-tools or should we embrace the democratization of data science as the golden age of data?
In this demo heavy session we explore Microsoft’s solutions to ensure democratization of data science and the possible dangers that lurk below the surface.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69007</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69007</id>
          <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Café</name>
      </location>
      <title>From SQL to R – Leverage Your T-SQL Knowledge to Learn R</title>
      <description>You are already familiar with T-SQL and are eager to learn R but do not know where to start? Start from what you already know: T-SQL. Both languages have many things in common on some levels, but are very different on others. You will learn how to begin your first steps in the new language and how to perform the most common tasks, typical for R: statistics, machine learning  data visualization.
This session will kick you off to the new language by using analogies from T-SQL. You will learn how to write your first R-scripts, make usage of packages and will leave this session with a basic understanding of typical use-cases of R and how to integrate that into your existing environment with SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69005</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69005</id>
          <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Café</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Game of Hierarchies: Introduction to Graph Processing with SQL</title>
      <description>Hierarchies are the bread and butter of most business applications and you find them almost everywhere:
* Product Categories
* Sales Territories
* Bill of Material
* Calendar and Time
Even when there is a big need from a business perspective, the solutions in relational databases are mostly sort of awkward. The most flexible hierarchies are usually modeled as self-referenced tables. If you want to successfully query such self-referenced hierarchies, you will need either loops or recursive Common Table Expressions. SQL Server 2017 comes now with a different approach: Graph Database. 
Join this session for a journey through best practices to transform your hierarchies into useful information. We will have fun playing around with a sample database based on G. R. R. Martin’s famous “Game of Thrones”.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69055</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69055</id>
          <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Scale-Out your SSIS Package Executions</title>
      <description>With a rising number of parallel SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) package executions the resource requirements on the SSIS server can be a limiting factor. In older SQL Server versions, scale-out architectures needed to be implemented by hand and required a lot of manual implementation effort. Beginning with SQL Server 2017, SSIS provides a built-in scale-out functionality for package executions. 
After the definition of scalability-types, the SSIS scale-out architecture and the involved system-parts are introduced. The attendees will learn the basics, get checklists and best practices when building up their own SSIS scale-out cluster. In addition to the configuration using SSMS other configuration options (command line, T-SQL,..) are presented. Behind the scenes information like logging, the programmability interfaces and configuration options will be shared.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 1:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69048</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69048</id>
          <name>Alex Whittles</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Café</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to U-SQL and Data Lake</title>
      <description>U-SQL is the new kid on the SQL language block. In this session we'll look at the what, where, why and how of the language. Is it a query language? Is it a data transformation language? Will it replace T-SQL? Should you learn it? Where is it? What is Data Lake? We'll discuss all this and more.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68798</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68798</id>
          <name>Jiří Neoral</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Shopping basket analysis with Analysis Services and Power BI</title>
      <description>What are the products commonly bought together? How can company increase sales by offering bundles of products? Current trend is to leverage Machine learning and Artificial Intelligence to drive sales. But will machine understand business better, that business person who is involved in his area for 20 years? Maybe. During presentation, you will see how to develop data model using SQL Server Analysis Services and Power BI for manual “Attached Sales” exploration and analysis. You will see how to prepare SQL Server layer, SSAS model and Power BI report.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69027</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69027</id>
          <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Café</name>
      </location>
      <title>APPLY operator in action</title>
      <description>APPLY operator is a T-SQL table operator that allows to boost query perfomance and to solve complex calculation problems in an very efficient way. 
But it isn't easy to understandt how does it work and how it can be applied to our queries. 
In this session, we will examine the various types of APPLY operator (CROSS APPLY, OUTER APPLY) to understand it's behaviour and the power it holds.
We will go through many real world cases to show how we can use the APPLY operator, when writing queries, instead of JOINs 
and we will show how performances can be improved by using this operator the right way.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68570</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68570</id>
          <name>Marek Chmel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Café</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning in Action</title>
      <description>This session will help you make your first successful experiment with Azure Machine Learning, where we will explore the workflow of creating an experiment, from the initial idea to the final solution. This session will include a lot of demonstrations to show you, how you can start using this amazing technology for your applications.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 1:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68885</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68885</id>
          <name>Miroslav Dimitrov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Backstage</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Myths and Misconceptions</title>
      <description>SQL Server is full of misunderstood features and misnomers that could affect how it is operating and respectively our applications. If you do not want to be surprised in a bad way by some intended, but not widely known SQL functionalities, join me in this session where we will, in an entertaining way, examine some of the most common behaviors that you probably have not expected.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 1:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67749</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67749</id>
          <name>Grzegorz Stolecki</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Backstage</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hello SQL! I'm Python! What can I do for you?</title>
      <description>At last... After SQL Server 2016 brought us the R language integration the newest 2017 version brings Python in its toolbox. Python is well known as tool for machine learning, advanced analytics and doing a lot of amazing and crazy things. Like its R companion it also has a powerful libraries support for scaling and big data handling. So let's see what the famous scripting snake can do for us.
During the session you will learn how to set up the integration, run simple scripts, use Python for transforming the data, use the Matplotlib library to visualise data in reports, create and run machine learning models with predictions.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67704</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67704</id>
          <name>Jakub Müller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Café</name>
      </location>
      <title>JSON in SQL Server</title>
      <description>SQL Server enables more flexibile approach to work with non-relational data with new JSON support. I'll show you what you can do with pure SQL functionality and where you need CLR functions to take full advantage of JSON.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67828</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67828</id>
          <name>Marcos Freccia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Stop everything! Top T-SQL tricks to a Developer</title>
      <description>Writing a better code is always a difficult challenge. In this session we are going to investigate some common issues and learn new tips that will help you to be a better developer and then help the DBA keep his databases safer.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68506</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68506</id>
          <name>Dmitry Pilugin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Backstage</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Processor Enhancements in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2017 brings a lot of new useful features, there are a number of query processor enhancements among them, that improve queries performance. In this session, we are going to talk about improvements in three main areas:  
- Adaptive Query Processing: Adaptive Memory Grant Feedback, Interleaved Execution and Adaptive Joins;
- Query Store: Automatic Plan Regression Correction and Wait Statistics;
- Query Optimizer: new Plan Operators, Batch Mode enhancements, Cardinality Estimation changes and improved Showplan diagnostics.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67807</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67807</id>
          <name>Michal Sadowski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Backstage</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database corruption</title>
      <description>In this session, you will learn how to detect and avoid common problems related to database corruption. There will be a description of the data structures in SQL Server and how it can affect the availability of SQL Server during corruption. On the session, there will be not only theoretical knowledge but many real life examples with demos.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69031</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69031</id>
          <name>Ivan Donev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Real world DevOps - challenges, tools and solutions</title>
      <description>So you want to use AlwaysEncrypted, but your app is not using driver level parameters? Or you want to parameterize ad-hoc queries, without rewriting your application? Or you just want to pretty print your t-sql code? SQLDOM is here to help. Not very popular but extremely useful utility/library that can help anyone to intercept and rewrite queries during runtime so they meet feature requirements or just fix performance.</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68784</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68784</id>
          <name>Damian Widera</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Travelling in time with SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 comes up with a very exciting feature called Temporal tables. You can make queries to historical data lot easier by using this feature. The mechanism is very simple however you all should know it in depth to make sure you can use it efficiently. And this is exactly what I am going to do during this session – show you how to create temporal tables, how to use and manage them</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69239</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69239</id>
          <name>Tomas Tucek</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Café</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Warehouse Testing and Why You Should Care!</title>
      <description>How do you test your data warehouse? Do you even test? Let's face the truth that data processing solutions are very rarely tested ... 
So let's start with fundamentals of (not only data warehouse) testing, why you should have sleepless nights (today) and how to avoid them (in the future). Two Joyful Craftsmen: Jaroslav Reken  Tomas Tucek will bring a piece of theory, but mainly practical examples, from real life ... mainly to get you out of your comfort zone!</description>
      <startTime>10/21/2017 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/21/2017 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>