<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #784 - Singapore 2018</name>
    <startDate>8/18/2018 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+08:00) Irkutsk, Ulaan Bataar</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatSingapore</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Singapore Operations Pte Ltd</name>
      <street> #22-01 One Marina Boulevard</street>
      <city>Singapore</city>
      <state>Singapore, Singapore</state>
      <zipcode>018989</zipcode>
      <longitude>103.85277</longitude>
      <latitude>1.28222</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1781</importID>
      <name>Microsoft</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1008/EventSponsor_14955.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82342</importID>
      <name>Jason Aw</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A passionate IT leader with over 20 years of experience in in technology, infrastructure, cloud environments particularly with high availability and disaster recovery solutions for different architectures including SQL database applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/awjason</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sios-apac.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84432</importID>
      <name>Sanjiv Venkatram</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Background in financial planning and analysis, sales analytics, program management and engineering. Over 20 years of experience in IT Cloud Services/Software, IT Professional Services and Automotive Electronics Hardware. Worked across North America (17 years) and now APAC (3.5 years).

MBA from the University of Michigan (2003) and Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering from the University of Rhode Island (1997). Hold 7 published US patents.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sanjiv-venkatram/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82454</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denny Cherry is the owner and principal consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates Consulting and has over a decade of experience working with platforms such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Microsoft SQL Server, Hyper-V, vSphere, and Enterprise Storage solutions. Denny’s areas of technical expertise include system architecture, performance tuning, security, replication, and troubleshooting. Denny currently holds several Microsoft Certifications related to SQL Server 2000 through 2019, including being a Microsoft Certified Master, Microsoft MVP and VMware vExpert Award.</description>
      <twitter>mrdenny</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrdenny</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.dcac.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mrdenny</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85285</importID>
      <name>Dharmendra Keshari</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dharmendra Keshari has strong and in-depth experience in Database Management. Currently, working as Technical Specialist for Data Platform at Microsoft in Singapore and handling one of the most critical databases support for clients.

Dharmendra is an avid, regular mentor on social media, helping several enthusiast in solving their problems related to Database management. he is co-leader and regular speaker at Singapore SQL Server Pass Chapter (User Group). He has done certification for “Microsoft SQL Server#174; 2008, Implementation” and “Maintenance amp; Administering Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Database”.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://sg.linkedin.com/in/dharmendra-keshari-a7043398</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dharmendrakeshari.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83792</importID>
      <name>Dinesh Priyankara</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dinesh is an experienced professional and database enthusiast with skills in database management systems and business intelligence. Possessing over 18 years of experience on data related technologies, he does training, consulting, and is a top contributor to the local SQL Server community. In recognition of his contributions and expertise he has demonstrated, he was awarded the Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) award for SQL Server for 13 consecutive years since 2006.
He is a Subject Matter Expert on SQL Server exams and has contributed for SQL Server 2012, 2016, 2017 and Azure Data Engineering exam development and Job Task Analysis (JTA).
Dinesh is the Founder/Principal Architect of dinesQL (Pvt) Ltd (http://dinesql.com). In his</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/dinesh_priya</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://lk.linkedin.com/in/dineshpriyankara/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dinesql.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/dinesh_priya</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85284</importID>
      <name>Senthamil V</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Microsoft MVP on Windows Development. SharePoint is my profession and Windows Dev is my Passion</description>
      <twitter>@altfo</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://msisgreat.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@altfo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84243</importID>
      <name>Sarbjit Singh</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sarbjit brings 24 years of IT experience spanning assessments, consulting, implementation and training for a wide range of Microsoft technologies from mid 1990s to 2017.  Sarbjit has cross-functional experience serving customer environments across a wide range of industries. Financial, Public Sector, Telecommunication, Media, Energy, Transport and Healthcare sectors.

Sarbjit have had experience leading and working with culturally diverse international teams across US, Europe, Asia Pacific and ANZ regions delivering business transformation outcomes for client organizations.  Sarbjit now runs experience4live.com as a life coach and is a FIA licensed race car driver, underwater photography and videography and travels.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sarbjitgill</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarbjitsinghgill</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/PublicProfile/4040012?fullName=Sarbjit%20%20Singh</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sarbjitgill</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83820</importID>
      <name>Asanka Padmakumara</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Asanka is an experienced data engineer who is currently performing the role of Business Intelligence Consultant in Qrious. He has worked close to 10 years in BI and data analytics field and has implemented BI solutions for different industries. As a technology enthusiastic, he enjoys conducting technical presentations both locally and internationally. He is a MCSE in Data Management and Analytics as well as a Microsoft certified Azure Data Engineer. He is passionate about Data Analytics, Business Intelligence and AI related technologies.</description>
      <twitter>asanka_e</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/asankapadmakumara/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://asankap.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=asanka_e</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82347</importID>
      <name>Manohar Punna</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Manohar Punna is an Data Platform Geek and Vice President of DataPlatformGeeks by passion and a Data Platform Consultant by profession. He is a speaker at various conferences like PASS Summit, SQLBits, DPS. He has authored over 150 blogs and has written a One DMV a Day series which is a longest one day series on any topic on SQL Server till date.
Manohar is a product of this community and strongly believes in giving back to the community. So, ask him anything you would like to know and he is happy to learn it with you.</description>
      <twitter>ManuSQLGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/manohar-punna/15/153/508</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservergeeks.com/author/manoharpunna/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ManuSQLGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82414</importID>
      <name>Kevin Boles</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Boles is a SQL Server expert, working exclusively with the product since v6.5. With over 25 years of database experience and over 45,000 man hours of SQL Server engine experience, he holds many related certifications, is an MCT and was a SQL Server MVP from 2007 to 2012. Kevin has been a very successful independent consultant for over 20 years. His passion is the relational engine, especially designing, building, analyzing and tuning high-performance database applications.</description>
      <twitter>@TheSQLGuru</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/thesqlguru</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TheSQLGuru</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84241</importID>
      <name>Amit R S Bansal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Amit R. S. Bansal is a SQL Server Specialist at SQLMaestros. He leads the SQL Server practice with a focused team providing consulting, training, and content development services to more than 160+ SQL customers globally. He frequently speaks at international conferences on SQL Server performance tuning, which is his core expertise. Amit is also honored with Microsoft Regional Director status, MVP award, and Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server credential. Amit has been working with SQL Server since 1999 and has been part of countless mission-critical SQL deployments. Performance Tuning in SQL Server is his core area of expertise. To learn more about Amit, visit http://sqlmaestros.com/amit-bansal.</description>
      <twitter>A_Bansal</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/AmitBansal2010</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=A_Bansal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84433</importID>
      <name>Karen Lopez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Karen Lopez is a Sr. Project Manager and Architect for InfoAdvisors. A frequent speaker at conferences and local user groups, she has 20+ years of experience in project and data management on large, multi-project programs. Karen is a chronic volunteer, a Data Platform MVP, and an active advocate for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education and data quality.

Karen’s presentations are known for their lively and interactive approach to learning. Her motto: “Love Your Data!”</description>
      <twitter>datachick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/karenlopez</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datamodel.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=datachick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82492</importID>
      <name>David Alzamendi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Delivering Business Intelligence and Data Analytics Solutions with On-Premises and Cloud technologies since 2011, David Alzamendi is a Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert and event speaker who solves problems with best practice procedures and the latest technology. 

David is passionate about the positive impact data can have on our lives, businesses, economy and the environment. He prides himself on using his creativity and optimism to solve what others thought impossible.</description>
      <twitter>techtalkcorner</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dalzamendi</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.techtalkcorner.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=techtalkcorner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82944</importID>
      <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Flynn is a Senior Database Administrator with 10 years experience in large 24 x 7 enterprise environments. He is a certified master for SQL Server and a regular attendee of the PASS Summit.

Has presented at SQLSaturday events in Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane and Auckland, Edmonton and Calgary, Oslo and Cambridge</description>
      <twitter>sqllensman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqllensman.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllensman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>82347</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82347</id>
          <name>Manohar Punna</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>Real-Time Analytics with Power BI</title>
      <description>Power BI helps you build appealing visualizations of your data. With ever growing footprint of data it is equally important to get real-time insights into your data. It can be as simple as monitoring a single metric or viewing real-time sales performance across multiple locations. Power BI real-time streaming enables you to stream data and update dashboards in real-time. Any time sensitive data can be a source of streaming data set like IoT sensor devices, social media sources, service usage metrics etc.

In this session 
1. I will dive deep into real-time analytics with Power BI.
2. How to build streaming tiles in Power BI Dashboards.
3. Demo using Power BI REST APIs.
4. Demo using Azure Event Hub and Azure Stream Analytics.</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82944</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82944</id>
          <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF15</name>
      </location>
      <title>Graph Databases with Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <description>Graph Database technology is one of the fastest growing fields of database design and evelopment.

In SQL Server 2017 a new option to process Graph Data within the database engine was  added.
This was based around the Cypher Query language from Neo4J

At the same time a Graph Data API was added to Azure Cosmos DB (Microsoft's Globally Distributed Mult-Model cloud databse)
This was built around the Apache TinkerPop graph traversal language, Gremlin

In this Session we will briefly look at use cases for Graph Database and then investigate how these have been implemented in Azure Cosmos DB.

This session is aimed at any developer/architect/DBA that is looking to understand Graph Database and how they have been implemented inside Microsoft's new Cloud based  NoSQL database.</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84241</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84241</id>
          <name>Amit R S Bansal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR01</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Developer Tricks</title>
      <description>Session will cover a few cool SQL Server tricks for Developers</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84433</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84433</id>
          <name>Karen Lopez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF15</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Database Designer's Favorite Features: Security,Privacy  More</title>
      <description>The launch of SQL Server 2016 means there will be a lot of blog posts and webinars of people talking about all the great administration features that come with this new release. In this session, Karen will be discussing the newer SQL Server features from a database designers point of view, including: - Dynamic Data Masking - Always Encrypted - Row Level Security - Deprecated Features - Data Type Seleciton We'll look at the new features, why you should consider them, where they work, where they don't, who needs to be involved in using them, and what changes, if any, need to be made to applications or tools that you use with SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83820</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83820</id>
          <name>Asanka Padmakumara</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR01</name>
      </location>
      <title>Want to move your data to Cloud ? what are your options?</title>
      <description>Due to certain limitations of On-Prem Solutions, people have started to move their data to Cloud. Since Azure provide unlimited storage and processing power, most organizations have started to use Azure data related technologies in their Big Data and Analytical Solutions.  However, Azure offers different options when it comes to Big Data,Data Analytic and Data Storage.  In this session , I will cover what are the best suited options when it come to your data requirements and comparison between Azure Data related technologies.</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82454</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82454</id>
          <name>Denny Cherry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF15</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Maintain the Same Level of utilities in Cloud Deployments</title>
      <description>In this session we will review the differences between deploying Microsoft SQL Server 2016 in Microsoft Azure and on-premises from a Security, Reliability and Scalability perspective.  

We'll review the common mistakes which people make when deploying SQL Server Virtual Machines to Azure which can lead to security problems including data breaches.

We'll review the common performance problems which people encounter, and how to resolve them.

We'll review the common scalability misunderstandings of Azure and SQL Server Virtual Machines.

Join us for this fun session and learn how to improve the security, reliability and scalability of your Azure deployments of SQL Server 2016.</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82342</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82342</id>
          <name>Jason Aw</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF15</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server on Linux High Availability Features and Considerations</title>
      <description>With SQL Server on Linux, Microsoft brings SQL Server’s core relational database engine to the growing enterprise Linux ecosystem. High Availability and Disaster Recovery (HADR)  are aspects of SQL Server that are critically important and in this session we discuss the features, limitations and options for High Availability and how SANless clustering can ensure proper functionality, availability and reliability for SQL Server on Linux, on-premise and in the Azure cloud.</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84243</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84243</id>
          <name>Sarbjit Singh</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>Don’t be naive, Learn machine learning algorithms</title>
      <description>Following session will provide an overview on Machine Learning</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85284</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85284</id>
          <name>Senthamil V</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>Fundamentals of Block chain  Development</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn about technical details of blockchain. Basics of data hashing and keys. I will also discuss how to do development on ethereum platform.</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85285</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85285</id>
          <name>Dharmendra Keshari</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>L22-CF15</name>
      </location>
      <title>Trend Analysis of SQL Server Logs using Powershell!</title>
      <description>DBAs regularly need to keep an eye on the error logs of all their SQL Servers.When server numbers get large, it becomes very difficult to manage them. If you don't maintaining the error logs, SQL Server will recycle the log and you are going to loose the valuable information. In this session, you will learn how to automatically parse the errors from multiple SQL error logs using PowerShell, store the data in a central location database, and create reports to visualize the information using PowerBI or Splunk.</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82414</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82414</id>
          <name>Kevin Boles</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tune Like a Guru - The Big Three!</title>
      <description>EVERY client I engage with is taught to RUN 3 SCRIPTS IMMEDIATELY, WITHOUT THOUGHT AND WITHOUT DELAY as soon as a performance problem is noted. I am exceptionally good at performance tuning and forensics, but I (nor anyone else out there) cannot get at the root cause of a problem without information about the occurrence. These scripts will give you said information (which is very often transient in nature)! I could be putting myself out of work teaching stuff like this! :-D</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83792</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83792</id>
          <name>Dinesh Priyankara</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR01</name>
      </location>
      <title>Accelerating and modernizing data integration with Azure Data Factory</title>
      <description>Integration Services (aka SSIS) has been serving us for years for building enterprise data integration solutions, not only for data warehousing but for all types of data integrations between heterogenous data sources. SSIS is not retiring but it is high time to check out its new neighbor; Azure Data Factory, fully managed ETL service in the cloud. Let me show you how we can use Azure Data Factory for implementing modern data integrations for on-premise and cloud sources with various type of transformations available including Azure services such as Azure Data Lake Analytics, HDInsight and Machine Learning.</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84432</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84432</id>
          <name>Sanjiv Venkatram</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR02</name>
      </location>
      <title>MS BI + AI experiences: Using PBI, Azure  AML across industries</title>
      <description>Use case in presentation is from discrete manufacturing (part 2)/ higher education industries, with following summary:

1. The relative ease with which Power BI and SQL Azure can be used and integrated to design and simulate performance of machine elements

2. Power BI and SQL Azure can be used to replace “design handbooks” which typically are paper based or static on a SharePoint – now these can be made “live” by leverage Power BI and SQL Azure

3. Output from physical tests of designs can be analyzed using ML to validate relationships and can be used to predict actual performance</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82492</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82492</id>
          <name>David Alzamendi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>L21-MPR01</name>
      </location>
      <title>Business Intelligence Solutions in Azure</title>
      <description>When the number of services is more than 600 in Azure, many questions arise surrounding the different services that can be included in a Business Intelligence Architecture. This session will cover traditional as well as modern Business Intelligence solutions taking advantage of technologies such as Azure HDInsight, Azure Data Lakes or Azure Event Hubs. 

I will go over the characteristics of the main services that can be implemented in a Business Intelligence solution in the cloud. The demo will include 5 of these services.</description>
      <startTime>8/18/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/18/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>