<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #915 - Bucuresti 2019</name>
    <startDate>10/5/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>150</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Harare, Pretoria</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat915</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Impact Hub Bucharest, Bucharest</name>
      <street>Splaiul Unirii 165 Timpuri Noi Square, clădirea 2, etaj 1 București 030133 Romania</street>
      <city>Bucharest</city>
      <state>Bucharest, Romania</state>
      <zipcode>030133</zipcode>
      <longitude>26.115709</longitude>
      <latitude>44.4158397</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/915/EventSponsor_14086.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2306</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Romania</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/ro-ro</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/915/EventSponsor_14275.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2590</importID>
      <name>Esential Training</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://esentialtraining.ro/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/915/EventSponsor_14276.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2591</importID>
      <name>Domino's Pizza</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.dominos-pizza.ro/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/915/EventSponsor_14277.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2592</importID>
      <name>GN-Outsourcing SRL</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.genosdanmark.eu/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/915/EventSponsor_14278.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/915/EventSponsor_13871.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96752</importID>
      <name>Rudi Bruchez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>(same as before)</description>
      <twitter>nepasderanger</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://fr.linkedin.com/in/rudibruchez</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.babaluga.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=nepasderanger</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96748</importID>
      <name>Sorin Peste</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a Technical Evangelist @ Microsoft and passionate about all things software development.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95109</importID>
      <name>ILIE Mugurel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data warehouse developer on MS SQL Server</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94550</importID>
      <name>Shehab El-Najjar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Shehab El-Najjar was the ONLY Microsoft SQL Server MVP in Gulf for the past 6 years and the 2nd one all over the Middle East  , he is the founder of SQL Gulf events series (SQL Gulf #1 , #2 and #3 ) where he spent so much time and efforts  to broadcast Microsoft SQL Server technologies all over the Gulf such as  KSA and Emirates and other Gulf cities ahead ..) 

	He is now Professional Services Manager at Saudi  Emircom 

	He was previously COO and business leader in KSA market through his startup WAJA IT for  3 years

	He is an influencing Database community leader all over the region  	
	A senior Database Consultant (SQL Server MVP for 6 years in row) -The 2nd MVP awardee SQL Server all over Middle East and Arabic region</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/MSQLPerformance</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=126446983amp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlserver-performance-tuning.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/MSQLPerformance</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95167</importID>
      <name>Liviu Ieran</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>More than 9 years of SQL Server experience working for Microsoft currently as a Support Escalation Engineer. 
My main area of expertise is SQL Server Performance where I helped optimize numerous query's and environments.</description>
      <twitter>@Liviu_Ieran</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/IeranLiviu</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Liviu_Ieran</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96773</importID>
      <name>Gabriel Petrescu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Experienced professional on Windows and Linux servers, virtualization, hardware and open source technologies. Many years of experience on open source database with a special interest on SQL Server Performance and Always On issues as long as SQL Server on Linux.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabriel-petrescu-904a168/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94561</importID>
      <name>Andrey Nikolov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrey is MCSA for SQL Server 2012/2014 with almost 20 years of experience in designing and implementing applications for Windows. He is working with various database platforms, but SQL Server is his favorite. He is also a leader of Plovdiv Power BI User Group and active member of local .NET, Power BI and SQL Server communities.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96869</importID>
      <name>Dragos Madarasan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Solutions Architect at Amazon Web Services, where he works with companies and their partners in Central and Eastern Europe by transforming their enterprise IT landscape and helping them design reliable, cost-effective cloud architectures. Dragos works with clients to assess their infrastructure and application portfolio while developing a shared vision, leading the customer and partner over the technical and business hurdles of cloud adoption. Before joining Amazon, he worked for Endava and Emerson and is an alumni of the Technical University of Cluj-Napoca.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dragospm</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dragosmadarasan</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dragos.madarasan.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dragospm</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98967</importID>
      <name>Cristian Lefter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cristian Lefter is Principal of Esential Training and one of the SQL Server MVPs. His primary competence is training. He is also a consultant, author, speaker and community leader. 
As his main expertise is Microsoft SQL Server, which resulted in founding an official PASS chapter, writing books and articles, contributing at the development of Microsoft Official Courseware, authoring certification exams, speaking at technical events and working as a Subject Matter Expert in various projects.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cristianlefter</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96816</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96741</importID>
      <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Catalin Gheorghiu is a solution architect from Romania. He has more than 15 years of experience in developing solutions, especially on Microsoft technologies in very demanding environments. Is contributing articles and blogs to several user groups (MrSmersh), lecturing all over Romania and abroad, is also RONUA Timisoara (PASS Chapter) user group leader. Since 2011, every year he was awarded the Microsoft MVP Award.</description>
      <twitter>MrSmersh</twitter>
      <linkedin>?https://ro.linkedin.com/in/catalingheorghiu?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ronua.ro/author/catalin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MrSmersh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96886</importID>
      <name>Alexandra Ciortea</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>2005-2009  Computer Science - Polytechnic University of Bucharest 
2009-2011 - Master -IT Management - Polytechnic University of Bucharest 

I started working for Microsoft in 2009 as a Support Engineer for Project Server and SQL Server for EMEA.
In 2012 I changed to a  Premier Field Engineer position working onsite for SQL Server and Project Server</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>94550</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94550</id>
          <name>Shehab El-Najjar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Francisco</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL Performance Guidelines for the optimal DB stress powers</title>
      <description>To reach your desired business functionalities, it can be easy using some common T-SQL practices like MTVF , scalar functions , Temp tables, Union…etc and they might perform pretty well on development server coz neither adequate stress of users nor adequate volume of data exist there but actually they seem totally strange once going to live where they become performing badly ending up eventually with and sharp skew of performance and standstill cases sometimes , this is due to the lack of stress powers of T-SQL codes which should be considered largely for critical mission DBs in particular more therefore I am going to talk to you about How to capture expensive queries using different techniques ..?and How to optimize them in the shortest time using scientific ways ..? (10 different T-SQL Practices will be explained within this session)</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96869</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96869</id>
          <name>Dragos Madarasan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Viena</name>
      </location>
      <title>Running Microsoft SQL Server on Amazon Web Services</title>
      <description>Amazon Web Services (AWS) has multiple ways to host and support Microsoft SQL Server.  This session will review the Relational Database Service (RDS) offering of Microsoft SQL Server as well as using our virtual machine service (Elastic Compute Cloud, or EC2) to host SQL Server database services.  We will review options for security, availability, and reliability operations in both offerings and how to choose the optimal solution for your existing and new SQL Server workloads.</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96748</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96748</id>
          <name>Sorin Peste</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Viena</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data Clusters: SQL Server 2019 Meets Big Data</title>
      <description>With the new Big Data Clusters feature in SQL Server 2019, you can store and reason over mountains of data, structured and unstructured, using both Transact-SQL and Apache Spark, a proven Open Source big data processing engine. You can dynamically scale-out your compute power by adding nodes, independently from the distributed storage (HDFS), to support your analytic workloads. You can also bring the power of Spark's Machine Learning library to build predictive models and operationalize them right inside SQL Server. And everything is running in containers and being orchestrated by Kubernetes. Come to this session to see what the Big Data future looks like for SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96752</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96752</id>
          <name>Rudi Bruchez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Francisco</name>
      </location>
      <title>What I have seen so far in my performance tuning audits</title>
      <description>In the last ten years, I have audited many SQL Server databases, for performance tuning. And I have encountered the same problems again and again. Let's call them SQL Server antipatterns. This session is designed to show you what those antipatterns are, and how to avoid them once and for all.</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96741</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96741</id>
          <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Viena</name>
      </location>
      <title>ML on the Edge</title>
      <description>Or options in running TensorFlow on Pi or similar class devices. My idea was (a bit born from need), to run TensorFlow on Pi class device. And this presentation is born from my adventures, showing pro and cons of each approach. From running directly on Pi to Azure IoT Edge on to Intel Neural Stick, and the list most probably is in “works” you will see the challenges and results of implementing TensorFlow using these technologies. Remark: Kinder chocolates have nothing to do with ML but will be present.</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95167</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95167</id>
          <name>Liviu Ieran</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Viena</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Explorer - Fast and highly scalable interactive analytics</title>
      <description>Azure Data Explorer is one of the newest offerings from Microsoft which went GA on the 7th of February. 
I am going to provide an overview of Azure Data Explorer, an interactive analytics service that will enable you to ask the questions on real time data. You can find answers in rapidly changing data generated by systems such as applications, websites, and IoT devices – anything really that generates volumes of streaming data that has potential to uncover a number of unknowns.</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94561</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94561</id>
          <name>Andrey Nikolov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Francisco</name>
      </location>
      <title>Embedding Power BI in your application</title>
      <description>Power BI is great tool and reports we made are always beautiful and catchy, right? But sometimes forcing users to open their browser to go to Power BI Service web site isn't so nice. In this session we will explore the various ways to embed Power BI reports, dashboards and tiles. We will learn what is needed to do this, what it will costs us (can we do it for free?) and what architecture decisions must be taken to build an embedded solution.</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96886</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96886</id>
          <name>Alexandra Ciortea</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Francisco</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Managed Instance - From the ground to the cloud</title>
      <description>The session focuses on migrating SQL onprem databases and objects hosted outside the database context to SQL MI . We will take a look at the migration life cycle and modernization best practices.  We’ll share stories and learnings from the field including our most common scenarios in the context of SQL 2008 end of support.</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96773</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96773</id>
          <name>Gabriel Petrescu</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Viena</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2019 on Linux - What's new?</title>
      <description>OS supported by SQL Server 2019
Presenting SQL Server on Linux 2019 and it is new features, things to have in mind when installing, running.
Advanced security features, Big data clusters, Data virtualization - the opening to open source source databases</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95109</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95109</id>
          <name>ILIE Mugurel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Viena</name>
      </location>
      <title>Handling JSONs in SQL Server</title>
      <description>Consuming data from JSON is now much easier with the new built-in support introduced in SQL Server 2016.
During this session will talk about JSON representation and will explore the new functions used for handling the content from a JSON file. Based on some examples we'll transform a JSON text to relational table and then will export some data from SQL Server as JSON.</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96816</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96816</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Francisco</name>
      </location>
      <title>BI Powers - The A.I. Who Tagged Me</title>
      <description>So everyone knows how to make some nice graphs in Power BI from Excel or SQL Server... But what about getting "intelligent" results from unusual data sources?
Disclaimer: A.I. will eventually take over the world. Unlike Doctor Evil, it won't ask for a ransom.</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98967</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98967</id>
          <name>Cristian Lefter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Francisco</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dataism</title>
      <description>The story of Dataism begins with David Brooks that used in the New York Times in 2013. Dataism is a term that has been used to describe the mindset or philosophy created by the emerging significance of Big Data. More recently, the term has been expanded to describe what social scientist Yuval Noah Harari has called an emerging ideology or even a new form of religion, in which 'information flow' is the 'supreme value'.
What is the impact of Dataism in our life? Let's discover that together!</description>
      <startTime>10/5/2019 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/5/2019 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>