<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #555 - Munich 2016</name>
    <startDate>10/8/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Sarajevo, Skopje, Warsaw, Zagreb</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat555</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Deutschland GmbH</name>
      <street>Walter-Gropius-Str. 5</street>
      <city>Munich</city>
      <state>Bavaria, Germany</state>
      <zipcode>80807</zipcode>
      <longitude>11.5957899</longitude>
      <latitude>48.17934</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1726</importID>
      <name>Solisyon GmbH</name>
      <label>You Rock! Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.solisyon.de/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/917/EventSponsor_13876.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>85</importID>
      <name>Pyramid Analytics</name>
      <label>You Rock! Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.PyramidAnalytics.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://pages.pyramidanalytics.com/rs/pyramidanalytics/images/logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1746</importID>
      <name>Trivadis AG</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.trivadis.com/de</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.trivadis.com/sites/all/themes/custom/img/header_logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1712</importID>
      <name>Alteryx</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.alteryx.com/de</url>
      <imageURL>https://passqlsat555sto01.blob.core.windows.net/sponsor/Alteryx_logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>761</importID>
      <name>JetBrains</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.jetbrains.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://johnbulla.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/logo_jetbrains_31.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1448</importID>
      <name>oh22</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.oh22.net</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/950/EventSponsor_14467.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1618</importID>
      <name>GDS Business Intelligence GmbH</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.gdsbi.de</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_14056.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>729</importID>
      <name>inovex GmbH</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.inovex.de</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.inovex.de/typo3conf/ext/contentelements/Resources/Public/img/logo.svg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53148</importID>
      <name>Ben Weissman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben Weissman has been working with SQL Server since SQL Server 6.5, mainly in the BI/Datawarehousing field. He is a Data Platform MVP, MCSE Data Management and Analytics, and a Certified Data Vault Data Modeler. He is also the first BimlHero Certified Expert in Germany and a co-author of  'SQL Server Big Data Clusters' and 'The Biml Book'.
Ben has been involved in more than 150 BI Projects and is always looking for ways to become more productive and make SQL Server even more fun!
Together with his team at Solisyon, Ben provides training, implementation and consultancy for SQL/BI developers and data analysts in upper-mid-market companies around the globe.</description>
      <twitter>bweissman</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://de.linkedin.com/in/weissmanben</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bweissman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52528</importID>
      <name>Oliver Engels</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Oliver Engels is CEO of oh22data AG, a Microsoft Gold Partner in Germany specializing in CRM and BI. His special interests are Azure, Data Governance and Integration, Visualisation Tools like SSRS, Power BI, Tableau, R, and SharePoint. He has worked with SQL Server since version 6.5 and is a founder and Board member of PASS Germany, a PASS Regional Mentor, and runs the Frankfurt PASS Local Group. For more than seven years he is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a Microsoft pTSP.</description>
      <twitter>@oengels</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ssis-components.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@oengels</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49787</importID>
      <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Uwe Ricken is working with IT systems since the 90’s. The primary passion for developments with Microsoft SQL Server expanded in 2007 with his engagement as a DBA for Deutsche Bank AG in Frankfurt am Main. After 6 years of operational experiences as a DBA and over 14 years as a developer of complex database models he achieved the “Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008” certification which “was” the highest technical certification. In the same year he earned his first award as a Data Platform MVP for his support to the Microsoft SQL Server community in Germany and Europe. Uwe Ricken is a speaker on many international conferences and events and preferred topics are “Database Internals”, “Indexing” and “Development”.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dbBerater</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=270775013amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmaster.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dbBerater</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50159</importID>
      <name>Bent Pedersen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bent is a Data Platform MVP and working as Senior Business Analytics Architect at Kapacity A/S, where he have been working with enterprise customers on solutions with SSAS Tabular, SQL Server and in general Azure Data Platform services for the last years. During the past years, he concentrated on working with architecturing, devOps, Automation, testing and simplifying development processes for the Azure Data Platform.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLBent</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://dk.linkedin.com/in/bentnissenpedersen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.biblog.eu</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLBent</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52296</importID>
      <name>Gabi Münster</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gabi Münster is working as a Business Intelligence consultant and team lead and brings in her experience with SQL Server, data warehousing, relational and multidimensional database design and implementation, report and dashboard design, and Master Data Services, as well as project management into the community as a regional PASS Local Group lead. She is also passionate about motivating other women to start a technical career and therefore initiates and supports "Women in Technology" events. Apart from SQLSaturdays, she also spoke at SQLBits, SQL Nexus, Tuga IT, and 2015's and 2017's PASS Summit. In October 2017 Gabi received her first Data Platform MVP award.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLMissSunshine</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabimuenster/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLMissSunshine</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49862</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo Kornelis is an established SQL Server community expert who spends a lot of time at various conferences. He is author of "the Execution Plan Reference" (sqlserverfast.com/epr), blogger, technical editor of Grant Fritchey's "SQL Server Execution Plans, 3rd edition" and some other books, and Pluralsight author. He was awarded SQL Server MVP and Data Platform MVP 12 times (2006 - 2016, and 2019-present).

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.</description>
      <twitter>Hugo_Kornelis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/hugokornelis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Hugo_Kornelis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53664</importID>
      <name>Regis Baccaro</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Regis has more than 15 years of experience with SQL Server, SharePoint and .Net as an architect and developer. R#233;gis is a SQL Server MVP since 2014 and a frequent speaker at SQL conferences, a PASS Regional Mentor and the founder of SQL Saturday Denmark community event. He is also a certified industry trainer on the APS/PDW platform. In his freetime he is an avid runner, cook and farmer.</description>
      <twitter>@regbac</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/regisbaccaro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://theblobfarm.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@regbac</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49804</importID>
      <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dejan Sarka, MCT and Data Platform MVP, is an independent trainer and consultant that focuses on development of database and business intelligence applications. Besides projects, he spends about half of his time on training and mentoring. He is the founder of the Slovenian SQL Server and .NET Users Group. Dejan Sarka is the main author or co-author of eighteen books about databases and SQL Server. Dejan Sarka has also developed many courses and seminars for Microsoft, Radacad, SolidQ, and Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>DejanSarka</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/dsarka/Home.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DejanSarka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53111</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53445</importID>
      <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niko Neugebauer is a Data Platform Consultant. A SQL Server MVP with over 20 years of experience in IT, he is passionate about the Microsoft Data Platform and community. Founder of the Portuguese SQL Server User Group and the main organizer of the first SQLSaturday event outside of North America (#78 Portugal), Niko speaks regularly at events such as PASS Summit, SQLRally, SQLBits, and SQLSaturday events around the world. Niko loves sharing information and knowledge and has authored over 130 blog posts on Columnstore Indexes, and regularly contributes to the open-sourced CISL library focused on Columnstore Indexes.</description>
      <twitter>NikoNeugebauer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pt.linkedin.com/in/webcaravela/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.nikoport.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=NikoNeugebauer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52757</importID>
      <name>William Durkin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>William Durkin is a DBA, Data Platform MVP, and Data Platform Architect for Data Masterminds (http://datamasterminds.io). He uses his decade of experience with SQL Server to help multinational corporations achieve their data management goals. Born in the UK and now based in Germany, William has worked as a Database Developer and DBA on projects ranging from single server installations, up to environments spanning 5 continents, using a range of high availability solutions. William is a regular speaker at conferences around the globe, organizes the popular event SQLGrillen (http://sqlgrillen.com).</description>
      <twitter>@sql_williamd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/wdurkin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://williamdurkin.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sql_williamd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50808</importID>
      <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Miloš Radivojević is a database consultant located in Vienna, Austria. He is Data Platform MVP and specializes in SQL Server for application developers and performance and query tuning. Currently, he works as a principal database consultant in bwin GVC (the largest regulated online gaming company in the world). He is co-founder of the SQL Pass Austria and speaks regularly at local and international database conferences. He is also co-author of the books SQL Server 2016 Developer's Guide, SQL Server 2017 Developer's Guide and Mastering SQL Server 2017.</description>
      <twitter>MilosSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://at.linkedin.com/pub/milos-radivojevic/1b/7bb/290/de</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://milossql.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MilosSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53285</importID>
      <name>Kenneth Nielsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kenneth M. Nielsen currently work at Microsoft as Data Platform Solution Architect, focusing on data services on Azure. Previously worked as managing consultant and teamlead for the company Rehfeld Partners in Denmark. He has worked at various consulting firms and worked on many small/large/very large bi installations in Denmark over the last 12 years. He really likes to advice the customers to take the right decisions, but also maintains a high technical knowledge, so he can act at both architect and developer.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DoktorKermit</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/kennethmnielsen/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://funkylab.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DoktorKermit</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53559</importID>
      <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kalen Delaney is a Data Platform MVP who has worked with SQL Server for more than 32 years. She has provided performance consulting services and taught advanced courses on SQL Server to thousands of people and organizations. In addition to her courseware development, Kalen has been writing about SQL Server for decades. She is the primary author of SQL Server Internals and the Inside SQL Server series. Kalen is also one of the primary editors for the Red Gate SQL Server Stairways tutorials.</description>
      <twitter>sqlqueen</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlqueen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54070</importID>
      <name>Heiko Böhm</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Heiko  Böhm ist bei Pyramid Analytics für den Vertrieb in Deutschland zuständig. Heiko arbeitet seit über 20 Jahren in der IT Industrie in verschiedenen Positionen u.a. als Business Evangelist und Partner Account Manager. In diesen Funktionen hat er viel Erfahrung in der Beratung, Business Development und Vertrieb von strategischen Themen wie Big Data, SaaS Enablement, Cloud- und Mobility-Consulting gesammelt.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/Bohei</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://de.linkedin.com/in/heikoboehm</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/Bohei</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50201</importID>
      <name>Gerhard Brueckl</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gerhard has been working with Microsoft BI tools since 2006 mainly focusing on Microsoft SQL Server and its components. As a consultant and architect he designed various enterprise BI solutions primary in the German-speaking areas. His personal interest has always been on analytical databases and their capabilities. In 2012 he achieved the SSAS Maestro certification. He is also very active in the community, has its own blog and speaks at conferences all over the world on a regular basis.</description>
      <twitter>gbrueckl</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://at.linkedin.com/in/gbrueckl/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.gbrueckl.at</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=gbrueckl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54069</importID>
      <name>Gabi Münster</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gabi Münster is working as a Business Intelligence consultant and team lead and brings in her experience with SQL Server, data warehousing, relational and multidimensional database design and implementation, report and dashboard design, and Master Data Services, as well as project management into the community as a regional PASS Local Group lead. She is also passionate about motivating other women to start a technical career and therefore initiates and supports "Women in Technology" events. Apart from SQLSaturdays, she also spoke at SQLBits, SQL Nexus, Tuga IT, and 2015's and 2017's PASS Summit. In October 2017 Gabi received her first Data Platform MVP award.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLMissSunshine</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabimuenster/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLMissSunshine</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50051</importID>
      <name>Andre Essing</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andre Essing advises, in his role as Technology Solutions Professional, customers in topics all around the Microsoft Data Platform. Since version 7.0, Andre gathering experience with the SQL Server product family, where he has focused on infrastructure topics, mission-critical systems and security. Today Andre concentrates on working with data in the cloud, like Modern Data Warehouse architectures, Artificial Intelligence and new scalable database systems like Azure Cosmos DB.

In addition to his work at Microsoft, Andre is engaged in the community as a chapter leader for the PASS chapter in Bavaria, Germany. You can meet him as a speaker at user groups and international conferences.</description>
      <twitter>@aessing</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aessing</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.andreessing.de/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@aessing</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52657</importID>
      <name>Ben Weissman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben Weissman has been working with SQL Server since SQL Server 6.5, mainly in the BI/Datawarehousing field. He is a Data Platform MVP, MCSE Data Management and Analytics, and a Certified Data Vault Data Modeler. He is also the first BimlHero Certified Expert in Germany and a co-author of  'SQL Server Big Data Clusters' and 'The Biml Book'.
Ben has been involved in more than 150 BI Projects and is always looking for ways to become more productive and make SQL Server even more fun!
Together with his team at Solisyon, Ben provides training, implementation and consultancy for SQL/BI developers and data analysts in upper-mid-market companies around the globe.</description>
      <twitter>bweissman</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://de.linkedin.com/in/weissmanben</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bweissman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53678</importID>
      <name>Scott Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Scott Klein is a senior consultant with SQL Solutions Group with over two decades of experience working with Microsoft SQL Server. Prior to SSG, Scott spent almost 10 years at Microsoft, traveling the globe as a technical evangelist training and speaking about SQL Server and Microsoft’s Azure data services. Scott’s recent focus has been on advanced analytics, including big data and IoT, providing real-world training to help bring intelligence to your data. Scott has authored several books focusing on data and data analytics. Scott is continuously striving and looking for ways to help developers and companies grok the wonderful world of data.</description>
      <twitter>SQLScott</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/sqlscott</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLScott</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53397</importID>
      <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wolfgang Strasser creates solutions based on the Microsoft Data Platform tools in his day-to-day job as Business Intelligence consultant. Either using SQL Server Database Engine, SSIS, reporting with SSAS and SSRS, implementing Power BI solutions or cloud tools for data analysis - the data-tools-landscape is broadening every day! Based on his professional careers as a software developer he likes to work on structured development processes.
Wolfgang shares his knowledge with the community at many national and international events. For his community work, Wolfgang has been awarded with the Microsoft MVP Award for Data Platform in October 2015</description>
      <twitter>wstrasser</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/wolfgang-strasser/7b/912/22b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://workingondata.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=wstrasser</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52700</importID>
      <name>Benjamin Kettner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr. Benjamin Kettner is a mathematician, founder and CTO of ML!PA Consulting GmbH. His fokus lies on consulting his clients technically and strategically for implementation of projects in different areas of the data platform. 
Er is regional chapter lead of the Berlin chapter of PASS, since 2020 he is a Microsoft MVP and he is a regular speaker on different events.</description>
      <twitter>DataMonsterBen</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.tsql-ninja.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataMonsterBen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53714</importID>
      <name>André Kamman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>André Kamman is a DBA and SQL Server Solutions Architect for CloudDBA. He has done a lot of DBA work on 1000’s of servers where he discovered his love for Powershell, architecting SQL Server solutions, building and tuning ETL processes (with BIML). He also likes to work with MPP platforms APS and AzureDW. André is a Data Platform MVP, Dutch PASS Chapter Leader and organiser of SQL Saturday Holland.</description>
      <twitter>@andrekamman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://andrekamman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@andrekamman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49799</importID>
      <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen, as the founder of Savory Data, has a long history of providing customer solutions in the areas of data engineering, data science, and Business Intelligence. He is a certified software engineer, a graduated business educator, and professor of Databases  Project Management at HTL Leonding, and is certified as an MCSE  MCT. He is a published author and writes articles for well-known journals. He co-founded PASS Austria and organizes SQLSaturdays in Austria. Markus is a founding member of Power BI Usergroup Austria. Since 2017 Markus was awarded as an Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>MEhrenmueller</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markus-ehrenmueller/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.savorydata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MEhrenmueller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50166</importID>
      <name>Marcel Tilly</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nach der Uni startete Marcel seine Odyssee durch die Software Entwicklung mit Fokus auf gro#223;e, verteilte Systeme. Im Jahr 2006 beschloss er aus der Java-Welt in die .Net-Welt zu wechseln und begann als Program-Manager bei Microsoft Research. Hier besch#228;ftigt er sich seitdem mit Big Data. Technologien zum Ermitteln von Mustern auf Datenstr#246;men, Echtzeit-Verarbeitung, der Einsatz von Azure Technologien und natuerlich das Internet der Dinge bilden einen Schwerpunkt in den letzten Jahren. Wenn dann noch Zeit bleibt, spricht er auf Konferenzen, schreibt Artikel oder programmiert einfach irgendetwas.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50901</importID>
      <name>Ryan Yates</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SharePoint amp; PowerShell Specialist - moving more into a dedicated PowerShell focus to help coach organisations in methods that they can use to improve their configuration management on a larger scale allowing them to deploy production ready code quicker, easier and with more confidence and importantly at scale in a repeatable manner.

Co-Ordinator of the UK PowerShell User Groups - with groups in Manchester amp; London but with a view to expand this across the UK in 2016 - If interested in getting one going in your area then lets talk about it :-)</description>
      <twitter>ryanyates1990</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.kilasuit.org/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ryanyates1990</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53800</importID>
      <name>Ralph Kemperdick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ralph Kemperdick is a long term supporter of the German technical SQL Server community. He has been working on the most challenging Big Data and Data warehouse projects in Germany and helps to shape the future of the Microsoft product suite as technical insider. His current position at Microsoft Germany is a digital business architect, data and he has a solid background as technical senior for large scale cloud enabled Enterprise architectures and data management. Before joining Microsoft he gained experience in Software development and marketing specializing on verticals like utilities, telecommunication, manufacturing and retail. Over 20 years he put his emphasis on analytical applications, data warehouse and data mining concepts.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ralphke</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blogs.technet.microsoft.com/sqlteamgermany</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>49862</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49862</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development (DEV-OPS)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL User-Defined Functions, or: Bad Performance Made Easy [EN]</title>
      <description>User-defined functions in SQL Server are very much like custom methods and properties in .Net languages. At first sight, they seem to be the perfect tool to introduce code encapsulation and reuse in T-SQL. So why is this feature mostly avoided by all T-SQL gurus?
The reason is performance. In this session, you will learn how user-defined functions feed the optimizer with misleading and insufficient information, how the optimizer fails to use even what little information it has, and how this can lead to shocking query performance.
However, you will also see that there is a way to avoid the problems. With just a little extra effort, you can reap the benefits of code encapsulation and reuse, and still get good performance.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49787</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49787</id>
          <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development (DEV-OPS)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>Daily problems with indexing and its - possible - solution [DE]</title>
      <description>Have you ever been in the situation that an application performed well the last day and - suddenly - you run into problems? Although you have Index Maintenance jobs and statistics up to date you will monitor a big degrade of performance! This session will demonstrate in a over 80 percent demo based presentation the following scenarios which happend this way in real life!
- Why performance degradation in spite of maintenance jobs?
- just one more database in the result set and the query runs really bad - why?
- usage of literals is completely different from the usage of variables - why?
- identical data types but the query runs in part perfect and in part bad...
- your execution plan shows an INDEX SEEK - but the table will be scanned!
- you get a query from the business which performs really bad but when you test it it runs pretty cool - why?</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50166</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50166</id>
          <name>Marcel Tilly</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud  Big Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - Cloud</name>
      </location>
      <title>Heute in der Suppenküche: Cognitive Services Allerlei [DE]</title>
      <description>Heute im Angebot eine Gericht das sowohl den Data-Veganer, als auch den Deep-Learning-Fruitarier befriedigen sollte: Cognitive Services Allerlei. Unser Chefkoch serviert eine ausgewogene Mahlzeit aus ein bisschen Computer Vision, gespickt mit ein wenig Spracherkennung. Nat#252;rlich darf der orientalische Geschmack von Language Understanding in Form von LUIS nicht fehlen. Immer wieder werden nebenbei klassische Geschmacksknospen angesprochen in Form von ein wenig Grundlagen zum Thema Deep Learning. Abschlie#223;end werden wir uns ein buntes Dessert aus Bot Framework g#246;nnen. Nat#252;rlich werden Demos und Anwendungen dem ganzen Gericht einen runden Abschluss bieten. Ein guten Appetit w#252;nschen wir schon im Voraus.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50051</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50051</id>
          <name>Andre Essing</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Security – Netzwerkkabel ziehen ist keine Lösung  [DE]</title>
      <description>Schon lange ist Sicherheit in der IT ein Thema mit hohem Stellenwert. Dabei steht der Schutz der unternehmenseigenen Daten und der Daten der Kunden an oberster Stelle. Doch wie Schütze ich meine Daten? Die Absicherung der Applikationen, Berechtigungen und Secure Code ist nur ein Teil eines sicheren Systems. Des Weiteren gehört auch die Absicherung der Infrastruktur und des SQL Servers selbst zu einem sicheren System. 
Der SQL Server liefert hier eine Vielzahl an Funktionen, welche mit SQL Server 2016 sogar noch um interessante Features wie Always Encrypted, Row Level Security oder Data Masking  erweitert werden.
Diese Session bietet einen Überblick über die wichtigsten Security Features des SQL Servers und anhand eines realen Beispiels durchleuchten wir die Absicherung der SQL Server Landschaft.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49799</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49799</id>
          <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Are You a DBA by Accident? Welcome to the Club! [DE]</title>
      <description>When I joined runtastic.com to build their very first centralized data warehouse with Microsoft SQL Server, no one really felt in charge of the server – so the responsibility fell into my humble hands. Besides my duties as a business intelligence architect (designing  implementing the database, ETL  cube), I had to quickly come up with a solution for the most important administrative tasks:
•	Disaster Recovery and Failover
•	Database Maintenance
•	Capacity Management
•	Job  Performance Monitoring
In this session I will invite you to discuss the pros  cons of the solutions I came up with and you will leave the session with helpful concepts and scripts which you can use freely.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50901</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50901</id>
          <name>Ryan Yates</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why and how to Implement PowerShell DSC for SQL Server [EN]</title>
      <description>In this Session we will delve into the need to deploy and manage SQL Server Configurations using PowerShell Desired State Configuration and the immediate benefits that this can and will bring to your deployment and administration of this very much vital technology.
Believe me when I say that I am no SQL Expert but this session will leave those that attend in a position to go away and look to implement this in their organisation and really reap the benefits that managing your Infrastructure as Code brings to a flexible an more maintainable environment.

This session will also briefly cover the other core necessities that will be required to get this underway which include the importance of Source Control for the configurations, Community Developed Resources  more.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52528</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52528</id>
          <name>Oliver Engels</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>2016! Data transformation with M, SSIS, POLY, ADF, ADLA, R [DE]</title>
      <description>It is 2016! Launch year! For the Data Platform Community at no time there were more possibilities and tools to transform data with Microsoft than today! This session will help you to find a way through the jungle. Based on a use case, we compare the tool sets in live demos and show the different approaches and when to choose what. We provide a decision matrix including the comparison by the variety of data sources, learning curve, security, scalability and many more. 
In this comparison you will find "M" (Power Query Language), SSIS (Integration Services), POLY (Polybase integration in SQL Server 2016), ADF (Azure Data Factory), ADLA (Azure Data Lake Analytics / U-SQL) and R (the Statistical Scripting Language that ships now with SQL 2016)
This gives you a good starting point for new data transformation projects or to review existing under the new approaching technologies.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52657</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52657</id>
          <name>Ben Weissman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Biml Rezepte für SSIS - Best Practices für das nächste Level [DE]</title>
      <description>Wer schon erste Erfahrungen mit Biml gesammelt hat, der wei#223;, welches Potenzial dahinter steckt. Er wei#223; aber auch, dass es sich um einen Baukasten handelt - viele Funktionen muss man sich m#252;hsam erarbeiten. Oder man #252;bernimmt sie einfach! In dieser Session zeigt Deutschlands erster und einziger BimlHero anhand von Beispielen, wie ihr eure Biml Solutions mit Hilfe von BimlScript und LINQ auf die n#228;chste Ebene bringt. Unter anderem betrachten wir Themen wie Timestamps und sonstige derived columns (sowohl mit Transformern als auch manuell), Beibehaltung von Indizes aus dem Warehouse oder Vorsystem
sowie die Inkrementelle #220;bernahme von #196;nderungen in eine Staging Area. Den verwendeten Beispielcode gibt es nat#252;rlich direkt zum mitnehmen, selbst ausprobieren und weiterentwickeln.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52757</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52757</id>
          <name>William Durkin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Replication - What, How and Why [EN]</title>
      <description>In an AlwaysOn world we focus on entire databases being highly available. However, replication offers another, arguably more powerful, way to make data available on multiple servers/locations that steps outside of "normal" High Availability scenarios. 

This session will explain what database replication is, what the different parts are that make up the replication architecture and when/why you would use replication. You will leave the session with an understanding of how you can leverage this feature to achieve solutions that are not possible using other High Availability features. 

The content will be valid for all versions of SQL Server from 2005 onward.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53664</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53664</id>
          <name>Regis Baccaro</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Kerberos for BI [EN]</title>
      <description>Have you ever seen this message quot;Login failed for user ‘NT AUTHORITY\ANONYMOUS LOGONquot; ?
Have you ever witnessed Kerberos mentioned in a conversation - or in a forum - and seen developers shiver, sysadmins crawl back under their rock and project managers fear for the consumed hours ?
Have you ever wondered why it seems so complicated ?
If you answered yes to any of these question then this demo-packed session is for you.
Because Kerberos is something that anyone who must deploy SQL Server wishes they didn’t have to worry about. It truly affects all aspects of SQL Server including the engine, Reporting Services, Analysis Services, SharePoint and PowerPivot. Furthermore we will have a close look at how to diagnose problems and troubleshoot the three-headed beast when it breaks loose.
This session is based on many hours spent sweating in setting up Kerberos in BI and SharePoint environments and explaining support people how to troubleshoot and fix Kerberos issues when they a</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53111</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53111</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>NSA Secrets - Hacking SQL Server [EN]</title>
      <description>How easy is it to hack a SQL Server? 
In this session we'll see a few examples on how to exploit SQL Server, modify data and take control, while at the same time not leaving a trace.
We'll start by gaining access to a SQL Server (using some "creative" ways of making man-in-the-middle attacks), escalating privileges and tampering with data at the TDS protocol level (e.g. changing your income level and reverting without a trace after payment), and more. 
Most importantly, we'll also cover recommendations on how to avoid these attacks, and take a look at the pros and cons of new security features in SQL Server 2016.
This is a demo-driven session, suited for DBAs, developers and security consultants (Jedi level). 
Disclaimer: No actual state secrets will be revealed. Please do not send agents to my house again.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53285</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53285</id>
          <name>Kenneth Nielsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud  Big Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - Cloud</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Lake Store / Analytics 101 [EN]</title>
      <description>In this session we take a look and a deep dive into Aure Data Lake, a new feature on Azure that will enable amost anyone to work with BIG DATA. It combines C# and SQL to a language that is way more intuitive than what we are used to.

Azure Data Lake Store, our new repository for data of various origins – we can collect, store and share data from this lake as we see fit. Azure Data Lake Analytics, a new way to scale and use your analytics on AZURE and BIG Data, it introduces U-SQL a new language combined of C# and T-SQL to make the task of analyzing BIG Data easier and more comprehendible. Azure Data Lake Tools for Visual Studio, provide an integrated development environment that spans the Azure Data Lake, dramatically simplifying authoring, debugging and optimization for processing and analytics at any scale. After this session, you will have an understanding of the new feature, and will hopefully be inspired to use it either in a Proof Of Concept or in a Production scenario.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53678</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53678</id>
          <name>Scott Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud  Big Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - Cloud</name>
      </location>
      <title>Fun with SQL Server 2016 Stretch Database, Temporal  Always Encrypted [EN]</title>
      <description>Your cold data growth is getting out of control, storage consumption is increasing faster than your budget, your end-users won't (or can't) tell you what can delete or truncate, but they demand their cold or archived data always be online and available. Now you have tables so big that you dread re-indexing, and you have to look for ever more creative solutions to manage this data, while still remaining compliant. There’s a solution that lets you take advantage of the Cloud, on your terms, all without impacting your existing end-user applications or queries. Come find out how you can move your data securely and transparently, free up disc space and reduce your enterprise storage consumption, while retaining full control from the on-premises SQL Server. You’ll reduce maintenance operations time and resources, plus lower overall cost. Learn how SQL Server Stretch database will simplify your journey to the Cloud!</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52700</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52700</id>
          <name>Benjamin Kettner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advanced Analytics im ERP-Umfeld [DE]</title>
      <description>Mit dem SQL Server 2016 wurden im Bereich Analytics durch die Integration von R neue M#246;glichkeiten geschaffen. Die Integration von R in den SQL Server bietet dabei M#246;glichkeiten, die weit #252;ber Ad-Hoc Analysen hinaus gehen. 
In der Session zeigen wir, wie man ein Vorhersagemodell in R in eine Standard-Software-L#246;sung integriert. Daf#252;r haben wir eine Vorhersage f#252;r eine Kennzahl im ERP der Firma abas auf Basis von reellen Unternehmensdaten  entwickelt und in die L#246;sung integriert. Zus#228;tzlich pr#228;sentieren wir den konkreten Weg zur Entwicklung des Vorhersagemodells sowie die Integration in abas ERP.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54070</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54070</id>
          <name>Heiko Böhm</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>Maximierung Ihres Investments in Microsoft mit Pyramid Analytics</title>
      <description>Die Datennutzung, d.h. die effektive Sammlung, Auswertung und Reporting von organisationsrelevanten Informationen, ist eine der wichtigsten Aufgaben, die CIOs derzeit als wettbewerbsfähigen Vorteil betrachten und für die CFOs bereit sind, erheblich zu investieren.
Zahlreichen branchenführenden Unternehmen ist es bereits gelungen, ihre Geschäftsabläufe von „datenblind“ auf „datengestützt“ umzustellen. Der Business Intelligence (BI)-Bereich wächst zweistellig.
Erfahren Sie in diesem Vortrag, wie Sie mit BI Office Ihr Investment in Microsoft optimieren können und zu einem datengestützten Unternehmen werden. Sehen Sie, wie dies mit Microsofts Power BI zusammenspielt. Hören Sie dazu auch hilfreiche Praxisbeispiele.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50201</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50201</id>
          <name>Gerhard Brueckl</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud  Big Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - Cloud</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deep-Dive into Polybase of SQL Server 2016 [DE]</title>
      <description>Polybase is a feature originally coming from APS but is now finally also available in native SQL Server 2016. It allows you to query external data sources, foremost Hadoop, directly from within SQL Server and combine it with any other data that already resides in your database. Especially the rise of the whole Hadoop data platform in the current markets makes this feature very interesting and is definitely worth a closer look. This session will guide you through the process of setting up Polybase on Hadoop and Azure Blob Stores, showing some real-world use-cases and highlight the most common pitfalls that you may encounter.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 5:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 6:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52296</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52296</id>
          <name>Gabi Münster</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Scoped assignments – Fluch oder Segen? Beispiele aus der Praxis... [DE]</title>
      <description>Kennt ihr das? Man möchte keinen weiteren Scope mehr in seinem Cube implementieren, weil man die Seiteneffekte nicht mehr überblickt? Oder weil man mit jeder Berechnung um die Performance fürchtet?
Gerade mulitdimensionale Lösungen können so komplex werden. Die Möglichkeiten sind vielfältig und mit zunehmender Komplexität wird es immer schwieriger, die Auswirkungen einer Änderung zu testen. Diese Session kann das Problem auch nicht lösen, aber an konkreten Praxisbeispielen Probleme und Lösungsmöglichkeiten aufzeigen.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54069</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54069</id>
          <name>Gabi Münster</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Women in Technology</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - Cloud</name>
      </location>
      <title>Women in Technology – Still a Rarity. Any Ideas? [EN]</title>
      <description>The proportion of women in the IT sector keeps to be below other occupational areas, even compared to other technical professions. A number of actions to positively influence this situation have been initiated by politics as well as private economy. But is this really enough?
The goal of this session is to provide you with information regarding those activities and concepts. But even more important: We want to get your feedback. How are your experiences as a woman in technology, as a colleague, as an employer…? What are your hopes and expectations? How do you see the role of PASS in this context? Do you have any ideas, proposals, criticism for us?</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53397</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53397</id>
          <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence  (BI)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Bauer BI und seine Pig Data [DE]</title>
      <description>Bauer BI hat#39;s nicht einfach. Viel Arbeit im Stall und dann soll er noch Daten #252;ber seine Schweine auswerten! Mit Excel kennt er sich ja aus, aber wie soll er hier f#252;r die Kontrolleure vom Landwirtschaftministerium eine #220;bersicht erstellen? Wie gut dass es seinen Nachbarn gibt - der stellt Bauer BI einen neuen Gehilfen im Datenstall vor: Power BI! 
Begleiten Sie uns auf der Datenanalysereise von Bauer BI und Power BI. Vielleicht kommt ja auch noch real-time streaming aus dem Schweinestall hinzu und schon haben wir ein Power BI Dashboard f#252;r das Landwirtschaftministerium. Und Bauer BI ist gl#252;cklich..</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 5:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 6:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53148</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53148</id>
          <name>Ben Weissman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Das ultimative Solisyon SQL Quiz [DE]</title>
      <description>Um nach dem Mittagessen wieder langsam wach zu werden, veranstalten wir mit euch das ultimative SQL Quiz - freut euch auf Fragen um alles rund um den SQL Server aus verschiedensten Kategorien!</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53800</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53800</id>
          <name>Ralph Kemperdick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development (DEV-OPS)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>Scenarios and value proposition for JSON data enabled in Azure SQ</title>
      <description>We will cover the following scenarios:
o	Loading JSON data into the database
o	Transforming Data with the database
o	Servicing JSON to the application layer
o	Advanced scenarios when working with JSON</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53445</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53445</id>
          <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development (DEV-OPS)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>Columnstore Technology Improvements in SQL Server 2016 [DE]</title>
      <description>Columnstore Technology has received one of the biggest number of improvements across all SQL Server 2016 technologies. Discover Operational Analytics and InMemory Analytics for the OLTP workloads with updatable Nonclustered Columnstore Indexes, Data Warehousing with vastly enhanced Clustered Columnstore Index that now can have all the typical functionalities of a well-designed amp; high performing database such as Unique Constraints, Foreign Keys and Secondary Indexes. Discover all the maintenance improvements that will allow to operate and manipulate the Columnstore structures with more precision and insights.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53559</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53559</id>
          <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development (DEV-OPS)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>Are You Optimistic About Concurrency? [EN]</title>
      <description>What exactly does it mean to have optimistic concurrency? What is the alternative? Is SQL Server 2012#39;s SNAPSHOT Isolation optimistic? How can SQL Server 2014’s In-Memory OLTP provide truly optimistic concurrency? In this session, we’ll look at what guarantees the various isolation levels provide, the difference between pessimistic and optimistic concurrency, and the new data structures in SQL Server 2014 that allow the enormous benefits of having totally in-memory storage with no waiting!</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50159</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50159</id>
          <name>Bent Pedersen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud  Big Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - Cloud</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hybrid BI [EN]</title>
      <description>With the introduction of SQL 2016 and all its new features, Hybrid BI is more in focus then ever. Doing BI is no longer bound to be on-premise or in the cloud. With all the new features and the Azure platform Microsoft has made it easier then ever to implement a hybrid platform.

When working with a hybrid platform your organisation will be able to select strategy and features based on the highest ROI. During this session I will go through three different aspects of Hybrid BI which is infrastructure, data-storage and reporting. 

As part of this i will go through the advantages and disadvantages of each area to supply you with the information you need to choose the right direction for your platform.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49804</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49804</id>
          <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud  Big Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - Cloud</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using R in SQL Server, Power BI, and Azure ML [EN]</title>
      <description>In SQL Server, Azure ML, and Power BI suites, you can find nearly anything you need for analyzing your data. SQL Server 2016 closes one of the last gaps - support for statistics beyond basic aggregate functions and support for other mathematical calculations. This is done with support for the R code inside SQL Server Database Engine. This session goes beyond showing the basics, i.e. how to use R in the Database Engine, Power BI and Reporting Services reports, and to enhance Azure ML; it shows and explains also some advanced statistical and matrix calculations.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53714</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53714</id>
          <name>André Kamman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (DBA)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Powershell community scripts for DBAs [EN]</title>
      <description>There are many community scripts out there that DBAs can use without having to write them yourself. Like Ola Hallengrens scripts, or Brent Ozars or sp_WhoIsActive by Adam Machanic. But how about Powershell? Turns out, this world is still a bit unknown to the DBA but there is a fast growing community with extremely useful scripts for day to day SQL Server management. In this session we will take a look into my favourite scripts and we will also write a bit of Powershell ourselves.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 5:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 6:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50808</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50808</id>
          <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development (DEV-OPS)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>What Application Developers Should Know About SQL Server? [DE]</title>
      <description>Nowadays many companies don't have dedicated developer positions. Therefore the most of the SQL code has been written by application developers. And they use only a subset of SQL Server features and usually in a suboptimal manner.
I spent last ten years working with application developers and have collected common mistakes and misunderstandings between them and DBAs that increase development, test and deployment costs and reduce the overall quality.
In this session we will cover the most important things they need to know about SQL Server and that cannot be easily or cheap fixed by DBAs or consultants.</description>
      <startTime>10/8/2016 5:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/8/2016 6:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>