<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #509 - Brisbane 2016</name>
    <startDate>5/28/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>150</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+10:00) Canberra, Melbourne, Sydney</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat509</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Brisbane</name>
      <street>Level 28, 400 George Street Brisbane</street>
      <city>Brisbane</city>
      <state>Queensland, Australia</state>
      <zipcode>4000</zipcode>
      <longitude>153.020645</longitude>
      <latitude>-27.468469</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1272</importID>
      <name>WARDY IT Solutions</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.wardyit.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/986/EventSponsor_14725.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1697</importID>
      <name>Pure Storage Qld  NT</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.purestorage.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.nyse.com/publicdocs/nyse/events/images/PSTG_Light-Backs_1920.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1115</importID>
      <name>SQL Sentry</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlsentry.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sentryone.com/Images/logos/sentryone-black.svg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1103</importID>
      <name>SQL Masters Consulting</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlmastersconsulting.com.au</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/986/EventSponsor_14638.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1616</importID>
      <name>Red Gate</name>
      <label>Swag Sponsors</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>44929</importID>
      <name>Manohar Punna</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Manohar Punna is an Data Platform Geek and Vice President of DataPlatformGeeks by passion and a Data Platform Consultant by profession. He is a speaker at various conferences like PASS Summit, SQLBits, DPS. He has authored over 150 blogs and has written a One DMV a Day series which is a longest one day series on any topic on SQL Server till date.
Manohar is a product of this community and strongly believes in giving back to the community. So, ask him anything you would like to know and he is happy to learn it with you.</description>
      <twitter>ManuSQLGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/manohar-punna/15/153/508</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservergeeks.com/author/manoharpunna/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ManuSQLGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49254</importID>
      <name>Nagaraj Venkatesan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nagaraj Venkatesan is a Data Platform MVP from Singapore and the leader of Singapore SQL PASS Chapter. As a SQL Server enthusiast, Nagaraj is a regular speaker in Asia Pacific region at Data Platform events like SQL Saturdays, SQL Server Geeks Summit, User group meetups etc.  Nagaraj shares his technical expertise at strictlysql.blogspot.com. Nagaraj also runs a YouTube channel called "DataChannel", which contains technical interviews with top Microsoft Data Platform experts in the world.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/arrnagaraj</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://in.linkedin.com/in/nagaraj-venkatesan-b6958b6</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://strictlysql.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/arrnagaraj</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48364</importID>
      <name>Hamish Watson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hamish Watson is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware Expert with a passion for efficient database and application deployment using DevOps methodologies. 

He has 20+ years of IT experience in managing and deploying large scale databases on SQL Server technologies. 

He has been managing SQL Server since SQL Server 2000, and pragmatic approaches to delivering business value to clients is his career passion.

Educating and helping others learn is a driver for Hamish. He is a Director-At-Large on the PASS Board, international speaker, and a repeat guest lecturer at a local university.</description>
      <twitter>theHybridDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/in/hamishwatson8</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/the-hybrid-dbas-blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=theHybridDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48573</importID>
      <name>Craig Bryden</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Craig has been working with SQL Server for over 20 years and currently holds several SQL Server based certifications. He has also previously held an MCT certification. Craig's contribution to the SQL Server community was recognised in 2018 with a Microsoft MVP award. He was involved with Microsoft Learning to set some of the current SQL server Exams. Craig is the Chief Data Strategist at BiTQ. Craig is an organiser of the QLD Power BI User Group</description>
      <twitter>@cbryden</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/craigbryden/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cbryden</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46961</importID>
      <name>Victor Isakov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Victor Isakov (MCA, MCM, MCSM, MCT, MVP) is a Database Architect and trainer who provides consulting and training services to various organizations in the public, private, and NGO sectors globally. He regularly speaks at international conferences such as Microsoft TechEd/Ignite, PASS Summit, IT/Dev Connections, and SQLSaturdays.
Victor has written a number of books on SQL Server and has worked with Microsoft to develop the SQL Server exams and certification. In 2017 he authored "Exam Ref 70-764 Administering a SQL Database Infrastructure (1st Edition)".
He is one of only three non-Microsoft, Microsoft Certified Architects in the world.</description>
      <twitter>@victorisakov</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/victorisakov</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.victorisakov.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@victorisakov</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46936</importID>
      <name>Reza Rad</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reza Rad is a Microsoft Regional Director, MVP, author, trainer, speaker and consultant. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for nine years from 2011.
Reza wrote many books on Power BI subjects including the Power BI from Rookie to Rock Star, and Pro Power BI Architecture.
Reza is the invited speaker at the world's well-known conferences such as Microsoft Ignite, Microsoft Business Applications Summit, Ignite Tour, PASS Summit, and many other conferences.
Reza is an active blogger and writes regularly about Power BI at https://radacad.com.</description>
      <twitter>Rad_Reza</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/in/rezarad/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://radacad.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rad_Reza</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48867</importID>
      <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Flynn is a Senior Database Administrator with 10 years experience in large 24 x 7 enterprise environments. He is a certified master for SQL Server and a regular attendee of the PASS Summit.

Has presented at SQLSaturday events in Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane and Auckland, Edmonton and Calgary, Oslo and Cambridge</description>
      <twitter>sqllensman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqllensman.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllensman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48424</importID>
      <name>Rob Douglas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robs SQL history started as a remote DBA, branched into consultancy and now includes providing SQL Solutions to a variety of businesses, government departments and banks throughout Australia and New Zealand using a variety of native SQL solutions to meet their performance, higher availability and Disaster Recovery needs.</description>
      <twitter>Rob_DouglasNZ</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=AAMAAAoSId0BNgwoSf_o5y24oIW3PjEHbAmdY-camp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gumption.co.nz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rob_DouglasNZ</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49243</importID>
      <name>Dandy Weyn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With over 20 years of experience in the database world, Dandy Weyn is very experienced on database platforms and business intelligence. As content developer for hands-on-labs, owner of technical events, and multiple years as international consultant and trainer Dandy offers the unique combination of deep technical and solid presentation skills. He is an MCM for SQL Server, Microsoft Certified Trainer and Global Technical Lead for Data Platform in the Enterprise Partner Group (EPG)  at Microsoft.</description>
      <twitter>ILIKESQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dandyweyn</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://WWW.ILIKESQL.COM</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ILIKESQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48704</importID>
      <name>Martin Catherall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin is a data consultant in Melbourne, Australia, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, and PASS Regional Mentor for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region.
Martin founded the Christchurch, New Zealand PASS Local Group and lead the group for a number of years before relocating to Melbourne.
He has been using SQL Server in various roles since 2000. In addition to anything data related, he enjoys playing the guitar and having fun with his family.</description>
      <twitter>MartyCatherall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/martincatherall</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://martincatherall.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MartyCatherall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49157</importID>
      <name>Stefan Riedel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stefan Riedel has been working with databases for more than 15 years, the last 10 of which have been focused on Microsoft SQL Server.  Stefan has led and contributed to the implementation of many data warehouse and business intelligence solutions built using the Microsoft BI stack.  To support these projects Stefan has designed and implemented automated testing and deployment tooling to support agile BI development methodologies.  Stefan has presented at previous SQL Saturday events in Melbourne, Brisbane and Singapore.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/stefan-riedel-59b0278</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49247</importID>
      <name>Peter Myers</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Myers is a consultant, trainer and presenter, and has worked with Microsoft database and development products since 1997. Today he specializes in all Microsoft Business Intelligence products and also authors training course content for Microsoft products and services.

He has a broad business background supported by a bachelor’s degree in applied economics and accounting, and he extends this with extensive experience backed by current MCSE certifications. He has been a Data Platform MVP since 2007.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/peterjsmyers</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48360</importID>
      <name>Dan de Sousa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dan de Sousa is a Senior Data Consultant for DSI in Mississauga, Canada. He has been working with SQL Server for the last 10 years and has been involved in the development of datawarehouses as well as creating reports and dashboards. Dan is currently working on a data security compliance project for Europe which involves making sure any personal information is secured/encrypted before leaving its country of origin.</description>
      <twitter>@dcasousa</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://au.linkedin.com/pub/daniel-de-sousa/28/198/b4</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlblog2017.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dcasousa</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49244</importID>
      <name>Dandy Weyn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With over 20 years of experience in the database world, Dandy Weyn is very experienced on database platforms and business intelligence. As content developer for hands-on-labs, owner of technical events, and multiple years as international consultant and trainer Dandy offers the unique combination of deep technical and solid presentation skills. He is an MCM for SQL Server, Microsoft Certified Trainer and Global Technical Lead for Data Platform in the Enterprise Partner Group (EPG)  at Microsoft.</description>
      <twitter>ILIKESQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dandyweyn</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://WWW.ILIKESQL.COM</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ILIKESQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>44334</importID>
      <name>Amit Arora</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Amit Arora is an SQL Server Consultant with WARDY IT Solutions. Amit has over 10 years of experience working with SQL Server including working as a Technical Advisor and DBA for Microsoft. Amit has recently been working on SQL Server solutions with Microsoft Azure and HDInsight as well as other big data technologies.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://in.linkedin.com/in/amit-arora-21633699</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>44334</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>44334</id>
          <name>Amit Arora</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Board Room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Temporal Databases in Microsoft SQL server 2016</title>
      <description>Introducing Temporal Databases in SQL Server 2016

More and more organizations are storing archives of data to help them make important business decisions. Traditionally, organizations had to rely on expensive, and tedious methods to go back in time and make sense of growth, negative growth, profit, loss, etc.

Microsoft SQL Server 2016 introduces a new feature called Temporal Databases which essentially solves all the problems mentioned above.

This presentation aims to go deep into Temporal Databases (requirements, use cases, technical know-hows) and present some demo’s in order to gain specific understanding on this new feature which is being called “Time Travel”.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>44929</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>44929</id>
          <name>Manohar Punna</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>North Stradbroke</name>
      </location>
      <title>Boost your SQL Server performance with Delayed Durability and BPE</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2014 has come with many performance boosting features. In-Memory OLTP being one of the favourites, there are two more less talked about heroes - Delayed Durability and Buffer Pool Extensions. With the increase of usage of SSDs in production environment it has become essential to use them to the full potential. In this session Manohar will explore Delayed Durability and how it is achieved. He will also cover a case study with delayed durability and SSDs. SSDs can be fully utilized by enabling Buffer Pool Extensions. He will cover the usage and caveats of both these features which boosts the transaction throughput.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48360</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48360</id>
          <name>Dan de Sousa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Board Room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automated Data Validation with SQL Server using nUnit</title>
      <description>Testing software is hard work. Testing BI solutions is even harder;there's lots of moving parts, the tools are thin and it takes a lot of time and effort. Software development uses unit testing and while this can be applied to the different parts of a BI solution, most people are more interested in the numbers the solution produces and proving that they are right. So can you validate the numbers in your BI solution? And can you do it quickly and easily? In this session we will cover an approach for automating the validation of your BI solution covering multiple scenarios with a hand full of demos. We will be using nUnit as a framework and some free codeplex tools, so we can run a suite of tests every time we load data into our BI platform. This is not continuous integration, and it is not unit testing in the true sense either. It is, instead, "continuous validation", and it can provide you with an awful lot of assurance for not very much extra effort.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48704</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48704</id>
          <name>Martin Catherall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>North Stradbroke</name>
      </location>
      <title>Moving from Profiler to Extended Events.</title>
      <description>Profiler has been with us for a long time and it's pretty much the goto tool for a lot of performance related issues but there's been a new tool around for a few years now - actually since SQL SERVER 2008 - but there doesn't seem to have been a big uptake of it. Well, after this session hopefully that will all change for you.
Profiler is now deprecated and all new work is going into extended events. This means that new monitoring events are constantly being added. These give deeper insights into performance problems withing SQL SERVER and also aid the developer / DBA in understanding the inner working of the SQL SERVER database engine.
An understanding of profiler would be advantageous but is definitely not required to get some good insights from this session.
</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49247</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49247</id>
          <name>Peter Myers</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>South Stradbroke</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning: From Design to Integration</title>
      <description>Machine Learning is a subfield of computer science concerned with systems that learn from data. So this isn’t about systems that follow explicitly programmed instructions, but rather about systems that find patterns and trends within datasets, and use them to deliver insight and predictions.

In this session, you will learn how an Azure Machine Learning solution comes to life: From the creation of a workspace, to the preparation of data, to experimentation with Machine Learning algorithms, and then finally to the integration and embedding of predictive insights into applications.

This session has been specifically designed to describe Machine Learning fundamentals, and to help enable and inspire existing data professionals taking their first steps to leverage cloud-based predictive models delivered with Azure Machine Learning. It is guaranteed to thrill you with potential, and excite you with the relative ease by which it can be accomplished.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49254</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49254</id>
          <name>Nagaraj Venkatesan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Board Room</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 -  Real Time Operational Analytics - "Real" Game changer</title>
      <description>Performing analytics on operational data has all along being a huge challenge for applications, due to its impact on
regular operations and day to day transactions. SQL Server 2016 has extended its analytic capablities by its
enahancements on "In memory tables" and Columnstore indexes."In memory tables" combined with columnstore indexes
is a boon for performing analytics on operational data with no impact to regular workload, with no delayed data,
no complex ETL tasks and without a need to maintain seperate data warehouse. 

The presentation would cover how "In Memory" Columnstore indexes help to perform real time operational analytics 
and would involve interesting demos show casing the gains using SQL Server 2016 "In Memory" and Column Store Index enhancements. Presentation would also demonstrate and compare the performances of "In Memory" columnstore indexes and disk based columnstore indexes.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48364</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48364</id>
          <name>Hamish Watson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Board Room</name>
      </location>
      <title>TempDB: The forgotten pillar of performance tuning</title>
      <description>TempDB is an integral part of SQL Server, and is often overlooked when trying to get the most out of your system. Researching the many suggested methods of tuning TempDB is a long, arduous and at times confusing process.

In this session we will go over what TempDB is used for, why it is a special and important type of database and how to tune it to enhance the performance of your overall system. 

We will start with determining the best configuration of TempDB database files to use, the impact disk configuration has, which trace flags are important and what changes SQL Server 2016 will bring us. We will look at what is stored in TempDB and how both developers and DBA can optimize how TempDB is configured and used.

We will then use these best practices to optimize our instance and performance tune our queries to make the system faster.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49157</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49157</id>
          <name>Stefan Riedel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>South Stradbroke</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automated and Repeatable Test Cases for SQL Server Development.</title>
      <description>Automated and repeatable test cases are required for agile software development.  In this session we will look at some of the tools and techniques for automated testing with SQL Server.  Demonstrations during the session will create tests using the Visual Studio toolset and discuss how they can be used for Test Driven Development (TDD), unit testing, integration testing and acceptance testing.  The presentation will cover testing SQL Server Databases, SQL Server Analysis Services and SQL Server Integration Services.  Following the session attendees will be able to incorporate these tools and practices into their projects.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48867</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48867</id>
          <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Board Room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Corruption - Advanced Recovery Techniques</title>
      <description>Being able to monitor, diagnose and recover from Database Corruption is  a critical skill for any SQL Server DBA. 
In this session we will walk through the techniques required to detect and repair various forms of Corruption 
Using a number of example corrupted database we will explore how to determine and fix corruption while avoiding some of the common mistakes.
Warning: Hex Editors and DBCC Page dumps will be involved!</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46936</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46936</id>
          <name>Reza Rad</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>South Stradbroke</name>
      </location>
      <title>Cortana Intelligence Suite; Where the Magic Happens</title>
      <description>Come to this session to learn what Cortana Intelligence is and why it is used for. Cortana Intelligence is a combination of tools and services that enables you to transform your data into intelligence action. Cortana uses powerful services such as Cortana digital assistance for hearing the voice commands, Power BI for visualization, Machine Learning for prediction, Stream Analytics for real-time interaction with data with IoT devices, and many other great features. Prepare to be amazed with what Cortana can do in demos of this session.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48573</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48573</id>
          <name>Craig Bryden</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>South Stradbroke</name>
      </location>
      <title>An Introduction to R and R Services</title>
      <description>R is the most popular programming language for advanced analytics today. With Microsoft's purchase of Revolution R, we are seeing native integration of R capabilities in the SQL Server 2016 database engine (R Services). We are also seeing R support in most of the Azure cloud products.
In this session I will provide an introduction to the R language as well as discuss how you go about using this inside SQL Server and other Microsoft provided tools.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46961</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46961</id>
          <name>Victor Isakov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>North Stradbroke</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Store Overview and Architecture</title>
      <description>Fixing performance problems and detecting query regressions has never been easy in SQL Server as the database engine fundamentally does not capture the relevant information.
With the release of SQL Server 2016, Microsoft has introduced a feature called Query Store that will help you capture vital query metrics that will help performance troubleshooting and regression detection.
In this session we will examine Query Store, examine it's architecture, configuration and how it can be used to solve real-world performance problems.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49243</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49243</id>
          <name>Dandy Weyn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>South Stradbroke</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI - Getting It Right - A Full Walkthrough</title>
      <description>In this session you will get a full walkthrough of Power BI:
What is it?
How is it done?
What's in it for me?

By the end of this session you will have a full understanding of the Power BI offering and the tools used to discover data,  design dashboards and visualizations , visualize them on all devices , how to optimize your data model for Power BI, and natural language query. You'll learn about sharing and collaborating, and working with multiple datasources to build live interactive dashboards and reports. </description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48424</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48424</id>
          <name>Rob Douglas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>North Stradbroke</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hitting the SQL Server "Go Faster" Button</title>
      <description>Tuning individual queries is incredibly resource intensive.  Everyone wants a "Go Faster" button that will improve performance across the entire SQL instance.  While there is no sp_gofaster command to run, there are a bunch of magic knobs and switches that can quite often achieve the desired results.
  In this session we'll look at some of the things you can do to get the best performance out of your SQL Server workload.  You'll leave with a shopping list of things to check and options to try in your environments to get the performance you are after.</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49244</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49244</id>
          <name>Dandy Weyn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>North Stradbroke</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building HA/DR Solutions with SQL Server and Azure SQL Database</title>
      <description>In the world of Data Platform a variety of solutions are available going from on premises, hybrid to cloud solutions. Database Administrators play a crucial role in application design and architecture, providing mission critical and highly available solutions. In this session you will learn everything a DBA needs to know about Azure. You’ll learn about SQL Server running in Windows Azure virtual machines, Azure Storage and network configurations, SQL Database and how to manage and support workloads running in a traditional, hybrid and cloud based environment. 
Become the DBA of the future!
</description>
      <startTime>5/28/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/28/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>