<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #326 - Tampa - BA Edition 2014</name>
    <startDate>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat326</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>5426 Bay Center Dr</name>
      <street>
      </street>
      <city>Tampa</city>
      <state>Florida</state>
      <zipcode>33609</zipcode>
      <longitude>-82.537757</longitude>
      <latitude>27.9437</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>369</importID>
      <name>Agile Bay, Inc.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.agilebay.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://tampabaybi.pass.org/Portals/239/agilebay170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1021</importID>
      <name>SanDisk</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sandisk.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/8c03ba71-c441-404f-9673-ff879cb4c5f7.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1250</importID>
      <name>Vaco Tampa</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.vaco.com/tampa</url>
      <imageURL>https://tampabaybi.pass.org/portals/239/vacologo170x60.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>70</importID>
      <name>Tegile Systems</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.tegile.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/SQLSaturday/EventSponsors/Tegile_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1184</importID>
      <name>Tek Systems</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.teksystems.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/855/EventSponsor_13925.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>869</importID>
      <name>MSSQLTips</name>
      <label>Swag Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.mssqltips.com/index.asp</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/e507d990-c152-464a-98f0-a5e6eb75d319.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16455</importID>
      <name>Jen Underwood</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jen Underwood is a Senior Director at DataRobot. Over the past 20 years, Jen has held worldwide product management roles at Microsoft and served as a technical lead for system implementation firms. She has a unique blend of product management and “hands-on” experience in data warehousing, reporting, visualization, and advanced analytics. In addition to keeping a constant pulse on industry trends, she enjoys digging into oceans of data to solve complex problems with machine learning. 

Jen has a Bachelor of Business Administration – Marketing, Cum Laude from the University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee and a post-graduate certificate in Computer Science – Data Mining from the University of California, San Diego.</description>
      <twitter>@idigdata</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jenunderwood</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.jenunderwood.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@idigdata</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19977</importID>
      <name>Mike Davis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mike Davis, MCITP, is a Consulting Team Lead at Pragmatic Works.  He is an author with books covering Business Intelligence and SSIS.  Mike is an experienced speaker and has presented at many events such as several SQL Server User Groups, Code Camps, SQL Server Launches, SQL Saturday,  and SQL Rally. Mike is an active member at his local user group (JSSUG) in Jacksonville, FL.</description>
      <twitter>@mikedavisSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/mikedavissql</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://MikeDavisSQL.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mikedavisSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13204</importID>
      <name>David Dye</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David is a Sergeant with the Cape Coral Police Department and currently works as a database administrator and developer in the Administrative Services Division. He began his career with the police department in 1990 in the patrol division and worked various assignments until being promoted to Sergeant in 1998. Based on his education and experience David was assigned to his current position in 2002 and is responsible for database administration, software integration, and development for public sa</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14315</importID>
      <name>Frank Quintana</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Doctor Quintana has been involved in optimization and math modeling since the ’80s. 
He is an IT University professor of Data Science, Databases, Data Mining, and Knowledge Discovery. He is a former head of an RD department. He worked as a research engineer at the Memorial University of Newfoundland. He also worked as a consultant in the role of a technical team leader and software architect for EDS responsible for critical parts of the SDLC for multi-million dollar projects. He is one of the Software Architects that designed and built the "Health and Benefits System for the of the Veteran Affairs of Canada"
He is a regular speaker at national and international events
In 2004 he started his consulting practice in South and Central Flori</description>
      <twitter>Frankqr2</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/FrankQuintanaDataArchitect</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.businessintelligencematters.us</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Frankqr2</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19008</importID>
      <name>Leigh Freijo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leigh Freijo is a Manager in Database Administration for Raymond James Financial. Leigh is an experienced SQL Server DBA and the chapter leader of the Pinellas SQL User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@leighfreijo</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/leighfreijo/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@leighfreijo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13298</importID>
      <name>Dmitri Korotkevitch</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dmitri Korotkevitch is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and Microsoft Certified Master, author of Pro SQL Server Internals and other books with years of experience working with SQL Server as an Application and Database Developer, Database Administrator, and Database Architect. 

Dmitri specializes in the design, development, and performance tuning of complex OLTP systems that handle thousands of transactions per second around the clock. He blogs at: http://aboutsqlserver.com.</description>
      <twitter>aboutsqlserver</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/dmitri-korotkevitch/5/980/b7</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aboutsqlserver.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=aboutsqlserver</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19917</importID>
      <name>Maximo Trinidad</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Maximo Trinidad (Florida Aka – Mr. PowerShell), currently work as a SAPIEN Technologies Evangelist and specialing in scripting automation on SQL Server  Microsoft Cloud Technologies. Also a Microsoft MVP (PowerShell) since 2009 and active speaker since 2007 participating at SQLSaturday, IT Pro  .NET Code Camps events.</description>
      <twitter>maxtrinidad</twitter>
      <linkedin>Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/pub/max-trinidad/12/47/775/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.maxtblog.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=maxtrinidad</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21011</importID>
      <name>Mitchell Pearson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mitchell is an experienced Business Intelligence Consultant and Trainer at Pragmatic Works and is currently the content training manager leading content development and delivery of training courses. Mitchell is experienced developing BI solutions using the full Microsoft BI Stack (SSRS, SSIS, and SSAS) as well as Microsoft Power BI. He is also very active in the community speaking at SQL Saturday events, local user groups, and online virtual events. Mitchell also blogs at mitchellpearson.com.</description>
      <twitter>@MitchellSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mitchellpearson.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MitchellSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21105</importID>
      <name>Michael Reed</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working with SQL Server for 14 years, have a background in business, worked in the Microsoft Online Services Division, Behavioral Targeting group, am employed by Pragmatic Works as a Senior BI Consultant. I am studying Data Science through online certificate programs and bring this experience to my presentations. I am particularly interested in how to apply Big Data to solve business problems.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=7999720amp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20636</importID>
      <name>Mikey Nelson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>For years Mike has had a passion for automating tasks  processes related to the Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), helping companies deliver the business value of their software more rapidly.  Whether establishing from scratch, working with a company’s existing Automation Toolset or identifying gaps in the set for appropriate additions, building a new team or augmenting or mentoring an existing team, I bring the clarity and experience required to get the job done quickly efficiently.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.therealmikenelson.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21104</importID>
      <name>Michael Reed</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working with SQL Server for 14 years, have a background in business, worked in the Microsoft Online Services Division, Behavioral Targeting group, am employed by Pragmatic Works as a Senior BI Consultant. I am studying Data Science through online certificate programs and bring this experience to my presentations. I am particularly interested in how to apply Big Data to solve business problems.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=7999720amp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22366</importID>
      <name>Pam Shaw</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pam Shaw has been in IT for over 30 years.  Since 2001, Pam has been working with SQL Server, first 2000, then 2005, 2008, 2008 R2, 2012 and now 2014.  Pam currently works as a BI Developer as an independent contractor.  Pam is also the Chapter Leader of the Hillsborough SQL Users Group PASS chapter and organizer of SQL Saturday Tampa.</description>
      <twitter>@PamShaw</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pshaw1129/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlpam.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@PamShaw</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18823</importID>
      <name>Andrey Korshikov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Работать с SQL Server начал в 2003 году. Довелось работать и сдавать сертификационные экзамены по версиям SQL Server от 2000 до 2012. Участник конференций SQLSaturday, Платформа, DevCon и TechEd. География выступлений от Тампы до Красноярска, от Санкт-Петербурга до Тбилиси. Основатель сообществ Krasnodar SQLamp;BI Usergroup и Global Russian Virtual Chapter. На данный момент являюсь PASS Regional Mentor for Central Eastern Europe. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17610</importID>
      <name>Joe Rossi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>“Big Data Joe” is the Engineering Lead and Big Data Architect at Trace3's Big Data Intelligence Practice. Joe is certified in most Hadoop distributions as an administrator, engineer and developer. Joe is the technical Big Data evangelist for Trace3 and speaks at T3’s workshops, training sessions and events. He has 16 years of experience in the IT field as hands-on engineer with startups to Fortune 5 companies. He enjoys sharing his findings and helping others make sense of new technologies.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://bigdatajoe.io/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>13204</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13204</id>
          <name>David Dye</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Location Location Location Preparing and Presenting Geographic Data </title>
      <description>This session will begin with the tasks necessary to model a dimensional data structure to maintain and present geographic data.  We will discuss various requirements that can affect a data model such as granularity, surrogate keys, slowly changing dimensions.  Real life examples and solutions will provided to give better context to each step in the process.
After the data structure has been created we will focus on how to best “clean” and validate the geographic data.  We will focus on using SSIS to obtain latitude and longitude and then how this can be converted SQL Server spatial types.
Finally we will cover presenting this data using SSRS and Power Map and how to create dynamic and aesthetically pleasing graphical reports.  This portion of the session concentrates on presenting reports using the geographic data type that answer specific questions such as:
Events that occurred at a specific address, zip code, and even block range and events within a mile radius.
</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20636</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20636</id>
          <name>Mikey Nelson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Affecting Change with Automation</title>
      <description>As a BA/BI Professional you are in a key position of influence.  Helping to guide your organization to embracing automation of testing, deployment and configuration will help your company deliver better, safer software faster.  If you are interested in understanding automation’s role 
•	What is automation, really?
•	Why is it important to me and my company?
•	Is this just one more thing to learn and do?
•	Where do you start?
•	When to start?
•	How can I be an influencer?
•	What’s in it for me?
•	What’s automation’s role in Big Data
Mike has spent years successfully helping companies start or restart their path to automation.  For some years Mike has had a passion for automating tasks  processes related to the Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), helping companies deliver the business value of their software more rapidly. </description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16455</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16455</id>
          <name>Jen Underwood</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advanced Analytics with Excel and Power BI</title>
      <description>Take your Power BI analytics skills to the next level. In this session we will introduce and walk-through a variety of popular advanced analytic techniques and tools. We will cover prescriptive and predictive analytics, methodology and tools including but not limited to Microsoft Power BI: Excel, Power Pivot, Power Query, SQL Server Data Mining, Predixion, Frontline Systems Solver and R. Advanced analytics lifecycle topics discussed include choosing the right analytic technique and tool, data preparation, developing analytic models, evaluating models and implementing analytics into smart reports, dashboards, business processes and applications.</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21105</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21105</id>
          <name>Michael Reed</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data- Part 2 of 3- Beyond the Basics</title>
      <description>In this hour I will build on the exercises in Part 1 of this series. I will cover more advanced data acquisition and transformations, building 'tidy' data sets, plotting and visualizations, and basic data mining using a variety of tools and utilities. This is part two in a three part series which takes you from setting up your environment to basic analytics to applying analytics to business decision making.</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13298</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13298</id>
          <name>Dmitri Korotkevitch</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Clustered Columnstore Indexes: Internals and Design Considerations</title>
      <description>In this session, Dmitri will talk about internal structure of Clustered Columnstore Indexes. He will demonstrate how to design ETL processes and Columnstore Index Maintenance routines in the way that improve query performance in the system. Finally, Dmitri will discuss how to utilize Columnstore Indexes in reporting solutions that work with volatile data in OLTP environments. </description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21104</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21104</id>
          <name>Michael Reed</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data- Part 1 of 3- Let’s Get Started</title>
      <description>In this hour I will show you how to set up a Big Data environment, how to load and transform data, and how to access the data using Hadoop and Microsoft utilities. I will leave you with all of the pieces, parts, instructions, and additional experiments to set up your own environment and get some actual stick time. This is part one in a three part series which will take you from setting up your environment to basic analytics to applying analytics to business decision making.</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19917</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19917</id>
          <name>Maximo Trinidad</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS - Integrating PowerShell in a ScriptTask comp</title>
      <description>This session will demostrate how you can reuse a PowerShell script in SSIS "Script Task" component as part on a ETL flow.  I'll be showing some basic .NET Script code in both C# and VB.  I'll be adding some useful tips when re-using existing Powershell code. Integrating different .NET technologies in a SSIS package: C#, VB.NET, XML, and PowerShell.  Everyone is welcome to attend.</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19008</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19008</id>
          <name>Leigh Freijo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why I won't hire you and what you can do about it!</title>
      <description>As a hiring manager, I see the same mistakes over and over again. In this session we'll talk about common mistakes in resumes, interviews, social media and how you can avoid them. We'll also discuss lost opportunities and how not to miss them. This information applies to both internal and external candidates.</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14315</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14315</id>
          <name>Frank Quintana</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>An introduction to Business Intelligence and Big Data</title>
      <description>The problem with the old way of organizing and analyzing data in RDBMS is that it is painfully slow, incomplete and costly. We are obligated to be selective and work with data in small chunks. In the best case scenario we partitioned our data and archived it with the hope to eventually use it, but the fact is that when data is being archived, usually, it is never used again. We don’t even bother with collecting all the data due to economics and technical limitations. 
In this presentation I will introduce BI and Big Data, explain advantages and disadvantages of OLTP, OLAP and Big Data.
</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18823</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18823</id>
          <name>Andrey Korshikov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dozen tips and tricks you should know when working with SSRS</title>
      <description>SQL Server Reporting Services have many useful but not well-known features. Many BI developers do not know how to create interactive reports or reports with dynamic columns; how to use JavaScript in reports or display an image in multiple columns.
Come to this session and you will learn 12 useful tips and tricks, which will help you to make impressive reports and simplify their development.</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17610</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17610</id>
          <name>Joe Rossi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hadoop - Past, Present and Future</title>
      <description>A session focused on ramping you up on what Hadoop is, how its works and what it's capable of. We will also look at what Hadoop 2.0 and YARN brings to the table and some future projects in the Hadoop space to keep an eye on.</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19977</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19977</id>
          <name>Mike Davis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mastering the Technology Interview</title>
      <description>Join Mike as he shows you how to be prepared for technology job interviews. Learn the do's and don'ts of interviewing for technology jobs. Learn what your resume says about you and your ability to grow. Learn how passion can overcome a lack of skills.</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21011</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21011</id>
          <name>Mitchell Pearson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to PowerPivot</title>
      <description>Building an SSAS cube isn't for everyone. PowerPivot is! This session is for anyone who wants to get started in PowerPivot. Join us as we build a PowerPivot model from the ground up and then create some reports, all in just over an hour. Learn how to use data from existing sources, such as SQL Server databases or Analysis Services, as well as how to integrate currently unrelated data from sources such as Excel workbooks.</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22366</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22366</id>
          <name>Pam Shaw</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tips  Tricks for dynamic SSRS Reports</title>
      <description>In this session we will explore the multitude of ways that you can make your reports adapt to the needs of your users.  This will include defining formats based on the data contents.  We will explore how to refine layouts based on the data to be delivered.  We will demonstrate how to create a parameter driven data source.  We will take a look at how creating templates can give your catalog of reports a more professional look.  All of this together will empower you to have more control over the reports you create.
</description>
      <startTime>10/25/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/25/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>