<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #1010 – Slovenia – Virtual 2020</name>
    <startDate>12/12/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Amsterdam, Berlin, Bern, Rome, Stockholm, Vienna</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlSatSlovenia</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Faculty of Computer Science</name>
      <street>Vecna pot 113</street>
      <city>Ljubljana</city>
      <state>Ljubljana, Slovenia</state>
      <zipcode>1000</zipcode>
      <longitude>14.4772701</longitude>
      <latitude>46.05019</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1781</importID>
      <name>Microsoft</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1010/EventSponsor_14927.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2313</importID>
      <name>Gen-I, d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Virtual Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.gen-i.si/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1010/EventSponsor_14941.JPG</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>709</importID>
      <name>IN516HT d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Virtual Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.in516ht.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1010/EventSponsor_14949.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2698</importID>
      <name>B2 BI d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Virtual Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.b2-bi.com/sl</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1010/EventSponsor_14948.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2678</importID>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://cloud.google.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1010/EventSponsor_14928.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2696</importID>
      <name>Melissa</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>http://www.melissa.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1010/EventSponsor_14930.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2689</importID>
      <name>Red Hat</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://www.redhat.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1010/EventSponsor_14929.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107928</importID>
      <name>Paul Turley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul is a Principal Consultant for Pragmatic Works, a Mentor and Microsoft Data Platform MVP. He consults, writes, speaks, teaches  blogs about business intelligence and reporting solutions. He works with companies around the world to model data, visualize and deliver critical information to make informed business decisions; using the Microsoft data platform and business analytics tools. He is a Director of the Oregon Data Community PASS chapter  user group, the author  and lead author of Professional SQL Server 2016 Reporting Services and 14 other titles from Wrox  Microsoft Press.  He holds several certifications including MCSE for the Data Platform and BI.</description>
      <twitter>paul_turley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pturley</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserverbiblog.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=paul_turley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108243</importID>
      <name>Cédric Charlier</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cédric is a talented architect and Data Platform MVP active in the domain of Business Intelligence and Data warehousing. He has more than 10 years of successful experiences with SQL Server in European industrial groups and services companies. Driven by quality and reliability, he is the main developer of an open-source solution for testing BI solutions (cubes, etl, reports) named NBi (www.nbi.io). Cedric also advocates for the introduction and general usage of agile practices in BI’s world.</description>
      <twitter>@Seddryck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://be.linkedin.com/in/cedriccharlier</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://seddryck.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Seddryck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108182</importID>
      <name>Benni De Jagere</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Benni De Jagere is a Senior Data Insights Consultant at Realdolmen, with a strong focus on the Microsoft (BI) Stack. 

On a daily basis he turns (large amounts) of coffee into insights for customers, and references witty British comedy way too often. Overly enthusiastic about anything data related, he’s trying hard to keep up with all things new and shiny.

Rumour has it that he's also involved with a ragtag band of data enthusiasts, enjoying themselves whilst organising cool community things. They go by the name of .. dataMinds!</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BenniDeJagere</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bennidejagere/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://bennidejagere.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BenniDeJagere</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107068</importID>
      <name>Gilberto Zampatti</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Time ago (a lot of time ago…) an excellent IT pro brought me with him and became my Mentor in the IT wonderland…it was a world full of mainframes…
I met the Relational theory when there were no commercial RDBMS, and I was spellbound by that “magic”. When Microsoft appeared in the IT market, I felt finally which trek I had to follow. I’m still walking on such road, and in my rucksack I’ve ben putting some other stuff (like SharePoint, for example). My sole regret:  I’ve left the College to consecrate all my time to my job; curiously, since then, I’ve never stop learning…</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108467</importID>
      <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wolfgang Strasser creates solutions based on the Microsoft Data Platform tools in his day-to-day job as Business Intelligence consultant. Either using SQL Server Database Engine, SSIS, reporting with SSAS and SSRS, implementing Power BI solutions or cloud tools for data analysis - the data-tools-landscape is broadening every day! Based on his professional careers as a software developer he likes to work on structured development processes.
Wolfgang shares his knowledge with the community at many national and international events. For his community work, Wolfgang has been awarded with the Microsoft MVP Award for Data Platform in October 2015</description>
      <twitter>wstrasser</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/wolfgang-strasser/7b/912/22b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://workingondata.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=wstrasser</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107118</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo Kornelis is an established SQL Server community expert who spends a lot of time at various conferences. He is author of "the Execution Plan Reference" (sqlserverfast.com/epr), blogger, technical editor of Grant Fritchey's "SQL Server Execution Plans, 3rd edition" and some other books, and Pluralsight author. He was awarded SQL Server MVP and Data Platform MVP 12 times (2006 - 2016, and 2019-present).

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.</description>
      <twitter>Hugo_Kornelis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/hugokornelis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Hugo_Kornelis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108224</importID>
      <name>Dean Savović</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dean is Senior DBA practicing SQL Server since version 7.0 and main areas of interest are performance tuning and troubleshooting SQL Server database. He speaks at Microsoft Windays Croatia, ATD Croatia, SSWUG, KulenDayz Croatia, SQL Saturday events, etc... Primary focus is on OLTP databases with occasional adventures with Business Intelligence. He finished Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing and MBA on Faculty of Economics in Zagreb. His premise was that it is very useful to combine technical knowledge with management process knowledge that help us in our everyday work. He works in SPAN which is specialized in data management field on Microsoft SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dsavovic</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dsavovic/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.savovic.com.hr</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dsavovic</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108416</importID>
      <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Broadbent is a Data Platform MVP and SQL Server MCM with more than 20 years of experience working with SQL Server and principal of SQLCloud, a consultancy specializing in concurrency control and highly available solutions. He is the founder of the UK's SQLSaturday Cambridge (its first and largest), SharePoint Saturday Cambridge, the Hybrid Virtual Chapter and the East Anglia SQL User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@retracement</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/retracement</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tenbulls.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@retracement</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107079</importID>
      <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erland Sommarskog is an independent consultant based in Stockholm, working with SQL Server since 1991. He was first awarded SQL Server MVP in 2001, and has been re-awarded every year since. His focus is on systems development with the SQL Server Database Engine and his passion is to help people to write better SQL Server applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sommarskog.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108088</importID>
      <name>Oliver Engels</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Oliver Engels is CEO of oh22data AG, a Microsoft Gold Partner in Germany specializing in CRM and BI. His special interests are Azure, Data Governance and Integration, Visualisation Tools like SSRS, Power BI, Tableau, R, and SharePoint. He has worked with SQL Server since version 6.5 and is a founder and Board member of PASS Germany, a PASS Regional Mentor, and runs the Frankfurt PASS Local Group. For more than seven years he is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a Microsoft pTSP.</description>
      <twitter>@oengels</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ssis-components.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@oengels</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108354</importID>
      <name>Björn Peters</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I've started with SQL Server 6.5 but only as a sys-admin and not as DBA. Later I'd worked as a full DBA with SQL Server 2000 and my love to SQL Server started. In 2015  I'd got more interested in SQL PASS and tried to speak for the first time... the main part of my job is to work as DB-Admin and solution architect but I'm trying to widen my horizons. In 2016 I've visited and volunteered at the German SQL Saturdays und SQLGrillen and since October 2016 I'm the organizer of Azure Meetup Hamburg.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sql_aus_hh</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bj%C3%B6rn-peters-b26b5813b/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sql-aus-hamburg.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sql_aus_hh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107182</importID>
      <name>Pedro Reis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pedro is a Microsoft BI Stack Professional and enthusiast, with a passion for Power BI, SSAS, Excel and DAX. During his career he has coordinated multiple teams, and the development of thousands of Power BI Reports.
He is the Leader of the Power BI Portugal Meetup group and the Porto Power BI User Group and an active Speaker at events like Power Platform World Tour, SQL Saturday, Porto Data, and meetups.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedrogoncalvesreis/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.meetup.com/Power-BI-Portugal</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107061</importID>
      <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Uwe Ricken is working with IT systems since the 90’s. The primary passion for developments with Microsoft SQL Server expanded in 2007 with his engagement as a DBA for Deutsche Bank AG in Frankfurt am Main. After 6 years of operational experiences as a DBA and over 14 years as a developer of complex database models he achieved the “Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008” certification which “was” the highest technical certification. In the same year he earned his first award as a Data Platform MVP for his support to the Microsoft SQL Server community in Germany and Europe. Uwe Ricken is a speaker on many international conferences and events and preferred topics are “Database Internals”, “Indexing” and “Development”.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dbBerater</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=270775013amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmaster.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dbBerater</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108197</importID>
      <name>Just Blindbaek</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Independent BI consultant with extensive experience in all phases of BI development on Microsoft SQL Server, Azure and Power BI. Founder and coordinator of Microsoft Business Intelligence Professionals Denmark (MsBIP.dk) and Power BI UG Denmark (PowerBI.dk). Is a Microsoft Certified Trainer at Orange Man.</description>
      <twitter>justblindbaek</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=5113407</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.justb.dk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=justblindbaek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107077</importID>
      <name>Javier Villegas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Javier Villegas is a Database Administrator Manager for Mediterranean Shipping Company. Javier has more than 20 years working with SQL Server on every version from 6.5 to SQL Server 2019, Including SQL Azure Database and SQL Azure Managed Instance. His specialization is Administration, Performance Tuning and High Availability.
He is a Microsoft MVP in Data Platform.
Javier is a frequent speaker in conferences and events such as SQL Saturday , PASS Virtual Groups, 24 Hours SQL PASS , vOpen(NetConf), GroupBy and DataPlatformGeeks.
@sqlargentina</description>
      <twitter>https://www.twitter.com/javier_vill</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://ar.linkedin.com/in/javiervillegas</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sql-javier-villegas.blogspot.com.ar/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://www.twitter.com/javier_vill</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107207</importID>
      <name>Gianluca Sartori</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gianluca Sartori is a Data Platform MVP, independent consultant and performance tuning specialist. He has been working in the software industry since 1999 and has been working with SQL Server ever since. He also works as a SQL Server trainer and in his spare time he writes technical articles and participates the SQL Server forums. Gianluca enjoys presenting SQL Server topics at conferences in Europe and in Italy in particular. He is currently working as lead DBA at a famous Formula 1 team.</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/#!/spaghettidba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://it.linkedin.com/pub/gianluca-sartori/23/50b/a12</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://spaghettidba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/#!/spaghettidba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107349</importID>
      <name>Nikola Ilic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I'm making music from the data! 

PowerBI and SQLServer addict, MCT, Pluralsight Author, blogger, speaker...Interested in everything related to data - always eager to extract valuable info from raw data in the most effective way. Multi-year experience working with (predominantly) Microsoft Data Platform (SQL Server, SSAS, SSIS, SSRS, and Power BI). Father of 2 and true football (and Barca) fan!</description>
      <twitter>DataMozart</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikola-ilic-data-mozart</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://data-mozart.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataMozart</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107066</importID>
      <name>Boriana Petrova</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Microsoft Certified Trainer with over 10 years experience as an IT instructor and Consultant. She has many qualifications and professional certifications, including: Excel MVP, MCT, MCITP, MCTS, MOS Master. In 2008 she is among the TOP 25 of the best instructors in Microsoft World Company business evaluation and measurement - Knowledge Advisors.</description>
      <twitter>borianapetrova</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/borianapetrova/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://itraining.bg/category/itraining-blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=borianapetrova</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107171</importID>
      <name>Thomas Hütter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thomas holds a degree in Business Administration, but has been a data explorer and a developer at heart ever since the days of dBase and Turbo Pascal. He touched his first SQL Server at V6.5 and used covering indexes before they became a feature.

Thomas has been developing in Navision/Dynamics/Business Central systems for quite some time (since 2001, one year before MS acquired Navision), joined PASS in 2006 and got his hands on R in 2014 (the year before MS bought Revolution Analytics). He has worked for ISVs as well as end-user companies, as a developer, consultant, accidental DBA and is an author for data-related articles as well as a speaker at SQL events across Europe.</description>
      <twitter>DerFredo</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://de.linkedin.com/in/derfredo</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlfredo.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DerFredo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108090</importID>
      <name>Gabi Münster</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gabi Münster is working as a Business Intelligence consultant and team lead and brings in her experience with SQL Server, data warehousing, relational and multidimensional database design and implementation, report and dashboard design, and Master Data Services, as well as project management into the community as a regional PASS Local Group lead. She is also passionate about motivating other women to start a technical career and therefore initiates and supports "Women in Technology" events. Apart from SQLSaturdays, she also spoke at SQLBits, SQL Nexus, Tuga IT, and 2015's and 2017's PASS Summit. In October 2017 Gabi received her first Data Platform MVP award.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLMissSunshine</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabimuenster/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLMissSunshine</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107598</importID>
      <name>Erwin De Kreuk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erwin de Kreuk is a passionate and very experienced Microsoft Solution Architect. 
Working as a Principal Consultant/ Lead Data and AI for InSpark, #1 Microsoft Partner of the Year in the Netherlands. Speaking at different national and international data community events.
He is working in the world of data on the Microsoft Platform for last 12 years and the last 4 years he has shifted his focus to the Azure Platform. 
Answering complex customer cases and technical issues are part of his day-to-day work. In addition to this work, he is a member of the Technology Board within InSpark and leads a team of highly experienced Data Expert in the field of Microsoft Data Platform.</description>
      <twitter>ErwindeKreuk</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nl.linkedin.com/in/erwindekreuk</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://erwindekreuk.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ErwindeKreuk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>108182</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108182</id>
          <name>Benni De Jagere</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>  YELLOW</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Designing impactful visualisations for your data</title>
      <description>As Data is key, visualising said data is even more important. We want our message to be understood with ease, and merely with a couple of glances. Hence making sure the receiving party can do so with ease will be vital to our success.

During this session, we'll go through some steps on how to maximise the potential of data visualisations. Starting at choosing the right types of visualisations, and which colour palettes are good matches for your message, we'll also make sure that our designs are as inclusive as we can possibly make them. Wrapping up with a few common use cases, you’ll definitely pick up a few new things to take home with you.

Walking out of this session, you can expect to have a decent understanding on a few common design principles for your data visualisations and reports.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108416</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108416</id>
          <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> RED</track>
      <location>
        <name>DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>2 Fast 2 Furious - designing for speed, concurrency, and correctness</title>
      <description>With the multitude of isolation levels, concurrency models, and specialist technologies available in SQL Server, it is no surprise that transaction throughput and correctness can be directly correlated to the ability and knowledge of the person that wrote the code.

In this session, we will reveal how SQL Server concurrency and correctness often goes wrong, how we can avoid this, and how we can use our knowledge to design and develop for optimal server throughput for our applications and processes using tips and tricks gained from real-world scenarios.

We will cover SQL Server’s traditional locking model, In-Memory OLTP, Columnstore, Delayed Durability, and many other technologies and techniques you can use to make your transactions more robust.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107077</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107077</id>
          <name>Javier Villegas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> RED</track>
      <location>
        <name>DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Evolution of SQL Server as a Service - Azure SQL Database Managed Instance</title>
      <description>In this session we will cover SQL Server running as a managed service (Paas) and will get to know it so that we can consider it as a possibility for our developments</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107928</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107928</id>
          <name>Paul Turley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> RED</track>
      <location>
        <name>DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Modeling Solutions for Challenging BI Data Modeling Problems</title>
      <description>Sorry to break the news but the world is not flat and neither is business data. Data modeling is an essential skill in Power BI design and hard problems require creative solutions. In this session, we will enumerate common challenges and demonstrate modeling techniques to resolve them. Session topics: implementing star and snowflake schema essentials, role-playing tables, many-to-many and bi-directional filters, working without relationships, disconnected lookup tables and calculation groups. We will also discuss the composite models and the future of BI data modeling.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 4:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 5:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107079</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107079</id>
          <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> RED</track>
      <location>
        <name>DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>When Things go Wrong - Error Handling in SQL Server</title>
      <description>Most modern programming environments offers exception handling in some form, and SQL Server provides the popular TRY-CATCH concept. However, error handling in SQL Server is not as straightforward as one may wish, but it is marred with inconsistencies and surprises. This session starts off by displaying the some of the surprises you can encounter, both when you use TRY-CATCH and when you don't.

The session presents a recipe for writing CATCH block where focus is on keeping things simple and you will learn why it is not a good idea to make your error handling "fancy", although it may seem to be a good idea in theory. The session also covers a few things to think of on client level.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108088</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108088</id>
          <name>Oliver Engels</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> RED</track>
      <location>
        <name>DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>Common Data Model - Our new buddy for Data Governance</title>
      <description>Common Data Model as the foundation of Power BI Dataflows and as part of the Open Data Initiative with SAP and Adobe, seems to be a pretty good move from Microsoft. We want to take a closer look to this approach. In this session we show how the Common Data Model will allow you to combine Self-Service ETL and Corporate Data Engineering. We will show you how Power BI and more specialised tools like ADF, DataBricks etc. can work together on the Azure Data Lake with one common model. We than extend this and show, what opportunities this standard brings to you, when we unleash the possibilities you have on managing Data Quality and Governance. We also will have a look in how you integrate CDM in a DataOps  Methodology.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107118</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107118</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BLUE</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Debugging without debugger: investigating SQL Server’s internal structures</title>
      <description>Have you ever wanted to know exactly how SQL Server stores data for temporary structures, such as for instance the spooled data in a Table Spool or Index Spool operator? No? I don’t blame you. It’s a bit like wanting to know who watered the rubber tree that produced the rubber your tires are made off before you get in the car to drive to work. You really don’t need it.
But you might still WANT to know. I did. And I figured it out.
Without ever touching the debugger (I’m a simple soul, that stuff is much too complex for me!), I figured out how I could look at the exact storage structures SQL Server creates and uses to store data in Table Spool and Index Spool operators.
If you are willing to commit to a fast-paced and deep internals session that is guaranteed to teach you exactly zero actually useful information, then this is the session for you.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 4:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 5:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107349</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107349</id>
          <name>Nikola Ilic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>  YELLOW</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>From XL to S - Reduce your Power BI model size by 90%!</title>
      <description>Have you ever wondered what makes Power BI so fast and powerful when it comes to performance? So powerful, that it performs complex calculations over millions of rows in a blink of an eye.

In this session, we will dig deep to discover what is “under the hood” of Power BI, how your data is being stored, compressed, queried, and finally, brought back to your report. After the session, you will get a better understanding of the hard work happening in the background and appreciate the importance of creating an optimal data model in order to get maximum performance from the Power BI engine.

Finally, you will see a real use-case demo showing how the Power BI data model was reduced by 90%!</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107066</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107066</id>
          <name>Boriana Petrova</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>  YELLOW</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Working with parameters in Power Query</title>
      <description>This session will show how to create and use parameters in Power Query. From basic to advanced techniques - from static to dynamic parameters and functions.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107598</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107598</id>
          <name>Erwin De Kreuk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BLUE</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Key Vault, Azure Dev Ops and Data Factory how do these Azur</title>
      <description>Can we store our Connectionstrings or BlobStorageKeys or other Secretvalues somewhere else then in Azure Data Factory(ADF)? Yes you can! You can store these valuable secrets in Azure Key Vault(AKV).
But how can we achieve this in ADF? And finally how do we deploy our DataFactories in Azure Dev Ops to Test, Acceptance and Production environments with these Secrets ? Can this be setup dynamically?
During this session I will give answers on all of these questions. You will learn how to setup your Azure Key Vault, connect these secrets in ADF and finally deploy these secrets dynamically in Azure Dev Ops. As you can see a lot to talk about during this session.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108224</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108224</id>
          <name>Dean Savović</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BLUE</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Intelligent Query Processing</title>
      <description>I will talk about new intelligent query processing features in SQL Server 2019. The features that will be described are adaptive joins, interleaved execution, memory grant feedback, table variable deferred execution, batch mode on rowstore, T-SQL scalar UDF inlining and approximate count distinct. The presentation will end with extensive demo.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108090</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108090</id>
          <name>Gabi Münster</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> RED</track>
      <location>
        <name>DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Synapse Analytics - Early Lessons learned</title>
      <description>We were in the lucky situation to actively accompany several customers on their POCs and early developments of Data Warehouse projects using Azure Synapse Analytics. Based on those experiences we will take you with us on a journey from the first steps into this new offer to use cases and scenarios from existing projects. Let's explore the current set of features, childhood diseases left behind and potential for improvement.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107068</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107068</id>
          <name>Gilberto Zampatti</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BLUE</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance Monitoring in SQL Server 2019</title>
      <description>Some new object and configuration option of our databases can enhance the 
efficiency of our monitoring and tuning. This session will show some new 
object (DMO) introduced in the new platform and a couple of new options 
that can change our approach to the monitoring, maintenance and tuning activity.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108467</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108467</id>
          <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>  YELLOW</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Connect your data artifacts with Azure Synapse Analytics</title>
      <description>In human brains, synapses are responsible to connect information pieces together. Over time, our knowledge increases when more and more synapses are connected together. Following that analogy, Azure Synapse Analytics wants to connect (all) information silos together and provide a single point of analytics. 
Join this session, if you want to hear about the building blocks of Azure Synapse Analytics, how Data Engineers and Data Scientists and even BI developer can work together in a single service and see how easy it is to start with Synapse Analytics!</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108354</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108354</id>
          <name>Björn Peters</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BLUE</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Change your skills - from an onpremise DBA to a cloud DBA</title>
      <description>In this session, everything will be around changing your daily business from an on-premise environment to a cloud world... new challenges, new tasks, and new options... in order not to struggle too often, you need to create new knowledge and learn a lot of new stuff, so I want to show several ways to update your skills and what you really need to become cloud database admin.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107182</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107182</id>
          <name>Pedro Reis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>  YELLOW</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>"DAX" the way to do it</title>
      <description>Love it or hate it, you just can't ignore DAX, the amazing language of Power BI. In this session, I'll show you it's true power and how knowing it can even make you completely rethink your data models.
No more hundreds of columns and weird aggregations in the database. With the Power of DAX, you can now achieve much more sophisticated and powerful calculations, while keeping it simple at its core.
I'll show you real-world applications of DAX and lots of tips and tricks that you will be able to use quickly and with little effort!</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107171</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107171</id>
          <name>Thomas Hütter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BLUE</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Poor man's SQL Server job monitoring with R</title>
      <description>Of course SQL Server (Management or Azure Data Studio) offers you a list view of the agent job history. But wouldn't it be nice to have a graphical overview of job durations and how they develop?

This session is for DBAs and R newbies alike: In one hour we'll develop a dashboard-like overview of your agent jobs' and their durations with the R language.

We'll work our way from finding the right system tables to use, generating one graph per job with the help of R, to adding that little trend line to every one of them. After creating it in RStudio, we'll eventually adapt our script to run in SSMS/ADS just as fine. Once finished, no additional tools are needed, no additional €€ spent.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108197</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108197</id>
          <name>Just Blindbaek</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>  YELLOW</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Hitchhiker's Guide to navigating Power BI</title>
      <description>Are you also sometimes lost in space? What is up and what is down, when it comes to navigation in Power BI. How much is controlled and what can you adjust yourself?

This session will cover all the options we have to change and setup navigation on three different levels. (1) Inside Reports, (2) between Reports in an App and finally (3) the Power BI Web Portal to help users finding the Apps and Reports. You will be amazed how much actually can be done, to give your users a better experience.

We will cover topics like, Power BI Service navigation, Linking from an Intranet, Setting up Dashboards, The new App navigation, Drillthrough, Buttons, Bookmarks and much more.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107061</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107061</id>
          <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> RED</track>
      <location>
        <name>DEV</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why Partitioning can boost your data management</title>
      <description>Partitioning is a great feature of SQL Server and since SQL 2016 you can use it in Standard Edition, too. See in this session the benefits of partitioning for ETL, maintenance and backup / restore.
The main area of application for partitioning is the optimization of load paths for complex DWH solutions and maintenance of large databases (statistics, indexes, backup, restore).After a brief introduction to partitioning, this session will focus on the key benefits of the above topics</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108243</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108243</id>
          <name>Cédric Charlier</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>  YELLOW</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automating the testing of your BI solutions with NBi</title>
      <description>If you want to accelerate the testing of your BI solutions, the best strategy is the automation of your tests with the help of a dedicated framework. During this session, we’ll take a look to the features of the open-source framework named “NBi” (www.nbi.io). This framework is providing support for automated tests on the fields of databases, cubes, reports and ETLs, without the need of .Net skills. The demos will show us the best approaches to quickly and effectively assert the quality of BI developments. We'll go a step further, generating the tests by an interesting system of templates and test-cases sources.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 4:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 5:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107207</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107207</id>
          <name>Gianluca Sartori</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BLUE</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Baking Extended Events recipes without breaking a sweat</title>
      <description>OK, you got the message: Extended Events is the way to monitor SQL Server from now on. However, you feel overwhelmed by XML shredding and the simplest of tasks seems impossible. 
Fear not: in this demo intensive session I will show you how to tackle the most challenging tasks without writing a single line of code. I will use the open-source tool XESmartTarget to audit logins, find unused objects, capture and notify deadlocks and much more.
Stop doing things the hard way! Join me and learn how XESmartTarget can do all the heavy lifting for you.</description>
      <startTime>12/12/2020 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/12/2020 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>