<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #274 - Slovenia 2013</name>
    <startDate>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>100</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Amsterdam, Berlin, Bern, Rome, Stockholm, Vienna</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatSlovenia</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>pixi labs</name>
      <street>Poslovna cona A 2</street>
      <city>Sencur - Ljubljana</city>
      <state>, Slovenia</state>
      <zipcode>SI-4208</zipcode>
      <longitude>14.409201</longitude>
      <latitude>46.261716</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>946</importID>
      <name>pixi* labs d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pixi.eu</url>
      <imageURL>https://shrani.si/f/2c/jB/13aHvtwg/pixilabslogo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>203</importID>
      <name>Microsoft d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://microsoft.com/slovenija</url>
      <imageURL>https://i.s-microsoft.com/global/ImageStore/PublishingImages/logos/hp/logo-lg-1x.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>709</importID>
      <name>IN516HT d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.in516ht.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1010/EventSponsor_14949.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1355</importID>
      <name>SolidQ</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.solidq.com/es</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14422.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1</importID>
      <name>Confio</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.confio.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/resized-confio_logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>83</importID>
      <name>PluralSight</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pluralsight.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.srnimbus.com.br/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Pluralsight_logo_novo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>783</importID>
      <name>Kompas Xnet</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.kompas-xnet.si/</url>
      <imageURL>https://kompasxnet.blob.core.windows.net/uploaded/images/image/Xnet.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>388</importID>
      <name>ApexSQL LLC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.apexsql.com/?utm_source=SQLSaturdaysutm_medium=sponsorlinkutm_campaign=%5BSQLSaturdays-Homepage%5D</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/864/EventSponsor_13700.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20737</importID>
      <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Miloš Radivojević is a database consultant located in Vienna, Austria. He is Data Platform MVP and specializes in SQL Server for application developers and performance and query tuning. Currently, he works as a principal database consultant in bwin GVC (the largest regulated online gaming company in the world). He is co-founder of the SQL Pass Austria and speaks regularly at local and international database conferences. He is also co-author of the books SQL Server 2016 Developer's Guide, SQL Server 2017 Developer's Guide and Mastering SQL Server 2017.</description>
      <twitter>MilosSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://at.linkedin.com/pub/milos-radivojevic/1b/7bb/290/de</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://milossql.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MilosSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26999</importID>
      <name>Tomaž Kaštrun</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tomaž Kaštrun is BI developer and data analyst. His main focus are data mining, T-SQL development, programming and query optimization. He has been working with SQL server since version 2000. He is Microsoft Certified Professional, Microsoft MVP for data platform and Microsoft trainer.</description>
      <twitter>@tomaz_tsql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/tomaz.kastrun</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tomaztsql.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tomaz_tsql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34751</importID>
      <name>Marco Parenzan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marco Parenzan is an independent Cloud and IoT Architect and .NET Developer. 
He has been awarded as a MVP on Microsoft Azure since 2014. 
He is a speaker in major community events in Italy about Azure and .NET development.
He is a community lead for 1nn0va, an official Microsoft community in Pordenone, Italy. 
He has written a book on Azure in 2016. 
He loves developing retrogames and reading comix.

Marco Parenzan è professionista per le architetture Cloud e IoT e lo sviluppo in .NET. 
Ha ricevuto il titolo di MVP su Microsoft Azure dal 2014. 
È uno speaker in Italia su Azure e lo sviluppo di .NET. 
E' un community lead per 1nn0va, una community ufficiale Microsoft a Pordenone, in Italia. 
Ha scritto un libro su Azure nel 2016.</description>
      <twitter>@marco_parenzan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://it.linkedin.com/in/marcoparenzan</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcoparenzan/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@marco_parenzan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18106</importID>
      <name>Kennie Pontoppidan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kennie Nybo Pontoppidan is a senior program manager in Microsoft working in the Dynamics NAV server backend team. He has worked in the dangerous field between developers, dbas, customers and project managers for many years and done his part of mistakes as a developer before that in his 15+ years in the it industry. He enjoys working with databases and really, really enjoys his daily dose of sql. Kennie has no humor.</description>
      <twitter>@KennieNP</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kennie</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.pontop.dk/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KennieNP</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20738</importID>
      <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Miloš Radivojević is a database consultant located in Vienna, Austria. He is Data Platform MVP and specializes in SQL Server for application developers and performance and query tuning. Currently, he works as a principal database consultant in bwin GVC (the largest regulated online gaming company in the world). He is co-founder of the SQL Pass Austria and speaks regularly at local and international database conferences. He is also co-author of the books SQL Server 2016 Developer's Guide, SQL Server 2017 Developer's Guide and Mastering SQL Server 2017.</description>
      <twitter>MilosSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://at.linkedin.com/pub/milos-radivojevic/1b/7bb/290/de</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://milossql.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MilosSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19450</importID>
      <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data Philosopher. Since 2006 invariably awarded Microsoft Most Valuable Professional title in the Data Platform category. A speaker at numerous conferences across Europe, as well as at user groups meetings. The author of many books and articles devoted to Microsoft Data Platform. An independent consultant, database-centric application practitioner and architect totally focused on SQL Server and Azure. Huge fan of Data Science and Machine Learning.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/marcinszeliga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13515</importID>
      <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dejan Sarka, MCT and Data Platform MVP, is an independent trainer and consultant that focuses on development of database and business intelligence applications. Besides projects, he spends about half of his time on training and mentoring. He is the founder of the Slovenian SQL Server and .NET Users Group. Dejan Sarka is the main author or co-author of eighteen books about databases and SQL Server. Dejan Sarka has also developed many courses and seminars for Microsoft, Radacad, SolidQ, and Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>DejanSarka</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/dsarka/Home.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DejanSarka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34558</importID>
      <name>André Kamman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>André is a freelance SQL Server specialist. In previous roles he’s done a lot of DBA work on 100’s of servers where he discovered his love for Powershell and automating processes in general. Today the better part of his day he’s building and tuning ETL processes.
André is a SQL Server MPV, Dutch PASS Chapter Leader and organiser of SQL Rally Amsterdam and SQL Saturday Holland</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://andrekamman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24786</importID>
      <name>Mladen Prajdić</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mladen Prajdić is a Data Platform MVP from Slovenia. He's been programming for 20 years, developing diﬀerent types of applications in .Net (C#) and SQL Server, ranging from standard line-of-business, image-processing applications to high performace and IoT applications. He's a regular speaker at various conferences and usergroup meetings, really likes to optimize slow SQL statements, analyze performance, and find unconventional solutions to difficult SQL Server problems. In his free time, he also develops a very popular add-in for SSMS, called the SSMS Tools Pack (www.ssmstoolspack.com).</description>
      <twitter>@MladenPrajdic</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mladenprajdic</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/mladenp</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MladenPrajdic</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>28199</importID>
      <name>William Durkin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>William Durkin is a DBA, Data Platform MVP, and Data Platform Architect for Data Masterminds (http://datamasterminds.io). He uses his decade of experience with SQL Server to help multinational corporations achieve their data management goals. Born in the UK and now based in Germany, William has worked as a Database Developer and DBA on projects ranging from single server installations, up to environments spanning 5 continents, using a range of high availability solutions. William is a regular speaker at conferences around the globe, organizes the popular event SQLGrillen (http://sqlgrillen.com).</description>
      <twitter>@sql_williamd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/wdurkin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://williamdurkin.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sql_williamd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20085</importID>
      <name>Mark Stacey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Stacey founded the Aphelion Software Group, and works tirelessly to cross the business/technical boundaries in Business Intelligence, working in both SharePoint and SQL. He has published two books on BI - Sharepoint 2010 BI and Visual Intelligence and frequently speaks at both SQL Saturday and SharePoint Saturday events. Mark is one of the few Microsoft PDW trainers, and has trained in Africa, India and Europe on the PDW, as well as all over the world on other technologies </description>
      <twitter>@MarkGStacey</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://MarkGStacey.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MarkGStacey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23500</importID>
      <name>Rasmus Reinholdt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rasmus is the Data Warehouse architect at UNOPS, the implementation arm of the UN, based in Copenhagen, Denmark. He has worked with Microsoft BI since 2005 both as a developer and architect, building large solutions on every release from sql2005 and onwards.
Rasmus is certified is MSCE SQLServer (Data platform amp; BI), a long time speaker at various SQLSaturdays, PASS SQLRally Nordic and SQLBits. He also co-organizes SQLSaturday Copenhagen and blogs at http://rasmusreinholdt.wordpress.com.</description>
      <twitter>@RasmusReinholdt</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/rasmusreinholdt/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://rasmusreinholdt.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@RasmusReinholdt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22141</importID>
      <name>Pieter Vanhove</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pieter Vanhove is a SQL Server MVP and Database Consultant in Belgium and has been working with SQL Server since 2000. Performance tuning, SQL audits, migrations and training are part of the job. Pieter has also a profound knowledge in implementing HA/DR solutions and loves the new Azure stuff. Together with the SQLUG in Belgium, he helps organizing SQL Server Days and is also a regular speaker at Belgian and international events. Pieter recently won the Speaker Idol Contest at PASS Summit 2014.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://pietervanhove.azurewebsites.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10903</importID>
      <name>Boris Hristov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Boris is a SQL Server Consultant, but also an Author for Pluralsight and a SQL Server MVP. He is frequently speaking at conferences all accross Europe and is heavily involved in training students and organizations in what he calls quot;The Art of SQL Serverquot;. Boris is frequently blogging and is the host of SQLHangouts.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BorisHristov</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://bg.linkedin.com/in/borishristov</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://borishristov.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BorisHristov</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>18106</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18106</id>
          <name>Kennie Pontoppidan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Autogenerating a process data warehouse</title>
      <description>In many data warehouses we model fact tables with measures based on attributes which we can count and do arithmetic upon. It is more difficult to handle fact tables with measures based on length of intervals of events happening in the source systems. So questions like "What are the typical waiting times in our order process?" are seldomly modelled in the data warehouse. Especially if the event data comes from different source systems. 

In this talk I will show you how Rehfeld has overcome this difficult problem using an autogenerated datawarehouse based on metadata on the objects in the EDW/DM layers. In this approach you can autogenerate the process data warehouse if only you have the timestamps present in the EDW layer and are able to correlate them. The talk will consist of slides and demos.</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22141</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22141</id>
          <name>Pieter Vanhove</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Harder, Better, Stronger and more secure</title>
      <description>With natural disasters like earthquakes and fires in the news so often, IT Professionals know that many disasters can shut down a SQL Server.
Microsoft has already implemented a lot of HA/DR solutions in previous editions of SQL Server, like AlwaysOn failover clustering, AlwaysOn Availability Groups, log shipping, ...  But,when it comes to high availability, SQL Server 2014 changes the game by enhancing the availability, scalability, and flexibility of AlwaysOn. 
How about your HA/DR solution? Did your management decide the DR site is still too expensive? Are your backups secure? In this session, you will learn all about the new and enhanced features of AlwaysOn in SQL Server 2014 like managing backups to Azure, encrypting backups, adding</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24786</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24786</id>
          <name>Mladen Prajdić</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>From SQL Traces to Extended Events. The next big switch.</title>
      <description>This session will give you insight into both of the current tracing technologies in SQL Server with emphasis on Extended Events.

The old SQL Trace which has served us well over the past 10 or so years is on its way out because the overhead and details it produces are no longer enough to deal with today's loads.
The new Extended Events are a new lightweight tracing mechanism built directly into the SQLOS thus giving us information SQL Trace just couldn't. They were designed and built with performance in mind and it shows. Mastering Extended Events requires learning at least one new skill: XML querying.
We'll look at how the Extended Events work with only a brief overview of old SQL Trace architecure.</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34558</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34558</id>
          <name>André Kamman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automate your SSIS development with BIML</title>
      <description>Ever tried to import a file with the Import/Export wizard?
Or created a bunch of SSIS packages to process a data warehouse load?
Then you know how much work it is to specify the metadata correctly just to create a package that actually works.
Wouldn't it be cool if you had a descriptive language which looks at your metadata and just created the packages for you?
This is what BIML is all about. 
In this session I explain what BIML is, how it works and I'll show you how you can generate your packages and quickly respond to changes.
You can expect a demo rich session with lots of notes from the field and practical examples.
This is not just for BI developers, DBA's or SQL dev's who need to import or export data occasionally will learn some quick and easy tricks as well.
</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20738</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20738</id>
          <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DEV</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2014 - New Cardinality Estimator</title>
      <description>In SQL Server 2014 query processing has been improved. What we can expect from new cardinality estimator? Does it really estimate better? Will our execution plans be better after migration to 2014? All of them? Is the key ascending column statistics problem solved in new version? Do we finally can have more than 200 steps in the statistics histogram per table? What about column correlation and cardinality estimates - are the predicates still completely independent?

This session will answers all these questions and will demonstrate new query processing capabilities and compare them with those from SQL Server2012.</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20085</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20085</id>
          <name>Mark Stacey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Analysis Services for the DBA</title>
      <description>Many DBAs have heard the term Analysis Services, but don't really know what it's for or who would use it. In this session, Mark will explain the use cases for Analysis Services, illustrate how it improves performance for large data sets and eases report writing, and will go through a practical example of building a first Analysis Services solution.This session will be practical for SQL 2005 through 2008 R2, but he will also take the time to explain what changes in SQL 2012 and Tabular mode.</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19450</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19450</id>
          <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DEV</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Indexing for denormalization</title>
      <description>What has the biggest impact on SQL Server overall performance? Hardware, SQL Server configuration or maybe query tuning? No, none of those frequently discussed options. They are important, but the single, most important factor is the database design.
A third normal form is great, but sometime a database really should be denormalized to gain a performance boost. This is where indices shine. During this session you will see: how important a proper table design can be, when to use indices on computed columns and why they are way better than triggers, how to create useful indexed views and how to asses their costs and benefits.
</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23500</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23500</id>
          <name>Rasmus Reinholdt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing BI with SQL2014 In-Memory tables</title>
      <description>Well - they named it SQL2014 In-Memory OLTP tables - BUT that does not mean we can't optimize our BI solutions with this new feature.  
This demo intensiv session is build around a number of hypothesis that are testet and show what we can - and cannot optimize with In-Memeory tables covering both the ETL and (R)OLAP angels of the BI process. 
The session will use the latest CTP release and is constantly updated to include the latest news on the topic.</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>28199</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>28199</id>
          <name>William Durkin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Consolidation - Resistance is Futile</title>
      <description>The IT world is currently in cost-saving mode - cutbacks are all over the place and then Microsoft pushes out SQL Server price hikes.  

In this session we will discuss how consolidating SQL Server can reduce overall costs and increase efficiency.  We will cover the reasons for consolidation along with the advantages and the disadvantages of consolidating SQL Servers.  We will also take a look at some of the tools that can assist with a consolidation project and some pitfalls that I have experienced on previous consolidation projects.</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13515</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13515</id>
          <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DEV</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing Temporal Queries</title>
      <description>Having a SQL Server solution for a problem does not mean the job is done. Of course, the next immediate issue is the performance. Temporal queries that involve intervals are typically very IO and CPU intensive. For example, a test for overlapping intervals was solved with inefficient queries for years. However, a handful of solutions with fast queries was developed lately. This high-level technical session introduces five different methods to get efficient queries that search for overlapping intervals. Of course, these solutions can be implemented on other temporal problems as well. Actually, the test for overlapping intervals is one of the most complex temporal problems.</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26999</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26999</id>
          <name>Tomaž Kaštrun</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Data Quality services on Customer related data</title>
      <description>Customer related data are center focus of every system dealing with customer orientated data. Having data prepared for statistical analysis, data mining, olap, reporting and any derived form of semi-aggregated data.  Providing a knowledge-driven solution for managing quality, integrity and consistency of data is of high value.  
Main focus of this session will be usage of data quality services with practical examples on managing quality, integrity and consistency of data for further data usage. Session will show how to build a knowledge base, manage domains and use data cleaning and matching.</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20737</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20737</id>
          <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DEV</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>TSQL Performance Tips</title>
      <description>SQL Server optimizer doesn't use and index seek for execution of your query although the quer is high selective? What is better, when and why: LIKE vs: SUBSTRING, IN vs. EXISTS, SUBQUERY vs. JOIN. Why you should not use the UPPER or LOWER functions? How to avoid non-SARG-able WHERE clauses? Which query takes about 3 minutes in SQL Server 2008 and only one second in SQL Server 2012?

In this session we will advice how to avoid common developer mistakes and show how bad designed queries reduce the SQL Server optimizer's capabilities for choosing an optimal execution plan. </description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10903</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10903</id>
          <name>Boris Hristov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Replay your workload as it's your actual one!</title>
      <description>Have you ever wanted to replay your application workload be that because you upgraded to a new hardware, added new indexes or something else? Now there's a feature for that! It's called Distributed Replay and in this session you will learn how this new feature in SQL Server 2012 can help you resolve that problem!</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34751</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34751</id>
          <name>Marco Parenzan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DEV</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>.NET Development for the SQL Server Developer</title>
      <description>Every SQL Server DBA or Developer needs to create some kind of applications: a dashboard for data, a management console, a data-entry tool. Like SQL Server, .NET have evolved over years. Linq and ORM, ASP.NET MVC, Javascript/jQuery, async programming, Azure and the Cloud. I'll present a fast entry to .net and some scenarios and sample applications that a typical SQL Server DBA or Developer can use in his daily work.</description>
      <startTime>12/21/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/21/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>