<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #404 - Nova Scotia 2015</name>
    <startDate>6/13/2015 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>75</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-04:00) Santiago</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatNS</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>NSCC - Waterfront Campus</name>
      <street>80 Mawiomi Place</street>
      <city>Dartmouth</city>
      <state>Nova Scotia, Canada</state>
      <zipcode>B4A 1Y8</zipcode>
      <longitude>-63.551239</longitude>
      <latitude>44.654187</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1273</importID>
      <name>WaterOx Consulting, Inc.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.WaterOxConsulting.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://wateroxconsulting.com/WaterOx-SQLSat.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>70</importID>
      <name>Tegile Systems</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.tegile.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/SQLSaturday/EventSponsors/Tegile_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>36460</importID>
      <name>Meagan Longoria</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Meagan Longoria is a business intelligence consultant with Denny Cherry  Associates, and lives in Denver, Colorado. She is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Meagan spends a lot of time thinking about how to use data integration, DAX, and data visualization techniques to make data useful for people. She enjoys sharing her knowledge and experiences at conferences and user group meetings, as well as through her blog (DataSavvy.me).</description>
      <twitter>mmarie</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/meaganlongoria/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datasavvy.me</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mmarie</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14210</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23617</importID>
      <name>Russ Allen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Russ Allen has over 30 years of experience as a software developer, technical instructor and database administrator for a variety of companies in Eastern Iowa. As a technical trainer he taught classes throughout the United States and in Spain and Australia. For the last nine years, Russ has been a SQL Server DBA and BI developer for the University of Iowa in Iowa City, Iowa.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>28344</importID>
      <name>Justin Dearing</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Justin Dearing has been working in IT in 2002. He started as a night shift AS/400 operator and rose through the ranks at a series of companies. He currently works as a developer in the capital markets industry.

Justin has served in both the development and production side of the house on Windows, Unix and Midrange Platforms. His database experience includes MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres and Microsoft SQL server. These days he programs in C#, PowerShell and PHP.</description>
      <twitter>zippy1981</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/justindearingnyc</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.justaprogrammer.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=zippy1981</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19988</importID>
      <name>Michael DeFehr</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael DeFehr is an independent SQL Server consultant based in Winnipeg, Canada. He is focused on database administration and development using Microsoft SQL Server.
A SQL Server MVP, Professional Engineer and MCITP in both Database Development and Administration, Mike has spent the past 15 years producing and maintaining database solutions. Mike specializes in the relational and storage engines and his solutions emphasize performance and simplicity.</description>
      <twitter>@mdefehr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/mdefehr</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mikedefehr.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mdefehr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>23617</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23617</id>
          <name>Russ Allen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room #1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Divide and Conquer - Creating and Managing Partitioned Tables and</title>
      <description>This presentation will provide an overview of table and index partitioning in SQL Server 2012 and 2014, and describe a step-by-step approach for creating and managing partitions in a large data warehouse. Topics will include:
•	The benefits of table and index partitioning
•	Partitioning requirements and considerations
•	Laying the partitioning foundation
•	Creating partitioned tables and indexes
•	Adding data to a table one partition at a time
•	Removing partitions when data has “aged out”
•	Performing piecemeal restores of partitioned databases
 
The presentation will include a live demonstration of partitioning using fact tables from the AdventureWorksDW2012 sample database. All scripts used in the demonstration will be available to attendees after the presentation.</description>
      <startTime>6/13/2015 9:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/13/2015 10:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>28344</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>28344</id>
          <name>Justin Dearing</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room #1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Version control with GIT for the DBA</title>
      <description>In 2005, Linus Torvalds developed a version control system (VCS) called git. Since then, it has become as platform agnostic and ubiquitous as the internet. In that same note, github, the most popular service for hosting git repositories has become so ubiquitous that Microsoft chose to host the source code for its OSS fork of the .NET framework there instead of its own codeplex.

What does this mean to a DBA? Well. whether or not you use SSDT, you should be storing your database schema in version control. In addition, your utility scripts certainly belong in VCS. 

In my session. We will cover:

What is version control?
How does a distributed version control system differ from traditional version control like Visual Sourcesafe, TFS, and SVN?
How do I setup git for internal use in my company?
How do I host public and private repositories on github.
How do pull requests work?
How do I fork a SVN repo to github?

We will be covering using git from both the command line and Vis</description>
      <startTime>6/13/2015 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/13/2015 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>36460</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>36460</id>
          <name>Meagan Longoria</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room #1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Overcoming Chartaphobia  Moving Toward Enlightening Data Viz</title>
      <description>Do your organization's reports consist mostly of giant tables of data? Perhaps you have gotten as far as adding KPI indicators or conditional highlighting to the tables. Although tables of data presented as reports are commonly found in many organizations, they may be doing you and your users a disservice. You should optimize your data viz just as you optimize your databases. Reports are a user interface that must be purposefully designed to help users achieve their goal of making informed decisions. In this session, we'll review requirements gathering and data viz best practices and apply those concepts to the use of Microsoft reporting tools such as Excel, Power View, and Reporting Services. You'll leave with guidance on how to take boring, unreadable tables of data and turn them into useful and visually appealing reports. </description>
      <startTime>6/13/2015 10:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/13/2015 11:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14210</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14210</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room #1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Working Effectively With Legacy SQL</title>
      <description>A legacy code base can be a frightening thing.  Between strict deadlines, ever-evolving requirements, differing skill levels of contributors over time, and historical circumstances, keeping database code clean and concise is difficult at best.  This example- and demo-driven talk will help you build out a mental framework to prune those gnarled code bases.  Much of this talk will be familiar to software developers who know of the "clean code" philosophy, but no knowledge of the topic is necessary.  If you shudder whenever you look at your SQL code base, this talk may be for you.</description>
      <startTime>6/13/2015 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/13/2015 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19988</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19988</id>
          <name>Michael DeFehr</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room #1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Plans and Indexes in SQL Server</title>
      <description>Data access can be easy to set up in your applications with wizards and ORMs, but sometimes your queries are just not as fast as you think they should be – especially on those tables that are getting bigger and bigger. In this session, we will take a peek under the hood and see how SQL server answers the questions you ask of it. This is an introductory session, but it will be jam-packed with demos and useful tips that you will be able to use to make your applications more responsive.</description>
      <startTime>6/13/2015 2:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/13/2015 3:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>