<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #470 - Washington DC 2015</name>
    <startDate>12/5/2015 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSATDC</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>The Microsoft Technology Center</name>
      <street>5404 Wisconsin Ave, Suite 700</street>
      <city>Chevy Chase</city>
      <state>Maryland</state>
      <zipcode>20815</zipcode>
      <longitude>-77.0860749</longitude>
      <latitude>38.9612894</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>607</importID>
      <name>DELL EMC</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.dellemc.com/en-us/index.htm</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/913/EventSponsor_14262.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>7</importID>
      <name>SIOS Technology</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://us.sios.com/company/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/956/EventSponsor_14655.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>836</importID>
      <name>Micron</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.micron.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/SQLSaturday/EventSponsors/micronlogo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1559</importID>
      <name>ICFI</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.icfi.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.icfi.com/~/media/Images/Global/Logos/icf_logo.ashx</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1578</importID>
      <name>Leidos</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.leidos.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/38/Leidos_logo_2013.svg/1024px-Leidos_logo_2013.svg.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>85</importID>
      <name>Pyramid Analytics</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.PyramidAnalytics.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://pages.pyramidanalytics.com/rs/pyramidanalytics/images/logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1499</importID>
      <name>DBmaestro</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dbmaestro.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://dbmaestro.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/main-logo1.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>89</importID>
      <name>Profisee</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.profisee.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.profisee.com/Portals/0/lp/assets/img/logo_profisee.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14586.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>41</importID>
      <name>Pearl Knowledge Solutions</name>
      <label>Swag/Insert Only Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pearlknows.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/aea3823d-2ecf-4c05-ae4a-15461859c093.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40851</importID>
      <name>Monica Rathbun</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Monica Rathbun lives in Virginia, is a Microsoft MVP for Data Platform and Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert. She has nearly two decades of experience working with a wide variety of database platforms with a focus on SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. She is a frequent speaker at IT industry conferences on topics including performance tuning and configuration management. She is the Leader of the Hampton Roads SQL Server User Group and a Mid‐Atlantic PASS Regional Mentor. She is passionate about SQL Server and the SQL Server community, doing anything she can to give back. Monica can always be found on Twitter (@sqlespresso) handing out helpful tips. You can find Monica blogging at sqlespresso.com</description>
      <twitter>SQLEspresso</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlespresso</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlespresso.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLEspresso</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41865</importID>
      <name>Mindy Curnutt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mindy Curnutt is a 5X Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Business Owner and Entrepreneur. Her specialties include SQL Server hardware, configuration, migrations, scalability, performance tuning.  She has been actively involved in the SQL Server Community for over two decades and has become a well known speaker within the SQL and Transportation Management communities. She is a two-time PASS Volunteer of the Month, has presented at 6 SQLPASS Summits, Live360, DevConnections, MVPMix and too many SQL Saturdays to count. She is currently the President of the North Texas SQL Server User Group out of Dallas/Fort Worth, TX.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mindycurnutt</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mindycurnutt.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39534</importID>
      <name>Andy Leonard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andy Leonard is founder and Chief Data Engineer at Enterprise Data  Analytics, Microsoft Data Platform MVP, creator of the DILM (Data Integration Lifecycle Management) Suite, an SSIS trainer, consultant, developer, Business Intelligence Markup Language (Biml) developer and BimlHero, SQL Server database and data warehouse developer, community mentor, engineer, and farmer. He is a co-author of "The Biml Book and SQL Server Integration Services Design Patterns" and author of "Managing Geeks - A Journey of Leading by Doing", "Data Integration Lifecycle Management with SSIS", "Building Custom Tasks for SSIS", and the "Stairway to Integration Services". Andy blogs at andyleonard.blog where you can learn more on the About Andy page.</description>
      <twitter>AndyLeonard</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/AndyLeonard</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://andyleonard.blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyLeonard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41501</importID>
      <name>Jason Horner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hi, my name is Jason. I spend most of my day helping clients solve business problems mostly in the Data and Advanced Analytics spaces. Sometimes this involves various and sundry cloud technologies including Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Data Lake Store, Azure Databricks, HDInsight and Azure SQL Database. I'm fluent in several languages including: SQL, C#, Python, and PowerShell.

I'm a Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server (MCM) and have been recognized for my technical excellence and evangelism efforts by Microsoft by being awarded the Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for the last 5+ years.

In my off hours I like to snowboard, karaoke, ride roller coasters, and play arcade games</description>
      <twitter>jasonhorner</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonhorner</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.jasonhorner.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jasonhorner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39571</importID>
      <name>Thomas Grohser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thomas Grohser has spent most of the past 26+ years exploring the deeper inner workings of SQL Server and its features while working for entertainment, pharmaceutical, and financial services industries. His primary focus is to architect, plan, build, and operate reliable, highly available, secure, and scalable infrastructures for SQL Server. Over the years he has managed thousands of SQL Server instances, processing trillions of rows, taking up petabytes of storage. Thomas has been a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for 9 years and has spoken regularly at conferences, SQLSaturdays, and user groups for 12 years.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomasgrohser/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41503</importID>
      <name>Jason Horner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hi, my name is Jason. I spend most of my day helping clients solve business problems mostly in the Data and Advanced Analytics spaces. Sometimes this involves various and sundry cloud technologies including Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Data Lake Store, Azure Databricks, HDInsight and Azure SQL Database. I'm fluent in several languages including: SQL, C#, Python, and PowerShell.

I'm a Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server (MCM) and have been recognized for my technical excellence and evangelism efforts by Microsoft by being awarded the Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for the last 5+ years.

In my off hours I like to snowboard, karaoke, ride roller coasters, and play arcade games</description>
      <twitter>jasonhorner</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonhorner</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.jasonhorner.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jasonhorner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39525</importID>
      <name>Jamie Wick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jamie Wick is the Systems  Database Engineer for The College of William  Mary and has been working with SQL databases for the past 10+ years.  His background includes working for several years as a SQL SysAdmin for the University of Queensland (Australia), a Masters degree in Computer Information Systems from Boston University, and assorted Microsoft SQL certifications.  He is the Chapter Leader of the Richmond SQL Server Users Group, a volunteer and speaker at regional SQL events (User Groups/SQLSaturdays), helps run the SQLSaturday RVA events, and is an avid photographer.</description>
      <twitter>Jamie_Wick</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamiewick/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.wicktech.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Jamie_Wick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41359</importID>
      <name>Patrick Keisler</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I#39;m a husband, a father, an Atlanta Braves fan, and oh yeah...I know a thing or two about Microsoft SQL Server, because I work for Microsoft supporting it as a Premier Field Engineer. I have over 15 years of DBA experience and have gained considerable knowledge in SQL Server by supporting lots of different type of applications ranging from high-volume trading applications to large data warehouses. I hold several certifications: MCSE: Data Platform, MCITP SQL 2008 Admin and Dev, and Security+.</description>
      <twitter>@PatrickKeisler</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrickkeisler</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.patrickkeisler.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@PatrickKeisler</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42788</importID>
      <name>Michael Wells</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Wells is a Microsoft Specialist at Dell EMC covering enterprise customers. He has worked in IT since 2000 and has supported all versions of SQL Server from SQL Server 2000 to SQL Server 2014. Michael has been presenting  since 2007 for local user groups, CodeCamps, SQLSaturday events, IT Pro Camps, and large conferences like PASS Summit and Oracle OpenWorld.</description>
      <twitter>@SqlTechMike</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/mikewells</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqltechmike.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SqlTechMike</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40756</importID>
      <name>Rick Heiges</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick is a Former Data Platfrom MVP  and Sr. Consultant for Microsoft where he focuses on working with customers on their data estate. His career includes work as a DBA, University full-time faculty member, Systems Analyst, Project Leader, and Developer. He has found his passion in working with data and the community. Rick served nine years on the PASS Board of Directors and spearheaded the popular 24 Hours of PASS event. He also started his local User Group in 2002. Today, he spends much of his time with his head in the clouds.</description>
      <twitter>heigesr2</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rick-heiges/1/b93/777/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/rick_heiges/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=heigesr2</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39625</importID>
      <name>David Dye</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David is a Sergeant with the Cape Coral Police Department and currently works as a database administrator and developer in the Administrative Services Division. He began his career with the police department in 1990 in the patrol division and worked various assignments until being promoted to Sergeant in 1998. Based on his education and experience David was assigned to his current position in 2002 and is responsible for database administration, software integration, and development for public sa</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40355</importID>
      <name>Steve Jones</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Jones is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and has been working with SQL Server since version 4.2 on OS/2. After working as a DBA and developer for a variety of companies, Steve co-founded the community website SQLServerCentral.com in 2001.
Since 2004, Steve has been the full-time editor of the site, ensuring it continues to be a great resource for SQL Server professionals. Over the last decade, Steve has written hundreds of articles about SQL Server for SQLServerCentral.com, SQL Server Standard magazine, SQL Server Magazine, and Database Journal.</description>
      <twitter>way0utwest</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/way0utwest</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.voiceofthedba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=way0utwest</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42898</importID>
      <name>John Morehouse</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Morehouse is currently a Consultant with Denny Cherry  Associates living in Louisville, Kentucky. With over 2 decades of technical experience in various industries, John now focuses on the Microsoft Data platform and specializes in Microsoft SQL Server.  He is honored to be a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, VMWare vExpert, Friend of Red Gate, Sentry One PAC member  Community Ambassador, and 2016 Idera Ace.  John has a passion around speaking, teaching technical topics, and giving back to the technical community as much as possible.  He is a user group leader, SQL Saturday organizer, and former PASS regional mentor. He is also a blogger, avid tweeter, and a frequent speaker at SQL Saturday’s as well as other conferences.</description>
      <twitter>SQLrUs</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlrus</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlrus.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLrUs</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41217</importID>
      <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wayne Sheffield, a Microsoft Certified Master in SQL Server and Microsoft Most Valuable Professional, started working with xBase databases in the late 80’s. With over 25 years in IT, he has worked with SQL Server (since 6.5 in the late 90’s) in various dev/admin roles, with an emphasis in performance tuning. He is the author of several articles at www.sqlservercentral.com, a co-author of “SQL Server T-SQL Recipes”, and enjoys sharing his knowledge by presenting at SQL events worldwide and blogging at http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</description>
      <twitter>@DBAWayne</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/WayneSheffield</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DBAWayne</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40604</importID>
      <name>Rafael Salas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rafael Salas is a recognized speaker and published author with more than 17 years of experience in business intelligence and information architecture. He is the recipient of multiple industry recognition, including the Microsoft MVP Award and The Data Warehouse Institute Best Practices Award. Rafael is also an active member of the SQL Server technical community and blogs regularly at www.rafael-salas.com.</description>
      <twitter>@RafSalas</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.rafael-salas.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@RafSalas</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41201</importID>
      <name>Amy Herold</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Amy Herold is currently a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft, specializing in APS. Prior to this, she was a Sr. Database Administrator, focusing on PowerShell and automation. She is also currently the Director of Programs for the North Texas SQL Server User Group (NTSSUG). She frequently speaks at SQL Saturday and user group events across the United States and has also participated in numerous Women in Technology sessions as a panelist. Amy currently blogs at sqlkitten.com.</description>
      <twitter>@texasamy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aherold</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlkitten.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@texasamy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41269</importID>
      <name>Melody Zacharias</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Melody is the Sr. Microsoft Solutions Manager at Pure and has been in love with data since 1991. She has been sharing her passion with the community in technical sessions and blogs since 2014. She has been a Microsoft MVP since 2016, including winning Rookie of the year for Canada that year. This last year, she was elected to the board of directors for PASS.org, the professional association for SQL Server and was awarded Regional Director by Microsoft. She has co-authored 3 books, including, SQL Server 2019 Administration inside out by Microsoft Press.</description>
      <twitter>SQLMelody</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/melodyzacharias</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlmelody.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLMelody</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40354</importID>
      <name>Steve Jones</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Jones is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and has been working with SQL Server since version 4.2 on OS/2. After working as a DBA and developer for a variety of companies, Steve co-founded the community website SQLServerCentral.com in 2001.
Since 2004, Steve has been the full-time editor of the site, ensuring it continues to be a great resource for SQL Server professionals. Over the last decade, Steve has written hundreds of articles about SQL Server for SQLServerCentral.com, SQL Server Standard magazine, SQL Server Magazine, and Database Journal.</description>
      <twitter>way0utwest</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/way0utwest</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.voiceofthedba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=way0utwest</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41218</importID>
      <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wayne Sheffield, a Microsoft Certified Master in SQL Server and Microsoft Most Valuable Professional, started working with xBase databases in the late 80’s. With over 25 years in IT, he has worked with SQL Server (since 6.5 in the late 90’s) in various dev/admin roles, with an emphasis in performance tuning. He is the author of several articles at www.sqlservercentral.com, a co-author of “SQL Server T-SQL Recipes”, and enjoys sharing his knowledge by presenting at SQL events worldwide and blogging at http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</description>
      <twitter>@DBAWayne</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/WayneSheffield</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DBAWayne</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41282</importID>
      <name>Matt Nelson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt Nelson is a Database Administrator and Business Intelligence developer for RDX (Remote DBA Experts) in Pittsburgh, PA. With over 10 years of experience, He works with more than 200 clients on general database administration needs and BI projects. Matt is also the Chapter Leader of the Pittsburgh SQL Server Users Group, and an organizer of Pittsburgh SQL Saturday. He occasionally blogs at www.nelsonsweb.net and http://www.rdx.com/Blog/</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/mattpgh</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mattpgh</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://wwww.nelsonsweb.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/mattpgh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40519</importID>
      <name>Slava Murygin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Started working with SQL Server 7.0 as DBA and Developer. Since then went through all SQL Server versions, migrations and multiple companies of different sizes and industries. Currently working as a  contractor with all aspects of SQL Server, including, but not limited to: troubleshooting performance, designing/developing: databases, systems, processes, data warehouses,  cubes, reports, ETLs; Refactoring old code; Migrating data from other systems to SQL Server; Securing the data on enterprise level.</description>
      <twitter>SlavaSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/slava-murygin/9/b95/858</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://slavasql.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SlavaSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41250</importID>
      <name>Reeves Smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reeves Smith, owner and principal architect of Macer Consulting, is passionate about applying data technologies that empower organizations. Reeves wields his knowledge and experience to lead, design, architect, and teach, working with both data center and business project teams. He approaches every project by first understanding the organization’s business challenges, and then developing a unique approach that targets those business needs accurately and effectively.

Reeves Smith has more than 20 years of experience working on the SQL Server stack. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and Microsoft Certified Master, and regularly delivers technical presentations at international, regional, and local conferences and user groups.</description>
      <twitter>SQLReeves</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/reevessmithiii/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://reevessmith.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLReeves</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40442</importID>
      <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tracy Boggiano is a Senior Database Administrator for DocuSIgn. She has spent over 20 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1999, and is currently certified as an MCSE Data Platform. Tracy has worked on SQL Server since 6.5. She has spoken at local user groups and numerous SQLSaturdays. She is currently a co-leader of a TriPASS Local Group in Raleigh, NC.   

Tracy also tinkered with databases in middle school to keep her sports card collection organized. She blogs at databasesuperhero.com. 

Her passion outside of SQL Server is volunteering with foster children as their advocate in court through volunteerforgal.org and being a mental health advocate as part of the PAIMI NC Advisory Council.</description>
      <twitter>TracyBoggiano</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyboggiano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://databasesuperhero.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TracyBoggiano</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41233</importID>
      <name>Kevin Goff</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin S. Goff (http://www.kevinsgoff.net) is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP 

Database architect/developer/speaker/author 

Regular columnist for CoDe Magazine on .NET, SQL Server, and Business Intelligence topics 

Frequent speaker at community events in the Mid-Atlantic region. 

Host of BDBI Radio (http://www.bdbiradio.com), a weekly webcast on SQL/BI topics </description>
      <twitter>@KevinSGoff</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.KevinSGoff.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KevinSGoff</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41321</importID>
      <name>Brent Ozar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brent Ozar loves to make SQL Server faster. He created sp_Blitz and the SQL Server First Responder Kit. He shares what he's learned at BrentOzar.com.</description>
      <twitter>BrentO</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/brentozar</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.BrentOzar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=BrentO</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40570</importID>
      <name>Ayman El-Ghazali</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ayman is a passionate SQL Server DBA, Developer, and BI Developer. His passion for technology started when he was a young boy playing DOS games on his father's computer. He can be reached via his blog or twitter handle and is looking forward to connecting with other SQL Geeks.</description>
      <twitter>thesqlpro</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aymansqldba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.thesqlpro.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=thesqlpro</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41133</importID>
      <name>Andy Mallon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>--</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41253</importID>
      <name>Cindy Bean</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cindy Bean is a Technical Consultant at DBmaestro, a pioneer and leading DevOps for database solution provider, enabling Agile development and Continuous Integration and Delivery for the database. She has worked with SQL Server and other relational database products for over 20 years as a DBA, product manager, and consultant. Cindy has previously worked at Idera, Bradmark Technologies, BMC Software, and Sybase.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cynthiabean</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42453</importID>
      <name>Chris Bell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Bell offers a unique view of how we live and work with data, both now and as we head into the future. Having braved many roles, lifecycles, and battles in the IT world, he has honed his DBA (Database Administration or Do 'Bout Anything) skills in Information Systems and development, focusing on SQL Server. Currently, he serves as the lead DBA at The Motley Fool. You can keep up with Chris' thoughts and technical community activities at WaterOxConsulting.com.</description>
      <twitter>@cbelldba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/christopher-bell/19/a08/93/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.wateroxconsulting.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cbelldba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39879</importID>
      <name>William Wolf</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bill is the Manager of SQL Server Performance Tuning for RDX.  He works with over 400 customers on solutions within the SQL Server environment and specialized in code tuning and mentoring the team within RDX. He has become a SQL Saturday veteran speaking at nearly 40 SQL Saturdays in the last 3 years.  He has also spoken at Summit and is an Idera Ace class of 2018. Bill is active in the Pittsburgh SQL Server User Group.  He is also the chapter lead for the DevOps Virtual User Group. He is passionate about educating users on SQL Server and mentoring others.</description>
      <twitter>sqlwarewolf</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamjwolf</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlwarewolf.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlwarewolf</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41323</importID>
      <name>Brent Ozar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brent Ozar loves to make SQL Server faster. He created sp_Blitz and the SQL Server First Responder Kit. He shares what he's learned at BrentOzar.com.</description>
      <twitter>BrentO</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/brentozar</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.BrentOzar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=BrentO</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40085</importID>
      <name>Danette Riviello</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Danette Riviello has been working with databases for thirty years.   With experience as a database developer, database administrator and manager of DBAs, she is now Lead System Architect at Magellan Health.   She has spoken at a SQL Pass Summit, Baltimore SQL Server Users Group and SQL Saturdays.  Her technical expertise is in Disaster Recovery Planning, Performance Tuning and Replication. </description>
      <twitter>n/a</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/ddriviello</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://n/a</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=n/a</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40590</importID>
      <name>Dave Fackler</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave Fackler is a business intelligence architect, focusing on enterprise data warehouse and business intelligence solutions using Microsoft technologies. Dave has helped organizations design and implement large-scale data warehouses, exploiting SQL Server enterprise database features using dimensional modeling design principles and best practices. He has also architected and developed several enterprise ETL processes using SSIS and its robust set of high-performance tasks and transformations. Dave has delivered various end-user reporting solutions using SSAS and SSRS, often coupled with SharePoint and Office components. Dave speaks about business intelligence at numerous technical conferences, user groups and professional groups each year.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlbiguru</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/davefackler</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://davefackler.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlbiguru</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41157</importID>
      <name>Ravi Kumar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have over 12 years of experience working with SQL Server and Business Intelligence Technology.  My current focus is cloud technologies: Power BI, Azure Analysis Services, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Data Factory.  As a PFE at Microsoft, I regularly deliver 2 - 4 day training workshops.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlravi</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlravi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41259</importID>
      <name>Carlos L Chacon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Chacon is the managing partner of SQL Data Partners LLC and co-host of the popular SQL Data Partners Podcast.  While getting his start as a typical accidental DBA, Carlos has sat on Microsoft exam review panels, served as regional mentor and chapter leader.  He enjoys traveling and has been to four continents, speaks Spanish and can eat his weight in raspberries (not yet proven).  He and his family live in Richmond, Virginia.</description>
      <twitter>@CarlosLChacon</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/carloslchacon</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldatapartners.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@CarlosLChacon</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41230</importID>
      <name>Mark Hudson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Hudson is an MCITP with many years of experience in business intelligence and data analysis.  He has developed data solutions using numerous platform tools including multiple SQL Server versions.  He is a data architect and developer with CapTech (www.captechconsulting.com) and served as a leader of the Richmond SQL Server User Group (www.richmondsql.org).</description>
      <twitter>HMarkHudson</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=HMarkHudson</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>39625</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39625</id>
          <name>David Dye</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-4 (BI 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advanced SSIS Techniques</title>
      <description>As an ETL developer using SQL Server Integration Services have you ever wondered how to:
1.	Import all .csv files from a folder
2.	Replace dynamic SQL using variables in SSIS
3.	How to configure the data flow buffer
4.	Create custom logging solutions
5.	Use a script component as a data flow transformation
This session focuses on advanced techniques that are used in SSIS and is meant for the experienced SSIS developer.  We will focus on tasks and techniques that are native to SSIS 2005-2014 as well as some of the more advanced and vague  properties.  
Attendees must have a good working knowledge of SSIS as well as familiarity with VB.NET or C# as some time will be taken looking at extending SSIS with script tasks and components.
Upon completion of this workshop attendees will be able to:
1.	Import/export multiple sources/destinations
2.	Use an execute SQL task with variables to replace dynamic SQL within a package
3.	Dynamically handle errors within any part of a package
4.	</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 8:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 9:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40570</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40570</id>
          <name>Ayman El-Ghazali</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-1 (Mix)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance Tuning Pit Stop for DBAs</title>
      <description>Our users are in constant demand of faster running servers that spill out data before they can blink. Performance can be hard to measure and improve.  Before we get in the race we will cover how to get a Performance baseline using the PAL Tools. The first Pit Stop will be to review TempDB setup to improve performance. Before getting into high gear we'll pull over to refuel on some Log File best practices and performance implications of VLFs. Finally before passing the checkered flag we'll make one more stop to talk about Data Files and improving your mileage from there. After this session you'll have a good idea of how to make changes transparent to any application to get your server crossing that finish line in style!
</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40590</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40590</id>
          <name>Dave Fackler</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-1 (Mix)</name>
      </location>
      <title>TFS for SQL/BI Developers</title>
      <description>If you do any kind of SQL Server or BI development, you eventually have to grapple with the problem of keeping multiple copies of your work.  You either need to maintain stored procedure and DDL scripts or you have copies of SSIS and SSRS reports to keep up with.  In most cases, this problem starts off small as you need to have development versus production copies of your code.  But eventually, it becomes harder and harder to maintain your "source code" as your environment becomes more complex and as you potentially have to start working with a team of other developers.  During this session, we'll talk about Team Foundation Server (TFS) and show you the different ways it can be used to keep up with all the different types of source code you might be responsible for -- from full database designs to complete BI solutions.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41250</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41250</id>
          <name>Reeves Smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-1 (Mix)</name>
      </location>
      <title>A New Approach to Unit and Integration Testing in SSIS</title>
      <description>Testing is a critical part of the release process and vital to a high-quality data management lifecycle. Unfortunately, Integration Services (SSIS) does not have built-in support for testing and the tools for relational database testing are limited. As a result, most organizations forgo automated testing and focus entirely on manual user testing, which is both expensive and often occurs too late in the process to address all of the issues discovered. 

In this session, a new approach to unit testing (focusing on verifying the correctness of individual packages, tasks, or dataflows) and integration testing (focusing on validating that the data produced by an entire sequence of transformations) will be discussed. This development pattern uses metadata authored by analysts to automatically generate testing logic within the corresponding packages or to automatically generate standalone test packages that contain all of the necessary validation logic.
</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40355</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40355</id>
          <name>Steve Jones</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>5-1 (Mix)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Get Testing with tSQLt</title>
      <description>tSQLt is a testing framework that is designed to help you write repeatable, isolated tests against your database code. In this session we will briefly examine the goals of testing, where it can be used in an automated deployment pipeline, and introduce you to the tSQLt framework. We’ll show you how to design and write tests to enforce standards, check calculations and other DML operations as well as check exception handling. You will see how a real world refactoring task can be tested in a repeatable manner. Learn how you can incrementally write tests that help you build higher quality code and minimize the introduction of errors against your existing objects.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41501</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41501</id>
          <name>Jason Horner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-4 (BI 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dimensional Modeling Design Patterns: Beyond Basics</title>
      <description>Dimensional modeling is arguably one of the most important
fundamentals of business intelligence.  It is still relevant even as
new technologies like PowerPivot and SSAS Tabular Models are becoming
more popular.  Correctly modeling your organization's data not only
protects the most important asset your company has but ensures that
your data mart or data warehouse will be responsive and capable of
accommodating emerging requirements.

This session provides a deeper dive into 
the art of dimensional modeling. We will look at the different types of fact tables and dimension tables, how and when to use them. We will also some approaches to creating rich hierarchies that make reporting a snap. Finally we will cover  physical design choices.This case study and demo based session promises to be very interactive and engaging, bring your toughest Dimensional Modeling quandaries.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41217</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41217</id>
          <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-1 (Mix)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Table Vars and Temp Tables – What you NEED to Know!</title>
      <description>Almost every SQL Developer is familiar with Table Variables and Temporary Tables. While each of these objects represents temporary storage, there are also substantial differences between them. Understanding the differences between Table Variables and Temporary Tables, and the ramifications that those differences cause, is essential to being able to properly select the appropriate object for use in your development tasks. In this code filled session, we’ll discover the differences and similarities of Temporary Tables and Table Variables, dispel some widespread myths about each, and answer the most important questions of them all, "When do I use one or the other and what are the various impacts of doing so?"</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40604</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40604</id>
          <name>Rafael Salas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-3 (BI 2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS: Design principles for robust ETL processes</title>
      <description>Is the design of your ETL processes robust?  Does your ETL process keep you awake at night?

Data integration is still the most common point of failure of data centric projects and choosing a mature ETL tool, such as SSIS, is not enough.  In many cases this is due to improper planning and the use of questionable design principles. During this session we will look at ETL processes from a holistic point of view to identify key areas that are often neglected and that have the potential to affect the system reliability and increase its maintenance cost. We will use SSIS to evaluate key ETL architecture areas - such as re-start ability, monitoring, error handling, among others- and discuss design principles you can use to improve the architecture of your ETL processes going forward. You will find the session valuable regardless of you level of expertise in ETL.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41133</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41133</id>
          <name>Andy Mallon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-5 (PD)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Wheaton's Law for Technology Pros: Level up your customer service</title>
      <description>DBAs (and IT folk in general) have a terrible reputation for being stubborn, jerky curmudgeons. These guys exist, and working with them is a miserable experience--but they're a minority. Unfortunately, they are a memorable minority and they give the rest of us a bad name.

It can be hard to enforce the rules, do what's best for your environment, and offer outstanding customer support. It can be tough--rules mean telling people no. Rules mean making decisions that might make some people unhappy. In this session, we'll talk about some of these challenges and how to deal with them, all while obeying Wheaton's Law.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41253</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41253</id>
          <name>Cindy Bean</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-2 (DB 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Avoiding the Pitfalls of Database Change Automation</title>
      <description>Automation and Continuous Delivery are at the forefront of software development processes today.  However, databases are being neglected because database code is different, harder to automate, and DBAs just don't seem to trust database automation. This is not surprising when you consider the number of incidents and instances of downtime that were caused by out-of-process updates, code overrides, and other database glitches. In this session, we will explain the options to automate database changes along with the benefits and issues with each option.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 8:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 9:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41157</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41157</id>
          <name>Ravi Kumar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-2 (DB 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL 101: Getting started with T-SQL</title>
      <description>Learn Basics of SQL and T-SQL querying in Microsoft SQL Server. This session will assume you have no or very little knowledge of writing T-SQL.  We will cover following in order: set based theory, select statement, joining two or more tables,  T-SQL functions, update statement.  We will also touch briefly on basic query performance tips.  By the end of the session, you will know how to query a database. 

If you want to follow along in the class, please have SQL Server and AdventureWorks2012 database installed on your computer. </description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41259</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41259</id>
          <name>Carlos L Chacon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-5 (PD)</name>
      </location>
      <title>If You Build It, They Will Come--Creating Your Own Opportunities!</title>
      <description>Often times we might feel like we are simply spinning our wheels and can't seem to move ahead.  Perhaps we see others getting opportunities and can't quite place why more doesn't come our way.  This session will discuss how we can put ourselves in the drivers seat when it comes to making opportunities so we can make some decisions about what we want to do rather than choosing from what is left.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41201</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41201</id>
          <name>Amy Herold</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-5 (PD)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Making the Leap from Developer to DBA</title>
      <description>You are a Developer (.NET, SQL or otherwise) but you have been doing some DBA work and have now decided that is all you want to do - how do you make the transition? What do you need to know? This session will cover this topic from first-hand experience. </description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41269</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41269</id>
          <name>Melody Zacharias</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-3 (BI 2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Distributed Replay: Testing With Your Data, Your Way!</title>
      <description>Do you want to test hardware upgrades, index tuning or multi-client applications? Would you like to do this with data specific to your organization?  Distributed Replay, introduced in SQL Server 2012, is a tool that will allow you to accomplish exactly that. In this session, we will cover why you should use it, how to set it up, and what types of data to collect for testing  and replay.  This session will demonstrate tangible methods and undocumented tidbits, that you can take back to your environment to create immediate, and measurable tests.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 8:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 9:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41233</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41233</id>
          <name>Kevin Goff</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-3 (BI 2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL for Application Developers - Attendees chose</title>
      <description>That's right, attendees choose! I'll show 30 possible topics on the screen, and the attendees vote on which topics I'll cover. Everything from isolation levels to ranking...everything from GUIDs to table-valued functions....everything from querying temporal data to instances where subqueries are necessary....everything from update triggers to reading execution plans. The good news is that you'll walk away with 30 code samples, even though we'll only cover a portion of them in the presentation. This has always been a very popular session.
</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>39571</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39571</id>
          <name>Thomas Grohser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>5-2 (DB 2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Storage Engine under the hood </title>
      <description>How SQL Server performs I/O

How is SQL Server really accessing the data and log files on the disk? What's done asynchronous and what's  synchronous and what impact does that have on our queries and DML statements.
Which impact have features  like database mirroring and replication, what's different when SQL Server is starting up.
#160;
Which I/O Subsystems (including SSD) are best for which type of data and what's the impact if you choose a different one.  Which files can be placed on the same volume and which should not.
</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>39879</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39879</id>
          <name>William Wolf</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-3 (BI 2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Service Broker: Introduction to wheeling and dealing</title>
      <description> This session is an introduction to Service Broker basics.  Service Broker is your way to process your data asynchronously in a single instance setting as well as use as a near real time ETL.  Wheel and deal your data processing.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41323</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41323</id>
          <name>Brent Ozar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>5-1 (Mix)</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Think Like the Engine</title>
      <description>You’re a developer or a DBA, and you’re comfortable writing queries to get the data you need. You’re much less comfortable trying to design the right indexes for your database server. In this session with Microsoft Certified Master Brent Ozar, you’ll role play as the database engine while Brent gives you queries. You’ll learn first-hand about clustered indexes, nonclustered indexes, execution plans, sargability, statistics, TempDB spills, and T-SQL anti-patterns.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41230</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41230</id>
          <name>Mark Hudson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-4 (BI 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>What Can Data Quality Services Do for You?</title>
      <description>In 2002, U.S. businesses lost an estimated $600 BILLION a year because of data quality problems. In 2012, Microsoft offered Data Quality Services (DQS) to reduce some of that loss.  DQS enables analysts to recognize data quality defects and manage business rules to correct those data defects. Once defined, those business rules are available for use throughout the enterprise in SSIS packages so the data loaded is as clean as the business-defined rules. Standardizing and de-duplicating data are no match for DQS. Join me as I profile and standardize data before your very eyes.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>39534</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39534</id>
          <name>Andy Leonard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-4 (BI 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using BIML as an SSIS Design Patterns Engine </title>
      <description>Business Intelligence Markup Language provides a powerful solution for creating and managing SSIS Design Patterns. Andy Leonard, one of the authors of SSIS Design Patterns, demonstrates the flexibility of BIML in this session.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42788</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42788</id>
          <name>Michael Wells</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-4 (BI 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding the Impact of Flash on SQL Server</title>
      <description>The concept of storing data on flash chips has been around since the late 80’s, but has traditionally been cost prohibitive in most cases.  As the technology continues to improve we are seeing much higher capacities with significantly lower pricing, so the power of flash is no longer limited to just those companies with multi-million dollar technology budgets.  This session will take a vendor-agnostic look at the different patterns for leveraging flash and what those mean for a SQL Server Database Administrator.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40756</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40756</id>
          <name>Rick Heiges</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-1 (Mix)</name>
      </location>
      <title>First Look at SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>Microsoft has been busy working on the next version of SQL Server - SQL Server 2016.  We will go over some of the new features at a high level and dig deeper on Row Level Security and StretchDB.  Row Level Security allows you to add another layer of security to your environment.  StretchDB will allow you to transparently place part or all of a table into a SQL Azure DB freeing up your valuable SAN space for data that is COLD.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 8:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 9:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41865</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41865</id>
          <name>Mindy Curnutt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-2 (DB 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>TSQL Coding Techniques - Are You Playing with Fire?</title>
      <description>The good news? T-SQL is one of the easiest coding languages to learn. 
The bad news? Writing scalable T-SQL that performs optimally is an art that takes years to master. 
In this session, learn about some common T-SQL Troublemakers - Looping, Scalar Functions, Implicit Conversions, Non-Parameterized SQL and Parameter Sniffing.
Through examples and demos in this session you will witness the situational pitfalls of the techniques above. With each demo, you will be given an alternate T-SQL solution that solves the same problem in an efficient and scalable manner. Let's get things moving!</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41321</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41321</id>
          <name>Brent Ozar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>5-1 (Mix)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Watch Brent Tune Queries</title>
      <description>You’re in a dark room with an ugly query. What do you do next? Microsoft Certified Master Brent Ozar shares his time-tested method of tuning queries starting with simplifying, analyzing the execution plan, making index tweaks, and measuring improvements with statistics. You’ll learn a repeatable process you can use to make queries go faster.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 8:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 9:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42898</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42898</id>
          <name>John Morehouse</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-2 (DB 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Only You Can Prevent Database Fires!</title>
      <description>Do you find yourself constantly putting out "fires"? Can't take anymore heat in the data center? We as DBAs can easily become burnt out with dealing with these daily blazes. Wouldn’t it be grand to learn how to prevent these fires from scorching us to begin with? In this session, we will jump into things you can start implementing as "fire prevention" to stop the "fire fighting".  We will talk about several things that you can take back to your shop and put into action easily ranging from code tuning, backup maintenance, monitoring and performance tuning!</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40085</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40085</id>
          <name>Danette Riviello</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>5-2 (DB 2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Become a SQL Server Performance Detective</title>
      <description>When your database is having performance issues, you need to quickly and accurately diagnose and resolve performance issues.  Like any good detective, you need to look for clues to find “The Smoking Gun.”  We will cover various tools we have in SQL Server 2008 and above at our disposal which can help us pinpoint and resolve issues quickly, using Dynamic Management Views (DMVs), SQL Profiler and other queries.   We will discuss emergent performance issues as well as chronic issues and find ways to piece together the clues to figure out the root cause of our problems.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40519</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40519</id>
          <name>Slava Murygin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-2 (DB 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Get Familiar with Spatial Data</title>
      <description>You've never worked with spatial data and would like to know how to do it.
We'll go through very basic SQL Server Spatial data functionality and draw some Spatial pictures using Management Studio.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42453</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42453</id>
          <name>Chris Bell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-2 (DB 1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Sponsor Session</title>
      <description>A session slot reserved for our Platinum Sponsor speakers to present a technical, non-marketing session in.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41359</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41359</id>
          <name>Patrick Keisler</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>5-2 (DB 2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Policy Based Management - Beyond the Basics</title>
      <description>Policy Based Management is a great feature of SQL Server and easy to implement; however, for most organizations you need a way to customize it to your enterprise. Join me for this session as we take a deeper dive into PBM to see how you can customize polices, evaluate those polices across your entire enterprise environment, track those changes over time, and deliver reports to management showing your progress.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40354</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40354</id>
          <name>Steve Jones</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>5-1 (Mix)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Branding Yourself for a Dream Job</title>
      <description>Everyone wants a dream job that they enjoy going to each week. However finding that job, and getting yourself hired can be hard for most people. Steve Jones will give you practical tips and suggestions in this session that show you how to better market yourself, how to get the attention of employers, and help improve the chances that the job you want will get offered to you. Learn about networking, blogging, and more.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41282</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41282</id>
          <name>Matt Nelson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-3 (BI 2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building dynamic SSIS packages for more flexibility</title>
      <description>After building a handful of SSIS packages, you probably want to have more flexibility to make the package execution more dynamic.  In this session, we will learn how to use  variables, expressions, and loops to do things like: extract data to a file with *today's* date in the file name, load all files in a directory at the same time, and loop through a set of servers to gather data.  For this session, you should already be familiar with how to create SSIS packages to load data from flat files and extract data to flat files.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40851</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40851</id>
          <name>Monica Rathbun</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>7-5 (PD)</name>
      </location>
      <title>I'm It - Survival Techniques for the Lone DBA</title>
      <description>Are you the only database person at your company? Are you both the DBA and the Developer? Being the only data professional in an environment can seem overwhelming, daunting, and darn near impossible sometimes. However, it can also be extremely rewarding and empowering.  This session will cover how you can keep your sanity, get stuff done, and still love your job. We'll cover how I have survived and thrived being a Lone DBA for 15 years and how you can too.  When you finish this session, you'll know what you can do to make your job easier, where to find help, and how to still be able to advance and enrich your career.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 8:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 9:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41218</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41218</id>
          <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>5-1 (Mix)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Window Functions in SQL Server</title>
      <description>Recent versions of SQL Server brings with it nearly full ANSI compliance with the window functions. Come to this code filled session to learn about all of the window functions in SQL Server 2012: Ranking functions, changes for windowing in the Aggregate functions and the new Analytic functions. We’ll examine how this latest implementation of the window functions allows us to perform running and sliding aggregations; retrieve data from adjacent rows in the partition, and much more – all without expensive self-joins or Row-By-Agonizing-Row (RBAR) back to the source table.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>39525</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39525</id>
          <name>Jamie Wick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>5-2 (DB 2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automated SQL Server installation and configuration using PowerShell</title>
      <description>Using the SQL setup wizard and management studio (SSMS) to install and configure a new SQL server is a time-intensive process.  PowerShell scripts can greatly reduce the time required to complete the process.  They can also ensure build standardization throughout your SQL environment.  In this session we will look at PowerShell scripting, including the basic syntax and commandlets needed to automate the installation and post-install configuration of a SQL Server.
</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 8:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 9:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40442</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40442</id>
          <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>5-2 (DB 2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Disaster Recovery 101</title>
      <description>So you have a good backup strategy in place, but now you have to think about a disaster recovery.  Where do you start and what are your options?  SQL Server offers several options, but then how do you choose the right one to meet your business requirements?  In this session, we will go over some of the common DR options including log shipping, replication, mirroring, clustering, and AlwaysOn.  Then we will talk about how to choose the best one to meet your business needs.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2015 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2015 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>