<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #4 Tweener(Sun) - Orlando 2008</name>
    <startDate>6/7/2008 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>500</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>Free training event for SQL Server professionals</description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat18</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Orange County Convention Center</name>
      <street>9990 International Drive</street>
      <city>Orlando</city>
      <state>Florida</state>
      <zipcode>
      </zipcode>
      <longitude>-81.461275</longitude>
      <latitude>28.423054</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34930</importID>
      <name>Andy Warren</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andy Warren is a SQL Server consultant and trainer based in Orlando, FL. Focusing on administration, performance tuning, and SQL Server patterns and practices, he’s been a SQL Server MVP since 2008. Andy served two terms on the PASS Board of Directors, was a founding principal in SQLServerCentral, and created both the SQLSaturday and SQLRally event models.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlandy</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlandy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlandy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>35001</importID>
      <name>Brian Knight</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brian Knight, a SQL Server MVP, MCSE, and MCDBA, is the owner and founder of Pragmatic Works. He is also the co-founder of SQLServerCentral.com, BIDN.com, and SQLShare.com. Brian runs the local SQL Server users group in Jacksonville (JSSUG), is a contributing columnist at several technical magazines, and does regular webcasts at PragmaticWorks.com. He is the author of 15 SQL Server books and a frequent speaker at conferences such as PASS Summit, SQL Connections, TechEd, and many Code Camps.</description>
      <twitter>@BrianKnight</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.bidn.com/people/brianknight</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BrianKnight</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>35001</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>35001</id>
          <name>Brian Knight</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL University</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>BI 101</title>
      <description>Looking for a place to start in the interesting if confusing world of Business Intelligence? Join Brian Knight for a 3 hour seminar/lab on how Integration Services, Analysis Services, and Reporting Services fit together, and learn some practical and useful skills while you participate with your laptop. Focused on the beginner user, a working knowledge of TSQL will be helpful.</description>
      <startTime>6/7/2008 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/7/2008 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34930</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34930</id>
          <name>Andy Warren</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL University</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>DBA 101</title>
      <description>Wanting to get a job as a DBA? Or maybe you're a developer that works without a DBA and would like to learn some of the critical skills to help you through? This 3 hour seminar will focus on stuff you WILL be doing as a DBA; backups, shrinking the transaction log, troubleshooting blocking, attending logins, settting object permissions, and more. Bring your laptop and follow along in the fast paced  fun seminar.</description>
      <startTime>6/7/2008 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/7/2008 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>