<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #270 - Krasnodar 2014</name>
    <startDate>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>100</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+03:00) Baghdad</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat270</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Конференц Холл</name>
      <street>Kommunarov st 268B</street>
      <city>Krasnodar</city>
      <state>, Russian Federation</state>
      <zipcode>
      </zipcode>
      <longitude>38.984599</longitude>
      <latitude>45.047997</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>329</importID>
      <name>????? ?????????? ????????</name>
      <label>Information Partner</label>
      <url>http://usk.ru/</url>
      <imageURL>https://i33.fastpic.ru/big/2014/0401/f5/20ec7141fb357e9143ba4f5b166172f5.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>129</importID>
      <name>co-working "CO-Place"</name>
      <label>Information Partner</label>
      <url>http://co-place.ru/</url>
      <imageURL>https://scontent-b.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash3/t1.0-9/600949_352827511506296_85295047_n.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18812</importID>
      <name>Andrey Korshikov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Работать с SQL Server начал в 2003 году. Довелось работать и сдавать сертификационные экзамены по версиям SQL Server от 2000 до 2012. Участник конференций SQLSaturday, Платформа, DevCon и TechEd. География выступлений от Тампы до Красноярска, от Санкт-Петербурга до Тбилиси. Основатель сообществ Krasnodar SQLamp;BI Usergroup и Global Russian Virtual Chapter. На данный момент являюсь PASS Regional Mentor for Central Eastern Europe. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25009</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13052</importID>
      <name>Dmitriy Kostylev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Работает в Лаборатории Касперского ведущим разработчиком баз данных. С SQL Server работает с 2000 года, участвуя в разнообразных проектов - от небольшого производства до одной из крупнейших баз знаний о программном обеспечении. Сконцентрирован на эффективности применяемых решений - от отдельных запросов и архитектуры решений до методологии разработки ПО. Активно участвует в жизни SQL-сообщества, выступая на конференциях с докладами об эффективном применении SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18666</importID>
      <name>Mikhail Komarov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Главный специалист в ООО #171;Газпром-информ#187;. Занимается поддержкой существующих и реализацией новых систем, направленных на повышение эффективности работы в корпоративном сегменте. До работы в крупном корпоративном секторе работал тренером по информационным технологиям. Общий опыт работы в сфере ИТ составляет более 20 лет.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18747</importID>
      <name>Tobias Koprowski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Founder of Shadowland Consulting. In January 2015 decided to permanently leave Poland and discover new worlds. Actually settled in Hucknall (The Last home of The Byron Family). Community leader focused on SQL Server, SharePoint, security, collaboration and ITIL, DR, BCM, and SLA. Love licensing stuff. 

Microsoft Certified Trainer, freelancer, and consultant. Subject Matter Expert at Microsoft. Member of Microsoft Terminology Community, Friends of RedGate PLUS, PASS, ISSA, ACM and more. Since 1st July 2010 Data Platform MVP. Creator of SQLDAY Conference and Conference CEO 2009-2011. Co-Leader of PASS East Midlands Group. Speaker at group meetings and conferences. STEM Ambassador. 

Traveler. Coffee Addicted.</description>
      <twitter>@KoprowskiT</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/koprowskit</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://koprowskit.eu/geek/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KoprowskiT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22161</importID>
      <name>Dmitry Pilugin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dmitry Pilugin, is a SQL Server DB developer from Russia, Moscow. He works with SQL Server for more than ten years. Currently he works as a database developer lead, responsible for the development of production databases in the media research company. 

Dmitry holds a blog about SQL Server query processing: QueryProcessor.com, where he writes about a query optimization and execution, and also likes to share his knowledge about it speaking at various community events and tech conferences. Data Platform Microsoft MVP since 2014.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SomewereSomehow</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/pilugin-dmitry-somewheresomehow/2b/210/277</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.queryprocessor.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SomewereSomehow</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18746</importID>
      <name>Tobias Koprowski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Founder of Shadowland Consulting. In January 2015 decided to permanently leave Poland and discover new worlds. Actually settled in Hucknall (The Last home of The Byron Family). Community leader focused on SQL Server, SharePoint, security, collaboration and ITIL, DR, BCM, and SLA. Love licensing stuff. 

Microsoft Certified Trainer, freelancer, and consultant. Subject Matter Expert at Microsoft. Member of Microsoft Terminology Community, Friends of RedGate PLUS, PASS, ISSA, ACM and more. Since 1st July 2010 Data Platform MVP. Creator of SQLDAY Conference and Conference CEO 2009-2011. Co-Leader of PASS East Midlands Group. Speaker at group meetings and conferences. STEM Ambassador. 

Traveler. Coffee Addicted.</description>
      <twitter>@KoprowskiT</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/koprowskit</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://koprowskit.eu/geek/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KoprowskiT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13753</importID>
      <name>Evgeny Khabarov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Разработчик и администратор SQL Server. Область применения знаний в основном устранение проблем с производительностью систем, в основе которых лежит SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>28306</importID>
      <name>Andrey Zavadskiy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrey has been leading the development of corporate information system for realty estate business based on MS SQL Server, ASP.NET and Sharepoint. He works with SQL Server since version 7.0. Currently holds MCSE certification for SQL Server, MCSD for Web development and active Microsoft trainer status. 
He loves to design enterprise-scale application architecture, take part in database development and optimization.</description>
      <twitter>@AndreyZavadskiy</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/zavadskiy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://andreyzavadskiy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@AndreyZavadskiy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>28334</importID>
      <name>Жанна Кривозубова</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Жанна Кривозубова, работает в MS и занимается продвижением продукта SQL Server на российский рынок. Богатый опыт проведения презентаций. Есть возможность из первых рук получить самую достоверную информацию про новую версию продукта. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24336</importID>
      <name>Sergey Olontsev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working with SQL Server since SQL Server 2000 version as a database administrator, developer, consultant and trainer, focusing on high availability and disaster recovery solutions, ETL, troubleshooting and performance tuning, developing high performance solutions . I'm a regular speaker at SQL Server user group meetings, SQL Saturday events and other conferences. An owner of MCM certification and MVP award on SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>SergeyOlontsev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/sergeyolontsev</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SergeyOlontsev.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SergeyOlontsev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24338</importID>
      <name>Sergey Olontsev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working with SQL Server since SQL Server 2000 version as a database administrator, developer, consultant and trainer, focusing on high availability and disaster recovery solutions, ETL, troubleshooting and performance tuning, developing high performance solutions . I'm a regular speaker at SQL Server user group meetings, SQL Saturday events and other conferences. An owner of MCM certification and MVP award on SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>SergeyOlontsev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/sergeyolontsev</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SergeyOlontsev.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SergeyOlontsev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>22161</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22161</id>
          <name>Dmitry Pilugin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Оптимизатор запросов и оценки кардинальности в SQL Server 2014</title>
      <description>Оценка кардинальности является одним из важнейших факторов при построении плана запроса. Качество оценки напрямую влияет на качество плана и на его производительность. В SQL Server 2014 появляется новый механизм оценки предполагаемого числа строк, отличный от более ранних версий. В докладе будут рассмотрены основные различия нового и старого механизмов, а также их влияние на процесс построения плана.</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18812</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18812</id>
          <name>Andrey Korshikov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Советы разработчику отчетов</title>
      <description>Существует много полезных мелочей, о которых не подозревают разработчики отчетов. Например, все привыкли, что отчёты в SSRS получаются статическими. Но использование встраиваемого программного кода позволяет не только упростить последующее внесение изменений в отчёты, но и создать интерактивные отчёты. Например, можно реализовать функционал, похожий на срезы в Excel 2010. В докладе мы рассмотрим 12 интересных и полезных возможностей SSRS.</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>28334</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>28334</id>
          <name>Жанна Кривозубова</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Лицензирование SQL Server 2014</title>
      <description>Весной 14 года выходит новая версия SQL Server 2014. Мы постараемся Вам рассказать про все нюансы лицензирования этого продукта, а так же расскажем, какие новые изменения будут с точки зрения лицензирования у новой версии. Зная эти тонкие моменты всегда можно рассчитать наиболее выгодный вариант приобретения решения.</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13052</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13052</id>
          <name>Dmitriy Kostylev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Оптимизация запросов в примерах</title>
      <description>Оптимизация запросов сродни искусству - каждый запрос, каждый набор данных уникальны и предугадать все возможные сценарии оптимизации пожалуй просто невозможно. Однако вполне реально на примерах рассмотреть возможные варианты оптимизации, рассказать о том, какими знаниями должен обладать разработчик или администратор базы данных и рассказать о том, какие инструменты могут быть использованы. Итак, 4 разных сценария, начинающихся одинаково: "У нас ничего не работает!"</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18746</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18746</id>
          <name>Tobias Koprowski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>2 AM. A Disaster just began...</title>
      <description>2AM. We sleeping well. And our mobile ringing and ringing. Message: DISASTER! In this session (on slides) we are NOT talk about potential disaster (such BCM); we talk about: What happened NOW? Which tasks should have been finished BEFORE. Is virtual or physical SQL matter? We talk about systems, databases, peoples, encryption, passwords, certificates and users. In this session (on few demos) I'll show which part of our SQL Server Environment are critical and how to be prepared to disaster. In some documents I'll show You how to be BEST prepared.</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24336</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24336</id>
          <name>Sergey Olontsev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>In-Memory OLTP (Hekaton) в SQL Server 2014</title>
      <description>Одно из самых ожидаемых нововведений в SQL Server 2014 - это технология In-Memory OLTP, ранее известная под кодовым именем Hekaton. В этом докладе мы подробно рассмотрим ее архитектуру, особенности и ограничения. Также уделим внимание некоторым аспектам практического применения In-Memory OLTP.</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>28306</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>28306</id>
          <name>Andrey Zavadskiy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Backup и recovery для начинающих</title>
      <description>Моя база данных не работает! Я не помню на память, как правильно пишется команда, я не могу найти ответ в Google, мои коллеги заняты, и никто не может помочь мне прямо сейчас. Какой ужас! Я хочу быть где-нибудь, но только не здесь … Не надо паниковать, лучше подготовиться к этому заранее. В этом докладе будет рассмотрен процесс создания и восстановления базы данных, а также некоторые другие вещи, о которых мы забываем, когда работаем с бэкапами (например, как оценить размер бэкапа, как проверить его целостность и другое).</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18666</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18666</id>
          <name>Mikhail Komarov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Windows Server 2012/R2: новые возможности для SQL Server и виртуализация на его платформе</title>
      <description>Windows Server 2012/R2: новые возможности для SQL Server и виртуализация на его платформе</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18747</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18747</id>
          <name>Tobias Koprowski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Source Control</title>
      <description>How to control Your data? Not only bare metal and installed environment are important. What about data? Backup and Restore Statements? Yes, both are important, but What about Data? The pure data? In the code? At this session I want to inviting You to discovering world of controlling data, for controling Your code. Which techniques You can use, where store your data and which tools are available. </description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13753</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13753</id>
          <name>Evgeny Khabarov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Конкуренция за ресурсы в многоядерных системах.</title>
      <description>В настоящее время все больше старых серверов с небольшим количеством ядер выводятся из эксплуатации и заменяются современными многоядерными системами, основанными на архитектуре NUMA.  В таких системах все чаще можно наблюдать конкуренцию при доступе к различным системным объектам в связи с параллельным выполнением большого количества запросов. В докладе пойдет речь о LATCHах и SPINLOCKах, основных типах проблем, связанных с конкурентным доступом, и методах их решения.</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24338</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24338</id>
          <name>Sergey Olontsev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Все о журнале транзакций в SQL Server</title>
      <description>Очень часть приходится слышать такие вопросы, как: зачем вообще нужен журнал транзакций, почему он занимает столько места на диске, как им лучше управлять, какая модель восстановления подходит больше всего и т.д. На эти и многие другие вопросы будут даны подробные и развернутые ответы.</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25009</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25009</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server HA 2008 R2, 2012  2014: Overview  Solutions</title>
      <description>As an architect or DBA it is important to develop the right HADR strategy and corresponding solution which meets the availability requirement and at the same time provide the cost benefit for your organization. Come to this session to learn about how you can develop the right HADR solution for your environment. In this session, we will overview different solution alternatives and explain the key metrics to use for making the decision as well as discuss best practices using 2008 R2 and 2012 with additional capabilities from 2014 version.</description>
      <startTime>4/26/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/26/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>