<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #918 - Charlotte 2019</name>
    <startDate>12/7/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>350</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatCLT</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>UNC - Charlotte - Cone Center</name>
      <street>9025 University Rd, Charlotte, NC</street>
      <city>Charlotte</city>
      <state>North Carolina</state>
      <zipcode>28262</zipcode>
      <longitude>-80.7332454</longitude>
      <latitude>35.3050925</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Platinum</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/918/EventSponsor_14295.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Platinum</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/918/EventSponsor_14314.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/918/EventSponsor_14106.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2536</importID>
      <name>BlueAlly Technology Solutions</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://blueally.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/918/EventSponsor_13972.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1042</importID>
      <name>Signature Consultants</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sigconsult.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/918/EventSponsor_14320.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>554</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry and Associates Consulting</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dcac.co</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/918/EventSponsor_14316.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96040</importID>
      <name>Ed Watson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ed Watson is a Principal Data Platform Consultant for Improving Enterprises, a full-stack Microsoft consulting firm in Atlanta.  Ed is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP since 2014 and like most children, Ed was born at an early age. Today, Ed specializes in the Business Intelligence stack and enjoys specializing in Power BI immensely.  He currently lives in Atlanta and is active with the Atlanta MDF and Atlanta BI user groups and is an organizer for SQL Saturday Atlanta, Atlanta BI, and Pensacola.</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/SQLGator</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/watsoned</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlgator.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/SQLGator</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99160</importID>
      <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tracy Boggiano is a Senior Database Administrator for DocuSIgn. She has spent over 20 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1999, and is currently certified as an MCSE Data Platform. Tracy has worked on SQL Server since 6.5. She has spoken at local user groups and numerous SQLSaturdays. She is currently a co-leader of a TriPASS Local Group in Raleigh, NC.   

Tracy also tinkered with databases in middle school to keep her sports card collection organized. She blogs at databasesuperhero.com. 

Her passion outside of SQL Server is volunteering with foster children as their advocate in court through volunteerforgal.org and being a mental health advocate as part of the PAIMI NC Advisory Council.</description>
      <twitter>TracyBoggiano</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyboggiano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://databasesuperhero.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TracyBoggiano</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99150</importID>
      <name>Andrew Kelly</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrew J. Kelly is a Senior Technical Subject Matter Expert with B3 Group Inc. and lives in Clarkdale, AZ. He has over 20 years experience with relational databases and application development, but his main focus now is SQL Server. In addition to general SQL Server training and mentoring, he specializes in performance, scalability, and maintainability of large-scale SQL Servers. He is a regular speaker at conferences and user groups and was a SQL Server / Data Platform MVP for 18 years.</description>
      <twitter>gunneyk</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/andrew_kelly/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=gunneyk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>97970</importID>
      <name>Lucas Feiock</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lucas Feiock is a Senior Business Intelligence Consultant with KiZAN Technologies. He has four years of experience with the Microsoft BI Stack. In addition to data warehousing, data integration and data visualization, Lucas is also involved with machine learning and advanced analytics. He has experience working in multiple industries including manufacturing, sales, gas and electric utilities, and health care.</description>
      <twitter>@LucasFeiock</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucas-feiock</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sql-stack.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@LucasFeiock</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100059</importID>
      <name>Shabnam Watson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Shabnam Watson is a Business Intelligence architect with 20 years of experience developing data warehouse and business intelligence solutions. Her work focus within the Microsoft BI Stack has been on Analysis Services and Power BI.

She is an active member of PASS community and has spoken at PASS Summit, SQL Saturdays, PASS Business Analytics and Women in Technology virtual chapters, and many other local user groups and conferences. She is one of the organizers of SQL Saturday Atlanta BI Edition.

She holds a master's degree in computer science, a bachelor’s degree in Computer Engineering, and a Certified Business Intelligence Professional (CBIP) certification by The Data Warehouse Institute (TDWI).</description>
      <twitter>ShbWatson</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/shabnamwatson</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://shabnamwatson.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ShbWatson</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96928</importID>
      <name>Prabhaker Potharaju</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Prabhaker Potharaju is a Senior Consultant at Microsoft and has been with Microsoft for almost 20+ years with experience in Business Intelligence, Database Development and Administration, and Application Development using Microsoft technologies. He has extensive understanding of SQL Server internal architecture, performance tuning, as well as data implementation and maintenance of high availability, disaster recovery, and high performance OLTP and OLAP systems. Also has experience on Public and Private cloud platforms, Hybrid IT and delivering SQL Azure offerings.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96179</importID>
      <name>Bhakthi Liyanage</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bhakthi Liyanage is a seasoned IT professional with many years of industry experience, a Microsoft MVP on AI, and is currently working as an AI Architect at one of the largest banks in the US where he leads projects to provide predictive analytics and AI solutions for complex business problems.</description>
      <twitter>@bhakthil</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bhakthi-liyanage/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@bhakthil</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98229</importID>
      <name>Sandra Peele</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sandra Peele started her career in the 1980’s as a demand forecaster in the materials planning department of ATT Network Systems.  She left the workforce in 1990 to raise a family and in 2010, returned to school to study database technology, eventually teaching courses herself.   She has both MSCE: Data Management and Analytics and Oracle 11g OCA certifications.  Sandra is a SQL Developer at CMI Solutions, a Microsoft Partner specializing in software for convenience stores.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://linkedin.com/in/sandrapeele</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96094</importID>
      <name>Johnathan Sluder</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>After 10 years as a systems admin, I'm taking a new adventure into the world of SQL. I currently work doing ETL testing in a Data Warehouse environment. I am currently studying database development and Data Science.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sqlslaughter</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jwsluder/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlslaughter.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sqlslaughter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99162</importID>
      <name>Erika Haase Nalley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erika Nalley works with STX Business Solutions in Bentonville, Arkansas specializing in retail data solutions for adult beverage suppliers and distributors.  As Microsoft Silver Partners in Data Analytics, STX uses all Microsoft Platform solutions.  With certifications in Category Management and Wine Production, Power BI has been our preferred way to slice and visualize data for the last few years. It's a rough life working with data, whiskey, and wine, but someone has to do it!

After work, Erika can usually be found hiking with her husband and three dogs or trying to keep up with friend and co-worker, Amber Muehlbach on a trail run (which usually doesn't happen:).</description>
      <twitter>ErikaHaase</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ErikaHaase</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99885</importID>
      <name>Adrian Mee</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A native of Melbourne, Australia - Adrian currently works for Falling Colors Technology in Santa Fe, NM.  In this role, he is responsible for Database administration, data security and infrastructure.  Adrian has been working with SQL Server since the Enterprise Manager days of SQL Server 2000.  

Adrian is an Idera ACE, class of 2020, and in 2017 he founded the Santa Fe SQL Server User group.  When out of the office, he loves biking and hiking the great outdoors.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SqlNoodle</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/adrian-mee/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SqlNoodle</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96704</importID>
      <name>Solomon Rutzky</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Solomon Rutzky has been working with databases for since 1996, focusing on SQL Server since 2002. He has written several articles for SQL Server Central (including the Stairway to SQLCLR series), and SimpleTalk, and has a blog: https://SqlQuantumLeap.com/ . Solomon is owner / founder of Sql Quantum Lift ( https://SqlQuantumLift.com/ ), and is the creator of the popular SQLCLR library of functions: SQL# (  https://SQLsharp.com/ ). He does what he can to help others by answering questions on a couple of StackExchange sites (  https://stackexchange.com/users/281451/ ), Ask.SqlServerCentral.com/users/20164/SRutzky.html , and SqlServerCentral.com/Forums/ .</description>
      <twitter>SqlQuantumLeap</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/srutzky</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SqlQuantumLeap.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SqlQuantumLeap</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98465</importID>
      <name>John Morehouse</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Morehouse is currently a Consultant with Denny Cherry  Associates living in Louisville, Kentucky. With over 2 decades of technical experience in various industries, John now focuses on the Microsoft Data platform and specializes in Microsoft SQL Server.  He is honored to be a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, VMWare vExpert, Friend of Red Gate, Sentry One PAC member  Community Ambassador, and 2016 Idera Ace.  John has a passion around speaking, teaching technical topics, and giving back to the technical community as much as possible.  He is a user group leader, SQL Saturday organizer, and former PASS regional mentor. He is also a blogger, avid tweeter, and a frequent speaker at SQL Saturday’s as well as other conferences.</description>
      <twitter>SQLrUs</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlrus</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlrus.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLrUs</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>97981</importID>
      <name>Jared Poché</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jared Poche began working with SQL Server as an instructor for certification classes and has a passion for teaching and performance troubleshooting. Jared spent 10 years providing customer support at Microsoft, most recently as a Sr. Support Escalation Engineer. He is currently working as a Database Engineer for ChannelAdvisor and is blogging about his current experiences at sqljared.com</description>
      <twitter>sqljared</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jared-poche-51102797</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqljared.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqljared</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100145</importID>
      <name>Ivan Peev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>N/A</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98453</importID>
      <name>Stephen Muliokela</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been a DBA for many years now and currently hold multiple SQL Server certificates.
In addition, I am also a Six Sigma Blackbelt.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/stephen-muliokela/32/a45/830</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95957</importID>
      <name>Monica Rathbun</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Monica Rathbun lives in Virginia, is a Microsoft MVP for Data Platform and Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert. She has nearly two decades of experience working with a wide variety of database platforms with a focus on SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. She is a frequent speaker at IT industry conferences on topics including performance tuning and configuration management. She is the Leader of the Hampton Roads SQL Server User Group and a Mid‐Atlantic PASS Regional Mentor. She is passionate about SQL Server and the SQL Server community, doing anything she can to give back. Monica can always be found on Twitter (@sqlespresso) handing out helpful tips. You can find Monica blogging at sqlespresso.com</description>
      <twitter>SQLEspresso</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlespresso</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlespresso.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLEspresso</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96106</importID>
      <name>Chris Pollock</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>In my over 10 years of working with databases, I've worked with many different technologies and aspects in software development.  SQL Server and the integration of getting data in and out has been my main focus area.  Nearly half of my career has really been focused around ETL; from home grown ETL solutions, to SSIS and now Azure Data Factory.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/chrispollock2/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100282</importID>
      <name>Kevin Kline</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Kline is a database and industry expert serving as Principal Program Manager at SentryOne, the industry leading SQL Server database tools vendor. A Microsoft SQL Server MVP since 2003, he is a founder and former president of PASS. Kevin is an author of many books, blogger, columnist, and popular international speaker. Kevin’s best known book is the best-selling SQL in a Nutshell and contributes monthly to Database Trends  Applications magazine. He tweets at @kekline and blogs at http://Blogs.SQLSentry.com/Author/KevinKline.</description>
      <twitter>kekline</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kekline/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.sentryone.com/author/kevinkline</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kekline</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98550</importID>
      <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server DBA with over 10 year's experience. Originally from Wales but now living in Ireland</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewpruski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbafromthecold.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98878</importID>
      <name>Chris Skorlinski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Skorlinski has been with Microsoft for 17 years. He is a Support Escalation Engineer at the Microsoft Charlotte NC office specializing in performance tuning and troubleshooting Replication. His is a contributor to SQLShare.com training as well as his own BLOGs on Replication Performance at http://blogs.msdn.com/ReplTalk/. 
#160;</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96160</importID>
      <name>Thomas Norman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tom Norman is a Database Architect at KPA with a strong fervor to protect data. He works daily to review and improve data protection methodologies while reviewing governing laws affecting finance, healthcare, and personal data. His areas of expertise include encryption, auditing, data identification, and database object deployment. He is the current leader of the PASS Virtualization Group and Vice President of the TRIPASS user group. You can read his blog at https://armordba.com/ and reach him on twitter at @armordba. Tom speaks at a number of SQLSaturday events and SQL Server user groups.</description>
      <twitter>ArmorDba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armordba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://armordba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ArmorDba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>97992</importID>
      <name>Anders Pedersen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>20+ years of experience with SQL Server, from version 6.0 to 2017.  Funnily enough, the only certification I have is on SQL 2012, the one version I have never used.
Mostly worked at medium sized companies, by choice.  Was a consultant for 6+ years, working on anything from facility security systems, background checks, retail PoS systems, to major financial systems.
Passion for performance, and teaching people easy ways to better SQL performance.</description>
      <twitter>@arrowdrive</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/anders-pedersen-993676</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.AndersOnSQL.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@arrowdrive</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98890</importID>
      <name>Leveat Ruse</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>As an Executive Technical Recruiter with Ctrl+f, I currently develop effective recruitment strategies to attract top talent at all levels of an organization. I am an IBM certified trainer and began my career performing general human resources duties. I quickly worked my way up through the ranks of technical recruiting from Lead Recruiter to Senior Recruiter to Business Development.</description>
      <twitter>www.twitter.com/ncsctechrecruit</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/leveatruse</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=www.twitter.com/ncsctechrecruit</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96095</importID>
      <name>Ganesh Lohani</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ganesh Lohani has 10 years of experience working with Business Intelligence platform and Data Analytics, with over 8 years of experience with MS BI tools and Business Intelligence processes. He is currently working for Stericycle as a senior Business Intelligence Developer. He also enjoy his evening and weekend time in providing online training, coaching and mentoring individuals who want to learn MSBI (T – SQL,  SSIS, SSRS, SSAS, and Power BI ) products. He holds MSIS degree from University of Texas at Arlington.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ganesh-lohani-6275a716</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98467</importID>
      <name>Ramu Pulipati</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ramu is the CTO/CoFounder of botsplash, an omni-channel platform to engage customers over messaging. At botsplash, Ramu focuses on building solutions that utilize open source technologies, including Postgresql and Clickhouse to enable communication choices for mid to large enterprises.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ramu_pulipati</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pulipati/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ramu_pulipati</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96008</importID>
      <name>Matt Gordon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and has worked with SQL Server since 2000. He is the leader of the Lexington, KY PASS local group and a frequent domestic and international community speaker. He's an IDERA ACE alumnus and 2020 Friend of Redgate. His original data professional role was in database development, which quickly evolved into query tuning work that further evolved into being a DBA in the healthcare realm. He has supported several critical systems utilizing SQL Server and managed dozens of 24/7/365 SQL Server implementations. Following several years as a consultant, he is now the Director of Database Management for rev.io, where he is implementing data governance, DevOps, and performance improvements enterprise-wide.</description>
      <twitter>sqlatspeed</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlatspeed</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlatspeed.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlatspeed</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96177</importID>
      <name>oscar garcia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Oscar Garcia is a Principal System Architect, Company Founder, Microsoft MVP and certified solutions engineer with many years of experience building solutions using .Net framework and multiple open source frameworks. Currently, he specializes in building cloud solutions using technologies like Azure, AWS data platforms. He enjoys sharing his technical experiences by maintaining a blog and delivering presentations. You can follow Oscar on Twitter via @ozkary or visiting his blog at ozkary.com.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ozkary</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/oscardgarcia/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://ozkary.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ozkary</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98164</importID>
      <name>Art Cardenas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Art Cardenas is a Data warehouse developer at Atrium Health, he has over 20 years experience with databases administration, design and development. SQL Server, Oracle, Tandem SQL non-stop. Most recently learning NoSQL databases such as MongoDB (document) and Neo4J (Graph) databases.  Currently studying the Masters degree in Data Science and Business Analytics at UNCC.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/Art_Cardenas_1</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/artcardenas/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://artcardenas.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/Art_Cardenas_1</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95927</importID>
      <name>Peter Doyle</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>On Jan 12, 2019, Peter attended his first SQL Saturday and experienced an engaging and uplifting community that encouraged everyone regularly to give back. That experience resulted in teaching eleven sessions and delivering a SQL Fundamentals pre-conference the last six months of the year.  He is passionate about sharing knowledge on building a solid T-SQL foundation without wasting time. 

Peter's journey from minimal Excel knowledge to writing Dynamic SQL all started from watching Youtube videos for three hours every morning before work. Managers took notice of the results and transferred him to the reporting department. A few months later, a co-worker suggested he should learn SQL Server and his world of data has never been the same.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/thepeterdoyle</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/thepeterdoyle/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/thepeterdoyle</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98896</importID>
      <name>Michael Wharton</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Wharton is a Project MVP.  He has been an independent consultant for the past 20 years, with over 30 Project/SharePoint Server deployments.  He has an MBA from Wake Forest and has over 44 Microsoft Certifications.  Michael's primary job is helping companies setup a PMO, Project Management Office using Project Server using SQL server on a SharePoint Farm. He has worked extensively with the back end support setting up SQL server, SharePoint Server and Project Server using PowerShell.</description>
      <twitter>MyProjectExpert</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelwhartoncomputer</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://MyProjectExpert.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MyProjectExpert</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96437</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98343</importID>
      <name>Marc Bushong</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marc is a data engineer at the Medical University of South Carolina. He loves to learn and constantly challenge himself through new concepts, technology, and techniques. For the first 2 and a half years of his career, Marc worked as an X-Ray Technologist in Philadelphia and Charleston. Currently, he is working with various Microsoft tools including SSIS, SSAS, SSMS, and SSRS to develop assets for the healthcare enterprise.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marc-bushong-606515121/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95954</importID>
      <name>Julie Smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Smith is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a BI consultant for Innovative Architects in Atlanta, GA. She#39;s implemented increasingly complex Business Intelligence solutions for over a decade at various organizations. She#39;s also worn many other database “hats” in her career – production DBA and database developer--but data integration and BI are her true passions. Julie holds a BA from the University of South Carolina. She and Audrey Hammonds co-created The Datachix.com blog.</description>
      <twitter>@juliechix</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliesmith0503/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datachix.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@juliechix</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99000</importID>
      <name>Melissa Coates</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Melissa Coates is a data architect with a background in data warehousing and business intelligence. Her current professional focus is enterprise-level Power BI governance, deployment, security, and administration. As the owner of Coates Data Strategies, Melissa produces training and consults to help companies strengthen and sustain their data-driven initiatives. Melissa is big supporter of the technical community, and has been a Microsoft Data Platform MVP since 2013. You can visit Melissa's website at CoatesDataStrategies.com, which includes community resources like diagrams, blogs, and videos.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLChick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/melissacoatesprofile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.CoatesDataStrategies/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLChick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98487</importID>
      <name>Hiram Fleitas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hiram Fleitas develops and manages database applications and AI bots using Machine Learning models trained on natural language, claims, policy, and social media data to predict business opportunities that grow customer satisfaction and loyalty in real-time.

He's worked with SQL Server for over 20 years, with some of the largest companies in the world. He's spoken on SQL Server, Azure and Power BI at User Groups, Code Camps, SQLSaturdays, and corporate events. He coded his first program in BASIC at 13 years old and developed a passion for computers ever since.

Hiram is also a code contributor to several open source projects and serves as the IS Flotilla Staff Officer for the United States Coast Guard Auxiliary.</description>
      <twitter>@hiramfleitas</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/hiramfleitas</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://fleitasarts.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@hiramfleitas</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99046</importID>
      <name>Leslie Andrews</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leslie Andrews is an IT professional with almost 20 years of experience working with databases, designing databases, as well as designing and developing applications against those databases. 2018-2019 Idera ACE.</description>
      <twitter>landrews5807</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/leslie-andrews-csm/9/491/b89</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.lace.technology/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=landrews5807</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95971</importID>
      <name>Ashwini Jain</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My interests span (but not limited to) application of analytics and technology in the construction industry, supply chain management and optimization, data science, analytics, data visualization, GIS and location analytics.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99014</importID>
      <name>Priscilla Camp</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Priscilla Camp is a Business Intelligence and Analytics Specialist at the University of Central Florida. She has over 9 years of experience in the field of IT working as a Business Intelligence Analyst. Priscilla started her career working for a startup small business in 2010 and several years later moved over to the Higher Education Industry where she currently resides. Priscilla's focus is T-SQL, Data Warehousing, MS Power BI, and B.I. Strategy. She is also the Leader of the Orlando Power BI User Group.</description>
      <twitter>ITDataDiva</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/itdatadiva/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://itdatadiva.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ITDataDiva</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99137</importID>
      <name>Chris Voss</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris is a data professional located in the Raleigh-Durham region of North Carolina. He has been working on data analysis and database development in SQL Server since 2008 R2. His experience includes hacking T-SQL code, using Reporting, Integration, and Analysis Services for solutions, and delivering data models and optimized queries. He has been a member of the TriPASS user group since 2013 and is part of the organizing committee for SQL Saturday Raleigh. In his spare time, you can spot him working within the autism spectrum community or running somewhere (most likely at a local run club).</description>
      <twitter>ceedubvee</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cwvoss</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ceedubvoss.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ceedubvee</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98673</importID>
      <name>Slava Murygin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Started working with SQL Server 7.0 as DBA and Developer. Since then went through all SQL Server versions, migrations and multiple companies of different sizes and industries. Currently working as a  contractor with all aspects of SQL Server, including, but not limited to: troubleshooting performance, designing/developing: databases, systems, processes, data warehouses,  cubes, reports, ETLs; Refactoring old code; Migrating data from other systems to SQL Server; Securing the data on enterprise level.</description>
      <twitter>SlavaSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/slava-murygin/9/b95/858</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://slavasql.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SlavaSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96413</importID>
      <name>Simon Kingaby</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Simon Kingaby has been moving data for 20 plus years.  In the last few years, he’s been moving data from DB2, Oracle, Netezza and SQL Server to Azure SQL and Azure Data Warehouse, using Azure Data Factory, SSIS and SQL.  At BMI, he developed a Rules Engine Sync application that uses DB2 QRep messaging and Azure ESB to move DB2 transactions to the cloud in near-real-time.  Now at Deloitte on the Big Data team, he is developing ETL processes to move API, SaaS and SQL data into reporting databases on-premise and in the cloud.  He is also creating SSRS and Power BI dashboards for the CIO and related Services.</description>
      <twitter>SimonKingaby</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/skingaby</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://omwtm.blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SimonKingaby</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99009</importID>
      <name>Anthony Mendoza</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Anthony Mendoza is currently employed as a Senior Development DBA with Transfast. He has worked with SQL Server in some capacity since 1998 across various industries such as government, elections, military, financial and transportation. He holds a Master's Degree in IT Management as well as a MCDBA  MCSD.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/anthonymendozajr/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99114</importID>
      <name>Donna Ellis Wilson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data professional with 25 years in the industry, nearly 10 of which at Microsoft in Product Support.  Areas of focus includes: SQL Server administration, general troubleshooting, HADR, replication, log shipping, connectivity, security, and performance tuning.  Passionate about women and diversity in tech, brain hacking, behavioral change, and psychology.</description>
      <twitter>sqlgrrl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/donna-wilson-26212a37</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlgrrl.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlgrrl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95943</importID>
      <name>Bill Anton</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bill Anton is an expert in Analysis Services and an experienced data warehouse practitioner. In 2013, he founded Opifex Solutions, a consulting firm with deep expertise in enterprise-scale architecture, design, and performance optimization of Analysis Services and Power BI solutions. He loves eating and spends most of his free time convincing his beloved wife to adopt more golden retrievers.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLbyoBI</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/bill-anton/12/526/4bb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://byobi.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLbyoBI</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96441</importID>
      <name>Justin Dearing</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Justin Dearing has been working in IT in 2002. He started as a night shift AS/400 operator and rose through the ranks at a series of companies. He currently works as a developer in the capital markets industry.

Justin has served in both the development and production side of the house on Windows, Unix and Midrange Platforms. His database experience includes MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres and Microsoft SQL server. These days he programs in C#, PowerShell and PHP.</description>
      <twitter>zippy1981</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/justindearingnyc</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.justaprogrammer.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=zippy1981</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99146</importID>
      <name>Kevin Kline</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Kline is a database and industry expert serving as Principal Program Manager at SentryOne, the industry leading SQL Server database tools vendor. A Microsoft SQL Server MVP since 2003, he is a founder and former president of PASS. Kevin is an author of many books, blogger, columnist, and popular international speaker. Kevin’s best known book is the best-selling SQL in a Nutshell and contributes monthly to Database Trends  Applications magazine. He tweets at @kekline and blogs at http://Blogs.SQLSentry.com/Author/KevinKline.</description>
      <twitter>kekline</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kekline/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.sentryone.com/author/kevinkline</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kekline</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96403</importID>
      <name>Meagan Longoria</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Meagan Longoria is a business intelligence consultant with Denny Cherry  Associates, and lives in Denver, Colorado. She is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Meagan spends a lot of time thinking about how to use data integration, DAX, and data visualization techniques to make data useful for people. She enjoys sharing her knowledge and experiences at conferences and user group meetings, as well as through her blog (DataSavvy.me).</description>
      <twitter>mmarie</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/meaganlongoria/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datasavvy.me</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mmarie</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99055</importID>
      <name>Rob Volk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob Volk is a SQL Server DBA in the Metro Atlanta area since 2001. He also moderates and answers the forums on SQLTeam.com. While an old-time cranky DBA, he no longer considers quot;business intelligencequot; an oxymoron or quot;the cloudquot; as merely atmospheric moisture, and is delightedly dipping his toes into both of these new oceans, and loves to do things in new and and unusual ways.</description>
      <twitter>sql_r</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rob-volk-134ba81</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/robv/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sql_r</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>96160</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96160</id>
          <name>Thomas Norman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>111 (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Encrypting Data within SQL Server</title>
      <description>Data breaches abound! Do you want to keep your company out of the headlines? What are some of the data privacy laws affecting you? How will encrypting data affect your database performance? What data fields should you encrypt?  What else can you do to protect your sensitive data?
 
In this session, we will review each option to encrypt data within SQL Server, Transparent Data Encryption, Cell Level Encryption and Always Encrypted. While we look at the encryption options, we will review both on-premise and cloud offerings.  This session will deep dive into setting up Always Encrypted encryption and share experiences implementing the encryption.   
 
You will leave this session with a deeper understanding about SQL Server encryption options and how encryption can affect your performance.  Also, you will gather information on how to fully protect and review your sensitive data usage.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96008</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96008</id>
          <name>Matt Gordon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>112B (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Feelings Quantified: Scoring, Storing, and Exploring Social Media Sentiment</title>
      <description>The job of a data professional is evolving rapidly, driving many of us to platforms and technologies that were not on our radar screen a few months ago. I am certainly no exception to that trend. Most of us aren't just monitoring backups and tuning queries - we are collaborating with teams throughout the company to provide them data and insights that drive decisions. Cloud providers are democratizing technologies and techniques that were complicated and proprietary just a few months ago. This presentation walks you through how a silly idea from a football podcast got me thinking about how Azure Logic Apps, the Cognitive Services API, Azure SQL DB, and Power BI combine to provide potentially powerful insights to any company with a social media and sales presence. Join me as I walk you through building a solution that can impact your company's bottom line - and potentially yours too!</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95927</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95927</id>
          <name>Peter Doyle</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>210B (80)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Become a T-SQL Pivoting Ninja in 60 Minutes Or Less</title>
      <description>Stop wasting time using Excel Pivot Tables. Create Pivot Tables in SQL with ease.

Become a query writing ninja who uses the Pivot operator to move unique column values into multiple column names for better data insight. In this demo-heavy presentation, you will learn how to create pivot tables enhanced with multiple aggregate columns and column totals using Rollup and Cube operators, and the grouping function. Attendees will also learn to use the Unpivot Operator.

Come join me, and by the end of this session, you will have the knowledge to level up your pivoting skills to that of a ninja or maybe even *Chuck Norris.
*Not Possible</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96413</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96413</id>
          <name>Simon Kingaby</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>111 (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Moving Data to the Cloud (with Azure Data Factory)</title>
      <description>You need to move data.  A lot of data.  To the cloud.  You’ve got data in a variety of on- and off-site data sources.  There are several ways to do it.  Some of them can be quite easily implemented using Azure Data Factory.  Learn how to use variables and looping in your Data Factory pipelines.  Use the Integration Runtime to pull directly from on-site sources.  See how to upload files to blob storage and import them.  Learn how to trigger Data Factory activities.  And, learn how to keep all those connection strings and passwords secret in Azure Vault.  After this session, you will have tools that you can readily implement in your own data migrations.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98229</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98229</id>
          <name>Sandra Peele</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>210B (80)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Working with Multiple DBMS Platforms: You're Not in Kansas Anymore</title>
      <description>Imagine you have a new employee with valuable SQL experience, but from a different DBMS platform.  Or imagine you’ve been assigned to a project that involves a DBMS other than SQL Server.  What do you need to know?  In this high-level presentation, Sandra will highlight differences between default Windows installations of Oracle, Postgres, DB2, SQLite, MySQL, and SQL Server.  She’ll share her experience moving from one platform to another and what she has found to be the most important thing to keep in mind when working with a new DBMS or working with a new employee who comes from another DBMS environment.

This presentation is for anyone with a basic knowledge of SQL.  It was co-produced with Stéphane Faroult, author of The Art of SQL, SQL Success and other technical books.  The presentation uses techniques found in his latest book, Getting the Message Across: Using Slideware Effectively for Technical Presentations.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96441</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96441</id>
          <name>Justin Dearing</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>210B (80)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Version control with GIT for the DBA</title>
      <description>In 2005, Linus Torvalds developed the version control system (VCS) git. Since then, it has become as platform agnostic and ubiquitous as the internet. Microsoft has fully embraced Git. It powers modern on premise and cloud versions of TFS (now know as Azure Devops) as well GitHub, which Microsoft recently acquired. 

What does this mean to a DBA? Whether or not you use SSDT, you should be storing your database schema in version control. In addition, your utility scripts certainly belong in version control.

In my session. We'll cover:

How do I use SSDT to help prevent developers from using code first ORMs?
What is version control?
How does a distributed version control system differ from traditional version control like Visual Sourcesafe, TFS, and SVN?
How do I setup git for internal use in my company?
How do I host public and private repositories on github.
How do pull requests work?
We will be covering using git from both the command line and Visual Studio.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95943</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95943</id>
          <name>Bill Anton</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>111 (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>What You Need To Know About Processing Tabular Models and Power BI Datasets</title>
      <description>Ever wondered what's happening under the covers when processing a tabular model or a Power BI dataset? Why is it taking so much memory? How can I make it run faster? Am I running into a resource bottleneck?

Processing a tabular model can be a very resource-intensive workload and depending on your specific goals (e.g. speed, availability, etc) it may not always be feasible to process the entire model.

In this session, you'll learn what actually happens and in what order during model processing, the difference between the various processing types, performance considerations and most common resource bottlenecks. We'll also cover the most common processing patterns and the associated trade-offs.

Keywords: Analysis Services, SSAS, Power BI</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96704</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96704</id>
          <name>Solomon Rutzky</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>112A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Module Signing: Use Certificates to Replace TRUSTWORTHY, EXECUTE AS, and Cross-DB Pwnership Chaining</title>
      <description>We often need to grant a higher-than-ideal level of permissions to a Login or Role so that someone can: start a SQL Agent job (but you don't want them to edit anything), get data from a DMV that requires "VIEW SERVER STATE" permission (but that permission gives access to too much data), query across databases, TRUNCATE a table, etc. These problems are usually solved with some combination of: EXECUTE AS (i.e. Impersonation), cross-DB ownership chaining, or TRUSTWORTHY ON. Unfortunately, those options are all security risks.

Module Signing — https://ModuleSigning.info/ — is more flexible and secure, but requires a Certificate or Asymmetric Key. Those can be confusing to work with, and the security mechanism isn't intuitive. However, that confusion ends here.

Come learn how to have more secure, granular permissions that handle cross-DB tasks, Dynamic SQL, and SQLCLR. See what module signing can do, how certificates and asymmetric keys work, and realize it's not as hard as you thought.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96437</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96437</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>210A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing Backup Performance Using Data Science Techniques</title>
      <description>One of the most important tasks for a database administrator is taking (and testing!) backups.  As databases get larger and larger, the amount of time it takes to perform a backup can grow as well, to the point where your backups take longer than your available backup window.  There are several settings we can use to optimize backup performance, such as buffer counts, maximum transfer size, and the number of files, but trying every combination of settings on a single production-sized database could take weeks or even months.  In this talk, we will apply data science techniques to the problem of backup settings optimization and look at different models for approaching the problem and analyzing data.  Some statistics background would be helpful, but is not required; the big requirement is a desire to speed up backups.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95971</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95971</id>
          <name>Ashwini Jain</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>112B (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to automate row level security in Power BI using DAX and SSAS</title>
      <description>Power BI is a business analytics solution that lets you visualize your data and share insights across your organization or embed them in your app or website. This session is for users are who want to automate Power BI row-level security by replicating the security of another data source such as corporate ERP. Many organizations maintain tight data security within their organization. Row-level security needs to be defined within Power BI. This can be difficult if you have many users and security changes happen quite often. If you are using a corporate ERP system that has security built into it, you would end up doing redundant work of managing security at two places, in ERP as well as in Power BI. DAX query can be used to filter out rows based on user ID/user name. We will go over the demo of the entire process starting from bringing data into SSAS, creating data model, applying row level security  publish the report. Never again you will have to manually manage roles within Power BI.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96403</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96403</id>
          <name>Meagan Longoria</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>113</name>
      </location>
      <title>Creating Accessible Power BI Reports</title>
      <description>Accessibility is catering for your whole audience, including those with disabilities. According to the US Census Bureau, 19 percent of the of the population had a disability in 2010. Do you know if your reports are designed in an inclusive way? In this session, we'll discuss accessibility standards and regulations of which you may want to be aware, how users with disabilities can consume Power BI reports, and guidance and pitfalls when designing inclusive reports.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99055</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99055</id>
          <name>Rob Volk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>210B (80)</name>
      </location>
      <title>That's So Metadata: Discover Your Database From The Inside</title>
      <description>Have you ever needed to learn a new database design and don't know where to begin? Or are trying to find out why a query doesn't perform well?  Or need to provide security information to auditors or your security team?

SQL Server has numerous metadata facilities available to help you with these tasks and more. Functions, dynamic management views, and system stored procedures can illuminate details from a single column up through an entire SQL Server instance. We will demonstrate metadata techniques to help you:

- Document your database schema objects such as procedures, functions, tables, columns and indexes
- Investigate performance and look for bottlenecks and tuning opportunities
- Discover metadata to administer your databases backups, index maintenance, and security
- Apply your own metadata using extended properties

We will also cover the official Microsoft documentation on these features and other resources on how to use them.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96094</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96094</id>
          <name>Johnathan Sluder</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>208 (50)</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Key. The Whole Key. And Nothing but the Key! So help me Codd!</title>
      <description>In this demo-heavy session, we will discuss best practices when it comes to data normalization, why it's important to normalize your data, and to go about getting started.  We will take a look at a set of data and discuss the best way to bring it into Third Normal Form. We will focus on The Key (1NF), The Whole Key (2NF), and Nothing but The Key (3NF)!</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99162</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99162</id>
          <name>Erika Haase Nalley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>112B (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>PR for PR! Get the word out on Paginated Reports.</title>
      <description>Take your company’s BI reporting to the next level with the Power BI Report Builder. 

We will cover:
•	How Report Builder differs/complements Power BI
•	Importing your Power BI dataset
•	Building a Paginated Report
•	Best Practices for Business Reports for max ROI

The Report Builder is to Power BI  as the Lasagna Pasta Accessory is to the Kitchen Aid. It works with the same data set and transforms sections of your report into perfect sheets! (and did I mention there is no export row limit?!?!?)</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96040</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96040</id>
          <name>Ed Watson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>112A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Psychology of Better Power BI Reporting</title>
      <description>In this course we identify some common mistakes that we see in the business world using Power BI.  We will identify the psychology behind the reporting techniques needed to create powerful and effective reports.  The attendee will leave the class ready to write better reports using Power BI in the real world.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99160</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99160</id>
          <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>210A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>More Common Than You Think: Mental Illness in Tech</title>
      <description>Mental illness is more common than you think.  One in four Americans suffers from a mental illness each year.  In the tech community, this is often not talked about.  Many times, people feel alone and isolated in the tech community with us mostly being introverted people.  It is time to start talking about mental illness out in the open and honestly about how it affects us and those around us.

In this session, we will talk about what mental illness is and what it is not.  How my mental illness has affected me.  How it effects the tech industry.  How mental illness can affect you and how you can tell if you are starting to have issues.  What to say and what not to say to people you know that are affected by mental illness.  Finally, how to get help and where reach out for help.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99146</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99146</id>
          <name>Kevin Kline</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>113</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to SQL Server Internals and Architecture</title>
      <description>Let’s face it.  You can effectively do many IT jobs related to SQL Server without knowing the internals of how SQL Server works.  Many great developers, DBAs, and designers get their day-to-day work completed on time and with reasonable quality while never really knowing what’s happening behind the scenes.  But if you want to take your skills to the next level, it’s critical to know SQL Server’s internal processes and architecture.  This session will answer questions like:
-       What are the various areas of memory inside of SQL Server?
-       How are queries handled behind the scenes?
-       What does SQL Server do with procedural code, like functions, procedures, and triggers?
-       What happens during checkpoints?  Lazywrites?
-       How are IOs handled with regards to transaction logs and database?
-       What happens when transaction logs and databases grow or shrinks?</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96177</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96177</id>
          <name>oscar garcia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>112A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Improve distributed system and web app performance by using in-memory cache system</title>
      <description>Applications often integrate with APIs for the purpose of retrieving data from a disk-based storage system like SQL Server. This poses challenges due slow queries and amount of data sent down the wire. In this presentation, we discuss the performance concerns with this type of architecture especially for big data scenarios.  Oscar Garcia shows how to address those concerns by following a series of steps in which an application is refactored with minimum changes to support an in-memory data store and data streaming.  We start by discussing the challenges when using data queries. We structure the data for in in-memory storage. We replace the API requests with real-time data streaming.

Learning Objectives:

SQL Server Query Challenges

Redis Cache Basic Operations and Structure

Angular App with Socket.io integration

Node.js Backend with Socket.io and Redis support

Real-time data integration</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98343</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98343</id>
          <name>Marc Bushong</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>210B (80)</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Beginner's Guide to Using GIT</title>
      <description>Source Control is a wonderful resource to improve team collaboration, reduce the risk of problems from lone wolf development and track change efficiently. Developers are already familiar with source control, but ANY Analysts or Operations teams can benefit! If you are struggling to use source control, are frustrated with not understanding the what, why, and how, or want to start using source control then look no further!  We will cover using source control for code in stored procedures and queries for SSMS, SSIS packages, SSAS models and cubes, and SSRS reports.

With this session, you will learn the foundational knowledge to not only to apply to your workplace right away but to lay the groundwork to continue building your skills in Git. We will cover basic terms/concepts of how Git works, understanding the process flow, executing some basic commands in Git, understanding why a merge conflict happens and how to solve it, and using different GUIs if the command line isn't your thing.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99046</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99046</id>
          <name>Leslie Andrews</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>210B (80)</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Power of Data: The Complete Beginners Data Warehouse Kit</title>
      <description>For many of us data is scattered in many different systems.  We almost all have data that someone wants to compare or track but can't without a lot of manual manipulation.  So, how do you tie disparate systems together? With a Data Warehouse! In this presentation you will get the skills you need to start building your own. We will discuss the basics of what a Data Warehouse is, the tools needed to create, deploy and manage the Data Warehouse process, and the benefits of using the data you collect to manage operational processes and create data visualizations. After attending this session you will be able to return to your job and amaze people with your ability to show them the power of the data!</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100059</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100059</id>
          <name>Shabnam Watson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>112A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Aggregations in Power BI: How to unlock the power of big datasets</title>
      <description>Aggregations are one of the most important optimization methods for managing big datasets in Power
BI. Combined with Direct Query storage mode, they allow big datasets to be analyzed efficiently by
answering high level analytical queries quickly from memory while sending more detailed queries back
to the source database.
In this session, you will learn about the concept of aggregations, different table storage modes in Power
BI, how to set up aggregation tables and configure them to improve query performance. You will also
learn how to use DAX Studio to determine if the aggregations are being used.
Prerequisite: Basic knowledge of data modeling in Power BI Desktop.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99009</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99009</id>
          <name>Anthony Mendoza</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>111 (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Test Driven Development (TDD) for T-SQL Database Development</title>
      <description>This session will cover the incorporation of Agile's Test Driven Development (TDD) into traditional T-SQL Database Development. The session will show the benefits of integrating this methodology into your database development processes. These benefits would include proper unit testing as well as the prevention of introducing performance issues into production.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96928</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96928</id>
          <name>Prabhaker Potharaju</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>210A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server on Linux and containers</title>
      <description>Overview of What is SQL Server on Linux. The Platform Abstraction Layer (SQLPAL), SQL Server on Linux feature compatibility, Implementing SQL Server on Linux. Performance and Security of SQL Server on Linux, HA/DR with SQL server on Linux.
What’s next for SQL Server in containers, Container orchestration using Kubernetes and SQL Server HA on Kubernetes.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100282</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100282</id>
          <name>Kevin Kline</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>210A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Fix Queries Fast with SentryOne Plan Explorer</title>
      <description>Using SentryOne Plan Explorer, a 100% free product, DBAs and Devs write better performing SQL code in a fraction of the time otherwise possible. Plus, troubleshooting existing SQL code becomes a fast, easy, and visually vibrant experience. Learn all the ways SentryOne Plan Explorer helps in this demo-packed session!</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95954</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95954</id>
          <name>Julie Smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>113</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Python In Power BI</title>
      <description>Python is a powerful general purpose programming language that has emerged as one of the main tools of data scientists. Python was added to Power BI in June of 2018. This session will demonstrate the two areas python can be used inside the Power BI desktop-- how to leverage python scripts inside the Power BI query editor and how to use python visuals in Power BI reports.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>97981</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>97981</id>
          <name>Jared Poché</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>208 (50)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using DMVs for Performance Root Cause</title>
      <description>What are your first steps when you hear one of your SQL Servers is having a performance problem? In this demo-driven session, we will discuss key DMVs that can provide us data quickly. We will examine a number of example queries that can lead us to a quick root cause analysis in a number of different situations. This session will be kept at a very functional level, and should be accessible for anyone interested in SQL Server performance.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98550</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98550</id>
          <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>112B (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Containers</title>
      <description>As containers are becoming more and more prevalent, this session provides an introduction to the different options of running containers in Azure. 

I'll cover the following different options for running Docker containers in Azure: -
Azure Container Registry
Azure Container Instances 
Azure Kubernetes Services

This session is aimed at SQL Server DBAs and Developers who have some experience with Docker  and want to know the different options that are available in Azure. 

Each topic will be backed up with demos which will show how simple it is to get up and running with these technologies.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98164</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98164</id>
          <name>Art Cardenas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>208 (50)</name>
      </location>
      <title>NoSQL vs. SQL, Real life database platform compare</title>
      <description>NoSQL is here, along with traditional SQL. In this session I will guide you to compare 3 different database technologies: Microsoft SQL Server, Mongo DB (Document) and Neo4J (Graph) databases. We will go from basic concepts, language syntax, Local  Cloud installation and operation, will focus on Azure.  Depending on your needs, the 3 of them have great use for different use cases.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96106</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96106</id>
          <name>Chris Pollock</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>111 (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dynamic Data Delivery Solution with Azure Data Factory</title>
      <description>This session will show attendees a way to dynamically ingest data into a centralized data store (i.e. SQL Server or Data Lake) using Azure Data Factory from multiple sources.  If going into SQL Server the processes will automatically create all needed tables and stored procedures for the process.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99014</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99014</id>
          <name>Priscilla Camp</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>208 (50)</name>
      </location>
      <title>How UCF IT uses Power BI to monitor our IT Services</title>
      <description>Curious how to monitor your IT Services using Power BI? Come see how UCF tracks our IT services to ensure our staff, students, and faculty are meeting their teaching, learning, research, and service objectives. Utilizing ITIL (Information Technology Infrastructure Library) practices, ServiceNow data, and Power BI we are able to take quantitative information and turn it into graphical visualizations to aid leadership and our customers in making informed decisions.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>97970</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>97970</id>
          <name>Lucas Feiock</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>112A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to SQL Spatial Data: Location Analytics</title>
      <description>In this session we will cover Spatial Data Types available in SQL Server. Then we will review the basics of spatial queries and the different methods to create points, lines, and polygons. Finally we will demo a few examples of location analytics and how to integrate into other data sets.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98878</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98878</id>
          <name>Chris Skorlinski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>210B (80)</name>
      </location>
      <title>911 What's your emergency?</title>
      <description>Come hear these "emergency" stories called into Microsoft's SQL Server Product Support team. I'll cover common backup\restore problems, SQL Server not starting, lost data, crash dumps, and infectious SQL found on Web just to name a few.  Learn background to the problem and what was done to correct in hope of avoiding your own SQL Server emergency.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98487</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98487</id>
          <name>Hiram Fleitas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>111 (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Power Platform Game Changer</title>
      <description>This is a game changing session. Lets go 0 to 100 real quick by building a business app in minutes using PowerApps, Microsoft Flow and SQL Server. Then lets look at the  enterprise-grade security to publish and share your app to iOS, Android, Web and Windows 10.

- AGENDA:
1. T-SQL Stored Procedure on SQL Server database (on-prem or cloud).
2. PowerApps (Inputs, Button, Outputs)
3. Flow (Input, SQL Server, Variables, Respond, Tests)
4. Gateway 
5. Publish  Share with Enterprise Governance.

We'll have time for QA. Maybe we'll even ask Cortana a few questions. I look forward to seeing you there!</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99000</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99000</id>
          <name>Melissa Coates</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>113</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Architecture End-to-End</title>
      <description>This session is a technical overview of Power BI architecture options. Power BI terminology and its most prominent features and functionality will also be reviewed to help attendees gain an understanding of the broad collection of tools, services, and features which represent the Power BI ecosystem.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>97992</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>97992</id>
          <name>Anders Pedersen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>208 (50)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why I use cursors in SQL for performance</title>
      <description>"Cursors are bad, never use them!" How many times have you been told this by your senior DBAs or developers? 
In this session I will explore why I use cursors to solve certain problems. Discuss when they are appropriate, and when they are not, as well as a performance comparison to non-cursor based solutions.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99137</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99137</id>
          <name>Chris Voss</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>112A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Moment in Time: About Temporal Tables</title>
      <description>Are you a developer or analyst who has been asked what changed for a particular record, and thus need to get the record at a given time? Well, in 2016, we were introduced to system-versioned temporal tables in SQL Server, which can tell you the full history of what the data looked like if you ever need to fend off questions. You will get to know the business uses for temporal tables, how they are built, the ways to query temporal table records, converting your current in-memory tables, and other elements to consider.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98467</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98467</id>
          <name>Ramu Pulipati</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>208 (50)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Migrating to PostgreSQL</title>
      <description>Postgresql is an Open Source, Free, and a Popular alternative database for building software applications. In this session, we will look into getting started with PostgreSQL, review unique features that make it exciting to work with and wrap up the presentation with strategies to migrate, deploy and scale for on-premise and cloud deployments.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99114</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99114</id>
          <name>Donna Ellis Wilson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>210A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Failure needs to be an option.</title>
      <description>Turbo charge your career, your projects, and your team by changing the way you approach failure, learning, practice, and praise.   This session will cover research in cognitive psychology and neuroscience in an actionable path forward to eliminate perfectionism and other career-stifling behaviors and thoughts, which those of us in the tech industry are particularly susceptible to.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98465</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98465</id>
          <name>John Morehouse</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>112B (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>What You'll Love in SQL Server 2019</title>
      <description>Technology moves at a blinding pace and the SQL Server platform is no exception.  With the release of SQL Server 2019, you will see some great improvement in the database engine of the platform.  In this session, you will examine some of the new features of SQL Server 2019 such as  Accelerated Database Recovery (ADR), resumable index creation, UTF-8 support, online columnstore rebuilds, an improved data truncation message, among other features.  After this session you will have a better understanding how you can leverage SQL Server 2019 to enhance your database environment.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99885</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99885</id>
          <name>Adrian Mee</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>210A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Management Studio - Beyond the basics</title>
      <description>Almost all of us use SQL Server Management Studio to interact with SQL Server, and thankfully it works right out of the box.  But did you know there are so many tricks and shortcuts that hide just under the surface that can make working with SSMS feel like second nature?

In this session, I will take a fresh install of SSMS and step through customizing it.  I will demonstrate features and help you become more efficient at utilizing SSMS to it's fullest potential - a lot of the time without using the mouse. Finally, I’ll show you some cool text editing tricks that will take your SQL skills to a whole new level.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100145</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100145</id>
          <name>Ivan Peev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>208 (50)</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server REST Integration the Easy Way</title>
      <description>REST has become the dominant technology for providing programmatic access to various cloud applications. We will show an easier way to interact with REST APIs with support for any authentication mechanism, support for complex, composite structures and unlimited flexibility. If you are a SQL Server user, you definitely must attend this session and get all your questions answered.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95957</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95957</id>
          <name>Monica Rathbun</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>113</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance Tuning, Getting the Biggest Bang for Your Buck</title>
      <description>Everyone wants to know if there are magic buttons you can push to make SQL Server run faster, better and more efficiently. In this session we will go over some of my go-to performance tricks that you can implement to get the biggest improvement with the least amount of change.  When it comes to performance tuning, every second counts. We will cover memory optimization, isolation levels, trace flags, statistics, configuration changes and more.  I’ll go over real life scenarios we come across as consultants and the changes we made to fix them.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96095</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96095</id>
          <name>Ganesh Lohani</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>208 (50)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building your Microsoft Business Intelligence (MSBI) Career</title>
      <description>Are you excited to know about the MSBI tools and work as a Business Intelligence Professional, a dynamic and rewarding career in Information Technology? If yes, this is the right time and place for you. In this session, I will give you the overview of the MSBI tools (SSIS, SSRS, SSAS, Power BI, Azure Analytics). I will also provide you some insights to build the MSBI career and to leverage the learning curve in Microsoft Data Platform, based on my knowledge and experience,  the proven strategies and techniques.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98896</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98896</id>
          <name>Michael Wharton</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>210A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deep dive into disk drives, partitions, controllers and hardware to improve SQL server performance.</title>
      <description>All kind of things can be done for improving query performance and IOPS (IO operations), however what if your hardware and disk drives were not properly configure to give SQL the best performance.  This session review the basics of disk drives, partitions, controllers and storage hardware and then looks into ways to improve SQL performance with correct  disk drive architecture.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99150</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99150</id>
          <name>Andrew Kelly</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>112B (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>CCI - Implementation Lessons Learned</title>
      <description>Are you thinking of converting your large databases from traditional row store tables to Column Store?  If so then you will want to attend this session. We will discuss some important lessons learned from actual deployments of CCI into production and highlight some key areas you want to focus on ahead of time. There are often many ways you can do things but getting it right the first time is crucial with CCI conversions on large scale databases. Come see what these are before it's too late.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98453</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98453</id>
          <name>Stephen Muliokela</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>210A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Corruption</title>
      <description>Database corruption could happen to you. When it happens to you, do you know what to do? Will you realize quick enough that you have corruption?
The presentation begins by talking about how to detect the corruption and the different strategies for handling unique corruption issues.
Highlight of topics
1.	Why corruption occurs?
2.	Detecting corruption – how SQL Servers detects corruption at the page level.
3.	Different types of corruption- e.g. False alarms, memory corruption etc.
4.	Limitation of DBCC  how to speed the DBCC process.
5.	Undocumented DBCC commands.
6.	Monitoring I/O errors.
7.	Verifying backup for corruption.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98673</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98673</id>
          <name>Slava Murygin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>113</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server on your fingertips</title>
      <description>You are a DBA, you are the Elite of Database World. Your time is valuable and you should not make a typing mistake.
In the first hour we'll go through the most common SSMS keyboard shortcuts and I'll show you how to setup your own shortcuts with your own queries.
In the second hour I'll show you how to set the best SQL queries developed by the best brains in the industry in your own SSMS and apply it to your environment.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98890</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98890</id>
          <name>Leveat Ruse</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>112A (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tips for Creating  Growing a Successful Professional Network</title>
      <description>Building a network is much more than LinkedIn and is crucial in career success. In this session, we will explore ideas and tips for building  growing a successful network. Everything from "ice breakers" to cultivating your current network.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96179</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96179</id>
          <name>Bhakthi Liyanage</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>112B (60)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building End-to-End ML Pipeline with Azure Machine Learning Services</title>
      <description>Azure Machine Learning services is an integrated, end-to-end data science and advanced analytics solution that provides professional data scientists and data engineers with tools not only to develop ML models, but also tools for data preparation and wrangling, data visualization, model deployment, and model management at cloud scale. This session will teach the attendees how to get their hands on each tool in the stack.</description>
      <startTime>12/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>