<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #538 - Sofia 2016</name>
    <startDate>10/15/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>400</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Cairo</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatSofia</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Telerik Academy</name>
      <street>бул. Александър Малинов 31</street>
      <city>Sofia</city>
      <state>Sofiya, Bulgaria</state>
      <zipcode>1729</zipcode>
      <longitude>23.3790428</longitude>
      <latitude>42.6508241</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>562</importID>
      <name>Devart</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.devart.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_14114.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1683</importID>
      <name>TechTalks.bg</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://techtalks.bg/</url>
      <imageURL>http://azure-camp.eu/sofia-bootcamp/images/sofia/sponsors/techtalks-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1155</importID>
      <name>SuperHosting.BG</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.superhosting.bg/</url>
      <imageURL>https://media.infragistics.com/community/SQLSaturday/SuperHostingBG-logo-small.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1773</importID>
      <name>SQL Master Academy</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlmasteracademy.com/</url>
      <imageURL>http://www.mateev.net/logos/SQLMA-hor-small.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1703</importID>
      <name>Programista</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.programista.bg/</url>
      <imageURL>https://programista.bg/webroot/images/logo-2.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1699</importID>
      <name>Bulpros</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.bulpros.com/</url>
      <imageURL>http://azure-camp.eu/sofia-bootcamp/images/sofia/sponsors/bulpros-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1765</importID>
      <name>Progress</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.progress.com/</url>
      <imageURL>http://www.mateev.net/logos/Progress_Brandmark_RGB_Primary_Medium.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1407</importID>
      <name>SBTECH</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sbtech.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/878/EventSponsor_14270.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1682</importID>
      <name>Dutch IT Cluster</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dutchitcluster.eu/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.dutchitcluster.eu/img/logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS USE ONLY </label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>426</importID>
      <name>Adastra Bulgaria</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.bg.adastragrp.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/980/EventSponsor_14952.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>201</importID>
      <name>MentorMate</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://goo.gl/53d5Fn</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/980/EventSponsor_14959.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50876</importID>
      <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Martorana Tusa is a Business Intelligence Team Manager at Würth Phoenix,  the IT and consulting company of the Würth-Group. 
He is awarded as MVP in the Data Platform category

Former BI Specialist at Widex, a Danish manufacturing company, and BI Developer in the IT department of an Italian banking group. 20+ years of experience working with data. 
He is focused on the entire BI stack: database development, data warehousing, data analysis, reporting, etc. 
Andrea is a usual speaker at many events: SQLSaturdays, conferences in Europe and PASS Summit, and for PASS Virtual Groups. 

Andrea is an author for sqlshack.com, sqlservercentral.com, and UGISS (User Group Italiano SQL Server).</description>
      <twitter>bruco441</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bruco441</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52487</importID>
      <name>Virendra Kumar Yaduvanshi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Competent, accomplished and result oriented information technology specialist with 20 years of experience, Dynamic leadership career, and demonstrated success in designing and implementing Database with emphasis on System Administration, Database Administration, Technologies deployment and technical analysis of multi-client operations, 
Innovative, result-driven leader with diverse IT experience emphasizing cross platform systems and network architecture, engineering, installation/implementation, integration, security and Administration for a VLDBs projects.
MCTS, MCITP and ITIL - applies broad technical expertise to resolve complex systems and DBs issues associated with progressive growth/expansion.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/v_yaduvanshi</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/virendrayaduvanshi</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://wikidba.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/v_yaduvanshi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54425</importID>
      <name>Samuil Aleksov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Currently a Lead Software Engineer at EPAM Systems, with a decade of experience in the most obscure places of CS.

Officially a CSharp.NET developer, 
but every language and framework work for me when they seem to offer the best solution. 

After years behind the monitor, collaborations with clients from different business fields, infinite requirements and the never ending search for unicorns, I have decided to start sharing with you the good, the bad and the evil of Computer Science.</description>
      <twitter>@samaleksov</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sam-aleksov-68594142</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.refractiondevelopment.com/category/blog/sam-aleksov/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@samaleksov</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48265</importID>
      <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr.SubraMANI Paramasivam is a Microsoft MVP, PhD, Microsoft Certified Trainer and Head of Data  AI at DAGEOP Ltd having 21 years of DB, BI, Analytics and AI experience. Mani has also spoken in various events like MS IGNITE, PASS Summit, MS Inspire, SQLBITS, Power Platform Summit, Global AI Bootcamp, Data  BI Summit, SQLRelay,  Power BI World Tour, Data Platform Summit, INSIDESQL UK, Global AI Nights, SQLServerGeeks Summit, MCT Global Summits, Data Day Events and various user group events. Mani also believes in Empowering Every Person in the planet and spreads the awareness on Global challenges via www.EmpoweringEveryPerson.com. He is also a co-owner of 1 Global AI Meetup and 3 Power BI PUG  PASS local / user groups.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dageop</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/dageop</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.yoursqlman.com/index.php/blogs</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dageop</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48577</importID>
      <name>Gilberto Zampatti</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Once upon a time a well skilled and valuable IT pro took care of me and elected himself as my mentor. I bumped into RDBMS when they were just prototypes and... when SQL Server appeared on the market I knew my trek. I#39;m still walking on it, glad to tell the people what I#39;m learning throughout my journey .</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52272</importID>
      <name>Sergiy Lunyakin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sergiy Lunyakin (MCSA, MCSE, MCTS) is a Big Data Architect at SoftServe, Inc.
He has extensive experience in designing and developing Big Data Analytics, Data Warehouse, and BI solutions, using both on-premises and cloud products. In 2016, Sergiy became Microsoft Data Platform MVP and has since maintained his MVP status. Sharing knowledge is another one of his passions. He regularly speaks at international conferences such as SQLSaturday, SQLDay, SQLNexus, and SQLBits. He also runs the Lviv SQL Server User Group in Ukraine and organizes SQLSaturday Lviv.</description>
      <twitter>slunyakin</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/slunyakin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://slunyakin.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=slunyakin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53955</importID>
      <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mihail Mateev is a technical consultant, community enthusiast, PASS Regional Mentor for CEE, chapter lead, Microsoft Azure MVP, Microsoft Regional Director. He works as a Senior Solutions Architect at EPAM Systems, focused on Data Platform, IoT and cloud related solutions. He also worked many years like a Technical evangelist in the Infragistics. Last years Mihail was focused on various areas related to technology Microsoft: Data Platform, Visual Studio, ASP.Net, Windows client apps, Data Platform, and Microsoft Azure. Michael also has a PhD in cloud computing area. He is a university lecturer on Smart Homes and Smart Energy IoT Solutions.</description>
      <twitter>mihailmateev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mihail-mateev/1/6b3/4b1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mmateev.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mihailmateev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54426</importID>
      <name>Branimir Giurov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Branimir is a UG Lead of SofiaDev .NET User group since 2003. He has been awarded by Microsoft with MS C# MVP award (2004-2014). 

Branimir is a Solution Architect in the Enterprise Software Development unit of Bulpros where he’s working on Enterprise-level projects in the area of Sharepoint, BizTalk, MSSQL and other Microsoft’s backend products. 

Branimir’s interests include: 
-	S.O.L.I.D. design principles
-	OOP design for maintainability
-	Agile development
-	ESB, messaging over and without SOAP
-	IoC, Unit testing, CI
-	Adapting software development

Branimir has a background in Software development with about 15 years in the area of Enterprise Software Development for solutions based on the Microsoft stack. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/branimirg</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48286</importID>
      <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dejan Sarka, MCT and Data Platform MVP, is an independent trainer and consultant that focuses on development of database and business intelligence applications. Besides projects, he spends about half of his time on training and mentoring. He is the founder of the Slovenian SQL Server and .NET Users Group. Dejan Sarka is the main author or co-author of eighteen books about databases and SQL Server. Dejan Sarka has also developed many courses and seminars for Microsoft, Radacad, SolidQ, and Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>DejanSarka</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/dsarka/Home.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DejanSarka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>51185</importID>
      <name>Miroslav Dimitrov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Miroslav Dimitrov is a Senior Big Data and Analytics Engineer at DXC Technology, regular speaker at various events and Microsoft Certified Trainer. He is MCSE: Data Platform for SQL Server and MCITP on SQL 2008. In the last years he had worked on great variety of customers' environments and involved in complex transitions and transformation projects as well as developing private and public cloud solutions. Miroslav is also leading database courses at Sofia University.</description>
      <twitter>@miro_dd</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://bg.linkedin.com/in/dimitrovmiroslav</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlshack.com/author/miroslav-dimitrov/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@miro_dd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48302</importID>
      <name>Janos Berke</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am  an IT professional with over a decade of technical and management experience. I am using SQL Server since version 6.5. Currently I am a  consultant and helping companies in SQL Server design, migrations, operation and developments as well as providing customized training .</description>
      <twitter>@JanosBerke</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://hu.linkedin.com/in/janosberke</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.iamberke.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@JanosBerke</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53936</importID>
      <name>Daniel Joskovski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Daniel Joskovski work in IT since 1985, he is a database-centric application developer and architect, instructor, course author, user group leader. Over the Past 17 Years as MCT he#39;s been teaching Microsoft SQL Server and .NET Development courses to premier customers in Macedonia, Serbia, Norway, Kosovo and Albania. From 2009 He is being awarded with Microsoft MVP award for SQL Server 8 times in a row. At the moment Daniel works for CloudCoder DOOEL Skopje.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54424</importID>
      <name>Kaloyan Kosev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kaloyan Kosev is a SQL Server expert working with enterprise companies for the last 12* years. His daily work routine is a mixture of troubleshooting bugs and issues, consulting and advising clients and presenting to students. Within his free time he is trying to balance between SQL and x-sports.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/nosqltillcoffee</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://bg.linkedin.com/in/kosev</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/nosqltillcoffee</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48253</importID>
      <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen, as the founder of Savory Data, has a long history of providing customer solutions in the areas of data engineering, data science, and Business Intelligence. He is a certified software engineer, a graduated business educator, and professor of Databases  Project Management at HTL Leonding, and is certified as an MCSE  MCT. He is a published author and writes articles for well-known journals. He co-founded PASS Austria and organizes SQLSaturdays in Austria. Markus is a founding member of Power BI Usergroup Austria. Since 2017 Markus was awarded as an Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>MEhrenmueller</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markus-ehrenmueller/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.savorydata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MEhrenmueller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53852</importID>
      <name>Ivan Miliovsky</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior Data Warehouse Consultant, Adastra Bulgaria Ltd.
Ivan Miliovsky is a Microsoft Certified Professional and a Database Developer @ Adastra Bulgaria. With over 7 years of hands-on experience in various projects in the Telco and Software Development sectors, he led and participated in many local and international projects. He possesses valuable expertise in design and development of Business Intelligence and ETL processes utilizing MS Technologies. Further Ivan is experienced in developing and testing processes with PL/SQL in Oracle, including optimization of PL/SQL queries and stored procedures. Enthusiastic follower of the latest developments in the area of MS technologies, he spends endless hours in researching and analyzing the poss</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53928</importID>
      <name>Anton Boyko</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Founder and main speaker at Ukrainian Microsoft Azure Community. 15+ years in application development. Builds apps based on Microsoft Azure platform since 2011. Microsoft Azure technical expert. Microsoft Azure MVP since 2014. Owner and one of the organizers of the most popular Microsoft Azure conferences in Ukraine: Azure Day and Global Azure Bootcamp.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BoykoAnt</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/boykoant</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BoykoAnt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53931</importID>
      <name>Ivan Donev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a Data platform MVP with more than 10 years of real-life experience with SQL Server and its stack of services. Besides the support and project work, I am also a trainer, conference speaker and user group organizer (and volunteer).</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ikdonev</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivandonev/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ikdonev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50970</importID>
      <name>Denis Reznik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denis Reznik is a Data Architect at Intapp, Inc. He has more than ten years experience in software development, database design, and performance tuning for cloud and on-premises solutions. In 2010 Denis became Microsoft Data Platform MVP and maintains MVP status today. Apart from his professional career, Denis actively participates in the development of the Ukrainian Data Community.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DenisReznik</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/denis-reznik/3/502/234</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://reznik.uneta.com.ua</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DenisReznik</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54980</importID>
      <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data Philosopher. Since 2006 invariably awarded Microsoft Most Valuable Professional title in the Data Platform category. A speaker at numerous conferences across Europe, as well as at user groups meetings. The author of many books and articles devoted to Microsoft Data Platform. An independent consultant, database-centric application practitioner and architect totally focused on SQL Server and Azure. Huge fan of Data Science and Machine Learning.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/marcinszeliga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53839</importID>
      <name>Margarita Naumova</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Magi Naumova is SQL Server Architect and Consultant, speaker and trainer, Microsoft Certified Master, MVP Data Platform, MCT, Founder of SQL Master Academy, founder and leader of the Bulgarian SQL User group. She has more than 15 years SQL Server training and consulting experience. Magi is a former member of Microsoft Services Worldwide Technical Leadership Team, а Microsoft Women worth watching http://zd.net/1lwNYKH Currently she speaks, writes, trains and consults people on SQL Server technology. She runs a Data Platform consulting company part of which is SQL Master Academy training program. It helps hundreds of specialists to feel knowledgeable in their daily work or to find an inspirational career path in the world of SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://bg.linkedin.com/pub/margarita-naumova/9/965/206</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>www.maginaumova.com; http://blogs.technet.com/b/magi/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>51069</importID>
      <name>Andrey Nikolov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrey is MCSA for SQL Server 2012/2014 with almost 20 years of experience in designing and implementing applications for Windows. He is working with various database platforms, but SQL Server is his favorite. He is also a leader of Plovdiv Power BI User Group and active member of local .NET, Power BI and SQL Server communities.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53662</importID>
      <name>Ivelin Andreev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ivelin is a Microsoft Azure MVP, software architect and senior project manager in one of the leading and highly innovative Bulgarian IT brands - Interconsult Bulgaria Ltd. He is an external ICT expert in the European Commission, Eurostars-Eureka programme, Innovation Fund Denmark and RIF Cyprus, Microsoft Professional Developer and Data Platform specialist.
With 18+ years of strong experience in design and development of web systems, SOA, enterprise integration, machine learning, web security and data management, he is a practical man who always tries to balance between risk and flexibility. As a master in Bio- and Medical computer science, his interest in IoT could be tracked back to times when the term was freshly coined and yet unpopula</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://bg.linkedin.com/in/ivelin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.slideshare.net/ivoandreev</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53840</importID>
      <name>Margarita Naumova</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Magi Naumova is SQL Server Architect and Consultant, speaker and trainer, Microsoft Certified Master, MVP Data Platform, MCT, Founder of SQL Master Academy, founder and leader of the Bulgarian SQL User group. She has more than 15 years SQL Server training and consulting experience. Magi is a former member of Microsoft Services Worldwide Technical Leadership Team, а Microsoft Women worth watching http://zd.net/1lwNYKH Currently she speaks, writes, trains and consults people on SQL Server technology. She runs a Data Platform consulting company part of which is SQL Master Academy training program. It helps hundreds of specialists to feel knowledgeable in their daily work or to find an inspirational career path in the world of SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://bg.linkedin.com/pub/margarita-naumova/9/965/206</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>www.maginaumova.com; http://blogs.technet.com/b/magi/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49396</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>48253</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48253</id>
          <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Enterprise (fl.3)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Are You a DBA by Accident? Welcome to the Club!</title>
      <description>When I joined runtastic.com to build their very first centralized data warehouse with Microsoft SQL Server, no one really felt in charge of the server – so the responsibility fell into my humble hands. Besides my duties as a business intelligence architect (designing  implementing the database, ETL  cube), I had to quickly come up with a solution for the most important administrative tasks:
•	Disaster Recovery and Failover
•	Database Maintenance
•	Capacity Management
•	Job  Performance Monitoring
In this session I will invite you to discuss the pros  cons of the solutions I came up with and you will leave the session with helpful concepts and scripts which you can use freely.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48265</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48265</id>
          <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Enterprise (fl.3)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tired of connecting on-prem  cloud data? Take a DB stretch</title>
      <description>You can stretch your legs and relax and get a quick session on delivering your analytics against hot, warm  cold data. If you are not aware of the concept behind hot, warm and cold data, it simply speaks about the age of the data that resides in your systems. 

Stretch Database is the new concept, which allows you to stretch your data from on-premises to cloud without a need of any SSIS packages or any other automation. In this session you will understand, enabling / disabling data stretch, reading data from stretched database, setup remote data archiving and backup  restore for the stretch enabled databases. Stretch DB also covers the concepts of Shallow  Deep backups.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50970</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50970</id>
          <name>Denis Reznik</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Enterprise (fl.3)</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Performance Tuning. Old-School Practical Guide.</title>
      <description>Nothing is perfect, which means that your database may be not perfect as well. And one day you may decide that your database is slow and it's time to optimize it. But.. Where to start? When to end? What to look at? Which queries are slow? How to identify the real bottleneck? And so on, and so on. There are a lot of questions that should be answered in a process of performance tuning. 

In this session, we will find answers to all these questions going from collecting data for analysis, through identifying bottlenecks to optimization of the particular queries. On this way, we will learn performance tuning practical techniques and solve a bunch of issues in real-time. All this will be done using plain old tools, which are available on your system by default: Profiler, Performance Monitor, SSMS, and DMVs. Minimum of theory and a lot of practice.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50876</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50876</id>
          <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room New (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mobile BI with Microsoft tools</title>
      <description>In SQL Server 2016 (currently availabe as a preview) Microsoft added support for mobile reports to Reporting Services.
They also released the Mobile Report Publisher for authoring and creation of mobile reports. This application is based on Datazen technology, a company that Microsoft acquired in 2015.
As Microsoft stated, using only one mobile BI app users will access dashboards and reports on mobile devices.

Now developers must choose a tool  for developing BI optimized for mobile devices: SSRS,  Mobile Report Publisher (former Datazen) or Power BI? The question is: which one to choose? What are the key factor for supporting the correct decision? 
We will provide a clear and understandable overview of each product, highlighting strengths and weaknesses.
Based on some real examples we will set out a comparison matrix to find the best way to meet your needs with the right mobile reporting tool. </description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53840</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53840</id>
          <name>Margarita Naumova</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Ultimate (fl.2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building an SQL Server 2016 AlwaysON Availability Solution (Part 2)</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 has major enhancements to existing features as well as brand new ones that will contribute to making SQL Server implementations more highly available. 
This two-part session will cover not only what is in SQL Server 2016, such as all of the improvements to availability groups like seeding and basic AGs, but important Windows Server 2016 features like site awareness, storage replica, and more that all DBAs should be aware of. With this extended session, most of what will be discussed will be shown so you can see how they work. The session is based on practical scenarios from a customer’s implementation. We will start with requirements list and will end up with an implemented solution.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53839</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53839</id>
          <name>Margarita Naumova</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Ultimate (fl.2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building an SQL Server 2016 AlwaysON Availability Solution (Part 1)</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 has major enhancements to existing features as well as brand new ones that will contribute to making SQL Server implementations more highly available. 
This two-part session will cover not only what is in SQL Server 2016, such as all of the improvements to availability groups like seeding and basic AGs, but important Windows Server 2016 features like site awareness, storage replica, and more that all DBAs should be aware of. With this extended session, most of what will be discussed will be shown so you can see how they work. The session is based on practical scenarios from a customer’s implementation. We will start with requirements list and will end up with an implemented solution.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53936</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53936</id>
          <name>Daniel Joskovski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Meetings (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Science on Premise with Microsoft SQL Server 2016 and R-Services</title>
      <description>R is coming to SQL Server. SQL Server 2016 includes new real-time analytics, automatic data encryption, and the ability to run R within the database itself. For deeper insights into data, SQL Server 2016 expands its scope beyond transaction processing, data warehousing and business intelligence to deliver advanced analytics as an additional workload in SQL Server with proven technology from Revolution Analytics.  Microsoft SQL Server team want to make advanced analytics more accessible and also to increase performance for your advanced analytic workloads by bringing R processing closer to the data and building advanced analytic capabilities right into SQL Server. With this update, data scientists will no longer need to extract data from SQL server via ODBC to analyze it with R. Instead, you will be able to take your R code to the data, where is will be run inside a sandbox process within SQL Server itself. This eliminates the time and storage required to move the data, and gives you al</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54426</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54426</id>
          <name>Branimir Giurov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Enterprise (fl.3)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Entity Framework Core - Did your feature got In, Out or Planned?</title>
      <description>EF Core is the new (.NET Core) version of Entity Framework on which the team have started working from scratch. 

It represents a lightweight and extensible version of the popular Entity Framework data access technology.
EF Core supports many database engines (SQLite, MSSQL, Posgre, MySQL, SQL Server Compact, IBM Data Servers and Oracle (soon)).

We'll talk about what's in the v1.0 release, and what is still planned. We'll look into some interesting demos as well (C#).</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54980</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54980</id>
          <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Ultimate (fl.2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data analytics with Microsoft R Server</title>
      <description>R is the world's most widely-used programming language for data analysis. Despite being the most popular, R suffers from lack of scalability and being slow. 
In this demo heavy session I will introduce you to the fundamentals of Microsoft R Server, it’s native file format XDF (eXternal Data Frame), data analytics and manipulation  functions, as well to scalable machine learning algorithms. 
Don’t miss the opportunity to see how MRS addresses open source R scalability and performance issues.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>51069</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>51069</id>
          <name>Andrey Nikolov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room New (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to SQL Server Extended Events</title>
      <description>Do you still prefer troubleshooting issues using SQL Server Profiler, because you find Extended Events too complicated? Or is it because you have never used Extended Events before, or it was in the dark ages of 2008 and your love for XML wasn’t strong enough to make you use them? The good news are that the recent versions of SQL Server give you a nice UI and made it all as user friendly as possible. The bad news are that you have no excuse anymore to not use them! Join this session to learn the basics of SQL Server Extended Events. You will see example use cases that could make your life easier and will learn how to troubleshoot issues in a modern and efficient way.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>51185</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>51185</id>
          <name>Miroslav Dimitrov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Meetings (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Myths and Misconceptions</title>
      <description>SQL Server is full of misunderstood features and misnomers that could affect how it is operating and respectively our applications. If you do not want to be surprised in a bad way by some intended, but not widely known SQL functionalities, join me in this session where we will, in an entertaining way, examine some of the most common behaviors that you probably have not expected.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54424</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54424</id>
          <name>Kaloyan Kosev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room New (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Life of a query</title>
      <description>Database queries have their own life. Sometimes it is not so long but for sure it is a fascinating one.
Come join me in a session where we will be chasing a wild query thru the SQL Server engine. Or at least put a DB Administrator on the interrogation table.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52272</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52272</id>
          <name>Sergiy Lunyakin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room New (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Data Warehouse: What, Where, How</title>
      <description>Have you heard about Azure SQL DWH? Do you want to move your current DWH into the Cloud? Can I use Azure SQL DWH like my regular DWH on-premise?
In this session I'm going to answer on these questions. Also, I will prodive information where is better to use Azure SQL DWH and what is more important, how to use it.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54425</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54425</id>
          <name>Samuil Aleksov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Meetings (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Crafting killer real time apps with SignalR and SQL Server</title>
      <description>This talk will introduce you to the world of real time apps.
Nowadays with the help of advanced SDKs like SignalR, real time apps are almost trivial to create and are the ones that provide the "Wow!" factor to our clients.
Having real time capabilities in your application is important, can solve you big problems and users gradually start taking them for a given.
You will learn how to create an app that magically updates its data and of course some nice tricks about SignalR and SQL Server.
Cool demos are guaranteed.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52487</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52487</id>
          <name>Virendra Kumar Yaduvanshi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Meetings (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Migration Strategies</title>
      <description>The best SQL ServerMigration Strategies</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49396</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49396</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Enterprise (fl.3)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data with Azure: where to begin? Concepts and best practices</title>
      <description>In order to ascertain the abilities of cloud computing platform, let us overview what is available  offered on Microsoft Azure.

Microsoft Azure has the ability to move, store and analyze data within the cloud. It is essential to evaluate multiple opportunities and options with Microsoft Azure data insights. In this session let us talk about strategies on data storage, data partitioning and availability options with Azure. A tour on how best these Azure components can help you achieve success for your Big Data platform.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53852</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53852</id>
          <name>Ivan Miliovsky</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room New (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Less known component in SSIS and cool features of Power BI</title>
      <description>-	Going through mountains of different methods and approaches to better understanding DWH loading. 
-	Show how to use standard components in Microsoft SSIS. 
-	Loading extremely fast data into DWH with components that we can develop or we can use. 
-	Better understanding of architecture of loading.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53955</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53955</id>
          <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Meetings (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>IoT Duel - Cloud vs. on Premises Solutions</title>
      <description>This talk is a parallel, between IoT solutions, based on premise and systems, build with Microsoft Azure components. The presentation will cover the architecture, technology stack, implementation and best practices. We will consider plusses and deltas in different cases, using both approaches. You will see also many demos, which will help you to build own cloud based or on premises Internet of Things systems.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48286</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48286</id>
          <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Ultimate (fl.2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Identity Mapping and De-Duplicating </title>
      <description>In an enterprise, merging master data, like customer data, from multiple sources is a common problem. Typically, you do not have a single, i.e. the same key identifying a customer in different sources. You have to match data based on similarity of strings, like names and addresses. In this session, we are going to check how different algorithms for comparing strings included in SQL Server  work. We are going to use four different algorithms that come with Master Data Services (Levenshtein, Jaccard, Jaro-Winkler and Ratcliff-Obershelp), and Fuzzy Lookup transformation from Integration Services. Finally, we are going to introduce how SQL Server Data Quality Services help us here.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53928</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53928</id>
          <name>Anton Boyko</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Enterprise (fl.3)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Search - full-text search in a cloud</title>
      <description>During this session we will talk about Azure Search - full-text search engine provided to us via SaaS model. The main advantage of this service is not only that is fully managed by Microsoft, scalable, reliable and all other cloud related stuff. It is more about numerous data sources you can use to populate your search indexes. Also, because you use HTTP to work with Azure Search, you can easily use it not only within your desktop or web applications, but also you can easily consume it in your mobile applications, IoT solutions, etc.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48577</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48577</id>
          <name>Gilberto Zampatti</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room New (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016: Evolution of the Columnstore Indexes</title>
      <description>The Columnstore Indexes technology has been subjected to a number of important improvements, including updateable nonclustered columnstore indexes, columnstore indexes on in-memory tables, and many more new features for operational analytics. In this session we will show this evolution, from the beginnings until today's state of the art.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48302</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48302</id>
          <name>Janos Berke</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Ultimate (fl.2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Good, the Bad and the Ugly - Always Encrypted in action</title>
      <description>As SQL Server 2016 is coming soon, it is important to see how new features are working. This session is about Always Encrypted feature and covers the followings:
- What encryption types are in SQL Server?
- A business scenario: handling sensitive data w/o giving access to DBA team.
- Always Encrypted basics
- Creating table with encryption by using AE
- Migrating data from regular table to AE table
- Decrypting data from AE table
- AE under the hood 
- Performance impact
</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53931</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53931</id>
          <name>Ivan Donev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Ultimate (fl.2)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tips and tricks to optimize data loading in SQL Server</title>
      <description>Have you ever needed to do initial data loads? Or regular ETL in Datawarehouse? And have you ever wondered how you can speed things up? There are number of tips and tricks you can apply and depending on your strategy you can reach throughput of more than 2 TBs per hour. How to do that? Join me on my session and see how companies are doing it all over the world.</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53662</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53662</id>
          <name>Ivelin Andreev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room Meetings (fl.1)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Native JSON support in SQL 2016</title>
      <description>Alongside with all other features SQL 2016 now natively supports JSON – one of the most common formats for data exchange. SQL 2016 now has built-in capabilities to query, analyze, exchange and transform JSON data. 
JSON functionality is quite similar to SQL XML support  but despite this being one of the most desired additions to SQL 2016 there is a flavour of something missing – the JSON data type. 
In this session we will talk about JSON support features, limitations and some tricks to overcome these.
</description>
      <startTime>10/15/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/15/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>