<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #534 - Krakow 2016</name>
    <startDate>10/1/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>350</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Belgrade, Bratislava, Budapest, Ljubljana, Prague</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatPoland</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Qubus Hotel Kraków</name>
      <street>ul. Nadwiślańska 6, Kraków</street>
      <city>Krakow</city>
      <state>Lesser Poland Voivodeship, Poland</state>
      <zipcode>30-527</zipcode>
      <longitude>19.95291</longitude>
      <latitude>50.04765</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1783</importID>
      <name>APN Promise S.A.</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.promise.pl/</url>
      <imageURL>https://az814542.vo.msecnd.net/App_Themes/promise/img/logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1794</importID>
      <name>Aon Hewitt Sp. z o.o.</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pracaaon.pl/</url>
      <imageURL>https://media.licdn.com/mpr/mpr/shrink_200_200/AAEAAQAAAAAAAAUKAAAAJGM5NGU4N2Y3LTM1ZjItNDZlMC1iOTk1LTMxN2E2OGU4MWI2Mw.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1788</importID>
      <name>ITMAGINATION Sp. z o.o.</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.itmagination.pl/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.itmagination.pl/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/itmagination-standard.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1797</importID>
      <name>PEPCO</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pepco.pl/</url>
      <imageURL>https://libera.net.pl/PEPCO-logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1801</importID>
      <name>Chatham Financial</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.chathamfinancial.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.chathamfinancial.com/wp-content/themes/chatham/images/chatham-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1790</importID>
      <name>Compendium Centrum Edukacyjne</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.compendium.pl/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.compendium.pl/_static/css/img/compendium-centrum-edukacyjne-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS USE ONLY</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54433</importID>
      <name>Kamil Nowinski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Blogger, speaker, #sqlfamily member. Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Data passionate, Data engineer and Architect.
Over 13 years of programming and experience with SQL Server databases, he worked both as developer and administrator big databases designing systems from the scratch. Passionate about tuning database engines, code transparency and maximising performance database engine.
Currently, he is expanding new horizons as a contractor in the UK market, making troubleshooting, prototyping BI and Big Data solutions, enhancing existing processes among Microsoft stuff environments, popularizing the DevOps approach and efficient solutions in the cloud.
An originator of the "Ask SQL Family" podcast and founder of SQLPlayer blog.</description>
      <twitter>@NowinskiK</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kamilnowinski/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlplayer.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@NowinskiK</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53324</importID>
      <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data Philosopher. Since 2006 invariably awarded Microsoft Most Valuable Professional title in the Data Platform category. A speaker at numerous conferences across Europe, as well as at user groups meetings. The author of many books and articles devoted to Microsoft Data Platform. An independent consultant, database-centric application practitioner and architect totally focused on SQL Server and Azure. Huge fan of Data Science and Machine Learning.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/marcinszeliga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52268</importID>
      <name>Sergiy Lunyakin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sergiy Lunyakin (MCSA, MCSE, MCTS) is a Big Data Architect at SoftServe, Inc.
He has extensive experience in designing and developing Big Data Analytics, Data Warehouse, and BI solutions, using both on-premises and cloud products. In 2016, Sergiy became Microsoft Data Platform MVP and has since maintained his MVP status. Sharing knowledge is another one of his passions. He regularly speaks at international conferences such as SQLSaturday, SQLDay, SQLNexus, and SQLBits. He also runs the Lviv SQL Server User Group in Ukraine and organizes SQLSaturday Lviv.</description>
      <twitter>slunyakin</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/slunyakin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://slunyakin.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=slunyakin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>47718</importID>
      <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Uwe Ricken is working with IT systems since the 90’s. The primary passion for developments with Microsoft SQL Server expanded in 2007 with his engagement as a DBA for Deutsche Bank AG in Frankfurt am Main. After 6 years of operational experiences as a DBA and over 14 years as a developer of complex database models he achieved the “Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008” certification which “was” the highest technical certification. In the same year he earned his first award as a Data Platform MVP for his support to the Microsoft SQL Server community in Germany and Europe. Uwe Ricken is a speaker on many international conferences and events and preferred topics are “Database Internals”, “Indexing” and “Development”.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dbBerater</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=270775013amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmaster.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dbBerater</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53467</importID>
      <name>Bartosz Ratajczyk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Database developer and (sometimes) administrator working with SQL Server Data Platform. Currently focusing on ETL development, delivery automation using TFS, query tuning, SQL Server training. Data Community Poland (DC) member, local group and conference speaker.</description>
      <twitter>@b_ratajczyk</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pl.linkedin.com/in/bartoszratajczyk</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.bartekr.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@b_ratajczyk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53109</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53525</importID>
      <name>Mikael Wedham</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mikael Wedham is the first SQL Server MCM in Sweden and the only one who also is a Microsoft Certified Trainer. He has been paid to do things in SQL Server since 1993. His long experience makes him an appreciated speaker at events and conferences all over Europe. To be prepared for deep dives, he is also certified as an Open Water Scuba Instructor.</description>
      <twitter>@wedham</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.wedham.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@wedham</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>47604</importID>
      <name>Cédric Charlier</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cédric is a talented architect and Data Platform MVP active in the domain of Business Intelligence and Data warehousing. He has more than 10 years of successful experiences with SQL Server in European industrial groups and services companies. Driven by quality and reliability, he is the main developer of an open-source solution for testing BI solutions (cubes, etl, reports) named NBi (www.nbi.io). Cedric also advocates for the introduction and general usage of agile practices in BI’s world.</description>
      <twitter>@Seddryck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://be.linkedin.com/in/cedriccharlier</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://seddryck.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Seddryck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52390</importID>
      <name>Grzegorz Stolecki</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Business Intelligence expert with 20+ years of experience. Grzegorz worked as architect, developer and trainer. Currently he focuses on developing specialized analytical and reporting solutions using machine learning models for large and mid-size enterprises. He also works on financial planning, consolidation and budgeting applications. Grzegorz is one of the leaders of Polish Data Community (former Polish SQL Server User Group PLSSUG). You can meet him very often at community meetings, conferences and other events. He is an active speaker and ATE member. Microsoft MVP in Data Platform Area since 2010.</description>
      <twitter>gstolecki</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/grzegorzstolecki</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=gstolecki</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53200</importID>
      <name>Damian Widera</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server MVP amp; MCT
Software engineer with 18+ years of professional experience in all aspects of software development.
Damian participated in a number of projects in international environments and possesses practical knowledge of procedures and tools which are necessary for successful implementation of such projects.
Now he focuses on building solutions based on Microsoft SQL Server environment (including complex database driven systems, database tuning and optimization).</description>
      <twitter>@DamianWidera</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/damian-widera-0b56284</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://codingfamily.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DamianWidera</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48864</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53625</importID>
      <name>Hubert Kobierzewski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hubert works at Codec-dss as BI Practice Lead. He helps customers to gather their data and convert it into valuable information using Microsoft Data Platform technologies. Hubert is also a board member of Data Community Poland and a leader of Warsaw Power BI User Group.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kobierzewski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50377</importID>
      <name>Lord Richard Douglas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lord Richard Douglas is a Principal Solutions Engineer at SentryOne, where he specialises in the SQL Server product range. He has worked with SQL Server since version 7.0 in various developer and DBA roles and holds a number of Microsoft certifications. Richard is a keen member of the SQL Server community, having run a PASS Chapter in the UK and having served on the organizing committee for SQLRelay.
Richard is on Twitter as @SQLRich.</description>
      <twitter>SQLRich</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/richardpdouglas</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SQL.RichardDouglas.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLRich</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>51153</importID>
      <name>Regis Baccaro</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Regis has more than 15 years of experience with SQL Server, SharePoint and .Net as an architect and developer. R#233;gis is a SQL Server MVP since 2014 and a frequent speaker at SQL conferences, a PASS Regional Mentor and the founder of SQL Saturday Denmark community event. He is also a certified industry trainer on the APS/PDW platform. In his freetime he is an avid runner, cook and farmer.</description>
      <twitter>@regbac</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/regisbaccaro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://theblobfarm.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@regbac</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53291</importID>
      <name>Denis Reznik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denis Reznik is a Data Architect at Intapp, Inc. He has more than ten years experience in software development, database design, and performance tuning for cloud and on-premises solutions. In 2010 Denis became Microsoft Data Platform MVP and maintains MVP status today. Apart from his professional career, Denis actively participates in the development of the Ukrainian Data Community.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DenisReznik</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/denis-reznik/3/502/234</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://reznik.uneta.com.ua</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DenisReznik</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53900</importID>
      <name>Pawel Potasinski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>CTO at Elitmind. Focused on determining the company's technological directions and transforming Clients into successful data driven organizations. Former Microsoft employee (Data Insights Product Manager for Poland). In 2007 Pawel started Polish SQL Server User Group (PLSSUG), currently known as Data Community Poland, an official PASS Chapter in Poland. Pawel has been a speaker at many conferences in Poland and worldwide (e.g. SQLDay, SQLSaturday, European PASS Conference). He has been awarded with Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) sixtimes in his career. Father of three. Avid runner.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/PawelPotasinski</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pawelpotasinski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.sqlgeek.pl</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/PawelPotasinski</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53327</importID>
      <name>Neil Hambly</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Neil Hambly is a SQL Server consultant, founder and consultant at Datamovements, a Gold Microsoft Data  Analytics Consulting company.
Neil has 20+ years in a variety of SQL Server roles and is an MCT. He is a regular presenter (200+ events) at user groups, and PASS events, including PASS Summit and SQLSaturday, and many UK events (SQLBits, SQLRelay). Neil is the leader of PASS London (UK), a Professional Development VC, a Melissa Data MVP, and a SQL Cruise Technical Lead, who loves Guinness, whisky, and dancing.</description>
      <twitter>Neil_Hambly</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/neilhambly</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataidol.com/NeilHambly</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Neil_Hambly</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52912</importID>
      <name>Agnieszka Cieplak</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Database administrator, Data Community Poland - Lublin chapter leader.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/AgCieplak</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/agnieszka-cieplak-27a9043</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/AgCieplak</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53569</importID>
      <name>Michał Janiec</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Od kilku lat pracuję jako administrator SQL Server i programista T-SQL. Posiadam kilka certyfikat#243;w związanych z bazami danych m. in. MCITP DBA oraz DEV. Jestem nastawiony na proaktywne wykrywanie i zapobieganie problem#243;w z silnikiem bazy danych. Moje gł#243;wne zainteresowania zawodowe to poprawna konfiguracja serwera, optymalizacja zapytań, troubleshooting oraz monitoring. W wolnych chwilach biegam oraz czytam książki z zakresu psychologii.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/michaljaniec</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SQLinspirations.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48103</importID>
      <name>Andrzej Pilacik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Database Manger / Solution Architect at BraceBridge Capital
15 years of experience in Database Platforms, SQL Server 7.0 - 2019, PostgreSQL, Redis, Oracle
Microsoft Certified Professional - SQL Server
Working with large data in Healthcare, Insurance, and Financial Sectors
Architecting HA/DR solutions
Developing frameworks around DEVOPS
Working with DW, SSIS, SSRS</description>
      <twitter>cypisek77</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrzej-pilacik-536a564?trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=cypisek77</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>47718</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>47718</id>
          <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM A</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN) Demystifying clustered indexes</title>
      <description>If you ask an expert about using a clustered index you will ALWAYS hear: Yes, you need a clustered index for your table. Last but not least Microsoft Azure Databases requires clustered indexes. But clustered indexes are not always a good choice for your database solution because of several different reasons. This session will start a debate about genius and madness of clustered indexes in your application.

This session will run several demos which will show in a very clear way why a clustered index isn't the best choice in several workload scenarios. "There's no lunch for free"! Not using clustered indexes will have ONE heavy drawback - this drawback will be demonstrated, too.

The session goal is to make decisions easier for you to use a clustered index or not!</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48103</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48103</id>
          <name>Andrzej Pilacik</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM C</name>
      </location>
      <title>(PL) Refresh a 1TB+ database in under 10 seconds</title>
      <description>The presentation covers recoverability options in SQL Server over time.  It will take us through many different ways of recovering a large 1TB+ database.  It will also walk us through many different options for creating development/test/uat environments.  It will highlight the benefits and shortcomings of these options while delivering a business value of each.  It will also evaluate a high level ROI of each of these options.
Finally, the presentation will focus on an architecture based on SAN technologies with respect to SQL Server.  I will demonstrate an architecture put in place resolving many business needs in a financial trading environment, working with large data sets and many different environments.   This section will highlight the benefits of using SQL Server together with newer SAN solutions and show the potential for reliability, scalability, and the delivery of a high quality HA/DR solution. That is where things get interesting...</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48864</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48864</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM C</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN)Upgrade, upgrade  more upgrade -know about SQL Server platform upgrade</title>
      <description>Why Upgrade? 
Data Platform Upgrade topic has been a popular session that I've presented in major conferences like Microsoft Tech-Ed (North America, Europe  India) and SQLbits since 2008. 

In this session, we will overview in depth end-to-end upgrade process that covers the essential phases, steps and issues involved in upgrading  SQL Server (2000 to  2012),  SQL Server 2014 (with a good overview on 2016 too) by using best practices and available resources. 

What to-do and what not-to-do?

A popular session that I have been presenting since the year 2008, in MS Tech-Ed, SQL Saturday  SQLbits UK.
We will cover the complete upgrade cycle, including the preparation tasks, upgrade tasks, and post-upgrade tasks. Real-world examples from my Consulting experience expanding on why  how such a solution.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50377</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50377</id>
          <name>Lord Richard Douglas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM C</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN) Natural Born Killers, Performance Issues to Avoid</title>
      <description>Learning SQL is easy, mastering it is hard. In this session you’ll learn simple but effective tricks to design your database objects better and write more optimized code. As an attendee you will gain a deeper understanding of common database development and administration mistakes, and how you can avoid them.

Ever thought that you were adhering to best practices but still seeing performance problems? You might well be. In this session I will be covering why the optimizer isn’t using all available processors, when the database engine fails to report all the resources a query has used and why the optimizer doesn’t always use the best plan.

You will leave this session with a list of things that you can check for in your environment to improve performance for your users.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>51153</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>51153</id>
          <name>Regis Baccaro</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM B</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN) Continuous Integration with SSDT and Team Foundation Server</title>
      <description>SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT) is Microsoft developer tools for working with SQL Server databases on premises and in the cloud. It supersedes Management Studio in development functionality. Team Foundation Server (TFS) is the collaboration platform at the core of Microsoft’s application lifecycle management (ALM) solution. TFS gives you the tools you need to effectively manage software development projects throughout the IT lifecycle. In this session, we are going to focus on the interaction between SSDT and TFS. Developing locally and publishing the changes to an on-premises instance of SQL Server. We will look at how we can do continuous integration between development and other environments pushing the schema changes and upgrading the version numbers in a seamless manner upon successful build of the solution. Furthermore we'll look at how to lift the integration to an even greater level by using Microsoft Release Management thus automating the deployment and testing of your software.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53109</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53109</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM B</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN) NSA Secrets - Hacking SQL Server</title>
      <description>How easy is it to hack a SQL Server? 
In this session we'll see a few examples on how to exploit SQL Server, modify data and take control, while at the same time not leaving a trace.
We'll start by gaining access to a SQL Server (using some "creative" ways of making man-in-the-middle attacks), escalating privileges and tampering with data at the TDS protocol level (e.g. changing your income level and reverting without a trace after payment), and more. 
Most importantly, we'll also cover recommendations on how to avoid these attacks, and take a look at the pros and cons of new security features in SQL Server 2016.
This is a demo-driven session, suited for DBAs, developers and security consultants (Jedi level). 
Disclaimer: No actual state secrets will be revealed. Please do not send agents to my house again.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52390</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52390</id>
          <name>Grzegorz Stolecki</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM A</name>
      </location>
      <title>(PL) Diving into hyperspace - how to make better OLAP calculation</title>
      <description>Fully additive measures and simple x minus y plus z formulas exist only in simple cubes. Business requirements are growing at very high rate. Complicated calculations with many conditions are needed - for months divide by 30, for quarters by 90, for years by...no... for years display nothing etc. And what about what-if analysis, simulations? The solution is only one. You must become an MDX Hero and dive deeply into multidimensional space of your cube. In my session I will present some real life analytical examples utilizing the SCOPE instruction - a truly hyperdrive for SSAS developer.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 4:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53200</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53200</id>
          <name>Damian Widera</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM B</name>
      </location>
      <title>(PL) Travelling in time with SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 comes up with a very exciting feature called Temporal tables. You can make queries to historical data lot easier by using this feature. The mechanism is very simple however you all should know it in depth to make sure you can use it efficiently. And this is exactly what I am going to do during this session – show you how to create temporal tables, how to use and manage them</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 6:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52912</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52912</id>
          <name>Agnieszka Cieplak</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM C</name>
      </location>
      <title>(PL) Rozwiązywanie problemów i optym. SQL Server przy użyciu Data Collect</title>
      <description>Data Collection nie jest nowym rozwiązaniem. Możliwość zbudowania hurtowni danych zbierających liczniki, parametry i charakterystykę obciążenia SQL Server jest dostępny od wielu lat. Nie wszyscy jednak wiedzą o jego istnieniu, używają, bądź kupują inne produkty firm trzecich, a może byłoby dobrze poznać to co jest w pudełku z SQL Server? W ramach sesji przedstawimy konfigurację, ale też pokażemy jak korzystać i co można znaleźć w raportach tego rozwiązania, by rozwiązywać bieżące problemy, czy dokonywać optymalizacji SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53327</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53327</id>
          <name>Neil Hambly</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM C</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN) Effective Index Partitioning, Compression Strategy</title>
      <description>We all know that ‘Indexing’ is KING when it comes to achieving high levels of performance in SQL Server. 
When Indexing also combines 2 of the Enterprise features: Partitioning  Compression, we can often see substantial gains.

Learn how to identify those objects that benefit greatly from being Partitioned or Compressed, OR combining both of these features to even greater effect.

Using Demos to illustrate the performance gains with real-world examples, Take away advanced scripts for use in your own environments.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>47604</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>47604</id>
          <name>Cédric Charlier</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM A</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN) Automating the testing of your BI solutions with NBi</title>
      <description>If you want to accelerate the testing of your BI solutions, the best strategy is the automation of your tests with the help of a dedicated framework. During this session, we’ll take a look to the features of the open-source framework named “NBi” (www.nbi.io). This framework is providing support for automated tests on the fields of databases, cubes, reports and ETLs, without the need of .Net skills. The demos will show us the best approaches to quickly and effectively assert the quality of BI developments. We'll go a step further, generating the tests by an interesting system of templates and test-cases sources.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53324</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53324</id>
          <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM A</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN) Microsoft R Server</title>
      <description>R is the world's most widely-used programming language for data analysis. SQL Server is say to be the most popular (or at least the fastest growing) DB engine. Guess, how popular MRS (Microsoft R Server) is going to be…
In this demo heavy session Marcin Szeliga will introduce you to the fundamentals of Microsoft R Server, it’s native file format XDF (eXternal Data Frame), data manipulation functions, and machine learning algorithms. 
Don’t miss the opportunity to see how MSR addresses open source R scalability and performance issues.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52268</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52268</id>
          <name>Sergiy Lunyakin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM A</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN) Azure SQL Data Warehouse: Deep Dive</title>
      <description>This is advanced topic about Azure SQL Data Warehouse. Here I will cover main concepts like Data Movement, Workload concurrency, Resource Management, Statistics.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53625</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53625</id>
          <name>Hubert Kobierzewski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM C</name>
      </location>
      <title>(PL) SQL Server talks Hadoop</title>
      <description>Nowadays (or in near future), when building data warehousing solutions we have to reach data saved on Hadoop nodes. With SQL Server 2016 you can do that leaving Hive, Pig and other animals behind and focus on your current skills. This session, fully packed with demos, will be focused mainly on new SSIS components keeping conversation with our Hadoop servers. I promise, your BI developer life will be easier from now on.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 6:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53291</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53291</id>
          <name>Denis Reznik</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM C</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN) Hidden gems of SQL Server 2014</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2014 is full of new features and improvements. Some of them are "Killer" features like InMemory OLTP, Clustered Columnstore Indexes, Buffer Pool Extensions, etc., which are discussed a lot and we always can get a lot of information about them. And in the same time, SQL Server 2014 have several fantastic features and improvements, which are more hidden from our sight. 

In this session, we will learn a lot about these features and improvements. Query Fingerprints, Cardinality Estimator, Tempdb improvements, and other overshadowed features will be covered in this session.

As a small bonus, we will talk a bit how these features are improved in SQL Server 2016.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53900</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53900</id>
          <name>Pawel Potasinski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM A</name>
      </location>
      <title>(PL) Think Mobile! Mobile Reporting with Microsoft Data Platform</title>
      <description>There are some business users wanting the information to be available at hand, wherever they are. A good example is a board member tracking profitability of his/her company on a favourite iPhone. Microsoft Data Platform allows BI developers to build reports and dashboards that can be delivered to the most popular mobile devices in the world (iPhone, iPad, Android devices, Windows devices). The purpose of this session will be to show up the capabilities (but also some caveats) of mobile reporting solutions built with SQL Server 2016 Reporting Services (ex-Datazen) and Power BI.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53569</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53569</id>
          <name>Michał Janiec</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM B</name>
      </location>
      <title>(PL) Optymalizacja zapytań opartych o linked servery</title>
      <description>Na sesji zostaną om#243;wione następujące kwestie związane bezpośrednio z wydajnością linked server#243;w:
- konfiguracja sieci
- konfiguracja linked server#243;w
- zasady kt#243;rymi kieruje się Query Optimizer przy zapytaniach opartych o linked servery
- zasady i przykłady pisania zapytań opartych o linked servery</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53467</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53467</id>
          <name>Bartosz Ratajczyk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM B</name>
      </location>
      <title>(PL) How minimal logging can help me?</title>
      <description>You have probably heard something about switching between FULL and BULK LOGGED recovery models and that it#39;s useful for minimally logged operations. But what exactly are these operations? How can you benefit from them and what conditions have to be met? Are there any downsides?

If you want to speed up data loading you should get familiar with minimal logging. In this sessiion I will show you real life examples (and - well - some not real life) how useful can it be, what downsides it has and how it changed over the SQL Server versions.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53525</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53525</id>
          <name>Mikael Wedham</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM A</name>
      </location>
      <title>(EN) When good pages go bad / The rise and fall of db corruption.</title>
      <description>We#39;ll walk through how to detect and repair corruption in a database. 
The DBCC command is the most important part and its output will be covered.
The different methods to repair the pages gives different amounts of data loss, so we#39;ll go through some of your options such as page level restore, DBCC repair options and some other options. 
Finally you#39;ll learn to estimate how much data loss you can expect. We#39;ll even going to see how to look at the corrupt page with DBCC PAGE to try to see approximately what data we are going to loose.</description>
      <startTime>10/1/2016 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/1/2016 6:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>