<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #858 - Athens 2019</name>
    <startDate>6/15/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>175</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Harare, Pretoria</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatAthens</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>OTE Academy</name>
      <street>1 Spartis and Pelika</street>
      <city>Athens</city>
      <state>, Greece</state>
      <zipcode>151 22</zipcode>
      <longitude>23.7880141000001</longitude>
      <latitude>38.048455</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/972/EventSponsor_14605.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2370</importID>
      <name>ENTERSOFT</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.entersoft.gr/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.entersoft.gr/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Untitled-26.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2447</importID>
      <name>OFFICE LINE SA</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.officeline.gr</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/858/EventSponsor_13642.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1114</importID>
      <name>SQLschool.gr</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlschool.gr</url>
      <imageURL>http://sqlschool.gr/images/SQLSCHOOL_LOGO_COLOR_BLACK_LETTERS_2019.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>562</importID>
      <name>Devart</name>
      <label>Raffle Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.devart.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/858/EventSponsor_13892.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90801</importID>
      <name>Sergio Govoni</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Since 1999 Sergio Govoni has been a software developer; in 2000 he got a degree in Computer Science at "Università degli Studi" in Ferrara (Italy). He has worked for over 18 years in Centro Software, a software house that produces the best ERP for manufacturing companies that are export oriented. Now, he manages the development product team and he is constantly involved on several team projects, where he focues his attention on the architecture and the mission-critical technical details. Since 2016 he is the vice president of the UGISS (www.ugiss.org). For the provided help to technical communities and for sharing his own experience, since 2010 he has received the Microsoft Data Platform MVP award.</description>
      <twitter>@segovoni</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sgovoni</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mvp.microsoft.com/it-it/PublicProfile/4029181?fullName=Sergio%20Govoni</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@segovoni</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89175</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo Kornelis is an established SQL Server community expert who spends a lot of time at various conferences. He is author of "the Execution Plan Reference" (sqlserverfast.com/epr), blogger, technical editor of Grant Fritchey's "SQL Server Execution Plans, 3rd edition" and some other books, and Pluralsight author. He was awarded SQL Server MVP and Data Platform MVP 12 times (2006 - 2016, and 2019-present).

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.</description>
      <twitter>Hugo_Kornelis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/hugokornelis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Hugo_Kornelis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94972</importID>
      <name>Stavros Menegos</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>- More than 30 years experience in S/W Engineering
- Very good Expertise on LOB Apps
- Have gone through working experience in large s/w systems in technologies and frameworks that have evolved through out all these years: Starting from Unix-C, to Visual Studio 1.0 and MFC, C++, SQL Server, .NET framework Full stack development, XCode Objective C, Xamarin Monotouch, Xamarin Forms, AngularJS, ASP.NET MVC, .NET Core, ML on Python, Anaconda, and ML.NET, Azure Services and Power Apps, Microsoft Power BI Connectors, Office 365 Application development and many more.
- Co-founder and Technical Director (formerly RD Director) of Entersoft SA
- Recently I have been nominated and awarded for the 3rd consecutive time as a Microsoft Regional Direc</description>
      <twitter>smeneg</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/smeneg</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=smeneg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88937</importID>
      <name>Guy Glantser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Guy Glantser, Data Platform MVP, is the leader of the Israeli PASS Local Group, as well as the CEO and founder of Madeira Data Solutions. His career has been focused on the Microsoft Data Platform for the past 20 years, performing various database roles as either an on-site DBA, an external consultant, or a speaker. His main area of expertise is SQL Server development and optimization. Guy is involved in many activities in the Microsoft Data Platform community. He occasionally speaks at community events, such as PASS Summit, SQLBits, SQLSaturdays, and user groups around the world. He also co-hosts the SQL Server Radio podcast.</description>
      <twitter>guy_glantser</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/glantser</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.madeiradata.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=guy_glantser</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89174</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo Kornelis is an established SQL Server community expert who spends a lot of time at various conferences. He is author of "the Execution Plan Reference" (sqlserverfast.com/epr), blogger, technical editor of Grant Fritchey's "SQL Server Execution Plans, 3rd edition" and some other books, and Pluralsight author. He was awarded SQL Server MVP and Data Platform MVP 12 times (2006 - 2016, and 2019-present).

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.</description>
      <twitter>Hugo_Kornelis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/hugokornelis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Hugo_Kornelis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93400</importID>
      <name>Sebastiano Galazzo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Passionate about Artificial Intelligence, Sebastiano @galazzoseba brings over 15 years of experience in AI and machine learning to his current position as CTO at Sistem-EVO srl.
Sebastiano has dedicated the last few years to designing and developing algorithms to tackle the challenges of Natural Language Processing, image recognition and predictive analysis through machine learning.
He is a Microsoft MVP and his work in AI has gained commendation in numerous publications and has received several national and international awards.</description>
      <twitter>@galazzoseba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://it.linkedin.com/in/sebastianogalazzo</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@galazzoseba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91702</importID>
      <name>Paul Wehland</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul Wehland has worked with SQL Server for a VERY long time and has supported customers on every version all the way back to v1 (16 bit). Paul is one of only 130 SQL Server Certified Masters (SQL-MCM) worldwide. He is a Director in the Data  Analytics service line at Avanade (joint venture between Microsoft and Accenture) supporting customers running very large and complex Data Estates.  Before Avanade, Paul worked at Microsoft in the SQL Server Product Group on many teams (QA-Performance, SQLCAT, SQL Clustering to name a few).  Prior to the SQL Product Group, Paul started in SQL-Product Support (PSS), where he co-founded the SQL Server MVP program, which he never imagined it would grow so large! Paul is based in Germany, but originally from the United States.</description>
      <twitter>@pwehland1433</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pwehland</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@pwehland1433</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89552</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88955</importID>
      <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr.SubraMANI Paramasivam is a Microsoft MVP, PhD, Microsoft Certified Trainer and Head of Data  AI at DAGEOP Ltd having 21 years of DB, BI, Analytics and AI experience. Mani has also spoken in various events like MS IGNITE, PASS Summit, MS Inspire, SQLBITS, Power Platform Summit, Global AI Bootcamp, Data  BI Summit, SQLRelay,  Power BI World Tour, Data Platform Summit, INSIDESQL UK, Global AI Nights, SQLServerGeeks Summit, MCT Global Summits, Data Day Events and various user group events. Mani also believes in Empowering Every Person in the planet and spreads the awareness on Global challenges via www.EmpoweringEveryPerson.com. He is also a co-owner of 1 Global AI Meetup and 3 Power BI PUG  PASS local / user groups.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dageop</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/dageop</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.yoursqlman.com/index.php/blogs</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dageop</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90093</importID>
      <name>Marcelo Fernandes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marcelo Fernandes is SQL Server MVP and has 12+ years experience with databases, specialized in High Availability, critical missions and very large databases. He holds the MCP / MCDBA / MCSA / MCTS / MCITP and MCT certifications, he lives and works in Berlin for an American e-commerce company that sells home goods. He share their knowledge through webcasts, presentations and articles on Microsoft technologies and can be cantacted by email fernandes_dba@hotmail.com or twitter @ marcelodba</description>
      <twitter>marcelodba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://br.linkedin.com/in/marcelodba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://marcelodba.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=marcelodba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>88937</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88937</id>
          <name>Guy Glantser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference Room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Working with Very Large Tables Like a Pro in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>A common use case in many databases is a very large table, which serves as some kind of activity log, with an ever-increasing date/time column. This table is usually partitioned, and it suffers from heavy load of reads and writes. Such a table presents a challenge in terms of maintenance and performance. Activities such as loading data into the table, querying the table, rebuilding indexes or updating statistics become quite challenging.
The latest versions of SQL Server, including 2017, offer several new features that can make all these challenges go away. In this session we will analyze a use case involving such a large table. We will examine features such as Incremental Statistics, New Cardinality Estimation, Delayed Durability and Stretch Database, and we will apply them on our challenging table and see what happens...</description>
      <startTime>6/15/2019 9:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/15/2019 10:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89174</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89174</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference Room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hash Match, the Operator - part 1</title>
      <description>SQL Server has a lot of difference execution plan operators. By far the most interesting, and the most versatile, has to be the Hash Match operator.
Hash Match is the only operator that can have either one or two inputs. It is the only operator that can either block, stream, or block partially. And it is one of just a few operators that contribute to the total memory grant of an execution plan.
If you ever looked at execution plans, you will have seen this operator. And you probably have a rough idea of what it does. But do you know EXACTLY what happens when this operator is used? In this two-hour 500-level session, we will dive deep into the bowels of the operator to learn how it performs.
It is going to be wild ride, so keep your hands, arms, and legs inside the conference room at all times; and please remain seated until the presenter has come to a full stop.</description>
      <startTime>6/15/2019 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/15/2019 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89175</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89175</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference Room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hash Match, the Operator - part 2</title>
      <description>SQL Server has a lot of difference execution plan operators. By far the most interesting, and the most versatile, has to be the Hash Match operator.
Hash Match is the only operator that can have either one or two inputs. It is the only operator that can either block, stream, or block partially. And it is one of just a few operators that contribute to the total memory grant of an execution plan.
If you ever looked at execution plans, you will have seen this operator. And you probably have a rough idea of what it does. But do you know EXACTLY what happens when this operator is used? In this two-hour 500-level session, we will dive deep into the bowels of the operator to learn how it performs.
It is going to be wild ride, so keep your hands, arms, and legs inside the conference room at all times; and please remain seated until the presenter has come to a full stop.</description>
      <startTime>6/15/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/15/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90801</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90801</id>
          <name>Sergio Govoni</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Master Class</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Query Optimizer end-to-end</title>
      <description>Execution plans are produced by the query optimizer that generates possible alternative execution plans for the same query through the use of the transformation rules. You already learned how to read an execution plan and the most significant things to look for such as warnings, most costly operators and table methods access. Now, you want to acquire a deeper understanding of how the Query Optimizer builds the optimal plan. In this session we will learn more about the phases of the optimization process, using undocumented trace flags we will discover the secrets of the Query Optimizer. Finally, we will show how to understand better the workload in terms of the percentage of time-out, the percentage of queries that contain sub-query and so on. At the end, Query Optimizer will not have any secret for you.</description>
      <startTime>6/15/2019 10:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/15/2019 11:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91702</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91702</id>
          <name>Paul Wehland</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Master Class</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Polybase</title>
      <description>Polybase started as a technology which allows you to query data stored in Hadoop or Azure Blob Storage as if it were just another table within SQL Server. As you move your data estate from on-premises to a cloud architecture, Polybase will be at the center of your cloud strategy.  Data Integration (DI) is replacing traditional ETL for cloud architecture, and central to this strategy is the separation of storage from compute.  

Come to this Intermediate talk to learn how you can get started using Polybase in SQL Server right away and learn about the 3 core EXTERNAL objects used in Polybase.  We will compare the differences and similarities between Polybase and Linked Servers.  In SQL 'Aris' (2019), Polybase will grow further and add additional connectivity and querying potential.  We will take a first look at how Polybase is central to SQL 2019 Big Data Clusters.  Azure Kubernetes Services makes SQL Server Big Data Clusters easy to create and deploy.</description>
      <startTime>6/15/2019 2:55:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/15/2019 3:55:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88955</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88955</id>
          <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Master Class</name>
      </location>
      <title>Exploiting Artificial Intelligence within Power BI</title>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence is dominating the world and not most of them had any chance to experience these features, due to various complicated reasons. How about if this can be made very easy and to exploit these AI features to visualise in our day to day Power BI? This AI session will cover all AI capabilities within Power BI and also using Azure Cognitive Services to build a live BOT  QnA, Vision (Face API), Language (Text Analytics).</description>
      <startTime>6/15/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/15/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89552</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89552</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Master Class</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hacking SQL Server Is Not Enough</title>
      <description>You already know how easy it is to hack SQL Server… But how do you protect your local and cloud servers against enemy agent attacks?
This is a demo-driven session, suited for DBAs, developers and security consultants. Both exploits and security recommendations to avoid them will be covered.
Disclaimer: No actual crimes will be committed. Please do not send agents to my house again.</description>
      <startTime>6/15/2019 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/15/2019 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93400</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93400</id>
          <name>Sebastiano Galazzo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Master Class</name>
      </location>
      <title>Machine Learning - Best Practices and Vulnerabilities</title>
      <description>It seems like Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning are a must nowdays.
For projects carrying a simple or well kown problem we can find a lot of ready-made solutions, but this extremne easy to use could be one of our best enemy when facing with specific custom problems.
With this session we will cover how to apply best practices in configurin ML but much more, do we reaaly need it always?
The second part will cover vulnerabilities of ML discovering how easy could be to fool a neural network by some techinques (Like pixel attack) and their implication in projects that requires no security issues.</description>
      <startTime>6/15/2019 9:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/15/2019 10:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94972</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94972</id>
          <name>Stavros Menegos</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference Room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Design, Build, Deploy  Monitor a Store on the Cloud using Azure Services as Lego blocks</title>
      <description>A walk through on how a real-life Store has been designed, developed, deployed and monitored on Azure Cloud by exploiting Azure Services such as CosmosDB, Azure Functions, Azure Queues, Azure Application Insights, Azure Log, etc. 
Furthermore, how all these can be orchestrated and programmed on Microsoft .NET Core 3.X, how to build custom API's and put all of them in action.</description>
      <startTime>6/15/2019 10:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/15/2019 11:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90093</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90093</id>
          <name>Marcelo Fernandes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference Room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Effectively Troubleshooting Latency and Failover of Always On Availability Group</title>
      <description>In this session, we will cover: The internals of SQL Server Always On, Identifying and detecting latency and failover issues with Always On, Artifacts and data pointers available to troubleshoot latency and failover issues, Tips and Tricks to troubleshoot Always On availability groups, New enhancements which make troubleshooting Latency and Failover issues easier</description>
      <startTime>6/15/2019 2:55:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/15/2019 3:55:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>