<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #880 - Munich 2019</name>
    <startDate>10/19/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>320</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Sarajevo, Skopje, Warsaw, Zagreb</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat880</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Deutschland GmbH</name>
      <street>Walter-Gropius-Str. 5</street>
      <city>Munich</city>
      <state>Bavaria, Germany</state>
      <zipcode>80807</zipcode>
      <longitude>11.5957899</longitude>
      <latitude>48.17934</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_14094.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1726</importID>
      <name>Solisyon GmbH</name>
      <label>You Rock! Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.solisyon.de/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/917/EventSponsor_13876.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1448</importID>
      <name>oh22</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.oh22.net</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/950/EventSponsor_14467.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2580</importID>
      <name>IT-xPerts.GmbH</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://it-xperts.gmbh</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_14223.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2427</importID>
      <name>adesso AG</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.adesso.de</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_13928.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>7</importID>
      <name>SIOS Technology</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://us.sios.com/company/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_14251.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2002</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.red-gate.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_13998.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14586.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_13542.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2556</importID>
      <name>Würth Phoenix srl</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.wuerth-phoenix.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_14036.svg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2292</importID>
      <name>DYMATRIX CONSULTING GROUP GmbH</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.dymatrix.de/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_13749.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1618</importID>
      <name>GDS Business Intelligence GmbH</name>
      <label>Doppelpack Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.gdsbi.de</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_14056.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1928</importID>
      <name>dbWatch</name>
      <label>Doppelpack Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://cilbuper.se/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_14061.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_13499.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96719</importID>
      <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wolfgang Strasser creates solutions based on the Microsoft Data Platform tools in his day-to-day job as Business Intelligence consultant. Either using SQL Server Database Engine, SSIS, reporting with SSAS and SSRS, implementing Power BI solutions or cloud tools for data analysis - the data-tools-landscape is broadening every day! Based on his professional careers as a software developer he likes to work on structured development processes.
Wolfgang shares his knowledge with the community at many national and international events. For his community work, Wolfgang has been awarded with the Microsoft MVP Award for Data Platform in October 2015</description>
      <twitter>wstrasser</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/wolfgang-strasser/7b/912/22b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://workingondata.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=wstrasser</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95010</importID>
      <name>Thomas Martens</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thomas "Tom" Martens has been awarded as a MSFT Data Platform MVP and works as Lead Expert at b.telligent (www.btelligent.com). For 20+ years Tom delivers Business Intelligence, Data Warehousing and Analytics solutions. Tom helps organizations to become data driven by implementing self service Business Intelligence tools at enterprise scale. His current interest is about the visualization of data and applying analytical methods to small and large amounts of data. Tom is a regular speaker at the PASS User Groups, Power BI User Group, SQL Saturdays, the PASS Camp and also the SQL Server Konferenz.</description>
      <twitter>tommartens68</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tommartens68</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://minceddata.info</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=tommartens68</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99226</importID>
      <name>Georg Gamsjäger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Georg Gamsjäger works as IT architect for business intelligence and datawarehouse at Sana IT Services GmbH. He has more than 5 years of business intelligence and datawarehouse experience in health care and more than 10 years of experience and deep understanding of Microsoft server technologies, especially Microsoft SQL Server. Previously, he was also a trainer for Microsoft server technologies and spokesman for various conferences.</description>
      <twitter>georggamsjaeger</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/georggamsjaeger/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=georggamsjaeger</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92902</importID>
      <name>Frank Geisler</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Frank Geisler is owner and CEO of GDS Business Intelligence GmbH. He is SQL Server MVP, MCT,  MCSE – Business Intelligence, MCSE – Data Plattform and MCSE - Azure Solutions Architect. In his Job he is building Business Intelligence Systems based on Microsoft Technology, mainly on SQL Server and SharePoint.</description>
      <twitter>@Frank Geisler</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=4839367</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gdsbi.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Frank Geisler</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92941</importID>
      <name>Andre Essing</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andre Essing advises, in his role as Technology Solutions Professional, customers in topics all around the Microsoft Data Platform. Since version 7.0, Andre gathering experience with the SQL Server product family, where he has focused on infrastructure topics, mission-critical systems and security. Today Andre concentrates on working with data in the cloud, like Modern Data Warehouse architectures, Artificial Intelligence and new scalable database systems like Azure Cosmos DB.

In addition to his work at Microsoft, Andre is engaged in the community as a chapter leader for the PASS chapter in Bavaria, Germany. You can meet him as a speaker at user groups and international conferences.</description>
      <twitter>@aessing</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aessing</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.andreessing.de/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@aessing</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92840</importID>
      <name>Felix Möller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Felix Möller has been working as a Consultant for Data Warehousing for more than five years. His focus is tradtional Enterprise Data Warehousing clear layered architecture and presenting easy to grasp dimensional models for complex business process to frontend users. Felix technology focus has been the relational engine and Integration Services and from time to time multidimensional or tabular Analysis Services.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99168</importID>
      <name>Thomas Jorczik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thomas Jorczik is regional lead for the German PASS Community in Saxony. He is in the IT business since more than 30 years - with national and international sales and business development functions in companies like Digital Equipment, Compaq and Capgemini. Today he is leading the SIOS Competence and Support Center for Central and Eastern Europe based in Dresden. He studied in Berlin and earned a diploma in communications engineering.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96461</importID>
      <name>Oliver Engels</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Oliver Engels is CEO of oh22data AG, a Microsoft Gold Partner in Germany specializing in CRM and BI. His special interests are Azure, Data Governance and Integration, Visualisation Tools like SSRS, Power BI, Tableau, R, and SharePoint. He has worked with SQL Server since version 6.5 and is a founder and Board member of PASS Germany, a PASS Regional Mentor, and runs the Frankfurt PASS Local Group. For more than seven years he is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a Microsoft pTSP.</description>
      <twitter>@oengels</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ssis-components.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@oengels</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93399</importID>
      <name>Aleksandar Talev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Aleksandar Talev is Chief Development Officer in Semos  - Microsoft Gold Partner. He is professionally oriented to development of IT projects based on Microsoft technologies, primary SQL Server, Microsoft Power BI and Microsoft Azure. He has been working with SQL Server 6.5 since 1996. As a Microsoft trainer he is holding a Microsoft Curriculum courses focused on SQL Server as well as Power BI. As one of the founders of SQL Server User Group (PASS) Macedonia his free time he is engaged in developing the SQL Server community in Macedonia. He is a regular speaker on Microsoft conferences as well as local and global community events. In 2005 Microsoft awarded him with SQL Server MVP award.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/aleksandar-talev-95159187</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://Www.sqlpass.org.mk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92051</importID>
      <name>Rob Sewell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob was once a production SQL Server DBA, but is now generally found automating the Data Platform and providing training for clients. He has a passion for PowerShell, Data, and DevOps. He is an MVP, an officer for the DevOps PowerShell VG, and has spoken and volunteered at many PowerShell and Data events. He is a member of the committee that organises Data In Devon and the European PowerShell Conference. He is a proud supporter of the Data and PowerShell communities. 
 
He relishes sharing and learning and can be found doing both via Twitter @sqldbawithbeard and his blog sqldbawithabeard.com. He spends most of his time looking at a screen and loves to solve problems.</description>
      <twitter>sqldbawithbeard</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/robsewellsqldba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldbawithabeard.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqldbawithbeard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99223</importID>
      <name>Erik Monchen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erik has worked with the Microsoft BI products for over 7 years at different organizations in The Netherlands, Germany and the United States, responsible in the areas of information gathering to information delivery.</description>
      <twitter>erikmonchen</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/emonchen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=erikmonchen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92900</importID>
      <name>Stefan Kirner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stefan Kirner ist Teamleiter BI Solutions bei der inovex GmbH in Karlsruhe und besch#228;ftigt sich seit dem SQL Server 2000 mit dem Microsoft BI Stack. In diversen spannenden Business Intellligence Projekten in unterschiedlichsten Branchen hat er als Entwickler, Architekt und Projektleiter die Entwicklung der Microsoft BI amp; Analytics Komponenten von kargen DTS Zeiten an bis heute verfolgt. Inzwischen hat sich der Horizont der Data Management L#246;sungen nat#252;rlich auch auf viele Dienste in der Cloud erweitert. Stefan ist Microsoft Certified Systems Expert (MCSE). Seit 2006 leitet er die SQL PASS Regionalgruppe Karlsruhe und er unterst#252;tzt Microsoft Deutschland als Partner-Technical Solution Professional im Presales Bereich.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91119</importID>
      <name>Ben Weissman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben Weissman has been working with SQL Server since SQL Server 6.5, mainly in the BI/Datawarehousing field. He is a Data Platform MVP, MCSE Data Management and Analytics, and a Certified Data Vault Data Modeler. He is also the first BimlHero Certified Expert in Germany and a co-author of  'SQL Server Big Data Clusters' and 'The Biml Book'.
Ben has been involved in more than 150 BI Projects and is always looking for ways to become more productive and make SQL Server even more fun!
Together with his team at Solisyon, Ben provides training, implementation and consultancy for SQL/BI developers and data analysts in upper-mid-market companies around the globe.</description>
      <twitter>bweissman</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://de.linkedin.com/in/weissmanben</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bweissman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95213</importID>
      <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen, as the founder of Savory Data, has a long history of providing customer solutions in the areas of data engineering, data science, and Business Intelligence. He is a certified software engineer, a graduated business educator, and professor of Databases  Project Management at HTL Leonding, and is certified as an MCSE  MCT. He is a published author and writes articles for well-known journals. He co-founded PASS Austria and organizes SQLSaturdays in Austria. Markus is a founding member of Power BI Usergroup Austria. Since 2017 Markus was awarded as an Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>MEhrenmueller</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markus-ehrenmueller/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.savorydata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MEhrenmueller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93722</importID>
      <name>Christoph Seck</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Christoph works as a BI Architect for KI Performance.  With SQL Server and its BI Stack he is dealing for more than 15 years.
He is cofounder and chapter leader of the German PASS chapter of Hannover, Visiting Lecturer at the University of Hildesheim and regular speaker at conferences and German PASS events on DWH topics and agile project management.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95528</importID>
      <name>Benjamin Kettner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr. Benjamin Kettner is a mathematician, founder and CTO of ML!PA Consulting GmbH. His fokus lies on consulting his clients technically and strategically for implementation of projects in different areas of the data platform. 
Er is regional chapter lead of the Berlin chapter of PASS, since 2020 he is a Microsoft MVP and he is a regular speaker on different events.</description>
      <twitter>DataMonsterBen</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.tsql-ninja.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataMonsterBen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92912</importID>
      <name>Jonathan Stewart</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jonathan Stewart is a Business Intelligence consultant specializing in data visualization, data warehousing, and data management technologies. An advocate for educating others, he is a public speaker, teacher and blogger, continually teaching people about the Microsoft BI Stack. Since 2000, he has been working in the database field with industry leaders in healthcare, manufacturing, financial, insurance and federal, state and local governments.

Jonathan is very active in the community. He has presented on SQL Server, SSIS, Reporting Services, Power BI and Business Intelligence at numerous SQLSaturday events, local user groups, and conferences throughout the United States and around the world. He participates in webcasts, podcasts, and on</description>
      <twitter>sqllocks</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqllocks/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqllocks.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllocks</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94883</importID>
      <name>Bob Ward</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Ward is a Principal Architect for the Microsoft Azure Data SQL Server team, which owns the development for all SQL Server versions. Bob has worked for Microsoft for 26+ years on every version of SQL Server shipped from OS/2 1.1 to SQL Server 2019 including Azure SQL. Bob is a well-known speaker on SQL Server, often presenting talks on new releases, internals, and performance at events such as PASS Summit, Red Hat Summit, Microsoft Ready, SQLBits, SQLIntersection, Microsoft Inspire, and Microsoft Ignite. You can follow him at @bobwardms or linkedin.com/in/bobwardms. Bob is the author of the books Pro SQL Server on Linux and SQL Server 2019 Revealed available from Apress Media.
Twitter: http://twitter.com/bobwardms.</description>
      <twitter>bobwardms</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/bobsql</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bobwardms</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94420</importID>
      <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dejan Sarka, MCT and Data Platform MVP, is an independent trainer and consultant that focuses on development of database and business intelligence applications. Besides projects, he spends about half of his time on training and mentoring. He is the founder of the Slovenian SQL Server and .NET Users Group. Dejan Sarka is the main author or co-author of eighteen books about databases and SQL Server. Dejan Sarka has also developed many courses and seminars for Microsoft, Radacad, SolidQ, and Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>DejanSarka</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/dsarka/Home.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DejanSarka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94610</importID>
      <name>Benni De Jagere</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Benni De Jagere is a Senior Data Insights Consultant at Realdolmen, with a strong focus on the Microsoft (BI) Stack. 

On a daily basis he turns (large amounts) of coffee into insights for customers, and references witty British comedy way too often. Overly enthusiastic about anything data related, he’s trying hard to keep up with all things new and shiny.

Rumour has it that he's also involved with a ragtag band of data enthusiasts, enjoying themselves whilst organising cool community things. They go by the name of .. dataMinds!</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BenniDeJagere</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bennidejagere/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://bennidejagere.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BenniDeJagere</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93380</importID>
      <name>Björn Peters</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I've started with SQL Server 6.5 but only as a sys-admin and not as DBA. Later I'd worked as a full DBA with SQL Server 2000 and my love to SQL Server started. In 2015  I'd got more interested in SQL PASS and tried to speak for the first time... the main part of my job is to work as DB-Admin and solution architect but I'm trying to widen my horizons. In 2016 I've visited and volunteered at the German SQL Saturdays und SQLGrillen and since October 2016 I'm the organizer of Azure Meetup Hamburg.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sql_aus_hh</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bj%C3%B6rn-peters-b26b5813b/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sql-aus-hamburg.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sql_aus_hh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94451</importID>
      <name>Sascha Dittmann</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sascha Dittmann ist Cloud Solution Architect bei der Microsoft Deutschland GmbH und unterst#252;tzt hierbei Kunden beim Implementierungsprozess erfolgreicher Cloud-L#246;sungen. Seine Schwerpunkte liegen in der Softwareentwicklung f#252;r die Microsoft Azure Plattform, sowie im SQL Server Business Intelligence und Big Data Bereich.

Bevor er Ende 2015 zu Microsoft kam, war er viele Jahre bei der heutigen Ernst amp; Young GmbH t#228;tig; Davon 13 Jahre als Softwareentwickler und 3 Jahre als Solution Architect. W#228;hrend dieser Zeit Gr#252;ndete er auch die Community-Webseiten cloudbloggers.de und cloudbloggers.net und war Mitbegr#252;nder des .NET Stammtischs Rheinhessen. Zwischen 2012 und 2015 wurde er 4-mal mit dem MVP-Award im Bereich Microsoft Azure ausgezeichnet.</description>
      <twitter>SaschaDittmann</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://de.linkedin.com/in/saschadittmann</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sascha-dittmann.de/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SaschaDittmann</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96359</importID>
      <name>Buck Woody</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Born helpless, naked, and unable to provide for himself, Buck Woody overcame these amazing handicaps to become a software developer, data professional, teacher, and a productive invertebrate member of society.</description>
      <twitter>BuckWoodyMSFT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/buckwoody</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://buckwoody.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=BuckWoodyMSFT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98965</importID>
      <name>Oleg Ulyanov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Oleg Ulyanov is a Sr. Solution Architect in VMware Technical Marketing focused on database virtualization and monitoring. He previously spend more than 6 years within VMware Professional Services (PSO) and have more than 15 years of experience in IT. He is a Subject Matter Expert in both monitoring and virtualization of business critical applications with tons of hands-on experience directly from customer sites.
He holds a broad range of industry certificates including VMware VCP 4/5, VCAP5-DCD/DCA/CID/CIA, VCAP6-DCV, SNIA, Microsoft, and speaks regularly at the official events like VMworld, VMware User Group, SQL Saturdays.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/oulyanov-vmware</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blogs.vmware.com/apps/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94184</importID>
      <name>Nico Jacobs</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr. Nico Jacobs is a Microsoft Business Intelligence and SQL Server trainer at the U2U training center since 2004. Before that, he was a machine learning researcher at the university of Leuven, Belgium.
At U2U, Nico creates and delivers courses on the SQL Server business intelligence stack (Integration Services, Analysis Services, Reporting Services …), Power BI, the traditional relational database environment (database development and administration) and the Azure AI and Big Data stack (Azure Data Factory, Machine Learning, Synapse Analytics,...)</description>
      <twitter>sqlwaldorf</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://be.linkedin.com/in/sqlwaldorf</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.u2u.be/u2u/author/Nico-Jacobs.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlwaldorf</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96377</importID>
      <name>Anna Hoffman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Anna is a Data and Applied Scientist on the Azure Data (SQL) product team at Microsoft. In her time at Microsoft, Anna has worked in Microsoft Consulting Services, AI Engineering, and now SQL Engineering. She spends most of her time working on Azure SQL and participating in the community to democratize intelligence over all your data, from ground to cloud. You can follow her on Twitter at @AnalyticAnna.</description>
      <twitter>AnalyticAnna</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/amthomas46/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AnalyticAnna</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96162</importID>
      <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server DBA with over 10 year's experience. Originally from Wales but now living in Ireland</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewpruski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbafromthecold.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96453</importID>
      <name>André Kamman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>André Kamman is a DBA and SQL Server Solutions Architect for CloudDBA. He has done a lot of DBA work on 1000’s of servers where he discovered his love for Powershell, architecting SQL Server solutions, building and tuning ETL processes (with BIML). He also likes to work with MPP platforms APS and AzureDW. André is a Data Platform MVP, Dutch PASS Chapter Leader and organiser of SQL Saturday Holland.</description>
      <twitter>@andrekamman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://andrekamman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@andrekamman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98781</importID>
      <name>Ben Weissman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben Weissman has been working with SQL Server since SQL Server 6.5, mainly in the BI/Datawarehousing field. He is a Data Platform MVP, MCSE Data Management and Analytics, and a Certified Data Vault Data Modeler. He is also the first BimlHero Certified Expert in Germany and a co-author of  'SQL Server Big Data Clusters' and 'The Biml Book'.
Ben has been involved in more than 150 BI Projects and is always looking for ways to become more productive and make SQL Server even more fun!
Together with his team at Solisyon, Ben provides training, implementation and consultancy for SQL/BI developers and data analysts in upper-mid-market companies around the globe.</description>
      <twitter>bweissman</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://de.linkedin.com/in/weissmanben</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bweissman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>92941</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92941</id>
          <name>Andre Essing</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Washington</name>
      </location>
      <title>From Datawarehouse, across BI, to modern data analysis and artificial intelligence, Azure Databricks</title>
      <description>Have you heard about Azure Databricks? The new kid in the Azure Big Data family? I would do wrong to call Azure Databricks as a managed Apache Spark service, as it is so much more.
In addition to transforming data, Databricks can also be used to analyze and stream data, run your ETL tasks, train Machine Learning models and explore your data. All of that can be done with the powerful compute engine, combined with an integrated development environment.
As a first-class citizen in Azure, Databricks is a Platform as a Service offering that makes Big Data accessible for everybody.

However, as always, the first steps are the hardest to take. Because of that, in this session, we have a look at how to provision Azure Databricks. You learn how to configure clusters, schedule jobs, stay secure and much more.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92051</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92051</id>
          <name>Rob Sewell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Chicago</name>
      </location>
      <title>Administrating SQL Server with PowerShell dbatools</title>
      <description>Let me show you how easy it is to use PowerShell to accomplish many everyday tasks straight from the command line with the community developed module dbatools.

Afraid of PowerShell? 
Worried its too complicated?
Don't want to go through the learning curve?

Let me show you with plenty of demos how easy and straight forward it can be and I will save you time starting Monday

Want to restore an entire servers databases to the latest available point in time of the backups in just one line?
Be useful to know the Last DBCC Check for your entire estate in only one line of code?
Need to test your restores but its complicated?
and many many more
All this in a fast paced, fun session</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92902</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92902</id>
          <name>Frank Geisler</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>Redmond</name>
      </location>
      <title>Fast like a Roadrunner - Get the M(eep) M(eep) into your M(eep)-Queries?</title>
      <description>Mit Power BI kann man recht schnell komplexe M-Scripte zusammenklicken die das gewünschte Ergebnis liefern. Aber sind diese Scripte auch performant? Welche Einflussmöglichkeiten habe ich als BI Entwickler wenn ich mal wieder eine Folge Punisher auf Netflix gucken kann während Daten mit meiner M-Query geladen werden? Dieser spannenden Frage gehen der deutsche Data Platform MVP Frank Geisler und Dr. Benjamin Kettner in ihrem Vortrag nach. Neben grundsätzlichen Informationen zum Aufbau von M-Scripten in Power BI erfahren Sie, was Sie machen können um langsame M-Queries zu beschleunigen. Sie bekommen direkte Handlungsanweisungen an die Hand gegeben die Sie direkt in eigenen Umgebungen einsetzen können.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92840</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92840</id>
          <name>Felix Möller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>Redmond</name>
      </location>
      <title>CI/CD for your Cloud Data Platform from Data Lake to Power BI</title>
      <description>On the one hand, traditional Enterprise Data Warehouses are transforming into modern Data Platforms. On the other hand, onPremise systems are moving to PaaS services in the cloud.

These changes come with the challenge of an increasing number of components that have to be manged. However, they provide the benefit of the flexibility and scalability of PaaS services.

This presentation will demonstrate how to build a full modern data platform with CI/CD. Resources will be deployed as ARM templates, a Data Lake is configured and created, a database is deployed, in addition, Azure Analysis Services is configured and finally Power BI reports are deployed to Power BI workspaces. The platforms' glue are Azure Data Factory including the brand new ADF Mapping Flows and Azure Functions.

This enables to spin up a fully configured environment within minutes.

The presentation will demonstrate how to integrate all above technologies based on Azure DevOps.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92900</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92900</id>
          <name>Stefan Kirner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>New York</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data flows in Azure Data Factory - endlich auch hier Transformationen!</title>
      <description>Die Data Factory steht seit längerem in der Microsoft Azure Cloud für das effiziente Kopieren von Massendaten zwischen vielen Arten von Datenspeichern zur Verfügung. Ergänzt wird dieses Angebot um die Modellierung von Abhängigkeiten zwischen mehreren Verarbeitungsschritten und seit der Version 2 auch durch einen Control Flow für die Abbildung von Schleifen und Bedingungen und dem Ausführen von Integration Services Paketen. Seit kurzem können jetzt auch visuell unterstützt Data Flows für das gezielte Anreichern, Korrigieren und Umwandeln innerhalb der Data Factory genutzt werden!  
Der Vortrag zeigt nach einem allgemeinen Überblick zur ADF, die Data Flows und andere top aktuelle Features des Platform-as-a-Service Dienstes mit wichtigen Tipps aus der Praxis.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 2:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 3:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93399</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93399</id>
          <name>Aleksandar Talev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Chicago</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to choose the right data model: SQL Server or Azure Cosmos DB. Which, When and Where ?</title>
      <description>When it comes to choosing a database, always there are considerations about picking a relational (SQL) or non-relational (NoSQL) data structure. While both are viable options, there are certain key differences between these two options that users must keep in mind.This session will cover the most important distinctions and will make a difference between two of a key players in the Microsoft database world: SQL Server and Azure Cosmos DB.  The session will also illustrate some of the fundamental differences between these databases - the language, scalability and structure which cause this distinctions to have  implications for the right choice.So which database is right for your business the attendance will take informations in this session.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94420</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94420</id>
          <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Washington</name>
      </location>
      <title>Statistical Analysis with T-SQL</title>
      <description>Transact-SQL language in latest editions of SQL Server has so many business intelligence (BI) improvements that it might become your primary analytic database system. You might even decide to use T-SQL for advanced analyses directly, without including R, Python, SSAS or Azure ML. However, to get the maximum out of these language constructs, you need to learn how to properly use them. This in-depth session shows extremely efficient statistical queries that use the window functions and are optimized through algorithms that use mathematical knowledge and creativity. During the session, the formulas and usage of those statistical procedures are explained as well. This session is useful not only for BI developers; database and other developers can successfully learn how to write efficient queries. Or maybe you want to become a data scientist? Then you need to know statistics and programming. You get the best of both in this session.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93722</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93722</id>
          <name>Christoph Seck</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>New York</name>
      </location>
      <title>Agile Data Warehousing</title>
      <description>Changing requirements, obscure sources, surprising successes - are DWH projects ideal candidates for agile approaches? It's not that easy. No matter if on-prem or “modern” with big data and on Azure: Fixed price requirements, challenging stakeholder setups, missing test cases and often the sheer size of the action, point in a different direction. So, what should be "agile" in DWH projects? And what are the actual benefits?

After a brief reminder of what makes BI / DWH projects "different", we first look at a practice-proven agile approach (test and backlog-driven, etc.). Extra bonbon: Agile projects  fixed price.
Afterwards the reality check: What exactly qualifies this process as "Agile”? Are there hidden waterfalls? And which advantages or risks are we dealing with?
We close with discussing how to adapt this to your specific projects and the old debate SCRUM versus Kanban.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94610</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94610</id>
          <name>Benni De Jagere</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>Redmond</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Dataflows? Why you need to implement it!</title>
      <description>Not so long ago, Power BI Dataflows have been added to the Power BI landscape. It is showing great promise, as they have the potential of becoming key in every (large) implementation of a Power BI or Hybrid BI Architecture.

During this session, the core concepts of Power BI Dataflows will be explained, and we'll discuss how Power BI Dataflows could alleviate some of the specific problems you might be experiencing in your current architecture.

How this feature ties into some other cool concepts, like Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 or the Common Data Model, obviously can't be missing from this speech.

Expect to walk out of this session with a decent grasp on the underlying architecture, and some key takeaways to take home with you.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95213</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95213</id>
          <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Washington</name>
      </location>
      <title>From Power BI to AI – Enrich your BI with Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <description>AI is everywhere – and now even included in Power BI. Sometimes AI might be very apparent when you enrich your data with predictions by explicitly calling an Azure Machine Learning web service in Power Query. Sometimes it might by hidden in a nice little context menu when Power BI is automagically explaining the reason of a difference or a change over time in your data to you.
No matter if you are a business user, analyst or data scientist – Power BI has AI capabilities tailored to you. In this session we will cover how you can integrate and leverage the use of language R, how to integrate an Azure Machine Learning Service when loading data, what kind of insights Power BI is capable of delivering automatically, how you can create a complex new column without typing a single formula/function, how you can explore your data by asking questions in plain English, ... and more!
Sounds like a lot of content? I omitted most of the slides in favour to spend the time in live demos instead.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96377</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96377</id>
          <name>Anna Hoffman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Chicago</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL in Azure: What to use When and How to Migrate</title>
      <description>Migrating SQL workloads to Azure can be a daunting task. In this session, you'll learn from the Microsoft Product Group about the different options for your SQL deployments in Azure. You’ll also learn about the tools and services that are available to help you assess, plan, and migrate your entire SQL Server stack. 

After this session, you should be able to: 
- Understand the benefits of SQL Server in Azure
- Articulate the key differentiators between SQL Server on-prem, in Azure VM, in Azure SQL DB (Single database, Elastic Pools, and Managed instance), and hybrid 
- Explain the different service tiers within Azure SQL DB, and evaluate what is best for your workloads and business requirements (Serverless, Hyperscale, General Purpose, Business Critical, etc)
- Understand the tools, processes, and partners available to migrate to Azure</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96162</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96162</id>
          <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Chicago</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server  Kubernetes</title>
      <description>Running SQL Server in containers has huge benefits for Data Platform professionals but there are challenges to running SQL Server in stand alone containers. Orchestrators provide a platform and the tools to overcome these challenges.

This session will provide an overview of running SQL Server in Kubernetes, which is the leading orchestrator.

Topics covered will be: -
An overview of Kubernetes.
Definition of pods and services.
Deploying SQL Server containers to Kubernetes.
Persisting data for SQL Server in Kubernetes.
An introduction to Helm
Chaos engineering for SQL Server in Kubernetes using Space Invaders!

This session is aimed at SQL Server DBAs and Developers who want to learn the what, the why, and the how to run SQL Server in Kubernetes.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94184</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94184</id>
          <name>Nico Jacobs</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Washington</name>
      </location>
      <title>Four questions machine learning can answer</title>
      <description>AI and machine learning are powerful tools! But as with all powerful tools you have to use them to solve the right problem: Even the most powerful hammer cannot do what a simple screwdriver can.

The aim of this talk is to help you identify business opportunities in which machine learning can help.
You will see four broad types of business problems for which machine learning can be the right tool for the job.

The next step will be to find answers to these questions. Azure provides many different ways to apply machine learning. In this session you will see demos of 4 different Azure services which can help you answer the questions: Cognitive services, ML Studio, SQL Server ML Services and Databricks.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96453</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96453</id>
          <name>André Kamman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>Redmond</name>
      </location>
      <title>ETL with Azure Databricks, The Complete Introduction</title>
      <description>Azure Databricks seems to be the new sheriff in town. It promises easy but capable ETL (amongst other things). But how does it work? For an SSIS (and possibly BIML) person this all looks new and strange. Python notebooks? Scala? Spark? What is all this, and where do I start? Well, you start by coming to this presentation. We’ll take a look at how to approach making an Azure Databricks based ETL solution from start to finish. Along the way it will become clear how Azure Databricks works and we will use our SSIS based ETL knowledge to see if it can handle the common use-cases from our daily jobs. And of course we will also have some fun and see how fast it can go!</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91119</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91119</id>
          <name>Ben Weissman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>New York</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Big Data Clusters</title>
      <description>Mit dem SQL Server 2019 bringt Microsoft in Form der Big Data Clusters neue Features für Daten Virtualisierung, Data Mart Scale-Out sowie Big Data Analysen. 

Was bedeutet das konkret? Wir schauen uns an, wie man die neuen Features installiert und nutzt, welchen Mehrwert sie bieten und wo man vielleicht dennoch mit anderen Funktionen besser aufgehoben ist.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99168</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99168</id>
          <name>Thomas Jorczik</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor/Lunch Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Chicago</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server high availability in cloud and hybrid environments</title>
      <description>SIOS Sponsor Session: Many believe that enterprise applications running in the public cloud are guaranteed to have high availability. But no cloud service provider currently guarantees uptime at the application level. There are, of course, ways to assure high availability for critical applications running in private, public and hybrid cloud environments. But that responsibility lies with the enterprise, not with the cloud service provider.

This session, presented by SIOS Technology, will highlight important information business and IT staff need to know to provide both high availability (HA) and disaster recovery (DR) protections for critical applications – and specifically SQL Server – running in public and hybrid cloud environments, as well as on-premise!</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98965</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98965</id>
          <name>Oleg Ulyanov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor/Lunch Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Redmond</name>
      </location>
      <title>VMWare Sponsor Session: Virtualizing SQL Server on vSphere</title>
      <description>Let us connect DBAs and Infrastructure Admins providing to DBAs vital information how to get best SQL Server deployment on top of VMware virtual platform. The session will cover both the design and the configuration of a SQL Server virtual machine with the special focus on:
•	vCPU allocation and deep dive in vNUMA
•	Memory allocation and configurations options
•	Storage configuration best practices including PMem/NFS/Snapshots
•	Network configuration myths and best practices

It all that you want to know about virtual platform configuration but hesitated to ask! Directly from the source with the ton of hands-on from VMware Professional Services.
BIO: Oleg Ulyanov is a Sr. Solutions Architect focused on Microsoft SQL Server workloads in the Cloud Platform Business Unit. He is a Subject Matter Expert in  virtualization, monitoring and performance tuning  of business critical applications workloads on VMware vSphere with tons of hands-on directly from customer sites.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94451</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94451</id>
          <name>Sascha Dittmann</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Washington</name>
      </location>
      <title>Von 0 auf 100 mit der Kusto Query Language (KQL)</title>
      <description>Die Kusto Query Language wird in verschiedenen Azure Diensten verwendet, wie beispielsweise Azure Log Explorer oder der Zeitreihendatenbank Azure Data Explorer (aka Kusto DB).
In dieser Session gibt Sascha Dittmann eine Einführung in die Abfragesprache. Dabei startet er mit den Grundlagen, spricht aber auch Fortgeschrittene Themen wie Machine Learning, Zeitreihenanalysen und das Zusammenspiel mit anderen Azure Diensten an.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99226</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99226</id>
          <name>Georg Gamsjäger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>Redmond</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Embedded with RLS Access to the on-prem Data Source</title>
      <description>In this session, I invite you to join me on a hike from the on-premise data source to the full Power BI Embedded sample solution. After a steep and long climb, we reach the summit from where we can enjoy the prospect of a complete Power BI Embedded sample solution with the non-domain users getting a Power BI report provided with them with row-level security on an on-premise data source and all without programming skills.

We start with an overview of the requirements for our Power BI Embedded sample solution, then we go to the question: "What is Power BI Embedded?". Next, we focus on how all components of our sample solution interact and configure in detail, and then we publish a first Power BI Report. Next, we want to prove that row-level security works and implement a solution for continuous monitoring. 

This is a 1-hour session that is a compact version of the Precon that was scheduled for 18.10.2019.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92912</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92912</id>
          <name>Jonathan Stewart</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>Redmond</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Visualization: How to truly tell a great story!</title>
      <description>We have more information available to us today than ever before. So much so that we run the risk of not being able to tell concise stories. There's a lot more to creating that story than just getting the correct information. Come learn not just the do's and don'ts, but the whys…</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 3:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 4:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93380</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93380</id>
          <name>Björn Peters</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Chicago</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Get Started with Azure Managed Instance</title>
      <description>This session will be about how to start with Azure Managed Instances and what you'll need to know before.

Showing and explaining how you to steer around all the cliffs and make sure everything works smoothly.

It is about the features and why it might save you costs and make the life of your admin much easier by using Azure Managed Instances. Showing how to deploy, connect and migrate your application data. 
After this session, you'll understand this great database a bit better and know how to deploy it via portal and Powershell and why it a step ahead.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99223</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99223</id>
          <name>Erik Monchen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor/Lunch Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>Washington</name>
      </location>
      <title>DYMATRIX: Die Data-Plattform im Kampagnenmgt und Marketing-Umfeld</title>
      <description>In dieser DYMATRIX Sponsor-Session werden diese Themen besprochen:
Was ist Kampagnenmanagement und wie kann ich es einsetzen?
Wo kann die Data-Plattform unterstützen? (Real-Life-Beispiele)
- AI mit Phyton in der Datenbank
- Einfacher Zugriff auf externe Daten mit Polybase
- Cloud-Szenarien mit Azure-Data-Factory und Databricks</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95528</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95528</id>
          <name>Benjamin Kettner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>New York</name>
      </location>
      <title>Der Klotz zeigt Dir den Weg - ins Internet of Legos</title>
      <description>Nachdem Robbi der Lego-Roboter auf dem SQL Saturday im Rheinland seinen Freund Damon wiedergefunden hat, hat er sich überlegt, wie er ein solches Desaster in Zukunft vermeiden kann. Natürlich hat der schlaue Roboter dafür eine Lösung gefunden, wie er mit Hilfe der Cloud immer auf dem richtigen Weg bleibt. Diese Lösung möchten wir euch zeigen. 
Unser Vortrag enthält Lego, LabView, Azure und künstliche Intelligenz. Wie das Zusammenspiel dieser Komponenten funktioniert, zeigen wir in unserer IoT Demo in der Session.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96359</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96359</id>
          <name>Buck Woody</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>New York</name>
      </location>
      <title>Presentation Skills for the Technical Professional</title>
      <description>Communication is one of the most important skills in business – whether it’s presenting to your peers on a technical topic or making the complex understandable for a more general audience, it takes great skill to deliver a compelling presentation. In this session, Buck Woody will show you how to create a great presentation. This session is based on a full-day workshop, and you'll learn (right from the start) how to get hands-on and learn from Buck and your peers on how to select a compelling topic, research and deliver a great session. It’s an action-packed hour of useful information and practice that will prepare you to present at events from user groups to professional associations.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96461</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96461</id>
          <name>Oliver Engels</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>New York</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Quality Round-trip in the MS Dataplatform 2019</title>
      <description>Do you need a Data Quality Solution? Do you work with Data Quality Services (DQS) or Master Data Services (MDS)? Are you interested what the Microsoft Data Platform has to offer in addition? We will show, based on various demos, how you can leverage Machine Learning Services, Common Data Model, Azure Data Factory, SQL Server 2019, and more to solve data quality problems.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96719</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96719</id>
          <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>Redmond</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hybrid Power BI - What is possible? What do you need?</title>
      <description>Power BI as a cloud-based SaaS solution is not limited to cloud data sources. In many projects, hybrid architectures are the key to successful projects using already existing infrastructure. 
Besides the on-premises data gateway, there are additional options how a hybrid approach can bring benefits and lead to better solutions.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 2:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 3:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98781</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98781</id>
          <name>Ben Weissman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Sponsor/Lunch Session</track>
      <location>
        <name>New York</name>
      </location>
      <title>Das super nerdige Solisyon Quiz</title>
      <description>Das super nerdige Solisyon Quiz</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95010</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95010</id>
          <name>Thomas Martens</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>Washington</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Charticulator - How to create No-Code Power BI custom visuals</title>
      <description>Charticulator (https://charticulator.com/) a Microsoft research project, enables you to create amazing custom visuals for Power BI without writing any line of code. Charticulator allows you to focus on the data without the need to split your attention between the design and a programming language. This demo packed session focus on the design process and the creation of selected charts. All data used during this session will be available via a GitHub repo with a detailed explanation of how to recreate the examples.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 2:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 3:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94883</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94883</id>
          <name>Bob Ward</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Chicago</name>
      </location>
      <title>Inside SQL Server Containers</title>
      <description>Containers are the new virtual machines. Containers present a new way to deploy, manage, and run SQL Server never possible before. This session will present an internal view of how Docker containers work and how SQL Server runs in them. Will cover the architecture of containers, how we have built SQL Server to run in containers, and how they work in environments such as Kubernetes. While this is an internal focused session you will walk away with knowledge of practical scenarios where SQL Server in Containers may be the right deployment model for you.</description>
      <startTime>10/19/2019 2:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/19/2019 3:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>