<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #222 - Sacramento 2013</name>
    <startDate>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>400</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-08:00) Pacific Time (US and Canada); Tijuana</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat222</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Patrick Hays Learning Center</name>
      <street>2700 Gateway Oaks Drive, Suite 2600</street>
      <city>Sacramento</city>
      <state>California</state>
      <zipcode>95833</zipcode>
      <longitude>-121.515327</longitude>
      <latitude>38.615985</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1</importID>
      <name>Confio</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.confio.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/resized-confio_logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1011</importID>
      <name>Robert Half International</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.roberthalftechnology.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/SQLSaturday/EventSponsors/RHT_Logo_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>560</importID>
      <name>DesignMind</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.designmind.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/files/b6ce27b4-6c94-4aae-b936-df92b6e0711a.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>6</importID>
      <name>Melissa Data Corp.</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.melissadata.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/931/EventSponsor_14597.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>772</importID>
      <name>Kaminario</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.kaminario.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/39c8496e-246b-4f5a-a6ea-17eae02987fc.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>225</importID>
      <name>OCZ Technology</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://ocz.com/enterprise</url>
      <imageURL>https://ocz.com/images/logo_ocze_blue.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>45</importID>
      <name>Cozy Roc</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.cozyroc.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.cozyroc.com/sites/default/files/down/cozyroc-big.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>7</importID>
      <name>SIOS Technology</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://us.sios.com/company/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/956/EventSponsor_14655.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>13</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/sqlsaturday/eventsponsors/Quest_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>48</importID>
      <name>Nimble Storage</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.nimblestorage.com/</url>
      <imageURL>
      </imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24494</importID>
      <name>Steve Jones</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Jones is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and has been working with SQL Server since version 4.2 on OS/2. After working as a DBA and developer for a variety of companies, Steve co-founded the community website SQLServerCentral.com in 2001.
Since 2004, Steve has been the full-time editor of the site, ensuring it continues to be a great resource for SQL Server professionals. Over the last decade, Steve has written hundreds of articles about SQL Server for SQLServerCentral.com, SQL Server Standard magazine, SQL Server Magazine, and Database Journal.</description>
      <twitter>way0utwest</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/way0utwest</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.voiceofthedba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=way0utwest</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10253</importID>
      <name>Ben Miller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben has been a member of the SQL Server Community since 2000. He loves a challenge and has fixed many SQL Servers and helped hundreds of people get more out of their DBA jobs.  He is a Data Platform MVP a SQL Server Certified Master (MCM). He has worked at various companies throughout the USA, as well as at Microsoft for 7 years. He is passionate about SQL Server Infrastructure, High Availability, Automation and Integration using SMO and PowerShell. He teaches DBAs how to use PowerShell to do their job and teaches SQL Server Internals. He is @DBAduck all around the web (Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, Blog) so let's catch up.</description>
      <twitter>DBAduck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dbaduck/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbaduck.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAduck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15713</importID>
      <name>Janis Griffin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Janis Griffin has over 30 years of DBA/database experience including design, development and implementation of many critical database applications. Before coming to Quest Software, Janis primarily worked in the Telecom/Network Industry, working with both real-time network routing databases and OLTP business to business applications.  Janis also held positions as a Principal Architect and Senior Manager, mentoring other DBAs on best practices in database performance tuning.</description>
      <twitter>DoBoutAnything</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/janis-griffin/0/914/aba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DoBoutAnything</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10250</importID>
      <name>Ben Miller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben has been a member of the SQL Server Community since 2000. He loves a challenge and has fixed many SQL Servers and helped hundreds of people get more out of their DBA jobs.  He is a Data Platform MVP a SQL Server Certified Master (MCM). He has worked at various companies throughout the USA, as well as at Microsoft for 7 years. He is passionate about SQL Server Infrastructure, High Availability, Automation and Integration using SMO and PowerShell. He teaches DBAs how to use PowerShell to do their job and teaches SQL Server Internals. He is @DBAduck all around the web (Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, Blog) so let's catch up.</description>
      <twitter>DBAduck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dbaduck/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbaduck.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAduck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9765</importID>
      <name>Argenis Fernandez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Argenis is a Principal Architect at Pure Storage. He works with customers around the world to make sure they don’t have to worry much about their infrastructure for Data.
He is a former Data Platform MVP, former VMware vExpert, Microsoft Certified Master, and more recently worked in the Microsoft Azure Data/SQL Server engineering team as a Principal PM in the Tiger team.</description>
      <twitter>DBArgenis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/argenis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.purestorage.com/author/argenisfernandez/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBArgenis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24949</importID>
      <name>Dan Hess</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dan has been in IT for the last 18 years, graduating from California State University, Chico with a computer science degree.  He#39;s been focused on SQL Server since 2007 when he was given the quot;accidental DBAquot; title.  After learning to swim in the deep end and moving jobs to Sacramento, he saw the need to help others who were in a similar position and helped to form the Sacramento SQL Server user group.   Database administration is his primary focus.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLDCH</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dan-hess-a789764</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.expressnetsolutions.com/sqldch</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLDCH</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34803</importID>
      <name>Michael Fal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mike is a specialist in data management technologies. As a community advocate, public speaker, and blogger, Mike is a practicing thought leader for data and automation. He is passionate about DevOps and data, building platforms to optimize, protect, and use data efficiently.

Since 1999, Mike has been working in the database field, focusing primarily on SQL Server and specializes in automating data solutions to improve the reliability and efficiency of his environments. He has been caught playing trombone in public on more than one occasion.</description>
      <twitter>@Mike_Fal</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelfal/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mikefal.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Mike_Fal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27397</importID>
      <name>Vicky Harp</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vicky Harp is the Group PM Manager for the SQL Server Tools Team, which is responsible for the full set of experiences from drivers and scripting libraries, to GUI tools, to the Azure Portal. She has been building tools for SQL Server for 15 years.</description>
      <twitter>vickyharp</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://vickyharp.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=vickyharp</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16212</importID>
      <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joseph D'Antoni is a Senior Consultant and Microsoft Data Platform MVP with over 20 years of experience working in both Fortune 500 and smaller firms. He is a Principal Consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates and lives in Malvern, PA. He is a frequent speaker at major tech events like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and Enterprise Data World. He blogs about all topics technology at joeydantoni.com. He believes that no single platform is the answer to all technology problems. Joseph holds a BS in Computer Information Systems from Louisiana Tech University and an MBA from North Carolina State University, and is the co-author of the Microsoft book "Introducing SQL Server 2016”.</description>
      <twitter>jdanton</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=3997984amp;trk=hb_tab_pro_top</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://joeydantoni.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jdanton</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21959</importID>
      <name>Peter Myers</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Myers is a consultant, trainer and presenter, and has worked with Microsoft database and development products since 1997. Today he specializes in all Microsoft Business Intelligence products and also authors training course content for Microsoft products and services.

He has a broad business background supported by a bachelor’s degree in applied economics and accounting, and he extends this with extensive experience backed by current MCSE certifications. He has been a Data Platform MVP since 2007.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/peterjsmyers</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12126</importID>
      <name>DIlip nayak</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dilip works as a Senior DBA at a financial services company. His specialization is in SQL performance tuning, high availability, and database administration. He has over 18 years of IT experience starting as a VB/.NET developer and has been working with SQL for the past 9 years.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21832</importID>
      <name>Paul Turley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul is a Principal Consultant for Pragmatic Works, a Mentor and Microsoft Data Platform MVP. He consults, writes, speaks, teaches  blogs about business intelligence and reporting solutions. He works with companies around the world to model data, visualize and deliver critical information to make informed business decisions; using the Microsoft data platform and business analytics tools. He is a Director of the Oregon Data Community PASS chapter  user group, the author  and lead author of Professional SQL Server 2016 Reporting Services and 14 other titles from Wrox  Microsoft Press.  He holds several certifications including MCSE for the Data Platform and BI.</description>
      <twitter>paul_turley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pturley</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserverbiblog.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=paul_turley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22276</importID>
      <name>Prakash Heda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Prakash Heda works as Manager (Data-IT) at SSC Advent. His expertise encompasses the work of automation, performance tuning/troubleshooting, high availability, san configuration and windows administration.  Heda has 13+ years of experience managing enterprise-wide data needs in both high volume transactional and data warehouse environments. Heda holds certifications for MCDBA and MCITP. His background includes administration  development using VB/ASP/SSIS with SQL server 2000 to 2017. He is an active member of PASS, SQLSaturday, and as well a frequent presenter at user groups, SQLSaturdays, and other community events. He is also an avid tweeter, blogger and runner.</description>
      <twitter>@prakashheda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/prakash-heda/8/a60/b77</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlfeatures.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@prakashheda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9659</importID>
      <name>Angel Abundez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Angel leads the Solutions Architecture team at DesignMind, helping design and build world class data-related systems. His expertise includes Microsoft SQL Server BI tools, Power BI, Azure-based database services, and Tableau. His team develops Proofs of Concept, Pilots, and highly scalable production systems. Angel co-leads the Bay Area Microsoft Business Intelligence User Group and the San Francisco Power BI User Group. He speaks at Data Analytics events throughout the U.S. and writes for SQL Server Central. He is a graduate of Cal Poly SLO with a BS in Mechanical Engineering.</description>
      <twitter>AngelStreamline</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedIn.com/in/angelstreamline</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://angelstreamline.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AngelStreamline</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20832</importID>
      <name>Mitchell Bottel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mitchell Bottel is a senior database administrator with Sutter Physician Services, owner of Innovative IT Consulting and President of the Sacramento SQL Sevrer User Group. He has 14 years of IT experience, focusing on SQL Server for the last ten years with an emphasis on database administration and high availability solutions. He has authored blog posts on the SQLServerPerformance website and written White Papers on using Dynamic Management Views.</description>
      <twitter>@SacSQLDude</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mitchespitch.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SacSQLDude</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24947</importID>
      <name>Phil Robinson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Phil Robinson is an independent consultant focused on developing Business Intelligence solutions using Microsoft Reporting Services and Power BI. He is founder of the San Diego SQL Business Intelligence Group and co-founder of SQL Saturday – San Diego.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12548</importID>
      <name>David Klee</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Klee is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware vExpert with a lifelong passion for technology. David spends his days focusing on the convergence of data and infrastructure as the Founder of Heraflux Technologies. His areas of expertise include cloud, virtualization, performance, and business continuity. David speaks at a number of national and regional technology related events, including PASS Summit, VMware VMworld, SQLBits, SQL Saturday events, and many SQL Server User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>kleegeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidaklee</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://davidklee.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kleegeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11338</importID>
      <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Bossy (MCTS, MCP BI, CBIP) is a data and cloud analytics architect with 25 years of experience in software and database development. As a principal of Datalere, Carlos focuses on developing BI, Data Science, and Advanced Analytics solutions, including modeling data warehouses and delivering predictive models, integration, and visualization. He has developed warehouses and BI solutions for a variety of industries and state agencies, including health insurance, solar energy, foster care, telecom, and manufacturing.</description>
      <twitter>@carlosbossy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin/in/carlosbossy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.carlosbossy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@carlosbossy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20136</importID>
      <name>Mark Gschwind</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Gschwind is VP of Business Intelligence at DesignMind, a Microsoft Gold consulting partner based in San Francisco.  He has been a BI Consultant since 1995, implementing Data Warehousing, OLAP, Reporting and Data Mining solutions to over 46 clients. He is an MCP and is certified in Oracle Essbase.  He has presented MDS to other SQL Saturday events, as well as local PASS chapters.  He has been using MDS since 2008 and has also used DQS on numerous client engagements.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12547</importID>
      <name>David Klee</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Klee is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware vExpert with a lifelong passion for technology. David spends his days focusing on the convergence of data and infrastructure as the Founder of Heraflux Technologies. His areas of expertise include cloud, virtualization, performance, and business continuity. David speaks at a number of national and regional technology related events, including PASS Summit, VMware VMworld, SQLBits, SQL Saturday events, and many SQL Server User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>kleegeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidaklee</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://davidklee.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kleegeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34837</importID>
      <name>John Morehouse</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Morehouse is currently a Database Architect/Engineer with Farm Credit Services of America in Omaha, Nebraska. He is one of the leaders of the Omaha SQL/BI User group and and a frequent speaker at SQL Saturday's as well as other conferences. In his spare time, you can find John running after one of his two sons or working on his 113 year old house. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlrus.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16802</importID>
      <name>Jim Murphy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jim Murphy has been using Microsoft SQL Server since version 6.0 back in the 90#39;s. He is the CEO of SQLWatchmen, LLC., a managed DBA service provider. He runs the Austin SQL Server User Group: CACTUSS Central. He has been a professional DBA and developer for over 25 years and has run a consulting company full time since 2001.</description>
      <twitter>http://www.twitter.com/sqlmurph</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlwatchmen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlwatchmen.com/blogs/jim/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://www.twitter.com/sqlmurph</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17486</importID>
      <name>Joseph Verftido</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A Data Quality Analyst at Melissa Data, Joseph has worked with numerous clients in understanding their business needs for data quality, analyzing their architecture and environment, and recommending strategic solutions to successfully integrate data quality within their infrastructure. He gives frequent webinars for implementing different techniques for data quality and also manages the MVP Program – a network that provides resources to community leaders, speakers, consultants and other experts.</description>
      <twitter>/melissadata</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/company/melissa-data</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.melissadata.com/data-quality-authority/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=/melissadata</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20385</importID>
      <name>Mickey Stuewe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mickey Stuewe has been working with SQL Server since 6.5. That gives her over 20 years of experience. She has not only been a database developer, but also an application developer, even before Visual Studio existed. She is now thankful to be focusing on database design, t-SQL development, and query optimization. She also has a habit of enjoying SSIS and data warehouse design.

She blogs regularly on her website mickeystuewe.com and contributes to sites such as SQL Server Central and SQL Server Pro. She enjoys presenting at PASS Summit, SQL Saturdays, User Groups and other events.

When she is not immersed in SQL related activities, she enjoys action movies, art, reading, and laughing. She laughs loudly and often...just ask her children.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLMickey</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/mickeystuewe/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.MickeyStuewe.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLMickey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17544</importID>
      <name>Tom Riggins</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sr. Systems Engineer with Nimble Storage</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11553</importID>
      <name>Chris Skorlinski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Skorlinski has been with Microsoft for 17 years. He is a Support Escalation Engineer at the Microsoft Charlotte NC office specializing in performance tuning and troubleshooting Replication. His is a contributor to SQLShare.com training as well as his own BLOGs on Replication Performance at http://blogs.msdn.com/ReplTalk/. 
#160;</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25742</importID>
      <name>Steve Stedman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Stedman is the Leader of a PASS Local Group in Bellingham WA USA. Steve runs his own SQL consulting firm Stedman Solutions, LLC. He has 29 years of programming and SQL experience.  He has written the book on SQL Common Table Expressions.  He teaches, speaks at conferences, writes, and has taught SQL server classes at Western Washington University.  Steve has previously spoken at PASS Summit, TechEd, DevTeach Vancouver, many SQL Saturdays, and more.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlemt</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stevestedman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SteveStedman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlemt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14743</importID>
      <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Grant Fritchey is a Data Platform MVP with over 20 years’ experience in IT, including time spent in support and development. He has worked with SQL Server since 6.0 back in 1995. He has also developed in VB, VB.NET, C#, and Java. Grant has written books for Apress and Simple-Talk. Grant presents at conferences and user groups, large and small, all over the world. He joined Redgate Software as a product evangelist in January 2011.</description>
      <twitter>@gfritchey</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/scarydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://scarydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@gfritchey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25744</importID>
      <name>Steve Stedman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Stedman is the Leader of a PASS Local Group in Bellingham WA USA. Steve runs his own SQL consulting firm Stedman Solutions, LLC. He has 29 years of programming and SQL experience.  He has written the book on SQL Common Table Expressions.  He teaches, speaks at conferences, writes, and has taught SQL server classes at Western Washington University.  Steve has previously spoken at PASS Summit, TechEd, DevTeach Vancouver, many SQL Saturdays, and more.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlemt</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stevestedman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SteveStedman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlemt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17844</importID>
      <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kalen Delaney is a Data Platform MVP who has worked with SQL Server for more than 32 years. She has provided performance consulting services and taught advanced courses on SQL Server to thousands of people and organizations. In addition to her courseware development, Kalen has been writing about SQL Server for decades. She is the primary author of SQL Server Internals and the Inside SQL Server series. Kalen is also one of the primary editors for the Red Gate SQL Server Stairways tutorials.</description>
      <twitter>sqlqueen</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlqueen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15882</importID>
      <name>Jason Hall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jason Hall is a systems consultant at Dell Software (formally Quest Software) specializing in assisting customers solve complex SQL Server problems.  </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.quest.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11556</importID>
      <name>Chris Skorlinski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Skorlinski has been with Microsoft for 17 years. He is a Support Escalation Engineer at the Microsoft Charlotte NC office specializing in performance tuning and troubleshooting Replication. His is a contributor to SQLShare.com training as well as his own BLOGs on Replication Performance at http://blogs.msdn.com/ReplTalk/. 
#160;</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25743</importID>
      <name>Steve Stedman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Stedman is the Leader of a PASS Local Group in Bellingham WA USA. Steve runs his own SQL consulting firm Stedman Solutions, LLC. He has 29 years of programming and SQL experience.  He has written the book on SQL Common Table Expressions.  He teaches, speaks at conferences, writes, and has taught SQL server classes at Western Washington University.  Steve has previously spoken at PASS Summit, TechEd, DevTeach Vancouver, many SQL Saturdays, and more.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlemt</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stevestedman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SteveStedman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlemt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>15882</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15882</id>
          <name>Jason Hall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Quest/Dell Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Lunch Session  Dell Software Solutions for SQL Server - Free Tools!!!</title>
      <description>This lunch session will serve to introduce the audience to high level challenges that face SQL Server DBA's, and how third party solutions can help.  Specific examples and use cases will be provided to demonstrate Dell Software solutions.  Specific challenges are Performance Management, Query Optimization and Tuning, and Backup and Recovery will be discussed.  The session will wrap up with a demonstration of Dell's freeware offerings for SQL Server, providing all attendee's with software they can take with them to immediately assist with complex and time consuming database problems.Tools to be discussed:Spotlight on SQL Server EnterprisePerformance Analysis for SQL ServerLiteSpeed for SQL ServerToad for SQL Server - FreewareProject Lucy - Freeware</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20136</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20136</id>
          <name>Mark Gschwind</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Nimble Storage Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Master Data and Data Quality in SQL Server 2012</title>
      <description>A recent survey by Information Week found that data quality is the greatest barrier to BI adoption in enterprises.  MDS addresses this challenge with modeling, validation, alerting and security capabilities.  In this presentation, you will learn how to use MDS to model your data to ensure correctness, update it with changes from your ERP, and create workflows with notifications.  Next you will learn the capabilities of DQS and see how it addresses data standardization, completeness and other challenges.  You will then see how to use them together to enable Enterprise Information Management.  BI professionals will come away with knowledge on how to use tools that address the greatest risk to success for BI projects - data quality.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22276</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22276</id>
          <name>Prakash Heda</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Quest/Dell Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Detect Worst Performing SQL Queries During Peak Hour</title>
      <description>How many times you have been thrown in a situation when you have been asked to fix performance issues of a database system which you have never seen before? Where do you start tuning? When do you stop tuning? Each application is different. With the ever increasing number of systems one production DBA has to manage today, it's very important to use TOP to BOTTOM approach to troubleshoot performance issues, which will lead to the answers in the right way for the application under consideration. 

While you can find top queries, wouldn't it be awesome if you can find out which ones are the exact queries taking most of the resources in last hour and current situation? Now you can focus on those specific queries!

In this session, Prakash walks you through with scenario  demos to find which exact queries are taxing production systems resources based on CPU/DISK/Memory/Network. They are all based on his own real-life experience from managing demanding database systems.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24949</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24949</id>
          <name>Dan Hess</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server encryption 3 ways - in transit, at rest and in the database</title>
      <description>Dude, where's my keys??!?!

Confused about the various ways SQL Server handles encryption? Tasked with securing your environment or trying to pass an audit? There's a lot of information that can be difficult to wade through. In this session, I'll go over three ways to encrypt SQL Server, showing practical examples of the various techniques. We'll look at encrypting the information at the network level (in transit), encrypting the data and backup files (at rest using Transparent Data Encryption) and encryption of sensitive information in the database (columns and stored procedures). 

This will be a high level, hands-on discussion that will enable any administrator to put the techniques discussed into practice immediately.  You'll see how encryption will fit into your overall security scheme.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10250</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10250</id>
          <name>Ben Miller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Nimble Storage Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SMO Internals for High Performance PowerShell</title>
      <description>Ever wanted to know what happens in SQL Server when you use PowerShell and SMO to manage a SQL Server?  How fast can your automation really go? I will take you through the most common objects in SMO and the internals of what happens when you use those objects. We will examine the TSQL that is generated, and learn techniques that lead to high efficiency.  We will dive deep through the collections that make SMO the powerful tool it is. Combining the flexibility of PowerShell and SMO Internals is a recipe for awesome sauce.  Come peek behing the curtain and squeeze the speed out of your automation scripts using PowerShell and SMO.  You'll be glad you did.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20832</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20832</id>
          <name>Mitchell Bottel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Nimble Storage Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Want a promotion? It’s up to you!</title>
      <description>Self-promotion is often times the best promotion you can get. In this session, we will talk about how to promote yourself, your brand and your career without looking like “That Guy”. We will discuss Social Medias, communities, volunteering and other ways to get your name out… What are the first steps? Come find out.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>12126</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12126</id>
          <name>DIlip nayak</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Quest/Dell Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>AlwaysOn Availability Groups in Action</title>
      <description>SQL 2012 AlwaysOn Availability Groups is a new unified High availability(HA) and disaster recovery(DR) solution introduced in SQL 2012.  This solution is an answer to both HA and DR requirements that is flexible, integrated, and easy to deploy. You'll see a demo that includes: •Setting up the Availability Group •Setting up multiple secondaries •Manual Failover •Automated Failover •AG Listener •and much more... You'll learn: •How to set up, manage, and maintain Availability groups in SQL 2012 •Create availability group failovers between data centers •How to utilize the replicas for backup and other tasks</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17486</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17486</id>
          <name>Joseph Verftido</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Red Gate Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Quality Services Approach to Cleansing</title>
      <description>Learn about Microsoft’s Data Quality Services (DQS), what it is and how it works. You will discover how DQS sets itself apart from conventional data cleansing routines and go through examples on how to begin your own Data Quality Project which includes data cleansing and deduplication. But what really makes DQS unique and powerful is its ability to access shared knowledge, so we will show you how to access and use this shared knowledge to your benefit</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9659</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9659</id>
          <name>Angel Abundez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Quest/Dell Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>5 Ways SSIS 2012 can Save You Time and Money</title>
      <description>Integration Services in SQL Server 2012 gives DBAs and BI developers new features that save time and money in terms of development and management. Whether you're automating DBA tasks, ETL processes, or System Integrations, SSIS has something for everyone. 

Come learn about:

-Improvements in the design interface 
-SSIS Parameters 
-Easier Deployment with the SSIS Catalog 
-New Standard Reports for monitoring SSIS 
-New ways to control SSIS on the server. 

If you're on SQL Server 2008, not to worry. I will show you an additional 3rd party tool that gives you a lot of this functionality. But nothing beats the ROI with SSIS 2012.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11556</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11556</id>
          <name>Chris Skorlinski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SIOS Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Read Hunter</title>
      <description>Are you suffering from High CPU, Low Memory, Query Timeouts, Decreasing Page Life Expectancy, CXPACKET Waits, or just a slow running application?  I'll show you how to become a "Read Hunter" to track down top logical reads queries bringing down your SQL Server performance.
</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17544</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17544</id>
          <name>Tom Riggins</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Nimble Storage Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Lunch Session  Accelerating SQL in the Datacenter with Hybrid Storage</title>
      <description>The leading edge Hybrid storage technology can significantly impact SQL application performance by providing Cache Accelerated IOPS at extremely low solid state latency.  In this session you’ll learn:·         How hybrid storage architecture benefits datacenter applications·         What are the SAN features that can accelerate data protection and recovery operations·         Instant and zero space re-purposing tools that have minimal to no disk overhead·         SQL application integration</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15713</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15713</id>
          <name>Janis Griffin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Nimble Storage Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Looney Tuner?  No, there IS a method to my madness</title>
      <description>SQL Server query tuning is often more art than science and it can quickly eat up a lot of DBA and/or Developer time. This presentation will outline a method for determining the best approach for tuning queries by utilizing response time analysis and SQL diagramming techniques. Regardless of the complexity of the statement, this quick, systematic approach will lead you down the correct tuning path with no guessing. If you are a beginner or expert, this approach will save you countless hours tuning a query.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11338</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11338</id>
          <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SIOS Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Real-time Data Warehouse and Reporting Solutions</title>
      <description>In this demo-rich session, we will explore database and ETL architectures that let you smoothly move data from your application databases across the enterprise in real-time to your data warehouse. You will see how to use SQL Server features such as replication, Change Data Capture, SSIS, and other techniques to extract, transform, and load data fast and dependably. We will develop an actual sample system during the session and discuss and walk through alternative real-time architectures. We will then see how to use Reporting Services to present data with a minimum amount of latency.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21959</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21959</id>
          <name>Peter Myers</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Red Gate Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data Analytics with PowerPivot and Power View</title>
      <description>This presentation will introduce big data analytics for the business analyst with PowerPivot and Power View. It will be of interest to those new to the concept of big data, new to self-service data modelling with PowerPivot, and those interested to understand what is new for PowerPivot and Power View in Excel 2013.

Demonstrations will include creating a big data solution by using HDInsight Server; producing a PowerPivot model based on the big data solution; using PowerPivot to integrate big data with local data; and, analyzing the PowerPivot model data by using Power View.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14743</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14743</id>
          <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Red Gate Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>What to Look for in Execution Plans</title>
      <description>You've heard often enough that you need to look at execution plans to understand what's going on with a query. But what are you supposed to look at? This session answers that question, providing a step-by-step set of considerations for evaluating your execution plans. We'll look at the aspects of an execution plan that should be immediately checked, why they should be checked, and provide some guidance for what to do about what you find. You'll be able to apply this information to your SQL Server 2012 systems as well as older versions of SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>12547</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12547</id>
          <name>David Klee</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Nimble Storage Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>It's All About the Performance, Right?</title>
      <description>Just about anyone can click through a SQL Server installation and get it working. But, it is not running close to efficient, and as the workloads grow, it will only get worse. This session by David Klee (@kleegeek) provides valuable details on how to tweak and tune your SQL Server installations to ensure maximum performance, as well as tips on capacity management so you know when you need to add more hardware to take your server to the next level.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24947</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24947</id>
          <name>Phil Robinson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SIOS Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Report Delivery - From Report Manager to the Cloud</title>
      <description>SQL Server Reporting Services Report Manager provides a great web platform for managing and delivering many types of reports. We will review delivering reports with Report Manager and explore integrating SSRS as the engine for report presentation within web and windows applications. We will also look at  options to feed reports to your document management system and push reports to the cloud for remote access and mobile devices.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34803</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34803</id>
          <name>Michael Fal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Managing Log File Obesity</title>
      <description>Have your efforts to trim a few pounds off your log file been met with frustration? Are you scratching your head on why that DBCC SHRINKFILE doesn’t seem to do anything?  Log file obesity is a problem that can challenge DBAs of any level.  This session will help you deal with your overweight database by covering how log files grow, why truncating the log is a bad idea, and what you can do to keep your files trim and fit.  </description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27397</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27397</id>
          <name>Vicky Harp</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Care and Feeding of Your System Databases</title>
      <description>Master, model, msdb, tempdb. You see them on all of your servers, but what do you really know about them? If you ever wanted to learn about the SQL Server system databases, their purpose, and the maintenance and configuration required to keep your server running its best, then this session is for you! Learn best practices and techniques, including how to restore master and how to configure tempdb to reduce contention. You'll leave with a better understanding of these shared resources and how they affect your database applications.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16212</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16212</id>
          <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Quest/Dell Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Compression to Improve Database Performance</title>
      <description>Back in the old days, compression and databases was a really bad idea. Now, with powerful CPUs we can use to both improve performance and save disk space. We will cover the basics of how all compression and deduplication works, and then we will learn how SQL Server page and row compression work, and the special compression that is used in SQL 2012 Columnstore Indexes. We will demo performance and space savings in using compression.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9765</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9765</id>
          <name>Argenis Fernandez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SIOS Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Code-Less Securing of SQL Server</title>
      <description>Learn from a Microsoft Certified Master how to secure your SQL Server
 infrastructure and your Windows installations to enhance resiliency
 and minimize exposure to attacks—all without touching any of your
 code!</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34837</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34837</id>
          <name>John Morehouse</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Databaseology 201</title>
      <description>Did you love "Bill Nye, the Science Guy" when you were a kid? Or maybe you were a MacGyver fan?  Did you take apart your Mom's toaster or your Dad's alarm clock just to see how it ticked? Ever wonder how that database you built or support works behind the scenes? SQL Server Databaseology 201 is the science concerned with the study of SQL Server databases and their structures.  This session will explore some of the deep inner workings of a SQL Server databases. The attendee will walk away with a deeper understanding of how SQL Server databases work which would allow them to build better and faster databases.  </description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11553</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11553</id>
          <name>Chris Skorlinski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Red Gate Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>RU Ready for the Cloud?</title>
      <description>Ready to begin your first SQL Database application?  Wondering what others have learned as the moved data into the cloud?  I'll cover best practices you'll need while planning your move to SQL Database in the cloud.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16802</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16802</id>
          <name>Jim Murphy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Quest/Dell Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>AlwaysOn - Finally, A usable 'mirror'!</title>
      <description>In the past, High Availability and Disaster Recovery (HADR) had many limitations. Clustering and Mirroring are great, but the mirror/secondary database is not very usable since it is not online.  Finally, AlwaysOn solves this limitation by merging both multi-node Clustering and mirroring. AlwaysOn also allows the secondary database to remain ONLINE, so we can use it for reporting purposes without resorting to a Snapshot!  Come see this lively session with extensive demos of setting up, configuring and testing AlwaysOn. We'll also test automatic fail-over using a real web app to see how well this feature works.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>12548</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12548</id>
          <name>David Klee</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Squeezing Performance from VMware-Based SQL Server</title>
      <description>Sure, your SQL Server is up and running. Anyone can click through a SQL Server install nowadays. But... is it running at its peak potential? Do you have your VMware environment configured properly? Have you measured the performance lately? Your business-critical SQL Server performance does not have to suffer just because it was virtualized. Very specific VMware and SQL Server tuning tips and tricks from David Klee (@kleegeek) will be presented in this session.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21832</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21832</id>
          <name>Paul Turley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Red Gate Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tabular Models: Easier  Faster Than Cubes; Really?</title>
      <description>The future of data analysis is the new, in-memory xVelocity Tabular analytic engine but is this new product ready for enterprise solutions?  Is it easier to build Tabular models than multidimensional cubes in SQL Server 2012?  Maybe…  Depends on what you need to do.  Is it faster?  Heck, yea.  Taking off the Microsoft BI marketing hat, let’s take a tabular journey together and learn some lessons from the first generation of real, enterprise-scale solutions: The Good, the Bad, the Ugly and the Beautiful.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25743</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25743</id>
          <name>Steve Stedman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Red Gate Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Lunch Session  A Day in the Life of a DBA</title>
      <description>Maybe your job consists of setting up security and dealing with backups. Maybe you're a DBA who supports multiple teams in development, QA, and production. Or maybe your day is spent attending meetings, setting up new servers, designing new apps, supporting old apps, and dealing with the myriad sources of pain that make up the daily life of most DBAs. This entertaining lunch-time session explains how Red Gate's tools can take the pain out of the difficult, time-consuming tasks you face each day.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25744</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25744</id>
          <name>Steve Stedman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SIOS Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Lunch Session  High Performance SANLess Clustering</title>
      <description>Powered by Fusion-io, Protected by SIOS: Learn how to eliminate the bottlenecks and costs of SAN-based clustering. Leverage the performance of high-speed Fusion ioMemory and achieve higher levels of availability with SIOS. It is the best of both worlds - performance and protection – at a price you can afford. Join us and you could win a $100 American Express gift card. </description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20385</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20385</id>
          <name>Mickey Stuewe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SIOS Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Table Partitioning in the Wild</title>
      <description>In this session we'll talk about the why and how of table partitioning. Expect to leave with real world scripts to help you create, breakdown, and manage your partitioned tables.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24494</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24494</id>
          <name>Steve Jones</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Red Gate Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Searching Binary Data in SQL Server 2012</title>
      <description>More and more data collected in organizations is in an encoded format, essentially a binary classification of data. These can be images, audio files, video, or even common formats like Word and Excel files. This data contains lots of important data, but the formatting must be stripped out in order for users to effectively search this data. Filestream, Filetable, Full-Text Search, and Semantic Search are covered.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10253</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10253</id>
          <name>Ben Miller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Nimble Storage Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL LogShipping with PowerShell</title>
      <description>SQL Server LogShipping is an option to keep a copy of a database on another site.  It is also a way to have a read-only copy of a database on another server for reporting, etc.  This session will cover going outside the box and using PowerShell to backup, ship, and restore the database backups to another server.  This has been used to LogShip over the internet and over an FTP infrastructure.  This session is intended to show the possibilities of PowerShell and SQL Server together.  There will be full end-to-end demos of the pieces that make this possible.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17844</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17844</id>
          <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Quest/Dell Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>What Happened? Exploring the Plan Cache</title>
      <description>If you haven't been pro-active and set up some sort of tracing, does that mean there is nothing you can do to find out what problematic queries might be running? The answer is no. 

In this session, we'll explore SQL Server's plan cache, from the way it is managed in memory, to the tools and techniques for discovering what plans are in cache, how long they've been there, how often they've been run, and whether they contain any suspected sub-optimal operators, such as table scans and hash joins. Knowing what's happened is the first step in knowing what needs to be fixed.
</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25742</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25742</id>
          <name>Steve Stedman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SIOS Room</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL Productivity</title>
      <description>Have crazy deadlines? Working long hours? Tasks that need to be done yesterday? This session is  all about getting things done faster tricks/tools you can use to improve productivity. Including macros, dynamic SQL, excel, and templates. The majority of this session will cover macros (because I am a fan) and shortcuts; however, we will also go over a few examples of dynamic SQL, excel, and templates. This session is designed for people who know how to write t-sql and will be semi-open to discussion; we want to hear your tricks/tips as well.</description>
      <startTime>7/27/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>7/27/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>