<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #898 - Gothenburg 2019</name>
    <startDate>9/14/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>120</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Sarajevo, Skopje, Warsaw, Zagreb</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatGothenburg</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Beda</name>
      <street>Forskningsgången 3</street>
      <city>Göteborg</city>
      <state>Västra Götalands län, Sweden</state>
      <zipcode>417 56 Göteborg</zipcode>
      <longitude>11.9369525</longitude>
      <latitude>57.7061764</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/898/EventSponsor_14074.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1473</importID>
      <name>SQL Service Nordic AB</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlservice.se</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/898/EventSponsor_14052.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1588</importID>
      <name>Quest</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/898/EventSponsor_13740.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1069</importID>
      <name>SolidQ Nordic</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.solidq.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/898/EventSponsor_13662.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/898/EventSponsor_13844.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2395</importID>
      <name>Snabbfoting Group AB</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://snabbfoting.se/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/898/EventSponsor_14198.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/898/EventSponsor_13646.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95554</importID>
      <name>Kamil Nowinski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Blogger, speaker, #sqlfamily member. Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Data passionate, Data engineer and Architect.
Over 13 years of programming and experience with SQL Server databases, he worked both as developer and administrator big databases designing systems from the scratch. Passionate about tuning database engines, code transparency and maximising performance database engine.
Currently, he is expanding new horizons as a contractor in the UK market, making troubleshooting, prototyping BI and Big Data solutions, enhancing existing processes among Microsoft stuff environments, popularizing the DevOps approach and efficient solutions in the cloud.
An originator of the "Ask SQL Family" podcast and founder of SQLPlayer blog.</description>
      <twitter>@NowinskiK</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kamilnowinski/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlplayer.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@NowinskiK</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93154</importID>
      <name>Philipp Lenz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Philipp works as a Business Intelligence Senior Consultant at XXXL Digital in Coblenz, Germany. With the advent of Power Pivot for Excel and SQL Server Reporting Services, he has discovered his passion for Microsoft Business Intelligence technologies over 12 years.

Since mid-2016 he has been a founding member of the Power BI Usergroup in Cologne and is Chapter Leader of SQL PASS Mittelrhein, Germany. In 2019 he has also founded the Power Apps and Power Automate Usergroup and he was in the end of 2019 recognized as an Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>lenz_philipp</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.flip-it.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=lenz_philipp</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95536</importID>
      <name>Daniel Hutmacher</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior database developer with a long-running passion for performance tuning on SQL Server. I run my own consultancy business where I help companies with database development, ETL work, performance tuning and technical training on SQL Server.
Board member of the Swedish SQL Server usergroup 2017-2019, organizer of SQL Saturday Stockholm, and co-organizer of GroupBy.org.</description>
      <twitter>@dhmacher</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://se.linkedin.com/in/danielhutmacher</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlsunday.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dhmacher</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93669</importID>
      <name>Anton Boyko</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Founder and main speaker at Ukrainian Microsoft Azure Community. 15+ years in application development. Builds apps based on Microsoft Azure platform since 2011. Microsoft Azure technical expert. Microsoft Azure MVP since 2014. Owner and one of the organizers of the most popular Microsoft Azure conferences in Ukraine: Azure Day and Global Azure Bootcamp.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BoykoAnt</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/boykoant</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BoykoAnt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93158</importID>
      <name>Aleksandar Talev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Aleksandar Talev is Chief Development Officer in Semos  - Microsoft Gold Partner. He is professionally oriented to development of IT projects based on Microsoft technologies, primary SQL Server, Microsoft Power BI and Microsoft Azure. He has been working with SQL Server 6.5 since 1996. As a Microsoft trainer he is holding a Microsoft Curriculum courses focused on SQL Server as well as Power BI. As one of the founders of SQL Server User Group (PASS) Macedonia his free time he is engaged in developing the SQL Server community in Macedonia. He is a regular speaker on Microsoft conferences as well as local and global community events. In 2005 Microsoft awarded him with SQL Server MVP award.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/aleksandar-talev-95159187</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://Www.sqlpass.org.mk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93210</importID>
      <name>Magnus Ahlkvist</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Independent database consultant and certified trainer with a passion for chasing that extra millisecond.
20 years of database development and administration but trying to be humble enough to understand that I'm still learning.</description>
      <twitter>Transmokopter</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://se.linkedin.com/in/magnusahlkvist</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tsql.nu</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Transmokopter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98258</importID>
      <name>Pau Sempere</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pau Sempere S#225;nchez is a Computer Science graduate, working at SolidQ as Data Platform Architect and is member of PASS Spanish Group. He#39;s worked in BI and database projects for top companies in the world, in diverse areas as communications, insurance, retail, transport, banking and automotive. He has been presenting in many Microsoft and community events such as SQL Saturday Madrid and Barcelona, the 12 hours of SQL Server, SolidQ Summit or TechNet Webcasts, and teaching in the SolidQ Master for 6 years in a row</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.solidq.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95245</importID>
      <name>Lord Richard Douglas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lord Richard Douglas is a Principal Solutions Engineer at SentryOne, where he specialises in the SQL Server product range. He has worked with SQL Server since version 7.0 in various developer and DBA roles and holds a number of Microsoft certifications. Richard is a keen member of the SQL Server community, having run a PASS Chapter in the UK and having served on the organizing committee for SQLRelay.
Richard is on Twitter as @SQLRich.</description>
      <twitter>SQLRich</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/richardpdouglas</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SQL.RichardDouglas.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLRich</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93797</importID>
      <name>Ted Malone</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ted is currently a Data and AI Solution Architect with Microsoft's Customer Success organization. In this role, he works with large organizations to ensure that they properly and efficiently apply AI, Machine Learning, Data Analytics, and Business Intelligence technologies to achieve their business goals. Prior to taking this role, Ted worked with the US Federal Government to help solve "Big Data" problems through the use of cloud technologies.

Prior to joining Microsoft, Ted was an architect in EMC's CTO organization, and led data development teams for a variety of startup organizations.

Ted has worked with SQL Server since it's inception, and focuses on applying new technologies and techniques to age-old problems.</description>
      <twitter>@tedmalone</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/temalone/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.sqltrainer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tedmalone</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94811</importID>
      <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erland Sommarskog is an independent consultant based in Stockholm, working with SQL Server since 1991. He was first awarded SQL Server MVP in 2001, and has been re-awarded every year since. His focus is on systems development with the SQL Server Database Engine and his passion is to help people to write better SQL Server applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sommarskog.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95552</importID>
      <name>Damian Widera</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server MVP amp; MCT
Software engineer with 18+ years of professional experience in all aspects of software development.
Damian participated in a number of projects in international environments and possesses practical knowledge of procedures and tools which are necessary for successful implementation of such projects.
Now he focuses on building solutions based on Microsoft SQL Server environment (including complex database driven systems, database tuning and optimization).</description>
      <twitter>@DamianWidera</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/damian-widera-0b56284</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://codingfamily.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DamianWidera</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94129</importID>
      <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>José Manuel Jurado currently works as SQL Escalation Engineer and Subject Matter Expert in Azure SQL Database at Microsoft Spain. With over 20+ years of experience in SQL Server environments (administration and database development), he is a speaker for internal events at Microsoft and for public events such as SQLSaturday, SQL Nexus, SQLBits, Pass Summit, SQL Server Konferenze, TechReady, DotNetConference, and Azure BootCamp. In the past, he worked as Project Manager for large global retail company for more than 10 years developing projects using different Microsoft Technologies.</description>
      <twitter>jmjuradodiaz</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-manuel-jurado-diaz-5a586014/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jmjuradodiaz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95017</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo Kornelis is an established SQL Server community expert who spends a lot of time at various conferences. He is author of "the Execution Plan Reference" (sqlserverfast.com/epr), blogger, technical editor of Grant Fritchey's "SQL Server Execution Plans, 3rd edition" and some other books, and Pluralsight author. He was awarded SQL Server MVP and Data Platform MVP 12 times (2006 - 2016, and 2019-present).

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.</description>
      <twitter>Hugo_Kornelis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/hugokornelis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Hugo_Kornelis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93309</importID>
      <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kalen Delaney is a Data Platform MVP who has worked with SQL Server for more than 32 years. She has provided performance consulting services and taught advanced courses on SQL Server to thousands of people and organizations. In addition to her courseware development, Kalen has been writing about SQL Server for decades. She is the primary author of SQL Server Internals and the Inside SQL Server series. Kalen is also one of the primary editors for the Red Gate SQL Server Stairways tutorials.</description>
      <twitter>sqlqueen</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlqueen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93929</importID>
      <name>Asgeir Gunnarsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ásgeir Gunnarsson is a Data Platform MVP and Chief Consultant at Datheos in Denmark. He works on Business Intelligence solutions using the whole of the Microsoft BI stack. Ásgeir has been working in BI since 2007 both as a consultant and internal employee. Before turning to BI, Ásgeir worked as a technical trainer and currently teaches BI courses at the Continuing Education Department of the University of Iceland. 

Ásgeir speaks regularly at events both domestically and internationally, and is the group leader of the Icelandic PASS Group, as well as the Icelandic Power BI User Group. 

Ásgeir is passionate about data and loves solving problems with BI.</description>
      <twitter>bidgeir</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://is.linkedin.com/in/asgeirgun</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bidgeir</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95296</importID>
      <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Broadbent is a Data Platform MVP and SQL Server MCM with more than 20 years of experience working with SQL Server and principal of SQLCloud, a consultancy specializing in concurrency control and highly available solutions. He is the founder of the UK's SQLSaturday Cambridge (its first and largest), SharePoint Saturday Cambridge, the Hybrid Virtual Chapter and the East Anglia SQL User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@retracement</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/retracement</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tenbulls.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@retracement</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93813</importID>
      <name>Bartosz Ratajczyk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Database developer and (sometimes) administrator working with SQL Server Data Platform. Currently focusing on ETL development, delivery automation using TFS, query tuning, SQL Server training. Data Community Poland (DC) member, local group and conference speaker.</description>
      <twitter>@b_ratajczyk</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pl.linkedin.com/in/bartoszratajczyk</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.bartekr.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@b_ratajczyk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94162</importID>
      <name>Alexander Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alexander Klein is a senior Business Intelligence consultant with more than 15 years of experience. He focuses on Business Intelligence and Data Warehouse projects with Microsoft technologies like SQL Server, Power BI, Azure ML or Cortana Intelligence. 

Since 2008, he has been a self-employed consultant in large and medium-sized projects in all sectors across Europe. He has been visiting SQL Saturdays and other Data Conference all over Europe since 2013. Speaker at national and international events since 2017.</description>
      <twitter>@SQL_Alex</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-klein-13a04b3a</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQL_Alex</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>93158</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93158</id>
          <name>Aleksandar Talev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Delta</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to choose the right data model: SQL Server or Azure Cosmos DB. Which, When and Where ?</title>
      <description>When it comes to choosing a database, always there are considerations about picking a relational (SQL) or non-relational (NoSQL) data structure. While both are viable options, there are certain key differences between these two options that users must keep in mind.This session will cover the most important distinctions and will make a difference between two of a key players in the Microsoft database world: SQL Server and Azure Cosmos DB.  The session will also illustrate some of the fundamental differences between these databases - the language, scalability and structure which cause this distinctions to have  implications for the right choice.So which database is right for your business the attendance will take informations in this session.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93797</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93797</id>
          <name>Ted Malone</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Other room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Construct Visual Data Flows by using Azure Data Factory</title>
      <description>Moving and transforming data has always been, and will always likely be, a very large part of the day-to-day operational requirements of a data analytics practitioner.  Cloud technologies and "Big Data" have complicated this task to a degree, and understanding how to effectively and efficiently produce ETL/ELT data pipelines is a necessary skill in today's data landscape. 

In this session, attendees will be introduced to Azure Data Factory Mapping Dataflows, which allows users to develop comprehensive data pipelines using a graphical interface. These pipelines are executed in Azure Databricks, which provides a very efficient Spark-based execution context. Attendees will learn how to effectively build visual pipelines using common transformations, and will learn how to monitor and debug ETL and ELT pipelines by using Azure Data Factory.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93929</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93929</id>
          <name>Asgeir Gunnarsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Other room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Who, What, When. Monitoring usage of your MS BI stack</title>
      <description>You have created great cubes, Power BI reports and Reporting Services reports but how do you know if it is being used? Learn how to set up the collection of the usage data and how you can use this data in your decision making. 

We will talk about how to collect the data, how to build something meaningful from the data and how you can report on top of the data. We will do this for SSAS cubes (tabular and multidimensional), for Power BI reports and for Reporting Services Reports and we will explore ways you can further develop this for your own organization. 

At the end of the session all participants will leave with all the code as well as the know how to get started with the collection of usage statistics for their Microsoft BI Solutions.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 9:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 10:10:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93813</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93813</id>
          <name>Bartosz Ratajczyk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Delta</name>
      </location>
      <title>First steps with SQL Server on Docker</title>
      <description>Containers are gathering more and more attention. Wherever you take a look at - you have them. SQL Server 2019 introduces Big Data Clusters that utilise Kubernetes to orchestrate SQL Server, Spark and HDFS containers. Starting with SQL Server Express 2014 each next version of SQL Server is available as a Docker container. If your contact with containers technology was somehow limited - it's time to change that.
 
Join me in the session where I will introduce you to the Docker containers world. You will see their phenomena and will take a look at how you can start using them in your work. During the hour we will start from the beginnings, through use cases, to configuring custom SQL Server environment within minutes and starting it in seconds. We will focus on SQL Server, but also take a look at the other applications.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94811</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94811</id>
          <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Gamma</name>
      </location>
      <title>Don't Bite Off More Than You Can Chew - Take It in Chunks</title>
      <description>Any SQL programmer with some experience knows that loops are bad and that you should work with all data at once in set-based statements. However, you may have experienced situations where this strategy did not work out well and you ran into problems like out-growing the transaction log or blocking other users.

You can solve this by operating on the data in chunks. Implementing chunking is not that difficult, but there are still pitfalls you can run into. In this session, I will discuss in what situations you may want to use chunking. I will give some best practices for how to implement chunking for good performance and I will highlight some things you need keep in mind, for instance, recovering from interruptions. 

I will also look at how you can use chunking for error handling: You want process many rows and you want the good rows to succeed even if some rows yield errors - something you cannot do in a single set-based statement.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95296</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95296</id>
          <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Delta</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Availability Groups for dummies</title>
      <description>Availability Groups have become Microsoft’s default high availability and scalability go-to solution for SQL Server, but due to their relative complexity is often misunderstood, or worse, feared. 

In this session, we will explain how to plan for, deploy, and manage Availability Groups from the ground up in easy to understand examples and demos.

We will cover both Basic Availability Groups (BAGs) and full deployments, and also cover their use in Windows and Linux environments as well as look at the new SQL Server 2019 availability group support on containers in a Kubernetes cluster.

If you want to finally get to grips with SQL Server Always On Availability Groups, then this is the session for you!</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95536</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95536</id>
          <name>Daniel Hutmacher</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Gamma</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting your ducks in a row - Understanding ordered data flows</title>
      <description>There's a lot of information out there to overwhelm you when it comes to performance tuning your queries. It's very easy to feel like you're drinking from a fire hose when you're reading long blog posts or listening to technical conference sessions. Operators, metrics, wait statistics, page life expectancy, parallellism and fragmentation.

But let's take a step back and understand the one fundamental principle of querying data - ordering. This session is all about interactively and visually explaining the flow of data in terms of ordering, and how that affects the performance of your queries and server.

Once you get these basics right, tuning will feel so much easier and execution plans may even start to appear quite intuitive.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93669</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93669</id>
          <name>Anton Boyko</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Delta</name>
      </location>
      <title>The future of serverless computing</title>
      <description>Are you still planning your servers capacity in CPU and RAM? Do you enjoy answering questions like “what amount of servers we need to buy to serve 10K and 10M users”? Do you enjoy paying for those servers while they are sitting idle?

In my session I will talk about the current state and the future of serverless computing. I will show several demos that show how to start using serverless computing, what are the application scenarios for it, how it can scale, what it will cost, etc.

This session will be useful for developers and architects who are seeking a way to create an app utilizing all your previous skills, but make it scalable, reliable, fast and cost efficient.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95017</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95017</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Gamma</name>
      </location>
      <title>From adaptive to intelligent: query processing in SQL 2019</title>
      <description>As announced in September 2018, SQL Server 2019 expands the "adaptive query processing" features of SQL 2017 and relabels them as "intelligent query processing". This name now covers many features, such as batch mode on rowstore, memory grant feedback, interleaved execution, adaptive joins, deferred compilation, and approximate query processing.

In this high-paced session, we will look at all these features and cover some use cases where they might help - or hurt! - you.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93309</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93309</id>
          <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Delta</name>
      </location>
      <title>What the Hekaton?!</title>
      <description>SQL Server Hekaton, aka In-Memory OLTP, will completely change the way you think about data management. As a DBA, you’ll need to analyze your memory and storage needs completely differently. In this session, I will show you the in-memory architecture for your Hekaton data and indexes, and discuss what gets written to disk during checkpoints, as well as what gets logged. Finally, I’ll go into detail on just what it is that makes Hekaton so much FASTER!</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93210</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93210</id>
          <name>Magnus Ahlkvist</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Gamma</name>
      </location>
      <title>It depends - don't mistake your Google search for my database knowledge</title>
      <description>"It depends". The answer to most questions about database development and database design. In this 60 minute session I will go through some "smart" solutions which turned out to be performance killers in the end. I will also try kill some myths about "best practices" in database development.
My powerpoints usually look terrible, so I will focus on T-SQL and execution plans.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93154</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93154</id>
          <name>Philipp Lenz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Other room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Microsoft Power BI Deployment Types</title>
      <description>This session gives you an overview how Microsoft Power BI can be deployed. The Focus is on the Cloud, Hybrid and on Premises.  After the session you will have an idea which type should be the best for each scenario, because every project has different requirements. So there is no right or bad way – it depends on the project and also on the budget and some other regularities.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95554</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95554</id>
          <name>Kamil Nowinski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Other room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Move part of your body to Azure SQL Data Warehouse</title>
      <description>Azure is cheaper, Azure is faster, Azure is more secure. Azure... everywhere is Azure. Data is everywhere.
Even if not today, certainly in the future (yes, believe me) you will face a case: how to move my data from on-premise Data Warehouse to Azure.
This session will reveal the ideas of how to do that, how to recognise if you are ready, what the best practices are and other important things we should be aware of. I will describe potential issues and give you hints on how to avoid them.
Finally, I will present one tool that can help you in preparation and also we will see what speed we can achieve during a migration.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94129</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94129</id>
          <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Database - Lessons learned from the trenches</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn the best practices, tips and tricks on how to successfully use Azure SQL Database on production environments. You will learn how to monitor and improve Azure SQL Database query performance. I will cover how Microsoft CSS has been using Query Store, Extended Events, DMVs to help customers monitor and improve query response times when running their databases in the Microsoft Azure cloud. These learnings are fruit of Microsoft CSS support cases, and customer field engagements. This session includes several demos</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98258</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98258</id>
          <name>Pau Sempere</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Other room</name>
      </location>
      <title>Churn Norris: Retain your customers with Machine Learning</title>
      <description>Your customers are your friends, and you should keep your friends as close as possible. To avoid them leaving your side and keep on building that precious friendship, come to this session where we will review the concept of churn or customer retention, what defines such situations and how to predict (and reducing) them using Machine Learning techniques</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95245</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95245</id>
          <name>Lord Richard Douglas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Delta</name>
      </location>
      <title>Managing Memory for Optimal Performance</title>
      <description>Memory is one part of the holy trinity of resources consumed by SQL Server, the others being CPU and disk. Most people know how to look at disk latency and throughput and then take remedial measures to fix those issues. But what about memory issues?
In this session, you will learn how SQL Server uses memory and various caches, how to gauge memory pressure, and how to address the significant problems it can cause.
You will leave with a much clearer understanding of how to monitor and manage memory consumption within SQL Server using native Dynamic Management Objects.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 9:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 10:10:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94162</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94162</id>
          <name>Alexander Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Gamma</name>
      </location>
      <title>Bringing AI to the edge - Azure Cognitive Services in docker containers</title>
      <description>Microsoft Cognitive Services (formerly Project Oxford) are a set of APIs, SDKs and services. They are available to developers to make their applications smarter, more engaging and easier to find. Cognitive services extend Microsoft's AI platform.

How can you use these API's if you don't want to send your data to an Azure Data Center? Not every data set should leave your company. That's why Microsoft now offers the whole thing as a docker image, which you can run on your own hardware. As a company, you regain control over your data.</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 9:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 10:10:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95552</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95552</id>
          <name>Damian Widera</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Gamma</name>
      </location>
      <title>AQP vs IQP - query optimization on steroids</title>
      <description>Adaptive or Intelligent? Maybe both? SQL Server 2017 has come into the light packed with automated query tuning based on the Query Store and Plan Cache. 
SQL Server 2019 has a lot more important features like  =batch mode on rowstore, memory grant feedback, interleaved execution, adaptative joins, deferred compilation and approximate query processing. So now we have entered the Intelligent Query Processing world!.

I would like to present both the AQP and IQP to show what you can expect in the nearest future and how these features help your queries running faster</description>
      <startTime>9/14/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/14/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>