<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #753 - Lviv 2018</name>
    <startDate>9/29/2018 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Cairo</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatLviv</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Hotel Taurus</name>
      <street>5, Kn. Sviatoslava Sq., Lviv, Ukraine</street>
      <city>Lviv</city>
      <state>L'vivs'ka Oblast', Ukraine</state>
      <zipcode>79016</zipcode>
      <longitude>24.00973</longitude>
      <latitude>49.84212</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/972/EventSponsor_14605.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>617</importID>
      <name>EPAM</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.epam.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/860/EventSponsor_14209.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>562</importID>
      <name>Devart</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.devart.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/880/EventSponsor_14114.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1525</importID>
      <name>SoftServe</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.softserveinc.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/979/EventSponsor_14643.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1524</importID>
      <name>ELEKS</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://eleks.com/?utm_source=SQLSaturday_Lvivutm_medium=partner_pageutm_content=site-linkutm_campaign=ua_events</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/860/EventSponsor_14174.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1882</importID>
      <name>Sigma Software</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://sigma.software/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sigma.software/sites/default/files/logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74193</importID>
      <name>Grzegorz Stolecki</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Business Intelligence expert with 20+ years of experience. Grzegorz worked as architect, developer and trainer. Currently he focuses on developing specialized analytical and reporting solutions using machine learning models for large and mid-size enterprises. He also works on financial planning, consolidation and budgeting applications. Grzegorz is one of the leaders of Polish Data Community (former Polish SQL Server User Group PLSSUG). You can meet him very often at community meetings, conferences and other events. He is an active speaker and ATE member. Microsoft MVP in Data Platform Area since 2010.</description>
      <twitter>gstolecki</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/grzegorzstolecki</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=gstolecki</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73884</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74110</importID>
      <name>Torsten Strauss</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Torsten (MVP, MCSE, MCT) has been working with Microsoft SQL Server since the turn of the millennium and is specialized in performance optimization for large SQL Server environments. He has been with bp as a database engineer for over two decades and collaborates closely with Sarpedon Quality Lab as a Principal Microsoft SQL Server Consultant. Torsten is the founder of inside-sqlserver.com and has given more than 120 presentations on Microsoft SQL Server performance optimization at national and international conferences and user groups. Torsten has been recognized as a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional for Data Platform since 2018.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83079</importID>
      <name>Maryna Popova</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a Big Data Engineer in a BI team. I have around 4 years of  professional expertise in the Information Technologies industry, mainly all around data Engineering and Data Warehousing.
I am working on my 3rd BI Project now. All of them are in different business areas and are using different technologies. What is common between them is the  willingness to find the most proper development methodology as it is not a canonical development team and no development methodology works "out of the box" . 
In my talk I would like to share my experience in this area.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73895</importID>
      <name>Mikael Wedham</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mikael Wedham is the first SQL Server MCM in Sweden and the only one who also is a Microsoft Certified Trainer. He has been paid to do things in SQL Server since 1993. His long experience makes him an appreciated speaker at events and conferences all over Europe. To be prepared for deep dives, he is also certified as an Open Water Scuba Instructor.</description>
      <twitter>@wedham</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.wedham.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@wedham</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85476</importID>
      <name>Andrii Zrobok</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>25+ years of experience in database development: development data-centric applications from scratch, support of legacy databases/applications, data migration tasks, performance tuning,  consulting, database trainer. I have experience with wide range of databases such as  FoxPro for DOS (Fox Software), MS SQL Server (started from version 6.5) , Oracle, Sybase ASE, MySQL, PostgreSQL.
Co-Leader of PASS Local Chapter in Lviv.
Speaker at PASS SQLSaturday conferences (since 2013); PASS Lviv/Vinnitsa/Virtual SQL Server User Group, EPAM IT Week (2015-2017), AIBig Data Day 2019.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/azrobok/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84963</importID>
      <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Catalin Gheorghiu is a solution architect from Romania. He has more than 15 years of experience in developing solutions, especially on Microsoft technologies in very demanding environments. Is contributing articles and blogs to several user groups (MrSmersh), lecturing all over Romania and abroad, is also RONUA Timisoara (PASS Chapter) user group leader. Since 2011, every year he was awarded the Microsoft MVP Award.</description>
      <twitter>MrSmersh</twitter>
      <linkedin>?https://ro.linkedin.com/in/catalingheorghiu?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ronua.ro/author/catalin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MrSmersh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73920</importID>
      <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen, as the founder of Savory Data, has a long history of providing customer solutions in the areas of data engineering, data science, and Business Intelligence. He is a certified software engineer, a graduated business educator, and professor of Databases  Project Management at HTL Leonding, and is certified as an MCSE  MCT. He is a published author and writes articles for well-known journals. He co-founded PASS Austria and organizes SQLSaturdays in Austria. Markus is a founding member of Power BI Usergroup Austria. Since 2017 Markus was awarded as an Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>MEhrenmueller</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markus-ehrenmueller/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.savorydata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MEhrenmueller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85663</importID>
      <name>Vitalii Bondarenko</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I've been designing data-centric systems for last 20 years and have gained huge experience in developing BI, AI and Big Data solutions. For the last 5 years I've mostly been focused on enterprise platform designing and implementing different innovative approaches for Fast Data Processing. At the moment I'm responsible for building Processional Services in Cloud Solutions for Enterprise Customers.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73942</importID>
      <name>Michal Sadowski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior Database Platform Engineer, leader of Krakow chapter of Data Community Krakow (former Polish SQL Server User Group) - PASS Chapter. With more than 10 years of experience in Microsoft technology, helps in advisory for performance optimization on database and application levels. Active speaker on SQL Server related events like SQLSaturday, SQLDay, MCT Global Summit etc. Holds many Microsoft certificates including MCSE: Data Platform, MCSA: SQL Server 2012/2014/2016, MCSA: Windows Server 2008/2012/2016 and MCT.</description>
      <twitter>SadowskiMichal</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/pub/michal-sadowski/4/b33/717</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlplayer.net/michal-sadowski</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SadowskiMichal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82328</importID>
      <name>Eugene Polonichko</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leader of PASS Local Chapter in Donetsk (Ukraine). I work  as DWH/BI architect.  Responsible for designing and developing Data Warehouse and BI solutions with using Microsoft  BI Stack products.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/EvgenPolonichko</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/eugenepolonichko/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://msolapblog.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/EvgenPolonichko</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74418</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73982</importID>
      <name>Jan Mulkens</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jan Mulkens is a Microsoft MVP in AI, a Solution Expert at Ordina Belgium, and a Microsoft Data Platform  BI Consultant.
In his spare time, he is a speaker at conferences and user groups in Europe and he organizes two user groups and a conference in Belgium.
Power BI Days conference (www.powerbidays.com), Belgium Microsoft Advanced Analytics User Group (bit.ly/msaaug), and Flemish Power BI User Group (meetup.powerbibelgium.com).</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/JanMulkens</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/janmulkens</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.janmulkens.be</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/JanMulkens</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84165</importID>
      <name>Denis Reznik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denis Reznik is a Data Architect at Intapp, Inc. He has more than ten years experience in software development, database design, and performance tuning for cloud and on-premises solutions. In 2010 Denis became Microsoft Data Platform MVP and maintains MVP status today. Apart from his professional career, Denis actively participates in the development of the Ukrainian Data Community.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DenisReznik</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/denis-reznik/3/502/234</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://reznik.uneta.com.ua</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DenisReznik</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>78647</importID>
      <name>Eugene Polonichko</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leader of PASS Local Chapter in Donetsk (Ukraine). I work  as DWH/BI architect.  Responsible for designing and developing Data Warehouse and BI solutions with using Microsoft  BI Stack products.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/EvgenPolonichko</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/eugenepolonichko/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://msolapblog.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/EvgenPolonichko</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73940</importID>
      <name>Andriy Pogorelov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been dealing with database administration and development for more than 16 years. Started from SQL Server 2000
- Active member of Data Platform community
- Organizer of SQLSaturday Kharkiv
- Speaker at various Data Platform related events
- I possess Microsoft certificates: MCDBA, MCITP, MCSA.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://ua.linkedin.com/in/pogorelovandrey</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74339</importID>
      <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>José Manuel Jurado currently works as SQL Escalation Engineer and Subject Matter Expert in Azure SQL Database at Microsoft Spain. With over 20+ years of experience in SQL Server environments (administration and database development), he is a speaker for internal events at Microsoft and for public events such as SQLSaturday, SQL Nexus, SQLBits, Pass Summit, SQL Server Konferenze, TechReady, DotNetConference, and Azure BootCamp. In the past, he worked as Project Manager for large global retail company for more than 10 years developing projects using different Microsoft Technologies.</description>
      <twitter>jmjuradodiaz</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-manuel-jurado-diaz-5a586014/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jmjuradodiaz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>80706</importID>
      <name>Marcos Freccia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Currently working as a Microsoft SQL Server DBA at Zalando SE, Marcos has over 9 years of SQL Server experience, working from small to enterprise environments with High Availability, Disaster Recovery, Database Optimization, etc.. Holding several Microsoft certifications such as: MCITP DBA  DEV, MCSE Data Plataform and his last certification on Microsoft Azure Design and Implement Cloud Data Platform Solutions. In 2013 Marcos was awarded as a Microsoft MVP by his contributions in the Brazilian SQL Server community. Marcos is a frequent speaker in the SQL Server Community and he was the organizer of the first SQL Saturday in South Brazil.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlfreccia</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://br.linkedin.com/in/marcosfreccia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://marcosfreccia.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlfreccia</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86074</importID>
      <name>Yevhen Nedashkivskyi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Yevhen Nedashkivskyi is a professional DBA and a database developer with more than 10 years of experience. MSCP, MSCA, MSCE, MVP.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://ua.linkedin.com/in/nedash</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82982</importID>
      <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>José Manuel Jurado currently works as SQL Escalation Engineer and Subject Matter Expert in Azure SQL Database at Microsoft Spain. With over 20+ years of experience in SQL Server environments (administration and database development), he is a speaker for internal events at Microsoft and for public events such as SQLSaturday, SQL Nexus, SQLBits, Pass Summit, SQL Server Konferenze, TechReady, DotNetConference, and Azure BootCamp. In the past, he worked as Project Manager for large global retail company for more than 10 years developing projects using different Microsoft Technologies.</description>
      <twitter>jmjuradodiaz</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-manuel-jurado-diaz-5a586014/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jmjuradodiaz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83716</importID>
      <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erland Sommarskog is an independent consultant based in Stockholm, working with SQL Server since 1991. He was first awarded SQL Server MVP in 2001, and has been re-awarded every year since. His focus is on systems development with the SQL Server Database Engine and his passion is to help people to write better SQL Server applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sommarskog.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>74193</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74193</id>
          <name>Grzegorz Stolecki</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Predictive Reporting Services Performance Monitoring</title>
      <description>Every user wants to have his/hers reports generated quickly. But reality isn't so cute. Sometimes you have to wait and wait, and wait again while looking at the rotating green circle.
During my session you will learn how to monitor Reporting Services with the Execution Log.  I will show the structure of the log and some useful queries to get precise insights into report generating process. Analysing the log gives you a quick way to find bottlenecks and sources of your problems. Especially when you use a tool like Power BI or Excel to create a functional dashboard. You also will learn how to use R powered models in Power BI to predict problems with your reports execution.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 12:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 1:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84165</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84165</id>
          <name>Denis Reznik</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Performance Tuning Nowadays</title>
      <description>Nothing is perfect, which means that your database may be not perfect as well. And one day you may decide that your database is slow and it's time to optimize it. But.. Where to start? When to end? What to look at? Which queries are slow? How to identify the real bottleneck? And so on, and so on. There are a lot of questions that should be answered in a process of performance tuning. 

In this session, we will find answers to all these questions going from collecting data for analysis, through identifying bottlenecks to optimization of the particular queries. On this way, we will learn performance tuning practical techniques and solve a bunch of issues in real-time. And despite I'm a big fan of Profiler and old-fashioned tools and technics, new, more interesting and useful instruments are available nowadays, so will use them to find the bottleneck and tune performance. Minimum of theory and a lot of practice.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 12:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 1:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85663</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85663</id>
          <name>Vitalii Bondarenko</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Migration Project for over 200 TB: Pre-sale, Architecture, PoC and Delivery</title>
      <description>We would like to describe a data migration project for Law Company from UK. 500M documents in more than 20 offices around the world were migrated from a legacy Document Management System to a new one. As the result, in total, over 200 TB of data were extracted, transferred, reshaped and loaded. The session will start from specifics of a pre-sale process, than cover in details "As Is" and "To Be" architecture, show the results of a PoC, which was done in Azure Cloud and finally describe delivery and results. During the presentation we will focus on specific aspects of Data Migration projects, scalability, security, etc. Also will discus several difficulties we dialed with. The session contains lots of architectural diagrams and examples of code.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 4:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 5:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86074</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86074</id>
          <name>Yevhen Nedashkivskyi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>ДБА мимоволі – що робити? (українською)</title>
      <description>Часто роль адміністратора баз даних закріплюється за принципом «може розібратися і має на це час», а іноді і просто ігнорується. На жаль, це призводить до проблем з продуктивністю, необгрунтованих витрат на обладнання, ризику втрати даних і простою основної діяльності.

Доповідач, в стислій, але доступній формі на прикладі СУБД Microsoft SQL Server розповість і покаже, що необхідно робити новоспеченим адміністраторам баз даних, навіть якщо ця роль дісталася їм мимоволі.

У цій сесії:

1. Планування
2. Інсталяція і налаштування
3. Регулярне обслуговування
4. Проблеми з продуктивністю і як їх вирішити
5. Масштабування
6. Побудова стратегії відновлення від збоїв
7. Сторонні утиліти і інструменти

Доповідь призначений для широкої кола в тому числі і для тих, хто не має досвіду в адмініструванні баз даних, а також тим, кому роль ДБА дісталася за сумісництвом.

Українською мовою.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 3:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 4:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73920</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73920</id>
          <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Create Stunning Visualizations with The Help of R</title>
      <description>R is the first choice for data scientists for a good reason: besides accessing and transforming data and applying statistical methods and models to it, it has a wide variety of possibilities to visualize data. As visual perception of data is the key to understanding data, this capability is crucial. This session will give you a broad overview over available packages and diagram types you can build with them on the one hand, and a deep dive into common visualizations and their possibilities on the other hand. Impress yourself and your peers with stunning visualizations which will give you insights into data you could not achieve with other tools of Microsoft’s BI stack.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85476</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85476</id>
          <name>Andrii Zrobok</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>MS SQL: Worst Practices</title>
      <description>Real project experience: Causes and how to avoid
Sunstroke. Butterfly effect (How optimizer allocates memory for different  operations? Is it possible to change allocated memory in-fly (without query recompilation)? Some data types  save disk space and what about memory?) Sequence (is it good or bad), Silver bullet (not only SQ-92)</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83716</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83716</id>
          <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dynamic Search Conditions</title>
      <description>A common requirement in database applications is that users want a function to search a set of data from a large set of possible search conditions. The challenge is to implement such searches in a way that is both maintenanble and efficient in terms of performance. This session looks at the two main techniques to implement such searches and highlights their strengths and limitaitons.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73940</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73940</id>
          <name>Andriy Pogorelov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Transaction Log: internals</title>
      <description>Подробно рассмотрим важнейший компонент базы данных - лог транзакций. Для чего он нужен, в каких процессах участвует. Облако затрагиваемых терминов: Backup, Recovery, Shrink, VLF, Replication, AlwaysOn, CDC, Best Practices.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 4:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 5:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73942</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73942</id>
          <name>Michal Sadowski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Encryption in SQL Server</title>
      <description>An application that you administer stores sensitive data in the database and you would like to keep them safe in Microsoft SQL Server - how to approach this issue? What type of encryption should you use in your environment? On the session I will walk through available options in Microsoft SQL Server and show when to use encryption, how to identify threats, and countermeasure them by using options like Transparent Data Encryption, SSL certificates, Always Encrypted, etc. After this session, you will know a set of best practices that you can apply in your environment.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 10:55:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 11:55:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82328</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82328</id>
          <name>Eugene Polonichko</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Databricks for Data Engineering</title>
      <description>How you know companies set their sights on making data-driven decisions.  Mastering data engineering is a business necessity.  So they need tool which can be simply and  powerfull at the same times. Now it's  Azure Databricks.   Built on Apache Spark™, Azure Databricks provides the scale, compatibility and reliability to expand your data engineering capabilities. Come to my session and I show you how you can scale mission-critical data cleansing, transformations, and manipulations to make business use cases such as real-time dashboards or fraud detection possible with Azure Databricks.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74339</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74339</id>
          <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Back to the future - Migrating our SQL Server OnPremise Database to Azure</title>
      <description>We will cover the main aspects to migrate to one of the three architectures available in SQL Server in Azure from SQL Server On Premise. 

This session consists of:
-&gt; What is the best platform for my environment? IaaS, PaaS, or SQL Datawarehouse.
-&gt; Best Practices and best tools for our migration process depending on the platform chosen.
-&gt; After the migration, we have several outstanding questions:
            Can I keep both environments synchronized?
             How is the performance of my database?</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 3:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 4:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74418</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74418</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB - What you need to know to build globally distributed apps?</title>
      <description>In this session let us find about (technical overview)what are the foundations and design goals of Azure CosmosDB.  There are many benefits which will fit for web, mobile and globally distributed applications that need elastic scaling, high availability with a predictable performance which can elevate ease of development with NoSQL capabilities that every developer/architect/DBA should know about.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 3:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 4:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73884</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73884</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hacking? Mission Possible!</title>
      <description>Everthing is connected. Everything is accessible. Everything is hackable.
This is a security "worst" practices session for developers (yes, yes, the boring "best" practices are also included).
As always, should you or any of your colleagues be hacked or exploited, the Demo Gods will disavow any knowledge of the speakers' actions. This session will self-destruct in 60 minutes. Luck has nothing to do with it, Jim…</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 10:55:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 11:55:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74110</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74110</id>
          <name>Torsten Strauss</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database tuning advisor vs. dynamic management views</title>
      <description>Query tuning is a challenging task for a developer and database administrator - so how can we achieve this?

SQL Server mainly offers two different tools we can use for this purpose: DTA Database Tuning Advisor and Missing Index Dynamic Management Views.
But what are the differences in terms of reliability, usage, limitations and tuning recommendations?
So, we will try to answer these questions in this deep dive session (300-400).</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84963</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84963</id>
          <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL database on IoT devices, could you? should you? would you?</title>
      <description>The current IoT devices are pretty powerful, so could very well run a version of SQL engine.
It would be a good idea?  What will be the use of it? How to make it work and make the most of it? 
How does all fit with the field gateway concept?  During the presentation, we will take a real word scenario, real hardware, and together we will try to answer these questions</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 4:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 5:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73982</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73982</id>
          <name>Jan Mulkens</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Practical SQL Server Machine Learning Services</title>
      <description>Admit to yourself that you’ve seen enough basic “R is coming to SQL Server” sessions with the same old examples!
Enough of that, in this session we'll walk through a real SQL Server Machine Learning Services scenario from idea to code and from deployment to monitoring  maintenance.
Learn how you can easily roll out your own Data Science projects or support the data scientists and analysts at your company.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83079</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83079</id>
          <name>Maryna Popova</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>AWS Redshift Introduction</title>
      <description>This session is Intro to AWS Redshift. 
Will give the overview of the architecture and important details</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 10:55:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 11:55:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>80706</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>80706</id>
          <name>Marcos Freccia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>10 Alerts that you should have it running in your SQL Server!</title>
      <description>Did you not get budget for that cool monitoring tool, but you still want to monitor your SQL Server? In this session I am going to show you 10 alerts that you should setup in your SQL Server instance. Going from CPU, IO, Corruption and Backups.

By the end of this session, your life as a DBA will be much easier with those alerts in place!</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 12:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 1:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73895</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73895</id>
          <name>Mikael Wedham</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Masters view on Query plans and indexing</title>
      <description>Do you find query optimization a mystery? This session will straighten out your question marks.
You will se how queries are run, how indexes are used and get an insight into what query plans tell you.
Further on you'll be introduced to In-Memory and Column Store indexing to get a fair chance of 
selecting appropriate indexing for your query load.</description>
      <startTime>9/29/2018 3:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/29/2018 4:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>