<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #1005 – Puerto Rico – Virtual 2020</name>
    <startDate>10/10/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-04:00) Caracas, La Paz</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatPuertoRico</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Engine 4</name>
      <street>Complejo Onofre Carballeira Esq. PR-2 con Int. PR-5</street>
      <city>Bayamon</city>
      <state>PR, Puerto Rico</state>
      <zipcode>00959</zipcode>
      <longitude>-66.1466369628906</longitude>
      <latitude>18.4142608642578</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1781</importID>
      <name>Microsoft</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1005/EventSponsor_14866.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2696</importID>
      <name>Melissa</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>http://www.melissa.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1005/EventSponsor_14897.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2689</importID>
      <name>Red Hat</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://www.redhat.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1005/EventSponsor_14867.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2678</importID>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://cloud.google.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1005/EventSponsor_14868.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107846</importID>
      <name>Martha Chávez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Profesional reconocida como MVP, certificada como MCT trainer oficial de Microsoft, MCSA Business Intelligence y MCP Microsoft Certified Professional, cuenta con más de 5 años en proyectos de Data Analytics  BI.
Actualmente trabaja en Arkano Software con roles como arquitecto de datos y lider técnico Perú.
Cuenta con cursos y especialización en Big Data, Machine Learning y Business Intelligence; así como  
experiencia comprobada en las siguientes herramientas de Microsoft: Azure, SSIS,  SQL, Power BI, entre otros.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marthachavezquispe/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108521</importID>
      <name>Jose L. Rivera</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jose L. Rivera is a seasoned data professional, speaker, homebrewer, trainer (former MCT), Data Platform MVP and community leader based in Puerto Rico working as Senior Financial Analyst for MCS. He shares his knowledge and experiences throughout his community work as Chapter Leader for the PASS Global Spanish VC (facebook.com/SpanishPASSVC), Vice-President of the Puerto Rico PASS (prpass.org), Mentor of GDG Puerto Rico (facebook.com/gdgpuertorico) and LATAM Regional Mentor at PASS. Jose L is a frequent speaker in SQL Saturday events throughout US and Latin America. He loves data, analytics, teaching, learning, having fun with his family, craft beer (a lot) and everything in between.</description>
      <twitter>SQLConqueror</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=189422534</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlconqueror.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLConqueror</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107781</importID>
      <name>Ana Maria Bisbé York</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Partner Microsoft en Power BI. Influencer en Pragmatic Works. Lic. en Cibernetica Economica con Master en Ciencias Economicas, Moscu; 1988. Master en Gestion del Conocimiento y Business Intelligence con tecnologia Microsoft(MS), y Master en Tecnologias de Desarrollo de MS. Colaboro activamente en grupos de usuarios de MS Visual FoxPro. Mantiene un blog personal. Actualmente es Consultora Business Intelligence con tecnologia MS, trabajando tanto en formacion como en proyectos. Ha sido ponente en eventos SQL Saturday, dentro y fuera de Espania, 24H SQL, IT Woman y Encuentros en Microsoft Espania.</description>
      <twitter>@ambynet</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ambynet</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://amby.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ambynet</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105526</importID>
      <name>David Patrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave has been developing database applications for over 25 years. An MCT since 2001, he has taught many classes from Intro to Visual Interdev to Advanced SharePoint Development. Dave runs two user groups, the Maryland and Pennsylvania Microsoft Developers User Group, www.mapamdug.com, and MAD SharePoint, www.madsharepoint.com. Dave does SharePoint training and development for DSA, Inc., a DoD contractor that does great work for the Army over at Aberdeen Proving Ground. Dave is also an MVP.</description>
      <twitter>DavidEPatrick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidepatrick</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.madsharepoint.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DavidEPatrick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107647</importID>
      <name>Itshak David</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Yitzhak has over 24 years of experience with SQL Server, Oracle, and Sybase. He is an applicative  infrastructure DBA for relational and Nosql solutions (MongoDB, Redis), Hadoop CDH and Spark. David is a specialist in HA and DRP solutions, tuning, Machine learning , security, High Performance Computing, replication (Oracle  SQL Server), BI infrastructure and system engineering. David Yitzhak holds 3 Degrees from Technicon (Israel Institute of Technology): BSC Information System , MBA and ME (System engineering) and research associate in one of the enterprise Organizations. He presents in Oracle open world 2010, Organize Oracle ILOUG for 3 years , SQL Server forums, Microsoft BI forums, Sqlsaturday Israel 2016/17/18/19 , 3rd Israeli</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>Global Hebrew Virtual PASS Chapter : Data virtualization with SQL Server 2019 PolyBase https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ixfwdZUj_A8feature=youtu.be https://globalhebrew.pass.org/MeetingDetails.aspx?EventID=15457    SQL Server 2019 Big Data Cluster BDC and Spark from Zero to an hero by David Yitzhak https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iKgMqyPOVS0   David Izhak: Performance Improvements in SQL 2014 – lessons from the field  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x4hGjYGBfkc   David Itzhak: Practical SQL 2014 Data Mining</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>106019</importID>
      <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>José Manuel Jurado currently works as SQL Escalation Engineer and Subject Matter Expert in Azure SQL Database at Microsoft Spain. With over 20+ years of experience in SQL Server environments (administration and database development), he is a speaker for internal events at Microsoft and for public events such as SQLSaturday, SQL Nexus, SQLBits, Pass Summit, SQL Server Konferenze, TechReady, DotNetConference, and Azure BootCamp. In the past, he worked as Project Manager for large global retail company for more than 10 years developing projects using different Microsoft Technologies.</description>
      <twitter>jmjuradodiaz</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-manuel-jurado-diaz-5a586014/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jmjuradodiaz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107863</importID>
      <name>Sam Nasr</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sam Nasr has been a software developer since 1995, focusing mostly on Microsoft technologies.  He’s a Sr. Software Engineer with NIS Technologies where he consults and teaches clients about the latest .Net technologies.  Sam has achieved multiple certifications from Microsoft (MCSA, MCAD, MCTS, MCT), and is the leader of the Cleveland C#/VB.Net User Group since 2003. In addition, he’s the leader of the .Net Study Group, an author for Visual Studio Magazine, and a Microsoft MVP since 2013.  When not coding, Sam loves spending time with his family and friends or volunteering at his local church.</description>
      <twitter>SamNasr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/samsnasr</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://samnasr.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SamNasr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108522</importID>
      <name>Kenneth Urena</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kenneth Ureña is an experienced technologist with 17 years of experience, including 14 years of experience in SQL server. He has worked on versions from SQL Server 7.0 to SQL server 2016. 

Kenneth has performed the role of Database Developer, Database Architect and Database Administrator, always relying on his disaster recovery and performance tuning skills.

He co-leads the Global Spanish Virtual chapter of PASS. PASS LatAm Regional Mentor, he speaks at multiple SQL Server events in both Spanish and English. Kenneth holds multiple SQL server certifications.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlcr</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlcr</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlcr.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlcr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107458</importID>
      <name>Orlando Mezquita</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Orlando is principal consultant and trainer at Master Data Analysis. He is a passionate analytics professional who shares his knowledge through MasterDataAnalysis.com. Orlando provides analytics training and consulting services with Power BI, Excel, R, and Minitab.</description>
      <twitter>orlandomezquita</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/orlandomezquita/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.MasterDataAnalysis.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=orlandomezquita</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107293</importID>
      <name>Ahias Portillo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Soy un loco entusiasta por aprender nuevas tecnologías asociadas a base de datos, análisis de datos, Big Data y Ciencia de datos, cuento con más de 15 años de experiencia. 

Cuento con una maestría en Base de datos, certificación profesional de Microsoft en ciencia de datos y Big Data, actualmente estoy estudiando una maestría académica en ciencia de datos.

Me gusta compartir el conocimiento lo que me ha permitido ser nombrado como MVP de plataforma de datos desde el 2014, también he participado como conferencista en países de El Salvador, Guatemala, Costa Rica, Panamá, Estados Unidos y España.</description>
      <twitter>PortilloAhias</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/jose-ahias-lopez-portillo/30/284/977</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=PortilloAhias</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107595</importID>
      <name>Edwin Martinez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hello, I'm Edwin. I'm a web developer with 5 years in the field. I live in Puerto Rico. Passionate in technology, I love to explore new techniques and tools to make my work efficient as possible and with a lot of love.</description>
      <twitter>dev_ejmartinez</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://linkedin.com/in/emartinez6</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=dev_ejmartinez</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107669</importID>
      <name>Vladimir Guzman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Consultor especialista en soluciones de Inteligencia de Negocios, con mas 12 años de experiencia en proyectos regionales  sobre tecnología Microsoft (SQL Server 2000,2005,2008, 2008 R2, 2012 y 2014, 2016, 2017).
Administrador de Proyectos de Tecnologia sobre soluciones de desarrollo, Inteligencia de Negocios e infraestructura
Experiencia en análisis, diseño y desarrollo de soluciones de BI sobre tecnología Microsoft</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107247</importID>
      <name>Eduardo Castro</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eduardo Castro, Microsoft Data Platform MVP and PASS Board of Advisor for LATAM, is well known LATAM SQL Server Expert and focuses on architecture, Business Intelligence and Data Analytics, Eduardo has an specialization and master degree in Data Analysis and Big Data. I have been speaker at PASS Summit delivering session about R and Data Science.

Eduardo Castro has presented in United States, Costa Rica, Colombia, Guatemala, Mexico, Panama, El Salvador and South Korea.</description>
      <twitter>edocastro</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=7313296amp;authType=NAME_SEARCHamp;authToken=pBHMamp;locale=en_USamp;srchid=73132961426368749508amp;srchindex=1amp;srchtotal=50amp;trk=vsrp_people_res_nameamp;trkInfo=VSRPsearchId%3A73132961426368749508%2CVSRPtargetId%3A7313296%2CVSRPcmpt%3Aprimary%2CVSRPnm%3A</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ecastrom.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=edocastro</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107482</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107356</importID>
      <name>Andrea Mascher</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Mascher (she/her) leads the SQL Server DBA team at The University of Iowa (UI). In addition to her experience in the education sector, Andrea previously supported systems in the biotechnology and healthcare fields.

Andrea is an advocate for gender diversity in STEM and co-founded the UI Women In Technology users group to promote a climate of inclusivity and professional growth for women and non-binary individuals in technical fields at UI. Andrea also serves as a member of the UI Council on the Status of Women.

Andrea's undergraduate and graduate coursework at UI was in Computer Science, with a focus on Electronic Voting Systems and Technology Law and Policy.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107607</importID>
      <name>Mohammad Darab</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mohammad Darab is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Certified Kubernetes Administrator, Certified Kubernetes Application Developer, speaker and blogger with over 19 years of IT professional experience, 10+ years of that working with SQL Server. He is passionate about SQL Server Big Data Clusters, Kubernetes and overall professional development.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/mwdarab</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mdarab/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mohammaddarab.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/mwdarab</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105887</importID>
      <name>Ruslan Zolotukhin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>BI Engineer at Jabil Software Services
Power BI Consultant
MCT, MSCA: BI Reporting
Speaker at SQL Saturday, Data Monsters and UNETA, PUG and PASS UG Meetups
Advisor at Power BI Community Forum
Leader of Kharkiv Power BI User Group
Former DAX, Excel  VBA trainer
Blog: www.zoloturu.com

My passion is:
* to learn new technologies in data management, analytics and science
* to wrangle data and provide meaningful output
* to automate routine processes and to build reporting systems
* to share my experience and knowledge in all these areas</description>
      <twitter>zoloturu</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/zoloturu/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.zoloturu.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=zoloturu</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107416</importID>
      <name>Ricardo Estrada</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Soy Ricardo Estrada consultor y conferencista en temas relacionados con SQL, resido en Costa Rica, curioso por la tecnología y apasionado por las bases de datos y sistemas de BI, gusta de compartir conocimiento, buscar soluciones a problemas cotidianos y construir aplicaciones que faciliten las operaciones y decisiones a nivel empresarial, es orgullosamente speaker de los SQL Saturdays de Centroamérica desde el año 2014, además de participar como expositor en los Summit para España y Panamá.
Mi primer contacto con SQL Server fue con la versión 2000 y no ha dejado de aprender trucos, metodologías, técnicas y estrategias nuevas... y desde entonces... las he compartido en diferentes posts, principalmente la página de fb: SeHablaSQL</description>
      <twitter>pricardo03@hotmail.com</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SeHablaSQL</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pricardo03@hotmail.com</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105750</importID>
      <name>Javier Villegas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Javier Villegas is a Database Administrator Manager for Mediterranean Shipping Company. Javier has more than 20 years working with SQL Server on every version from 6.5 to SQL Server 2019, Including SQL Azure Database and SQL Azure Managed Instance. His specialization is Administration, Performance Tuning and High Availability.
He is a Microsoft MVP in Data Platform.
Javier is a frequent speaker in conferences and events such as SQL Saturday , PASS Virtual Groups, 24 Hours SQL PASS , vOpen(NetConf), GroupBy and DataPlatformGeeks.
@sqlargentina</description>
      <twitter>https://www.twitter.com/javier_vill</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://ar.linkedin.com/in/javiervillegas</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sql-javier-villegas.blogspot.com.ar/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://www.twitter.com/javier_vill</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107620</importID>
      <name>Deepthi Goguri</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Deepthi is a SQL Server Database Administrator with 7+ years of experience in administering SQL Servers. She is a Microsoft certified Trainer and professional with an Associate and Expert level certification in Data Management and Analytics. Deepthi completed her Masters in Computer Technology at Eastern Illinois University. She blog for DBANuggets.com.</description>
      <twitter>dbanuggets</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbanuggets.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=dbanuggets</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105759</importID>
      <name>Ondrej Aubrecht</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ondrej has been working with SharePoint, O365 (cloud) and security in the industry for more than 12 years. Working on various projects maximalize the benefits, improvements and reduce the cost in the big enterprise and governments.

Ondrej takes data into a new level of challenges and setting Precision and organize system specifically in IT technology which he is passionate about. He is also running Wellington PowerShell user group.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.pwsh.org.nz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107376</importID>
      <name>MAYRA BADILLO VILLAMIZAR</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) Business Applications. Microsoft Subject Matter Expert (Enero 2020 a la fecha) como Field Enablement Coach trabajo con equipos internos en diferentes subsidiarias de Microsoft Latam a través del WW Learning. Arquitecta en Productividad, Colaboración, Seguridad y BizAPPs en Microsoft 365 y Power Platform apoyando el ecosistema de socios de negocios, mayoristas y clientes finales de acuerdo a la estrategia vigente a trabajar en un Fiscal Year. Speaker Internacional. Microsoft Partner Services desde 2008. Freelancer con cobertura en clientes (Microsoft, Partners, Mayoristas y clientes finales) de Centroamérica, Suramérica y España. Microsoft SWAT SENIOR 7 años.</description>
      <twitter>mabvill</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mabvill/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mabvill/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mabvill</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105986</importID>
      <name>Alex Rostan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>software engineer, Tech passionate, AI and congnitive services lover</description>
      <twitter>rostanker</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexrostan/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=rostanker</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107456</importID>
      <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tracy Boggiano is a Senior Database Administrator for DocuSIgn. She has spent over 20 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1999, and is currently certified as an MCSE Data Platform. Tracy has worked on SQL Server since 6.5. She has spoken at local user groups and numerous SQLSaturdays. She is currently a co-leader of a TriPASS Local Group in Raleigh, NC.   

Tracy also tinkered with databases in middle school to keep her sports card collection organized. She blogs at databasesuperhero.com. 

Her passion outside of SQL Server is volunteering with foster children as their advocate in court through volunteerforgal.org and being a mental health advocate as part of the PAIMI NC Advisory Council.</description>
      <twitter>TracyBoggiano</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyboggiano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://databasesuperhero.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TracyBoggiano</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>107647</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107647</id>
          <name>Itshak David</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Mayaguez</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2019 on containers and Kubernetes(k8s) from zero to an hero !</title>
      <description>If containers are the new virtual machines, then Kubernetes are the new servers. Kubernetes is an important technology to the future of containerized applications, especially running enterprise workloads like SQL Server
•	SQL Server 2019 on containers and Kubernetes(k8s) from zero
•	Install and Configure Docker on Windows Server 
o	Download and Install the Docker-Microsoft PackageManagement Provider 
•	Install and Configure Docker on Ubuntu Linux 
•	The Docker Ecosystem
•	Managing and Administering Containers 
•	Persisting Data
•	Working with SQL Server on Linux and Windows 
•	Creating Custom SQL Server on Windows\linux Container Images .
•	Docker Networking for SQL Server DBAs
If time permits : 
•	What Is k8s? 
o	k8s internal and Objects  
o	k8s Deployment Options
o	Deploying SQL Server on k8s 
o	SQL Server High Availability on k8s
o	Updating SQL Server on k8s
o	Using Helm Chart
o	SQL Server Availability Groups on k8s
This is  a demo session only with minimum theory  lessons from the</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107456</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107456</id>
          <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Mayaguez</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Configuration with dbatools and dbachecks</title>
      <description>Automating the configuration of SQL Server instances and being able to check the configuration for standard configuration is an important role for any DBA when you have lots of instances.  But how can we automate the configuration easily?  How can we check to make sure the proper configuration is in place and hasn’t changed?

In this session, we will look at how to configure your SQL Server Instances using PowerShell and the dbatools module.  Then we will look at how to use dbachecks to confirm the configuration of our instances and how to check for changes in the future of the configuration. 
 
Attendees will see how easy it is to use PowerShell via dbatools to configure their SQL Server instances.  Attendees will see how easy it is to use PowerShell via dbachecks and PowerBI to see if their servers are configured properly.  Attendees will be given a set of scripts that take back to use to configure and test the configuration of their SQL Server instances.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107416</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107416</id>
          <name>Ricardo Estrada</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Mayaguez</name>
      </location>
      <title>¡Cross Selling con SQL Grafos!</title>
      <description>La teoría de grafos tiene la capacidad de ayudar a solucionar problemas que afrontamos a diario, simplificando la manera en que se aborda un problema, como se exploran los datos y en cómo se construye el código y la relación entre los datos, minimizando la cantidad de código necesario para lograrlo.
Esta sesión está hecha para que nosotros los técnicos podamos entender el valor de esta tecnología y que tengamos parámetros de: ¿Cómo? ¿Cuándo? y ¿Por qué? incluirlos entre nuestras bases de datos transaccionales.
	El código de las demos estará disponible al final de la sesión para el uso de discrecional de los participantes en sus trabajos, proyectos, experimentos o aprendizaje.
¡Los esperamos! 
fb: SeHablaSQL</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107607</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107607</id>
          <name>Mohammad Darab</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Fajardo</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data Clusters for the Absolute Beginner</title>
      <description>Are you a DBA or data professional working with out-dated technology or feel your skills are quickly becoming irrelevant? Stay ahead in today's ever changing tech space and take your career to the next level.

Join Mohammad Darab this session to explore the cutting-edge technology that SQL Server 2019 has to offer: Big Data Clusters.

Topics include:
-Big Data Cluster architecture and its components such as: Containers, Kubernetes and the newly enhanced Polybase
-Unique advantage of SQL Server Big Data Clusters
-Data Virtualization, Scale-out Data Marts, and Data Hub concepts</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107846</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107846</id>
          <name>Martha Chávez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Mayaguez</name>
      </location>
      <title>Databricks for data engineers</title>
      <description>En esta sesión se realizará distintos ejemplos de como usar databricks con los diferentes códigos que existen y como se utilizan en la limpieza y transformación de datos</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107620</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107620</id>
          <name>Deepthi Goguri</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Fajardo</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Engine: Its Working Style</title>
      <description>Many DBA's and Developers work with SQL Server but don’t fully understand how it really works behind the scenes. Join Deepthi on her dive into the internals of SQL Server to explain why knowing what goes on under the covers will help you make better decisions quickly when solving performance problems in SQL Server. This session will cover ACID properties, key components of the Relational Engine, Storage engine, Cache and the Transaction manager. We will also cover what happens  under the covers during read and write operations within SQL Server. 
 Deepthi will show you how the SQL engine thinks – enabling you to think like it!</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107863</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107863</id>
          <name>Sam Nasr</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Mayaguez</name>
      </location>
      <title>14 T-SQL Functions You May Not Know</title>
      <description>Newer releases of SQL Server have introduced many new functions developers may not know or use. This includes functions for type conversion, date/time calculation, enhanced logic, and string manipulation. In this session we’ll cover the ins and outs of these new functions, in addition to some best practices for using these functions.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107458</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107458</id>
          <name>Orlando Mezquita</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Juan</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query folding in Power BI: maximizing the performance of database connections</title>
      <description>When connecting to a database from Power BI, your best bet in terms of data transformation performance is folding your queries to the database. In other words, to perform the data transformation operations in the database rather than Power BI. In this talk, I’ll explain the concept of query folding, how to maximize it, and some tips to make sure you don’t break the folding.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108522</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108522</id>
          <name>Kenneth Urena</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Juan</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2019: Estrategias de Indexación para alto desempeño</title>
      <description>Multiples estrategias de indexacion para obtener los mejores resultados sobre SQL Server, se coveran temas como:
- Noncluster Coverage
- Culstered Page Split
- Heaps
- Indices Filtrados</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107376</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107376</id>
          <name>MAYRA BADILLO VILLAMIZAR</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Mayaguez</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI and Common Data Service</title>
      <description>Sesión demostrativa de exploracion del conector Common Data Service para Power BI, y cómo embeber en una aplicacion de PowerAPPS contenido de Power BI</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107356</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107356</id>
          <name>Andrea Mascher</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Fajardo</name>
      </location>
      <title>SELECT Questions FROM Diversity.Inclusion WHERE AfraidToAsk = 1</title>
      <description>In the past several years Diversity, Equity,  Inclusion (DEI) have become more important and visible in the workplace.  Studies have shown that organizations are often more successful when they are more diverse, yet the tech sector is moving slowly to improve representation and inclusion.  Many IT professionals want to improve but don't know where to start.  

This session will cover key concepts in DEI and how they apply to data practitioners.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108521</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108521</id>
          <name>Jose L. Rivera</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Juan</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Composite Models</title>
      <description>In this talk we will explore a very powerfull set of features called Composite Models and Aggregations. These two new features bring a new level of data modeling and data prep to Power BI Desktop and PowerBI Service. Join us to see it in action.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105986</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105986</id>
          <name>Alex Rostan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Ponce</name>
      </location>
      <title>Get data easily and fast with Cognitives Services</title>
      <description>In this session will see how to get data from forms, letters and other digital documents using cognitive services and then how to store this data into databases</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107482</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107482</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Ponce</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hacking SQL Server Is Not Enough</title>
      <description>You already know how easy it is to hack SQL Server… But how do you protect your local and cloud servers against enemy agent attacks?
This is a demo-driven session, suited for DBAs, developers and security consultants. Both exploits and security recommendations to avoid them will be covered.
Disclaimer: No actual crimes will be committed. Please do not send agents to my house again.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107669</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107669</id>
          <name>Vladimir Guzman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Juan</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL DevOps</title>
      <description>En esta sesion veremos los conceptos de DevOps orientados a entornos a Base de datos, herramientas de apoyo a los desarrolladores y CI/CD en Azure</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105526</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105526</id>
          <name>David Patrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Fajardo</name>
      </location>
      <title>3 Ways for Getting Data from SharePoint : SSIS, Excel and Access</title>
      <description>Need to report on some data from SharePoint? We will look at three different techniques to pull data from a SharePoint Server. We will start with SSIS and the SharePoint List Source and Destinations. Next, We will use Excel to connect to various SharePoint lists (both online and on premise), and finally We will use Microsoft Access to do the same thing (and throw in the capability to do updates as well). At the end of the talk, We will have three different ways to get data from SharePoint.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>106019</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>106019</id>
          <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Ponce</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to get the most from Azure SQL Database</title>
      <description>In this session we will show how to get the most advantages out from Azure SQL Database.
We will learn how to monitor the performance of our workload, how to improve it and how to secure it using the tools and features at our disposal on the Azure portal without having to install 3rd party tools.
We will also see some ways to lower the costs or increase performance without having to also increase costs.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107595</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107595</id>
          <name>Edwin Martinez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Ponce</name>
      </location>
      <title>PowerBI Embedded First Steps</title>
      <description>Session about what is PowerBI Embedded, its benefits and how you can get value from it. View your reports embedded. Customize the views on your app and more...</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107781</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107781</id>
          <name>Ana Maria Bisbé York</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Juan</name>
      </location>
      <title>Escenarios de modelado en DAX, el súper lenguaje de Power BI.</title>
      <description>En el camino a la creación de buenos cuadros de mandos y modelos analíticos, se impone la necesidad de contar con un buen modelado tabular. En la sesión se analizan y solucionan un grupo de escenarios de modelado con DAX y Power BI. Estos escenarios son los que nos encontramos con frecuencia en proyectos.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105750</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105750</id>
          <name>Javier Villegas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>San Juan</name>
      </location>
      <title>Monitoring SQL Server using Community solutions (Free)</title>
      <description>In this session we will cover how to monitor and support any SQL Server Environment using free tools created by community members</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107247</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107247</id>
          <name>Eduardo Castro</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Ponce</name>
      </location>
      <title>Forecasting con SQL Server R Services y PowerBI</title>
      <description>En esta sesión veremos las capacidades que tiene SQL Server 2019 en conjunto con R Services para realizar operaciones de forecasting en nuestros sistemas, así como las capacidades que tiene PowerBI Desktop para hacer Forecasting con código R y también con R Visuals.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105759</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105759</id>
          <name>Ondrej Aubrecht</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Fajardo</name>
      </location>
      <title>Can really Naming Convention and standards save your environment ?</title>
      <description>Are you managing your "chaos" environment but still can't move forward to start any improvements and automation successfully?

Do you really know how is your SQL instance, permissions and servers configured and why are you still missing strong and persistence naming structure and standards? 

This session will be focusing on the Naming convention and standards in the infrastructure environment and how to apply it correctly, which also includes SQL Database objects.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107293</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107293</id>
          <name>Ahias Portillo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Ponce</name>
      </location>
      <title>Delivering a Data Warehouse in the Cloud</title>
      <description>When you need to scale your data warehouse's storage and processing capabilities in minutes, not months, you need a cloud-based massively parallel processing solution.

What you'll learn

Choosing a massively parallel processing architecture for a cloud-based data warehouse.
Designing tables and indexes to efficiently distribute data in tables across many nodes.
Loading data from a variety of sources, querying using PolyBase, securing and recovering data, and integrating into Big Data environments.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105887</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105887</id>
          <name>Ruslan Zolotukhin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Fajardo</name>
      </location>
      <title>Demystification of Calculation Groups in Analysis Services Tabular</title>
      <description>Calculation Groups is a new feature for Analysis Services Tabular and Power BI Premium. They can significantly reduce the number of redundant measures by grouping common measure expressions as elements of a calculation. At the webinar, we will look at creating such groups, managing them, their limitations, and how to use them from Power BI Desktop.</description>
      <startTime>10/10/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/10/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>