<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #717 - Wheeling 2018</name>
    <startDate>4/28/2018 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatWheeling</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>West Virginia Northern Community College</name>
      <street>1704 Market Street</street>
      <city>Wheeling</city>
      <state>West Virginia</state>
      <zipcode>26003</zipcode>
      <longitude>-80.7218085</longitude>
      <latitude>40.0630222</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1296</importID>
      <name>West Virginia Northern Community College</name>
      <label>Venue Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.wvncc.edu/CampusWheeling/AboutWheelingCampus.htm</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.johnsterrett.com/img/WNCCLogo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2023</importID>
      <name>New Horizons Computer Learning Centers of Pittsburgh</name>
      <label>Personal Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.nhpittsburgh.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.nhpittsburgh.com/Portals/131/nh-logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74229</importID>
      <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tracy Boggiano is a Senior Database Administrator for DocuSIgn. She has spent over 20 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1999, and is currently certified as an MCSE Data Platform. Tracy has worked on SQL Server since 6.5. She has spoken at local user groups and numerous SQLSaturdays. She is currently a co-leader of a TriPASS Local Group in Raleigh, NC.   

Tracy also tinkered with databases in middle school to keep her sports card collection organized. She blogs at databasesuperhero.com. 

Her passion outside of SQL Server is volunteering with foster children as their advocate in court through volunteerforgal.org and being a mental health advocate as part of the PAIMI NC Advisory Council.</description>
      <twitter>TracyBoggiano</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyboggiano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://databasesuperhero.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TracyBoggiano</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71123</importID>
      <name>John Deardurff</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John has been a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) for over 20 years teaching Azure, SQL Server, Exchange Server, and Windows Server networking courses. He is currently a SQL Premier Field Engineer for Microsoft. He is an MCT Regional Lead for the Eastern United States and a former Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>SQLMCT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/JohnDeardurff</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlmct.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLMCT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74284</importID>
      <name>Hilary Cotter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hilary Cotteris a 20 year IT veteran who has answered over 20,000 questions on the forums. Some of them correctly. He specializes in HA technologies, especially replication, performance tuning, full-text search, and SQL Server Service Broker.
 
Hilary is also an author, or contributor on a number of books on SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73943</importID>
      <name>Jeremy Frye</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeremy Frye is the manager of the Business Intelligence and data warehousing team at RDX. He is a Business Intelligence architect and developer with a background in database administration as well. Jeremy has over 9 years of experience in SQL Server. He has spoken on BI topics at many SQLSaturday's throughout the country, webinars, and local and remote SQL user groups. In his spare time, Jeremy often spends time trying to bridge the gap between keyboard strokes and workout reps.</description>
      <twitter>SQLBInstein</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremyilfrye</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://jeremyfrye.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLBInstein</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71378</importID>
      <name>Peter Shore</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Shore is a seasoned IT professional with over 25 years of experience. He took the accidentally intentional DBA plunge in 2013 and has discovered that he loves to find the stories the data has to tell. Peter is comfortable working with both physical and virtual servers, where he tries to apply best practices to attain performance improvements. He is also adept at bridging the gap between technical and business language in order to bring technology solutions to business needs.</description>
      <twitter>pshore73</twitter>
      <linkedin>Public Profile         https://www.linkedin.com/in/petershore</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pshore73</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71198</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74220</importID>
      <name>Jeremy Sinclair</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I'm an Enterprise .NET Developer with years of experience with PowerShell, SharePoint, Xamarin, Windows Phone/UWP Development. Finding interesting and awkward ways of achieving results are my specialty.</description>
      <twitter>sinclairinator</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremy-sinclair-39b6256</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sinclairinat0r.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sinclairinator</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74222</importID>
      <name>Devon Leann Ramirez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Devon Leann Ramirez is a SQL Developer and PASS community volunteer with 7 years of SQL Server experience. She graduated with a degree in Actuarial Science from the University of Texas at Austin and has since worked on business intelligence projects, data governance, and data quality initiatives in the insurance sector. In her free time, she loves karaoke, bravo TV, and staring at puppies on Instagram.</description>
      <twitter>@RestinBeachFace</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/devon-leann-ramirez-425b1a27/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blogs.sentryone.com/author/devon_ramirez/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@RestinBeachFace</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71217</importID>
      <name>Jim Donahoe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jim is a Premier Field Engineer for Microsoft in the Data/AI space.  He lives in Pittsburgh in a small suburb.  He loves working with all things Azure(ARM templates, DBaaS, SQL on IaaS).  He is an avid collector of retro video games! He is a member of the Idera ACE program for 2018.</description>
      <twitter>SQLFlipFlopsDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlflipflopsdba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLFlipFlopsDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71176</importID>
      <name>Eugene Meidinger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eugene Meidinger works as a BI consultant and full time Pluralsight author. He currently focuses on content on Power BI and related products. He also leads the Pittsburgh Power BI User Group. He is certified in querying and administering SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlgene</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlgene.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlgene</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73991</importID>
      <name>Kevin Boles</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Boles is a SQL Server expert, working exclusively with the product since v6.5. With over 25 years of database experience and over 45,000 man hours of SQL Server engine experience, he holds many related certifications, is an MCT and was a SQL Server MVP from 2007 to 2012. Kevin has been a very successful independent consultant for over 20 years. His passion is the relational engine, especially designing, building, analyzing and tuning high-performance database applications.</description>
      <twitter>@TheSQLGuru</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/thesqlguru</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TheSQLGuru</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74035</importID>
      <name>Andrew Loree</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrew Loree has over nineteen years of database experience with roles in architecture, design, development, and implementation of enterprise-scale SQL Server data solutions, supporting industries from legal e-discovery to manufacturing. Areas of expertise since SQL 
Server 2000 include data migration and ETL/ELT solutions, disaster recovery planning, high availability service design, licensing and virtualization. Andrew holds fourteen Microsoft certifications, has both a  Bachelor and Masters of Science in Computer Science from Wright State University and is a Columbus (Ohio) PASS board member.</description>
      <twitter>@LowOnDiskSpace</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewloree</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.andyloree.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@LowOnDiskSpace</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74264</importID>
      <name>Kerry Tyler</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kerry Tyler is a SQL Server, Business Intelligence, and Azure consultant. His initial IT experience was in network engineering and Windows system administration before moving into the data realm. This infrastructure background builds a firm foundation for performance tuning and cloud infrastructure design and implementation. Kerry has full-time DBA experience in SQL Server since version 2000 and business intelligence architecture since SQL Server 2005. In addition to consulting work, he delivers presentations and training on SQL Server administration, business intelligence, and Azure data and infrastructure components.</description>
      <twitter>AirborneGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kerrytyler</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://airbornegeek.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AirborneGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71715</importID>
      <name>Drew Furgiuele</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Drew Furgiuele is a senior DBA that lives in Dublin, Ohio who is passionate about SQL Server and PowerShell. He's been working with SQL Server since 2002. When he’s not accidentally dropping tables in production, he likes writing automation scripts, blogging about SQL Server Replication, wiring electronics, playing board games, and spending time with his dog. He's also not embarrassed by his Spotify playlists.</description>
      <twitter>pittfurg</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pittfurg</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.port1433.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pittfurg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72782</importID>
      <name>Michael John</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With 20 years experience in all aspects of development and administration of SQL Server, from version 6.5 to 2016, I have seen, broken, and fixed just about everything in SQL Server!</description>
      <twitter>#Progeek11</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-john-3403b45/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=#Progeek11</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74252</importID>
      <name>Brian Carrig</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brian Carrig is a Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server and is currently a Senior Program Manager on the SQL Server Tiger Team at Microsoft focusing primarily on persistent memory technology and replication. In a previous life, Brian spent some time as an academic and holds a PhD in Computer Science. He is a native of Dublin, Ireland but now lives with his wife and two daughters in Redmond, Washington. If he is not talking about, thinking about or working with technology you will usually find him watching Chelsea FC.</description>
      <twitter>@briancarrig</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@briancarrig</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72774</importID>
      <name>Hasan Savran</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hasan Savran is a BI Architect at Progressive Insurance Company. He spends his days architecting cutting edge business solutions by using the latest Web and Database technologies. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer.
Hasan has spoken at many SQL Saturdays, Code Camps and User groups. He is an active member of the HTML5 and WebAssembly W3C groups. He likes to write about SQL, CosmosDB, C#, and Front End development on his blog.</description>
      <twitter>Savranweb</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/hasansavran/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://h-savran.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Savranweb</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74277</importID>
      <name>Tamera Clark</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tamera Clark has been involved in the IT industry for greater than ten years, with experiences ranging from systems analysis/engineering to SQL Server and SSRS administration/development. She is an active member of the SQL Server community, participating in the Women in Technology Virtual Chapter, Co-leading the Nashville BI Chapter, assisting the Nashville PASS Chapter and serving as a Regional Mentor.  Tamera is also the event chair of SQLSaturday Nashville.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/tameraclark</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/tameraclark/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tameraclark.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/tameraclark</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73795</importID>
      <name>Jay Falck</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I started as a night shift computer operator out of high school. I moved to applications development after graduation from SAC. After a few years with the State as an applications developer, the manager of Systems Programming decided it would be better to have me on the inside looking out rather than on the outside trying to get in. I spent the next 14 years as a mainframe system programmer for two state agencies. In 1996 I moved to Healthcare IT and have been that ever since. I’ve spent most of the past 14 years doing ETL, performance and HIPAA security. In these various jobs, I’ve used all manner of databases including InfoTec IMP, IBM VSAM and DB2, Interbase, Informix, Universe, Oracle 9i and SQL Server from 6.0 to 2008 R2.</description>
      <twitter>@jayfalck</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jayfalck</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@jayfalck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72863</importID>
      <name>Carlos L Chacon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Chacon is the managing partner of SQL Data Partners LLC and co-host of the popular SQL Data Partners Podcast.  While getting his start as a typical accidental DBA, Carlos has sat on Microsoft exam review panels, served as regional mentor and chapter leader.  He enjoys traveling and has been to four continents, speaks Spanish and can eat his weight in raspberries (not yet proven).  He and his family live in Richmond, Virginia.</description>
      <twitter>@CarlosLChacon</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/carloslchacon</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldatapartners.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@CarlosLChacon</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>71378</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71378</id>
          <name>Peter Shore</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 312</name>
      </location>
      <title>Infrastructure for the DBA: An Introduction</title>
      <description>It doesn’t matter if you are a Junior DBA, an accidental DBA or all the way up to a Senior DBA, the infrastructure your SQL Server environment runs on is important.  Many among the DBA community came in as developers or perhaps directly into database administration roles it is equally possible that you have been out of the operations world long enough to have fallen out of the loop with what is happening.  This session is intended to provide a full stack infrastructure overview so that you can talk shop with your cohorts in operations to resolve issues and maybe even be proactive.  We will discuss, in an introductory fashion, hardware, network, storage, virtualization and operating system layers.  Additionally, some suggestions as to where to find more information will be provided.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71217</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71217</id>
          <name>Jim Donahoe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Development  Implementation</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 301</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting started with SQL Azure Database: What you need to know</title>
      <description>Azure SQL Database offers a way quickly spin up new databases with minimal management requirements. However, the number of differences between on-premises SQL Server and Azure SQL Database can be overwhelming. Even worse, with DBaaS it’s not clear who is responsible for what anymore.
In this session, we will cover all the basic steps of getting your first Azure SQL Database instance spun up. We’ll cover common gotchas, like firewall settings and resource locks. We’ll also dive into some more advanced options with templates, allowing you to make your processes reproducible.
By the end of this presentation, you’ll understand if Azure SQL Database is the right choice for you and your needs. You’ll understand how it can simplify management and allow you to scale easily. Finally, you’ll have the confidence to go and create your own instance with ease.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71715</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71715</id>
          <name>Drew Furgiuele</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 303</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server and PowerShell: Let's Get Serious</title>
      <description>Whether you’ve dabbled in PowerShell or wondered what all the fuss is about, make no mistake: PowerShell isn’t going away. It is definitely something worth learning to make your life as a SQL Server professional easier, and allow you to advance in your career as a DBA.

In this session, you’ll see practical, real-world examples of how you can blend SQL Server and PowerShell together. You’ll also get a look at the SQL Server PowerShell provider and how you can incorporate it into your automation scripts.

Instead of focusing on syntax, the session will plunge straight into examples and highlight various snippets of code and how they work. You can expect to see code examples on how PowerShell can do anything from comparing tables across servers, automating and centralizing your backups, and even doing in-depth security audits.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74035</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74035</id>
          <name>Andrew Loree</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 301</name>
      </location>
      <title>Microsoft Machine Learning Services</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2017 Machine Learning Services is more than just R and Python language support for SQL Server.  SQL Machine Learning Services provides analytics for any size of data, runs in SQL Server, or alongside Windows, Linux, HDInsight Spark or Hadoop clusters, is simple to administer and allows you to integrate and deploy simply.  In this session, learn architecture and deployment options, stand-alone and in-database, along with some real-world use-cases.  Learn how to leverage Machine Learning Services with new TSQL language support, training and deploying models, scaling beyond memory with RevoScaleR to generating millisecond predictions in-database.  With any size data environment, SQL Machine Learning Services can provide analytics in both an operationally sound and easy to administer paradigm.

A beginner level understanding of Machine Learning and process is highly recommended but not required.  Beyond SQL Machine Learning Services, an overview of all Microsoft Machine Learning</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74264</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74264</id>
          <name>Kerry Tyler</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery, Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 313</name>
      </location>
      <title>45 Minutes to Your First SSAS Tabular Model</title>
      <description>Have you been watching SSAS Tabular develop? What about the new Azure Analysis Services product? Or you've looked at these and like what they can add in Power BI or classic BI scenarios, but haven't had a chance to dive in and figure all of this out? Now is the time!
SSAS Tabular is a new-ish form of business intelligence model released with SQL Server 2012, intended as an alternative to more traditional Multidimensional cubes. In this session, we will talk briefly about what Tabular is and what it does, in addition to the various options for deployment, before exploring the development process of creating a tabular model ready for ad-hoc querying through Excel or Power BI.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74222</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74222</id>
          <name>Devon Leann Ramirez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 313</name>
      </location>
      <title>Handcrafting Covering Indexes</title>
      <description>Do you have a need for speed but cannot change the code? Covering indexes might be your best friend. You might have heard about covering indexes, but what are they exactly and how do you design one? In this session, we explore what covering indexes are, why you might or might not need one, how to craft them, and how to test them for effectiveness. By the end of the session, you will be prepared to make effective indexing decisions while tuning individual queries.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>72782</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>72782</id>
          <name>Michael John</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 301</name>
      </location>
      <title>What I wish I knew as a beginning DBA.</title>
      <description>This session will pull everything together about being a DBA.  What steps to take to get hired as a DBA, , continuous learning ideas, and QA with a panel of experienced DBA's</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74229</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74229</id>
          <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 303</name>
      </location>
      <title>Monitoring Availability Groups</title>
      <description>Once you have successfully configured Availability Groups, what comes next? In this session, we will go beyond setup and look at how to monitor your Availability Groups.  We will define and cover important metrics and alerts you need to manage a database in an Availability Group.  

You will walk away from this session with tools you need to monitor your environment and know how to respond to alerts.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>72863</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>72863</id>
          <name>Carlos L Chacon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 303</name>
      </location>
      <title>How can containers for my database help me?</title>
      <description>It seems like web apps are getting all the love and at first glance it may be hard to identify a good way to use the database in containers.  This session will review the concept of containers and attempt to identify ways we might benefit from this new technology as we support our users.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74220</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74220</id>
          <name>Jeremy Sinclair</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 303</name>
      </location>
      <title>Eliminating the CRUD with Entity Framework Core</title>
      <description>Developers need to insert and query data stored in databases, but never want to enter the land of building SQL stored procedures for everything. I want to give an approach to CRUD without caring about the underlying database container. We're .NET Developers, we like to write structures in a way that makes sense to us. In this case, Entity Framework Core is a brilliant option that layers on top of MySQL, Postgres SQL, and MS SQL, to name a few.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>72774</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>72774</id>
          <name>Hasan Savran</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>IT Professional or Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 301</name>
      </location>
      <title>What's new in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2017 has great new additions and features for everybody. If you are a developer, you want to learn about new Graph tables, new M.O.T enhancements, and new functions. If you are a BI developer, you want to learn about how to run R and Python in SQL Server. If you are a DBA, you might want to learn about new features like Resumable Online Indexes, Automatic Query Optimization and how to monitor R and Python scripts. This session will have overall information about new features of SQL Server 2017</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74284</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74284</id>
          <name>Hilary Cotter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 312</name>
      </location>
      <title>Stress testing SQL Server</title>
      <description>How high can we go? Frequently in your career as a DBA you will be asked how much load can your SQL Server support. In this session,  Hilary Cotter, shows you how to Microsoft tools to stress test your application and determine what your bottlenecks are and how high you can ramp up your workload.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71176</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71176</id>
          <name>Eugene Meidinger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 312</name>
      </location>
      <title>Execution Plans 101</title>
      <description>Do you have a query that you want to tune, but don't know where to start? Execution plans can be a great starting point for understanding what your query is doing under the hood. This course covers the bare bones basics: what an execution plan is, how to run them, how to read them, and additional features.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74277</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74277</id>
          <name>Tamera Clark</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery, Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 313</name>
      </location>
      <title>45 min to build your first SSRS report</title>
      <description>Does this sound like you? You've been BI curious and now you've been given access to SSRS and you want to make a report. Or, you're a DBA or DBA Dev and could use a report to reduce daily task. Either way, I've got your back! You will learn everything you need to know to get that first report out the door quickly and how to tweak it once it’s deployed.  We’ll use SSRS (SQL Server Reporting Services) 2016. The query makes no difference, this time it's all about the output.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71123</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71123</id>
          <name>John Deardurff</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>IT Professional or Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 301</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to get Microsoft Certified</title>
      <description>Microsoft has recently streamlined the certification process and this session focuses on what you need to know to get Microsoft Certified on SQL Server. The session is led by an expert Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) and Microsoft MVP who regularly teaches the SQL Server certification courses. The presenter walks you through the certifications, exams, and resources available to get you ready for success.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74252</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74252</id>
          <name>Brian Carrig</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 303</name>
      </location>
      <title>Successfully Running SQL Server in AWS</title>
      <description>Amazon Web Services (AWS) is the world's largest public cloud hosting provider, with many companies successfully running SQL server on AWS infrastructure, but trying to make sense of the available options can be daunting. In this session, we will explore the options available for running SQL server in AWS, either as a managed service or using dedicated EC2 instances. We will document the different storage options, High Availability strategies, as well as important security and maintenance caveats. We will also cover various licensing approaches  available when running SQL server in AWS.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71198</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71198</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 312</name>
      </location>
      <title>Working Effectively With Legacy SQL</title>
      <description>A legacy code base can be a frightening thing.  Between strict deadlines, ever-evolving requirements, differing skill levels of contributors over time, and historical circumstances, keeping database code clean and concise is difficult at best.  This example- and demo-driven talk will help you build out a mental framework to prune those gnarled code bases.  Much of this talk will be familiar to software developers who know of the "clean code" philosophy, but no knowledge of the topic is necessary.  If you shudder whenever you look at your SQL code base, this talk may be for you.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73943</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73943</id>
          <name>Jeremy Frye</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery, Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 313</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS Incremental Loading:  The Tortoise and The Hare</title>
      <description>Extracting, transforming and loading data has become a major component to satisfying business requirements and needs.  Depending on the size of the data you are working with, the way you design your SSIS packages can have an impact on performance and run times.  

In this session, we will cover a variety of incremental design approaches centered around large data sets using SSIS.  We will look at the architecture of each ETL strategy to determine the pros and cons and generate specific use cases to decide which strategy yields optimal results.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73991</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73991</id>
          <name>Kevin Boles</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 312</name>
      </location>
      <title>Know What Your Code is Doing to SQL Server!</title>
      <description>ORMs - oh how I LOVE them! As a consultant, when I see them in play at a client I go KACHIIINNNNGGGG!! :-D Seriously though, they can provide some substantial benefits for coding throughput. But if you don't Read The Fine Manual and do some things right and avoid some major gotchas you will fall prey to one of my favorite Guruisms: "Anything that allows developers to slap code together more quickly is inversely proportional to the performance and concurrency you will get from that code"! Although this talk is based on Entity Framework, most ORMs suffer from a lot of the same flaws.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73795</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73795</id>
          <name>Jay Falck</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 313</name>
      </location>
      <title>Linux for SQL Server</title>
      <description>SQL Server is now available on Linux but you only know Windows, now what? During this session we'll introduce the Linux version of Windows commands you use on a daily basis for administering SQL Server. We'll look at updating Linux, updating SQL Server, moving files between Windows and Linux, and backing up and restoring databases from one system to another. We'll also look at default file locations for SQL Server and what can be moved and how to accomplish that.</description>
      <startTime>4/28/2018 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/28/2018 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>