<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #962 – Richmond - Virtual 2020</name>
    <startDate>4/25/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSATRVA</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Goodwill</name>
      <street>6301 Midlothian Turnpike, Richmond, VA</street>
      <city>Richmond</city>
      <state>Virginia</state>
      <zipcode>23225</zipcode>
      <longitude>-77.5108124</longitude>
      <latitude>37.5029113</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2321</importID>
      <name>Marathon Consulting</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.marathonus.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/962/EventSponsor_14764.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1088</importID>
      <name>SQL Data Partners LLC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqldatapartners.com/podcast</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/962/EventSponsor_14767.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101121</importID>
      <name>George Walkey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server DBA, Developer, IT Manager, Business Owner from the Richmond, VA USA Area
Interested in pushing the limits of both hardware software and my own brain</description>
      <twitter>sqlbytehd</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://insyncva.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlbytehd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103790</importID>
      <name>Travis Lawrence</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Travis Lawrence is an Azure Data Engineer working at CapTech as a consultant with five years of experience in analysis, design, and development. His recent focus has been building out real-time data solutions and migrating on-prem DW’s and operational systems to the cloud.  Travis is a certified Azure Data Engineer and Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/datatravis/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>102282</importID>
      <name>Sarah Patrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sarah has presented at several TechGirlz workshops for the Boys and Girls Club of Harford County, as an advocate for women in STEM. Sarah graduated from the Science and Mathematics Academy in Aberdeen, MD in May 2018, where she presented her senior capstone project "Engineering peer credibility via mastery of roles," where she designed roles for an ad hoc team. She worked with an army professional from CERDEC. She is currently attending the University of Maryland - College Park to major in Information Science. Sarah completed an internship with the Project Management Institute, helping them with their Professional Development Event, and worked as at the SharePoint Intern at Smithsonian Institution’s Office of the Chief Information Officer.</description>
      <twitter>sarahepatrick</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarahepatrick/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sarahepatrick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101119</importID>
      <name>David Patrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave has been developing database applications for over 25 years. An MCT since 2001, he has taught many classes from Intro to Visual Interdev to Advanced SharePoint Development. Dave runs two user groups, the Maryland and Pennsylvania Microsoft Developers User Group, www.mapamdug.com, and MAD SharePoint, www.madsharepoint.com. Dave does SharePoint training and development for DSA, Inc., a DoD contractor that does great work for the Army over at Aberdeen Proving Ground. Dave is also an MVP.</description>
      <twitter>DavidEPatrick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidepatrick</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.madsharepoint.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DavidEPatrick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103787</importID>
      <name>Kevin Kline</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Kline is a database and industry expert serving as Principal Program Manager at SentryOne, the industry leading SQL Server database tools vendor. A Microsoft SQL Server MVP since 2003, he is a founder and former president of PASS. Kevin is an author of many books, blogger, columnist, and popular international speaker. Kevin’s best known book is the best-selling SQL in a Nutshell and contributes monthly to Database Trends  Applications magazine. He tweets at @kekline and blogs at http://Blogs.SQLSentry.com/Author/KevinKline.</description>
      <twitter>kekline</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kekline/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.sentryone.com/author/kevinkline</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kekline</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104286</importID>
      <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wayne Sheffield, a Microsoft Certified Master in SQL Server and Microsoft Most Valuable Professional, started working with xBase databases in the late 80’s. With over 25 years in IT, he has worked with SQL Server (since 6.5 in the late 90’s) in various dev/admin roles, with an emphasis in performance tuning. He is the author of several articles at www.sqlservercentral.com, a co-author of “SQL Server T-SQL Recipes”, and enjoys sharing his knowledge by presenting at SQL events worldwide and blogging at http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</description>
      <twitter>@DBAWayne</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/WayneSheffield</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DBAWayne</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103681</importID>
      <name>Louis Davidson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Louis Davidson has worked in the IT industry for over 25 years as a corporate database developer and architect. He has been a Microsoft SQL Server MVP for 15 years and has written five books on database design, and contributed to many other SQL Server books as an author and tech editor. He has a bachelor's degree in Computer Science from the University of Tennessee at Chattanooga. You can read more about Louis at http://drsql.org.</description>
      <twitter>drsql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/louisdavidson</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/louis-davidson/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=drsql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104539</importID>
      <name>Taiob Ali</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Taiob Ali, MVP Data Platform, is an accomplished technical leader with a proven record of success. For 14 years, he has worked with the Microsoft Data Platform and MongoDB both on-premise and cloud. His experience includes all three major business sectors: finance, e-commerce, and healthcare. Taiob has hands-on experience in managing large database projects, massive data migration, intricate process design, testing and deployment, performance tuning, long term capacity planning.
Taiob is currently working at “GMO LLC” as a Database Solution Manager, focusing on cloud migration, automation, improving, and streamlining operational workflow. He is a regular speaker at local and virtual PASS chapters, SQL Saturdays, and Azure conferences.</description>
      <twitter>SqlWorldWide</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlworldwide</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlworldwide.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SqlWorldWide</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101139</importID>
      <name>Mohammad Darab</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mohammad Darab is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Certified Kubernetes Administrator, Certified Kubernetes Application Developer, speaker and blogger with over 19 years of IT professional experience, 10+ years of that working with SQL Server. He is passionate about SQL Server Big Data Clusters, Kubernetes and overall professional development.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/mwdarab</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mdarab/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mohammaddarab.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/mwdarab</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103805</importID>
      <name>Stephen Leonard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Howdy, my name's Stephen. I hail from the flatlands of Virginia. I'm 17 and really into Linux and putting software on devices that they don't belong on.</description>
      <twitter>StephenRL221</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=StephenRL221</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104522</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101167</importID>
      <name>Tony McGovern</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hacker. Artist. Storyteller. Data lover.

Using machine learning models and data mining techniques, I solve hard, analytical problems for my clients to create meaningful insight out of data. I find the whole process of discovering, cleaning, analyzing, and visualizing data extremely rewarding. I have both an unending love for cutting-edge technologies and a dogged determination to solve the difficult problems others run away from.</description>
      <twitter>twitter.com/tonmcg</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tony-mcgovern-1ab6778/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://tonymcgovern.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=twitter.com/tonmcg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103519</importID>
      <name>Steve Jones</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Jones is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and has been working with SQL Server since version 4.2 on OS/2. After working as a DBA and developer for a variety of companies, Steve co-founded the community website SQLServerCentral.com in 2001.
Since 2004, Steve has been the full-time editor of the site, ensuring it continues to be a great resource for SQL Server professionals. Over the last decade, Steve has written hundreds of articles about SQL Server for SQLServerCentral.com, SQL Server Standard magazine, SQL Server Magazine, and Database Journal.</description>
      <twitter>way0utwest</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/way0utwest</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.voiceofthedba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=way0utwest</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104525</importID>
      <name>Jim Donahoe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jim is a Premier Field Engineer for Microsoft in the Data/AI space.  He lives in Pittsburgh in a small suburb.  He loves working with all things Azure(ARM templates, DBaaS, SQL on IaaS).  He is an avid collector of retro video games! He is a member of the Idera ACE program for 2018.</description>
      <twitter>SQLFlipFlopsDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlflipflopsdba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLFlipFlopsDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104470</importID>
      <name>Jason Brimhall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jason Brimhall has more than 20 years of experience and has worked with SQL Server 6.5 through SQL Server 2019. He has experience in performance tuning, high transaction environments, and large environments. He is currently a consultant specializing in performance tuning, server analysis, and problem resolution. Jason is a Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) and a Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>sqlrnnr</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbajbrimhall/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://jasonbrimhall.info</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlrnnr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103785</importID>
      <name>Kevin Kline</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Kline is a database and industry expert serving as Principal Program Manager at SentryOne, the industry leading SQL Server database tools vendor. A Microsoft SQL Server MVP since 2003, he is a founder and former president of PASS. Kevin is an author of many books, blogger, columnist, and popular international speaker. Kevin’s best known book is the best-selling SQL in a Nutshell and contributes monthly to Database Trends  Applications magazine. He tweets at @kekline and blogs at http://Blogs.SQLSentry.com/Author/KevinKline.</description>
      <twitter>kekline</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kekline/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.sentryone.com/author/kevinkline</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kekline</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>102454</importID>
      <name>Rick Heiges</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick is a Former Data Platfrom MVP  and Sr. Consultant for Microsoft where he focuses on working with customers on their data estate. His career includes work as a DBA, University full-time faculty member, Systems Analyst, Project Leader, and Developer. He has found his passion in working with data and the community. Rick served nine years on the PASS Board of Directors and spearheaded the popular 24 Hours of PASS event. He also started his local User Group in 2002. Today, he spends much of his time with his head in the clouds.</description>
      <twitter>heigesr2</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rick-heiges/1/b93/777/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/rick_heiges/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=heigesr2</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104469</importID>
      <name>Jason Brimhall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jason Brimhall has more than 20 years of experience and has worked with SQL Server 6.5 through SQL Server 2019. He has experience in performance tuning, high transaction environments, and large environments. He is currently a consultant specializing in performance tuning, server analysis, and problem resolution. Jason is a Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) and a Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>sqlrnnr</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbajbrimhall/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://jasonbrimhall.info</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlrnnr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104521</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104556</importID>
      <name>Thomas Norman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tom Norman is a Database Architect at KPA with a strong fervor to protect data. He works daily to review and improve data protection methodologies while reviewing governing laws affecting finance, healthcare, and personal data. His areas of expertise include encryption, auditing, data identification, and database object deployment. He is the current leader of the PASS Virtualization Group and Vice President of the TRIPASS user group. You can read his blog at https://armordba.com/ and reach him on twitter at @armordba. Tom speaks at a number of SQLSaturday events and SQL Server user groups.</description>
      <twitter>ArmorDba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armordba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://armordba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ArmorDba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103679</importID>
      <name>Louis Davidson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Louis Davidson has worked in the IT industry for over 25 years as a corporate database developer and architect. He has been a Microsoft SQL Server MVP for 15 years and has written five books on database design, and contributed to many other SQL Server books as an author and tech editor. He has a bachelor's degree in Computer Science from the University of Tennessee at Chattanooga. You can read more about Louis at http://drsql.org.</description>
      <twitter>drsql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/louisdavidson</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/louis-davidson/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=drsql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104534</importID>
      <name>Angela Henry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Angela is a Solution Architect, living in High Point, NC and loves what she does. She's worked with all versions of SQL Server  worn all the hats that come with dealing with SQL Server throughout the years: developer, administrator, data architect and BI developer. She has her MSCE in Data and Analytics (f.k.a., Business Intelligence), is a Data Platform MVP, and a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT).  She is the former chapter leader for the PASS Triad SQL User Group in Greensboro, NC. In her spare time you can probably find her in or at the pool, she's an avid US Masters Swimmer, Coach and Instructor.</description>
      <twitter>SQLSwimmer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/angelahenrydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SQLSwimmer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLSwimmer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>102659</importID>
      <name>Andy Leonard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andy Leonard is founder and Chief Data Engineer at Enterprise Data  Analytics, Microsoft Data Platform MVP, creator of the DILM (Data Integration Lifecycle Management) Suite, an SSIS trainer, consultant, developer, Business Intelligence Markup Language (Biml) developer and BimlHero, SQL Server database and data warehouse developer, community mentor, engineer, and farmer. He is a co-author of "The Biml Book and SQL Server Integration Services Design Patterns" and author of "Managing Geeks - A Journey of Leading by Doing", "Data Integration Lifecycle Management with SSIS", "Building Custom Tasks for SSIS", and the "Stairway to Integration Services". Andy blogs at andyleonard.blog where you can learn more on the About Andy page.</description>
      <twitter>AndyLeonard</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/AndyLeonard</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://andyleonard.blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyLeonard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103729</importID>
      <name>Chris Bell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Bell offers a unique view of how we live and work with data, both now and as we head into the future. Having braved many roles, lifecycles, and battles in the IT world, he has honed his DBA (Database Administration or Do 'Bout Anything) skills in Information Systems and development, focusing on SQL Server. Currently, he serves as the lead DBA at The Motley Fool. You can keep up with Chris' thoughts and technical community activities at WaterOxConsulting.com.</description>
      <twitter>@cbelldba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/christopher-bell/19/a08/93/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.wateroxconsulting.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cbelldba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104467</importID>
      <name>Jason Brimhall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jason Brimhall has more than 20 years of experience and has worked with SQL Server 6.5 through SQL Server 2019. He has experience in performance tuning, high transaction environments, and large environments. He is currently a consultant specializing in performance tuning, server analysis, and problem resolution. Jason is a Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) and a Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>sqlrnnr</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbajbrimhall/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://jasonbrimhall.info</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlrnnr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104540</importID>
      <name>Timothy McAliley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am currently a Microsoft Cloud Solutions Architect in the Washington, DC area.  Previously, I was a Microsoft Technology Solutions Professional (TSP), a Microsoft Account Technology Strategist and a SQL Server Premier Field Engineer. Prior to Microsoft, I was a Technical Trainer and DBA in the Enterprise Security Group at Symantec . I have been in IT for over 20 years. My particular interests are IT operations, IT auditing, IT audit frameworks, IT service management (ITSM), ITIL, information security, project management, and database/application tier high availability solutions. I also co-run the Northern Virginia SQL Server User Group ( @novasl) and also co-run the Azure Datafest events.</description>
      <twitter>sysframeworks</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothymcaliley/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sysframeworks</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>101167</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101167</id>
          <name>Tony McGovern</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure / Cloud / Big Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track1 - Sponsored By SQL Data Partners</name>
      </location>
      <title>Choosing the Right Data Science Services in Azure: Scale, Automate, and Deploy with Ease</title>
      <description>Microsoft Azure offers a multitude of cloud-based products that simplify the data science workflow in unique ways. Together these products each have different purposes that help the data science team with various aspects of the machine learning process.

In this session, we'll unpack the challenge in determining which product is best suited for each task. We'll explore the most popular machine learning products on Azure and describe how each fit into a typical data science workflow.

We'll also explore how to right-size your data science team to best utilize each Azure machine learning product so you’re efficiently solving problems as quickly and cheaply as possible.

By the end of this session, you'll understand how to choose the set of Azure machine learning products that fit your data science team within a typical data science workflow, allowing them to scale, automate, and deploy a machine learning process with ease.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103519</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103519</id>
          <name>Steve Jones</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track1 - Sponsored By SQL Data Partners</name>
      </location>
      <title>Adopting a Compliant Database DevOps Process</title>
      <description>DevOps is transforming software development, with many organizations and individuals adopting lean development practices, implementing Continuous Integration (CI), Continuous Deployment (CD), and performing on-demand deployments to their production environments. However, the database is largely ignored and seen as a bottleneck for a DevOps software development process. We will discuss the challenges of database development and deployment and examine why many developers find the database to be an impediment. We examine the risks of sensitive data in the development process and how you can ensure that data security concerns do not get in the way of the need for speed and agility. We’ll look at how you can adopt a Compliant Database DevOps approach that removes the database bottleneck while ensuring compliance with regulations governing the use of data within your organization such as GDPR, HIPPA or SOX.  We’ll discuss the techniques used to include the data</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103681</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103681</id>
          <name>Louis Davidson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Design  Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track1 - Sponsored By SQL Data Partners</name>
      </location>
      <title>Relational Design Critique</title>
      <description>The process of designing a relational database is not overly complex, and may be done by almost anyone on the development team. The process requires one to take the time to understand the requirements, when they exist, and apply a straightforward set of transforms to produce table structures that meets the needs. The tough part is that the process requires time and experience, neither of which anyone has enough of. In this session, to help the attendee differentiate right-enough designs from overly simple or overly complex designs, we will look at a variety of database snippets, each inspired from a real life design. We will discuss the pros and cons of the approach taken, and consider possible remediations to learn from a failure that was made by someone else.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 11:25:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 12:25:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104470</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104470</id>
          <name>Jason Brimhall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Bare Naked Skinny on SQL Server</title>
      <description>Ever feel like there are just too many layers with SQL Server? You peel off a layer and behold there is yet another layer. SQL Server is rather complex. The complexities can be rather frustrating from time to time. 

Join this NSFW (not safe for whining) session as we strip SQL down to the bare bones. I will help you undress the complexities of a few of the basic SQL Server concepts. These concepts will include locks, principals, query directives and deadlocks.

In this session I will disrobe misunderstandings related to the aforementioned topics. I will show the different types of principals in SQL Server. I will also show various scenarios involving locks and deadlocks along with some of their effects with and without query directives. The goal is to better understand these topics and to hopefully stop using and perpetuating common mis-uses of terminology and common misconceptions about the technology.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104286</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104286</id>
          <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Internals  Performance</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intelligent Query Processing in SQL Server 2019</title>
      <description>SQL Server has evolved many times over the years. SQL Server 2019 introduces “Intelligent Query Processing”, greatly enhancing the “Adaptive Query Processing” which was introduced in SQL Server 2017. Intelligent Query Processing allows your queries to operate more efficiently (resulting in better query performance) – without needing to make changes to the code or the application. In this session we will explore all the Intelligent Query Processing features in SQL Server 2019. Time permitting, we will go into other changes in recent versions of SQL Server (such as execution plan changes and new Dynamic Management Objects) that will help improve your efficiency at troubleshooting and tuning SQL Server. Coming away from this session, you will have plenty of reasons to want to upgrade to SQL Server 2019 immediately!</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103785</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103785</id>
          <name>Kevin Kline</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Internals  Performance</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track3</name>
      </location>
      <title>An In-depth Look Inside SQL Server</title>
      <description>Let’s face it.  You can effectively do many IT jobs related to SQL Server without knowing the internals of how SQL Server works.  Many great developers, DBAs, and designers get their day-to-day work completed on time and with reasonable quality while never really knowing what’s happening behind the scenes.  But if you want to take your skills to the next level, it’s critical to know SQL Server’s internal processes and architecture.  This session will answer questions like:
-       What are the various areas of memory inside of SQL Server?
-       How are queries handled behind the scenes?
-       What does SQL Server do with procedural code, like functions, procedures, and triggers?
-       What happens during checkpoints?  Lazywrites?
-       How are IOs handled with regards to transaction logs and database?
-       What happens when transaction logs and databases grow or shrinks?</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104467</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104467</id>
          <name>Jason Brimhall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Master Level</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Becoming Ever More Intimate with your Indexes</title>
      <description>Among the many critical and basic concepts to understand within SQL Server comes the concept of indexes. Indexes can be a significant asset or a scary detriment to your environment. During this session we will work through the basics of indexing within SQL Server and then explore some of the more interesting misconceptions I have encountered. 

Do you know how useful your indexes are? Do you know if your indexes might be a bit piggy? Do you know the impact of the indexes on your execution plans? These are just a few of the many questions that I will cover throughout the session as we move quickly through this important topic.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 11:25:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 1:25:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104556</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104556</id>
          <name>Thomas Norman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Encrypting Data within SQL Server</title>
      <description>Data breaches abound! Do you want to keep your company out of the headlines? What are some of the data privacy laws affecting you? How will encrypting data affect your database performance? What data fields should you encrypt?  What else can you do to protect your sensitive data?
 
In this session, we will review each option to encrypt data within SQL Server, Transparent Data Encryption, Cell Level Encryption and Always Encrypted. While we look at the encryption options, we will review both on-premise and cloud offerings.  This session will deep dive into setting up Always Encrypted encryption and share experiences implementing the encryption.   
 
You will leave this session with a deeper understanding about SQL Server encryption options and how encryption can affect your performance.  Also, you will gather information on how to fully protect and review your sensitive data usage.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104521</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104521</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track4 - Sponsored By Marathon Consulting</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Virtualization with PolyBase</title>
      <description>PolyBase is Microsoft's data virtualization technology, allowing you to integrate SQL Server with external systems such as Hadoop and Azure Blob Storage.  As of SQL Server 2019, PolyBase also allows you to connect to diverse systems such as Oracle, MongoDB, Cosmos DB, Teradata, Apache Spark, and even other SQL Server instances.  In this talk, we will walk through the mechanics of PolyBase, showing how we can write T-SQL queries to access data from heterogeneous sources.  We will investigate the Dynamic Management Views (DMVs) and other resources needed to tease out what the PolyBase engine is doing behind the scenes and where to go when things break down.  Finally, we will look at several interesting use cases for PolyBase in the modern data environment.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103790</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103790</id>
          <name>Travis Lawrence</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track1 - Sponsored By SQL Data Partners</name>
      </location>
      <title>Git Ready to Reduce Errors and Deploy Faster with Azure DevOps and tSQL-t Unit Tests</title>
      <description>DataOps is becoming increasingly important to keep pace with application development in a manageable way. With Azure DevOps and tSQL-t unit test, data professionals can set up data-friendly CI/CD pipelines that will reduce errors and decrease deployment time. 

In this session, we will explore the following:
•	Challenges of implementing DataOps
•	Creating the Visual Studio database solution project
•	Integration with source control
•	Creating tSQL-t unit tests for the database
•	Creating Azure DevOps Pipelines 
•	Deploying Changes

Join this session and reduce your stress the next time you deploy your DB. After this session you will have the foundational knowledge for implementing DataOps on your project.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104539</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104539</id>
          <name>Taiob Ali</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track4 - Sponsored By Marathon Consulting</name>
      </location>
      <title>Think like the Cardinality Estimator</title>
      <description>SQL Server uses a phase during query optimization, called cardinality estimation (CE). This process makes estimates bases on the statistics as to how many rows flow from one query plan iterator to the next.  Knowing how CE generates these numbers will enable you to write better TSQL code and, in turn, influence the type of physical operations during query execution.  Based on that estimated rows, the query processor decides how to access an object, which physical join to use, how to sort the data.  Do you know how the CE generates these numbers?  What happens when you have multiple predicates, range predicates, variable values that are “NOT KNOWN” to the optimizer, or you have predicate values increasing in ascending order? Do you know what will happen if your predicate is using a value that is outside of the histogram range?  

In this session, I will show you how CE estimates in all of these scenarios, and you will walk out better equipped to tackle those nasty, hard to solve query p</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104525</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104525</id>
          <name>Jim Donahoe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track4 - Sponsored By Marathon Consulting</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting started with Azure SQL Database: What You Need To Know!</title>
      <description>Azure SQL Database offers a way quickly spin up new databases with minimal management requirements. However, the number of differences between on-premises SQL Server and Azure SQL Database can be overwhelming. Even worse, with DBaaS it’s not clear who is responsible for what anymore. In this session, we will cover all the basic steps of getting your first Azure SQL Database instance spun up. We’ll cover common gotchas, like firewall settings and resource locks. We’ll also dive into some more advanced options with templates, allowing you to make your processes reproducible. By the end of this presentation, you’ll understand if Azure SQL Database is the right choice for you and your needs. You’ll understand how it can simplify management and allow you to scale easily. Finally, you’ll have the confidence to go and create your own instance with ease.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103787</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103787</id>
          <name>Kevin Kline</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Uncommon Techniques Every SQL Programmer Should Know</title>
      <description>SELECT statements have a reputation for being very easy to write, but hard to write very well. This session will take you through ten of the most problematic patterns and anti-patterns when writing queries and how to deal with them all.  Loaded with live demonstrations and useful techniques, this session will teach you how to take your SQL Server queries mundane to masterful.

You'll learn things like a T-SQL code test harness, the value of clone databases, which temporary object is best, why CTE's don't help performance and can sometimes hurt, which cursors are good for performance, how data type inconsistencies can bring your server to a screeching halt, what single line of T-SQL code can provide double-digit percentage increase in performance, and much more. Attend this session to take your query writing and query tuning skills to the next level!</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104522</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104522</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track4 - Sponsored By Marathon Consulting</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing Backup Performance Using Data Science Techniques</title>
      <description>One of the most important tasks for a database administrator is taking (and testing!) backups.  As databases get larger and larger, the amount of time it takes to perform a backup can grow as well, to the point where your backups take longer than your available backup window.  There are several settings we can use to optimize backup performance, such as buffer counts, maximum transfer size, and the number of files, but trying every combination of settings on a single production-sized database could take weeks or even months.  In this talk, we will apply data science techniques to the problem of backup settings optimization and look at different models for approaching the problem and analyzing data.  Some statistics background would be helpful, but is not required; the big requirement is a desire to speed up backups.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103679</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103679</id>
          <name>Louis Davidson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Characteristics of a Great Relational Database</title>
      <description>When queried, most database professionals would mention normalized as one of the most important characteristics that tell the difference between a good and bad relational database design (whether they know what the term "normalized" means or not.) Normalization is a key to great relational designs, but there is so much more to be considered. A normalized database that suffers from poor naming, too many or too few indexes, terrible interfaces, and so on can derail your design's value to the user.  In this session I will present primary characteristics of a design that differentiates between an ugly design that will have your colleagues nitpicking you to death and one that will have them singing your praises. Characteristics such as comprehendible, documented, secure, well performing, and more (including normalized, naturally) will be discussed.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101121</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101121</id>
          <name>George Walkey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Centralized Alert Dashboarding</title>
      <description>Its easy to build a Centralized Dashboard for all your Server's Agent Alerts that can monitor all your Servers. In 60 minutes we will create a Dashboard using SQL Agent, Powershell and SSRS that is easy-to-maintain and deploy.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>102454</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>102454</id>
          <name>Rick Heiges</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track4 - Sponsored By Marathon Consulting</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL DB Managed Instance: Today</title>
      <description>It has been about a year since Azure SQL DB Managed Instance has been released. What is it? Where does it fit? What limitations does it have? What has changed? What changes should I see next?  These questions will be addressed and more.  Will we see Managed Instance in action? We can, but it is just SQL Server presented in a different wrapper.  Along with Managed Instance, a discussion of Serverless and Hyperscale options will also be included.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 11:25:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 1:25:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103805</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103805</id>
          <name>Stephen Leonard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track1 - Sponsored By SQL Data Partners</name>
      </location>
      <title>Installing SQL Server on a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <description>The Raspberry Pi is a series of small single-board computers developed in the United Kingdom by the Raspberry Pi Foundation to promote the teaching of basic computer science in schools and developing countries. It is a multi-faceted device that can be used for many functions, one of which being Internet of Things, or IoT, applications. In our case, SQL Server. The primary goal of this session is a walkthrough tutorial on how to properly install SQL Server on a Raspberry Pi.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103729</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103729</id>
          <name>Chris Bell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building Your First SQL Server Container Lab in Docker</title>
      <description>A few years back, virtualization changed the way to work with SQL and infrastructure. Now, the next chapter is opening and it’s all about containers. Containers can make the DBA’s job of creating and deploying servers much easier freeing them up for other tasks such as performance tuning and security. 

In this session, we will go over the concepts of containers, their general capabilities, and then build, connect, and configure a SQL Server in a container for use as a private lab.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 11:25:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 1:25:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>102282</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>102282</id>
          <name>Sarah Patrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Case Study: How I used SharePoint, Flow, PowerApps, and Forms to build a Speaker Database</title>
      <description>In this case study, I detail how I went about designing and implementing a Speaker Database for the Project Management Institute using SharePoint, Flow, Power Apps, and Microsoft Forms. We will do a brief intro of what each technology is and it's pros and cons, and then dive into what I learned about each, each strengths and weaknesses, and how I was able to build a functional Speaker Database.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104540</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104540</id>
          <name>Timothy McAliley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>High Availability</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Database: High Availability and Disaster Recovery Options</title>
      <description>In this session we will review options for high availability and disaster recovery for Azure SQL Databases. We will delve into high availability and back up/restore options for singleton databases, elastics pools and managed instances. We will discuss the pros and cons and best practices for each high availability and disaster recovery option (from an operations perspective and the all important cost perspective).</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101119</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101119</id>
          <name>David Patrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Microsoft and Big Data - An Overview of the Power Tools and more!</title>
      <description>Come see Microsoft's Power tools demonstrated for advanced analytics and hear about Microsoft's embrace of Open Source and the Hadoop platform. We'll also present on Microsoft's tools for handling Big Data, such as the Parallel Data Warehouse and HDInsights.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101139</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101139</id>
          <name>Mohammad Darab</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data Clusters for the Absolute Beginner</title>
      <description>Are you a DBA or data professional working with out-dated technology or feel your skills are quickly becoming irrelevant? Stay ahead in today's ever changing tech space and take your career to the next level.

Join Mohammad Darab this session to explore the cutting-edge technology that SQL Server 2019 has to offer: Big Data Clusters.

Topics include:
-Big Data Cluster architecture and its components such as: Containers, Kubernetes and the newly enhanced Polybase
-Unique advantage of SQL Server Big Data Clusters
-Data Virtualization, Scale-out Data Marts, and Data Hub concepts</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>102659</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>102659</id>
          <name>Andy Leonard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track1 - Sponsored By SQL Data Partners</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure DevOps and the SSIS Development Lifecycle</title>
      <description>Data Integration Lifecycle Management - or DILM - is challenging regardless of your chosen data integration platform. 
The primary goal of this session is an explanation - via demonstration - of the production release of an SSIS Project. We will walk this project through lifecycle management using Azure DevOps - from initial development, through testing, to production.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104534</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104534</id>
          <name>Angela Henry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track4 - Sponsored By Marathon Consulting</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to Azure Data Catalog</title>
      <description>Your company has amassed more data than it can possibly use, yet no one can find the data they need.  This is more common than you think.  With Azure Data Catalog, anyone can find the data they are looking for, no matter the data source.  This session will introduce you to Azure Data Catalog, what it is, how you can use it and why everyone should be using it.</description>
      <startTime>4/25/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/25/2020 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>