<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #561 - Durban 2016</name>
    <startDate>9/17/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>150</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Jerusalem</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat561</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Derivco Offices</name>
      <street>77 Armstrong Ave</street>
      <city>Durban</city>
      <state>KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa</state>
      <zipcode>4051</zipcode>
      <longitude>31.067534</longitude>
      <latitude>-29.746734</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53689</importID>
      <name>Niels Berglund</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niels works as Software Architect at Derivco, where he develops software as well as "dreaming" up new and innovative ways to use existing and new technology. Before joining Derivco, Niels worked as researcher/instructor at Developmentor where he was responsible for the database curriculum. He was a co-author of the first SQL Server 2005 book for developers: quot; A First Look at SQL 2005 for Developersquot;. He has presented at all leading technical conferences; Tech-ED, SQL PASS, DevWeek, Ignite the Tour, etc., and is also a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>nielsberglund</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://za.linkedin.com/in/niels-berglund-0122593</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://nielsberglund.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=nielsberglund</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54174</importID>
      <name>André Pelser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I’ve started my DBA career in 2006 as an Informix DBA also working with SQL Server 2000. A few years later because of demand at that stage, my focus turned to SQL specifically. I’ve been privileged enough to work not just be a DBA but also as SQL developer and report writer. For the last three years this focus is now more focused on database administration.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54031</importID>
      <name>Marius Erasmus</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Been working in IT for the last MANY years.
Started at Derivco in 2005 as DBA, and eventually moved over to BI.
Spend a lot of my time on SSIS designing packages for Data Warehouse collections.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52890</importID>
      <name>Desmond Norton</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Desmond is a senior database developer at Derivco, with 15 years development experience.  He started out as a full stack developer, and made the move to a purely SQL developer 9 years ago.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53799</importID>
      <name>Gail Shaw</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gail Shaw is a Database Specialist focusing on database performance tuning and database recovery, with a particular interest in topics such as indexing strategies, execution plans, and writing T-SQL code that performs well and scales gracefully. Gail holds a Microsoft Certified Master certification for SQL Server 2008 and is a Data Platform MVP. She's a frequent poster on the SQLServerCentral forums, a Pluralsight author, writes articles for both SQLServerCentral.com and Simple-Talk.com, and has spoken at SQLSaturdays, SQL Bits and at the PASS Community Summit. Gail has been responsible for extending the lifespan of many an application, by performance-tuning their databases and providing technical guidance on all things SQL Server related.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLInTheWild</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlinthewild.co.za</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLInTheWild</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53193</importID>
      <name>Steve Simon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Simon is a Database Solutions Architect with Business Knowledge Services Inc. He has been involved with database design and analysis for over 35 years. Steve has presented papers at numerous PASS Summits and PASS SQL Rallies. He is also regular presenter on the SQL Saturday circuit and he is a contributor on SQLShack.com</description>
      <twitter>SQLServerBoffin</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stephenrsimon/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/simon_says/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLServerBoffin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53788</importID>
      <name>Rory Bolle</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rory studied Information technology, ran a small computer shop then found Derivco as a Tester. Moved as soon as possible to Data Development and it has stuck.

Rory really loves wood work, general garage tinkering and has a second child on the way which his wife has told him he is excited about.

Rory's Derivco career has centered around delivering data from 40+ busy source databases to +-120 consumer databases. The main focus in this space is deduplication and compression of data while finding the correct balance between RBAR and batching.
If moving data is your thing, Rory can help.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53194</importID>
      <name>Steve Simon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Simon is a Database Solutions Architect with Business Knowledge Services Inc. He has been involved with database design and analysis for over 35 years. Steve has presented papers at numerous PASS Summits and PASS SQL Rallies. He is also regular presenter on the SQL Saturday circuit and he is a contributor on SQLShack.com</description>
      <twitter>SQLServerBoffin</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stephenrsimon/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/simon_says/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLServerBoffin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53798</importID>
      <name>Gail Shaw</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gail Shaw is a Database Specialist focusing on database performance tuning and database recovery, with a particular interest in topics such as indexing strategies, execution plans, and writing T-SQL code that performs well and scales gracefully. Gail holds a Microsoft Certified Master certification for SQL Server 2008 and is a Data Platform MVP. She's a frequent poster on the SQLServerCentral forums, a Pluralsight author, writes articles for both SQLServerCentral.com and Simple-Talk.com, and has spoken at SQLSaturdays, SQL Bits and at the PASS Community Summit. Gail has been responsible for extending the lifespan of many an application, by performance-tuning their databases and providing technical guidance on all things SQL Server related.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLInTheWild</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlinthewild.co.za</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLInTheWild</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54270</importID>
      <name>Gary Hope</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cloud Data and AI Solution Architect at Microsoft South Africa</description>
      <twitter>GaryHope</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=GaryHope</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50227</importID>
      <name>Clinton van Blommestein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Clinton is a senior developer at Derivco in Durban (South Africa), a company that is a leader in the online gaming space. He has over 16 years experience in highly transactions systems, with focus on the services and data tiers. He is a regular speaker at SQL events in South Africa, is also the co-leader for the Durban SQL User Group and has recognised as a Couchbase Champion for his contribution to their community.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://za.linkedin.com/in/clintonvb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54074</importID>
      <name>Sean Cremer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sean Cremer is a Senior Developer at Derivco.  He has worked with SQL Server for nearly two decades on Large OLTP and Data Warehousing  Systems and has a wealth of accumulated  Database Design and Implementation knowledge.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/seanCremer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/preview?locale=en_UStrk=prof-0-sb-preview-primary-button</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://seancremer.github.io/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/seanCremer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54291</importID>
      <name>Michael Johnson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Johnson is a Microsoft data platform MVP and leader of the Johannesburg SQL User Group and Business Analytics Virtual Group. He works as an Independent Business Intelligence Consultant and regularly presents at local user groups, SQL Saturdays and PASS Virtual Chapters.</description>
      <twitter>MikeJohnsonZA</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://za.linkedin.com/pub/michael-johnson/22/73/735</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://michaeladrianjohnson.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MikeJohnsonZA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53688</importID>
      <name>Niels Berglund</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niels works as Software Architect at Derivco, where he develops software as well as "dreaming" up new and innovative ways to use existing and new technology. Before joining Derivco, Niels worked as researcher/instructor at Developmentor where he was responsible for the database curriculum. He was a co-author of the first SQL Server 2005 book for developers: quot; A First Look at SQL 2005 for Developersquot;. He has presented at all leading technical conferences; Tech-ED, SQL PASS, DevWeek, Ignite the Tour, etc., and is also a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>nielsberglund</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://za.linkedin.com/in/niels-berglund-0122593</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://nielsberglund.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=nielsberglund</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53185</importID>
      <name>Chris Olivier</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I used to work on financial models and had a natural progression to using Data Warehouses for analysis, and progressed into doing Data Warehouse / BI Development. I later led a BI team in an administration company but missed the technical side which brought me to Derivco which was a great decision as I have been extending my knowledge ever since. I mainly deal with Business Intelligence, where my travels have taught me skills in SQL Server, Data Warehouses, Integration Services, Reporting Services, etc. I also dabble a lot in Data Science and trying to use Machine learning to solve real world problems.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://za.linkedin.com/in/chris-olivier-b987794a</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>50227</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50227</id>
          <name>Clinton van Blommestein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>So, when you say database what do you mean?</title>
      <description>These days when you say "database server" it could really mean many things.

For something like SQL server there are so many options: on-premise server, off-premise server. On-premise server with off-premise data. Then there are the various  Azure offerings with fancy names like Azure SQL, Data Lake, Hadoop.

You also get graph databases and document databases.

This session will cover some of the more popular types of data stores that are available today and we will look at their use cases. While SQL server is great for many things, one has to be aware of the other options that are available out there.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54270</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54270</id>
          <name>Gary Hope</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building a Lambda Architecture using Azure Warehouse and Stream A</title>
      <description>It’s been a while since Nathan Marz wrote the first Lambda Architecture post and a lot has happened since. 

The principals described in this approach have been applied and refined, especially within the Hadoop ecosystem. However in this talk we will look at using some of the Microsoft Azure based technologies, specifically Azure Stream Analytics and Azure Data Warehouse to implement this approach to data management and realize some of this benefits of this architecture.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53688</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53688</id>
          <name>Niels Berglund</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>What R You Analyzing</title>
      <description>R has become one of the leading analysis tools for developers and data scientists alike. 

However, in order for R to do its magic it needs data so historically we have imported data from various sources, SQL Server being one of those sources. In SQL Server 2016, Microsoft has embedded R in the SQL engine. Yes, we do now have access to R natively in SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54291</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54291</id>
          <name>Michael Johnson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Simple tips for better data warehouse design</title>
      <description>Building a data warehouse can be complicated. There are two competing philosophies and a myriad of other best practice documents out there on building high performance data warehouses and you probably don’t have time to read any of them.
In this session we will discuss a key approaches that you can use to design simple, easy to use data warehouses.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53193</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53193</id>
          <name>Steve Simon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016: A dive into Data Quality Services</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016: Data quality and data cleansing have always been major challenges to any enterprise that deals with data. For those of us who have dealt with Data Profiler Tasks in SQL Server 2008, we were shocked yet pleasantly surprised with the great advances that Microsoft has made with the advent of Data Quality Services, in the SQL Server 2012 release. In this hands-on presentation we shall be looking at how to set up a new knowledge base, based upon an existing one, set up rules, do knowledge discovery within the new knowledge base and finally cleanse the data through a data quality project. The end results being more effective data, guaranteed to keep end users and management happy.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53788</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53788</id>
          <name>Rory Bolle</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Top Tips for C# developers deploying Database code</title>
      <description>Everyone has experienced a live costly issue on a production database. This is made worse is when the live costly issue can be blamed on a non-Database Developer overlooking something “Obvious”.

Normally this type of problem is followed by someone blaming a process or shouting about peer reviews or arguing about training… What if there was a better way? Is it possible to create a short list of guidelines for non-Database developers to follow that remove almost all of the pain points? 

Let’s find out!</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53798</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53798</id>
          <name>Gail Shaw</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Go, go, QueryStore!</title>
      <description>One of the hardest things to do in SQL is to identify the cause of a sudden degradation in performance. The DMVs don’t persist information over a restart of the instance and, unless there was already some query benchmarking (and there almost never is), answering the question of how the queries behaved last week needs a time machine. Up until now, that is. The addition of the QueryStore to SQL Server 2016 makes identifying and resolving performance regressions a breeze.
 
In this session we’ll take a look at what the QueryStore is and how it works, before diving into a scenario where overall performance suddenly degraded, and we’ll see why QueryStore is the best new feature in SQL Server 2016, bar none.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53194</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53194</id>
          <name>Steve Simon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016: Master Data Services and Rapid Application Development</title>
      <description>Master Data Services can be readily be employed for Rapid Application Development. We shall be looking at important development, data security and data maintenance aspects, all based upon a recent client implementation.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54031</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54031</id>
          <name>Marius Erasmus</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS Tips, Tricks and Design Patterns</title>
      <description>Anybody can quickly build a SSIS package to collect some data…. But it takes a lot of experience and patience to fully understand how to build a full scale solution.

SSIS has loads of little settings and “hidden” features that can be tweaked, modified and changed to turn an standard package into a proper solution.

This presentation is just a highlight of some of the Tips, Tricks and Design Patterns that can be used to make your SSIS experience a joyful one.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53689</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53689</id>
          <name>Niels Berglund</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Beyond Relational with SQL 2016</title>
      <description>There is a saying "no man is an island", and that holds true for SQL Server as well. 

In your organization you have data stored all over the place, and your data may not always be relational. In this talk we will see how you can handle both relational as well a non relational data in SQL Server 2016. Among the things we will talk about are JSON support, Hadoop and Polybase.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54074</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54074</id>
          <name>Sean Cremer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Database Design</title>
      <description>Far too few database developers in this day and age get the opportunity to learn how to design relation databases. In most cases, they will on occasion be asked to add a few objects to an existing system while following the standards of the organisation. 

These relatively infrequent changes do not hone the skills needed for effective design. 

This session will go through the fundamentals of database design. Topics such as normalization, Understanding Data Relationships as well as the Language of Data Modeling and Design will be discussed. The Database Design Sequence Phases of Conceptual, Logical and Physical will be introduced as well.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52890</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52890</id>
          <name>Desmond Norton</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Windows on Data</title>
      <description>A look at Window functions, and how their performance has improved over the SQL versions.
Also ideas/samples of potential use cases.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54174</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54174</id>
          <name>André Pelser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Always On  - Overcoming some administration nightmares</title>
      <description>Getting an overview of SQL availability solutions, taking a look at some pros and cons with focus on SQL AlwaysOn High Availability and some administration constrains and how to overcome them.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53799</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53799</id>
          <name>Gail Shaw</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>On Transactions and Atomic Operations</title>
      <description>If there’s one thing that we, as SQL developers, do, it’s not use enough transactions.
 
Transactions are critical when multiple changes need to be made entirely or not at all, but even given that it’s rare to see transactions used at all in most production code
 
In this session, we’ll look at what transactions are and why we should use them. We’ll explore the effects transactions have on locking and the transaction log. We’ll investigate methods of handling errors and undoing data modifications, and we’ll see why nested transactions are a lie.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53185</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53185</id>
          <name>Chris Olivier</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Basics of Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <description>The Azure Machine Learning workspace is an easy to use, visual way of doing machine learning, however, it is also very powerful and a great tool to use to start with Machine Learning. Initially it can be a bit overwhelming to figure out how exactly to go about using it to get some results. We will give a basic introduction to machine learning, the Azure Machine Learning workspace, a demo on how to get your first model running in a few minutes as well as some of the functionality offered in this great and quickly evolving tool.</description>
      <startTime>9/17/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/17/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>