<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #806 - Charlotte 2018</name>
    <startDate>10/20/2018 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>350</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatCharlotte</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Central Piedmont Community College - Harris Campus</name>
      <street>3210 Cpcc Harris Campus Dr</street>
      <city>Charlotte</city>
      <state>North Carolina</state>
      <zipcode>28208</zipcode>
      <longitude>-80.9193279</longitude>
      <latitude>35.215848</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/972/EventSponsor_14605.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>466</importID>
      <name>Cardinal Solutions</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.cardinalsolutions.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://csgflyers.com/csglogo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1042</importID>
      <name>Signature Consultants</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sigconsult.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/864/EventSponsor_13629.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2002</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.red-gate.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/991/EventSponsor_14803.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/908/EventSponsor_14257.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>607</importID>
      <name>DELL EMC</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.dellemc.com/en-us/index.htm</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/913/EventSponsor_14262.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1588</importID>
      <name>Quest</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/967/EventSponsor_14754.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14586.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1086</importID>
      <name>SQLChick</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlchick.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://static.squarespace.com/static/52d1b75de4b0ed895b7e7de9/t/52d1c47de4b07aac36444107/1405645727746/?format=150w</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2141</importID>
      <name>Dallas DBAs</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dallasdbas.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/945/EventSponsor_14294.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2254</importID>
      <name>SQLCoop.com, LLC</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc1u_C8ukXd1Lkd9uF-Tj4w/videos?view=0sort=pview_as=subscriberflow=grid</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/877/EventSponsor_13514.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2258</importID>
      <name>SQL Swimmer</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://sqlswimmer.wordpress.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlswimmer.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/swimmer-avatar-transparent.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83824</importID>
      <name>Thomas Norman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tom Norman is a Database Architect at KPA with a strong fervor to protect data. He works daily to review and improve data protection methodologies while reviewing governing laws affecting finance, healthcare, and personal data. His areas of expertise include encryption, auditing, data identification, and database object deployment. He is the current leader of the PASS Virtualization Group and Vice President of the TRIPASS user group. You can read his blog at https://armordba.com/ and reach him on twitter at @armordba. Tom speaks at a number of SQLSaturday events and SQL Server user groups.</description>
      <twitter>ArmorDba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armordba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://armordba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ArmorDba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85688</importID>
      <name>Mike Burek</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>He started by building a complete computerized inventory management system for a multi-state store. Next, he managed Texas Medicare and Medicaid claim data to keep it processing, and building new monitoring metrics. Afterwards, he processed and analyzed  marketing data on tens of millions of customers and sent hundreds of millions of multi-lingual marketing messages worldwide. Upgrading those marketing skills, he then worked to process and query tune marketing data for tens of thousands of worldwide enterprise customers, bringing in tens of millions of dollars per campaign. Now he monitors database servers to keep them running well, tunes queries, and helps businesses build new ETL processes. He also runs the Austin, TX user group.</description>
      <twitter>mikeburek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mikeburek</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tikiwiki.mikeburek.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mikeburek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85315</importID>
      <name>Jeff Burns</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeff Burns has enjoyed solving problems in many aspects of his life and has been told that sometimes he even makes them (to be able to solve, of course). After becoming immersed in the world of marketing and CRM consulting, he found BI and Analytics as an extension and fell in love. It felt like a natural combination of his business background, interest in the arts, and love of data.
Today, Jeff leads an ever-expanding team of analytics consultants at Cardinal Solutions who share his love of problem-solving and data. They work primarily in all layers of SQL Server and the Microsoft Azure environment.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-m-burns</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83996</importID>
      <name>Brad Llewellyn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brad Llewellyn is a Service Engineer on Microsoft's FastTrack for Azure Team in Charlotte, NC. Brad helps individuals and organizations leverage Analytics and Azure to revolutionize themselves and their industries. He has an M.S. in Statistics from the University of South Carolina, MCSE Certification in Data Management and Analytics, MCSE Certification in Cloud Platform and Infrastructure, and various MCSA Certifications in Business Intelligence and Advanced Analytics. Brad is an active blogger at breaking-bi.blogspot.com. He is also an organizer for the Charlotte BI Group, a local PASS chapter in Charlotte, NC. You can connect with him on LinkedIn at https://www.linkedin.com/in/bradllewellyn and on Twitter @BreakingBI.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BreakingBI</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bradllewellyn/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://breaking-bi.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BreakingBI</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85534</importID>
      <name>Meghana Vasavada</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I'm currently a SQL Server Developer Consultant working for one of the clients of an IT Consulting firm in New Jersey, and have a Master's degree in Bioinformatics from NJIT, USA. With over five years of Professional experience using MS SQL Server Database, I have extensive knowledge and solid understanding of Data warehouse concepts with strong expertise in T-SQL Objects, Business Intelligence (SSIS, SSAS, SSRS, and Power BI) and Database Administration. My curiosity in understanding the complexity across the data further enhanced me to pursue a certification in Data Science and Big Data Analysis. Last but foremost, I love to learn and share knowledge.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/meghana-vasavada-4a654b2a/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85627</importID>
      <name>Linda Groszyk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Linda Groszyk, M.S., CCC-SLP is a nationally certified Speech-Language Pathologist who specializes in social communication, emotional regulation, and accent modification. Developing her expertise over the past 19 years, Linda provides individualized coaching services for people to achieve their professional and social goals through increased self-awareness, confidence, and communication competencies. Linda is also a certified PESL (Pronouncing English as a Second Language) Instructor. She graduated from Boston College with a BA in Human Development and earned her masters in Communication Disorders at Pennsylvania State University. Linda currently resides in San Francisco and serves a global clientele. Find out more at prosocialcoach.com.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ProSocialCoach</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/linda-groszyk-m-s-ccc-slp-993121148/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ProSocialCoach</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85503</importID>
      <name>Jamie Wick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jamie Wick is the Systems  Database Engineer for The College of William  Mary and has been working with SQL databases for the past 10+ years.  His background includes working for several years as a SQL SysAdmin for the University of Queensland (Australia), a Masters degree in Computer Information Systems from Boston University, and assorted Microsoft SQL certifications.  He is the Chapter Leader of the Richmond SQL Server Users Group, a volunteer and speaker at regional SQL events (User Groups/SQLSaturdays), helps run the SQLSaturday RVA events, and is an avid photographer.</description>
      <twitter>Jamie_Wick</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamiewick/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.wicktech.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Jamie_Wick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85607</importID>
      <name>Justin Randall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Justin Randall is a Senior Consultant at SQL Sentry, LLC. He has over 30 years of data management experience in a variety of roles from Enterprise Data Modeler to DBA, supporting development in DB2, Sybase, and SQL Server. Justin frequently speaks at SQL Server User Group meetings and SQL Saturdays, and has presented at several SQLintersection conferences. His current professional interests are SQL Server performance monitoring and tuning, and career development.</description>
      <twitter>jh_randall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/public-profile-settings?trk=prof-edit-edit-public_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.sqlsentry.com/justinrandall</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jh_randall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84016</importID>
      <name>Jim Donahoe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jim is a Premier Field Engineer for Microsoft in the Data/AI space.  He lives in Pittsburgh in a small suburb.  He loves working with all things Azure(ARM templates, DBaaS, SQL on IaaS).  He is an avid collector of retro video games! He is a member of the Idera ACE program for 2018.</description>
      <twitter>SQLFlipFlopsDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlflipflopsdba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLFlipFlopsDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85685</importID>
      <name>Mitchell Pearson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mitchell is an experienced Business Intelligence Consultant and Trainer at Pragmatic Works and is currently the content training manager leading content development and delivery of training courses. Mitchell is experienced developing BI solutions using the full Microsoft BI Stack (SSRS, SSIS, and SSAS) as well as Microsoft Power BI. He is also very active in the community speaking at SQL Saturday events, local user groups, and online virtual events. Mitchell also blogs at mitchellpearson.com.</description>
      <twitter>@MitchellSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mitchellpearson.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MitchellSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83559</importID>
      <name>Spencer Swindell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Spencer Swindell is the Lead Architect with Think Data Insights, LLC. Think Data Insights a consulting group based out of Nashville, TN that works with companies to implement and maintain their Enterprise Data Platform. Since graduating from Tennessee Tech in 2011, he has built and delivered solutions for numerous organizations in the Nashville area utilizing SQL Server and the Microsoft BI Toolset. Spencer lives in Mount Juliet with his wife and son.</description>
      <twitter>@SpencerSwindell</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/spencerswindell/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SpencerSwindell</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83983</importID>
      <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tracy Boggiano is a Senior Database Administrator for DocuSIgn. She has spent over 20 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1999, and is currently certified as an MCSE Data Platform. Tracy has worked on SQL Server since 6.5. She has spoken at local user groups and numerous SQLSaturdays. She is currently a co-leader of a TriPASS Local Group in Raleigh, NC.   

Tracy also tinkered with databases in middle school to keep her sports card collection organized. She blogs at databasesuperhero.com. 

Her passion outside of SQL Server is volunteering with foster children as their advocate in court through volunteerforgal.org and being a mental health advocate as part of the PAIMI NC Advisory Council.</description>
      <twitter>TracyBoggiano</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyboggiano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://databasesuperhero.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TracyBoggiano</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85523</importID>
      <name>Jeff Renz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeff Renz is a Senior Architect at RevGen Partners, currently working as the design architect and implementation lead on several projects for a Fortune Top 50 company. Jeff has worked with SQL Server and BI for 15+ years and has 10 years’ experience with data warehouse design and implementation. In addition to consulting, he is joining the University of Denver adjunct faculty and is expected to begin teaching in the ICT program starting in June.  He received his bachelor’s degree in Computer Science, his master’s degree in Operations Research from Colorado School of Mines, and will be graduating from the Harvard Business Analytics Program in December.</description>
      <twitter>jeff_renz</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-renz/29/82a/aa4</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.revgen.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jeff_renz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85625</importID>
      <name>Aaron Bertrand</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Architect at Wayfair. Long-time MVP and bad habits attacker.</description>
      <twitter>AaronBertrand</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlblog.org</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AaronBertrand</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84028</importID>
      <name>Prabhaker Potharaju</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Prabhaker Potharaju is a Senior Consultant at Microsoft and has been with Microsoft for almost 19+ years with experience in Business Intelligence, Database Development and Administration, and Application Development using Microsoft technologies. He has extensive understanding of SQL Server internal architecture, performance tuning, as well as data implementation and maintenance of high availability, disaster recovery, and high performance OLTP and OLAP systems. Also has experience on Public and Private cloud platforms, Hybrid IT and delivering SQL Azure offerings.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85672</importID>
      <name>Devin Knight</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Devin Knight a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and the Training Director at Pragmatic Works. He is an author of seven SQL Server and Business Intelligence books and speaks at conferences like PASS Summit, PASS Business Analytics Conference, SQL Saturdays and Code Camps. He is also a contributing member to several PASS Virtual Chapters. Making his home in Jacksonville, FL, Devin is the Vice President of the local Power BI User Group and SQL Server User Group (JSSUG).</description>
      <twitter>@knight_devin</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/deknight/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://devinknightsql.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@knight_devin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83938</importID>
      <name>Michael Wharton</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Wharton is a Project MVP.  He has been an independent consultant for the past 20 years, with over 30 Project/SharePoint Server deployments.  He has an MBA from Wake Forest and has over 44 Microsoft Certifications.  Michael's primary job is helping companies setup a PMO, Project Management Office using Project Server using SQL server on a SharePoint Farm. He has worked extensively with the back end support setting up SQL server, SharePoint Server and Project Server using PowerShell.</description>
      <twitter>MyProjectExpert</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelwhartoncomputer</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://MyProjectExpert.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MyProjectExpert</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85871</importID>
      <name>Melissa Coates</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Melissa Coates is a data architect with a background in data warehousing and business intelligence. Her current professional focus is enterprise-level Power BI governance, deployment, security, and administration. As the owner of Coates Data Strategies, Melissa produces training and consults to help companies strengthen and sustain their data-driven initiatives. Melissa is big supporter of the technical community, and has been a Microsoft Data Platform MVP since 2013. You can visit Melissa's website at CoatesDataStrategies.com, which includes community resources like diagrams, blogs, and videos.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLChick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/melissacoatesprofile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.CoatesDataStrategies/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLChick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84208</importID>
      <name>Leveat Ruse</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>As an Executive Technical Recruiter with Ctrl+f, I currently develop effective recruitment strategies to attract top talent at all levels of an organization. I am an IBM certified trainer and began my career performing general human resources duties. I quickly worked my way up through the ranks of technical recruiting from Lead Recruiter to Senior Recruiter to Business Development.</description>
      <twitter>www.twitter.com/ncsctechrecruit</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/leveatruse</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=www.twitter.com/ncsctechrecruit</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86725</importID>
      <name>Andy Leonard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andy Leonard is founder and Chief Data Engineer at Enterprise Data  Analytics, Microsoft Data Platform MVP, creator of the DILM (Data Integration Lifecycle Management) Suite, an SSIS trainer, consultant, developer, Business Intelligence Markup Language (Biml) developer and BimlHero, SQL Server database and data warehouse developer, community mentor, engineer, and farmer. He is a co-author of "The Biml Book and SQL Server Integration Services Design Patterns" and author of "Managing Geeks - A Journey of Leading by Doing", "Data Integration Lifecycle Management with SSIS", "Building Custom Tasks for SSIS", and the "Stairway to Integration Services". Andy blogs at andyleonard.blog where you can learn more on the About Andy page.</description>
      <twitter>AndyLeonard</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/AndyLeonard</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://andyleonard.blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyLeonard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85645</importID>
      <name>Sandra Peele</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sandra Peele started her career in the 1980’s as a demand forecaster in the materials planning department of ATT Network Systems.  She left the workforce in 1990 to raise a family and in 2010, returned to school to study database technology, eventually teaching courses herself.   She has both MSCE: Data Management and Analytics and Oracle 11g OCA certifications.  Sandra is a SQL Developer at CMI Solutions, a Microsoft Partner specializing in software for convenience stores.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://linkedin.com/in/sandrapeele</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84054</importID>
      <name>Michael Moen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>As a long time technologist interested in Data and Data Science, I love to discover new things, and share them with my community. I  have traveled teaching SQL topics all over the world. I look at this new data century as the challenge of a lifetime!

I am an MCT with MCSE throughout the SQL Server Editions 2000-2017. I love to interact with folks and help them gain an understanding of the field.</description>
      <twitter>@mmoencfi</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mmoencfi/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mmoencfi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84100</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85034</importID>
      <name>Neal Waterstreet</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Neal is a BI Architect/Consultant with more than 20 years of industry experience. Neal is skilled in the entire BI spectrum, including dimensional modeling, ETL design and development using Integration Services (SSIS), designing and developing multidimensional cubes and Tabular models using Analysis Services (SSAS) and Master Data Management using Microsoft Data Services (MDS). He's also involved with the database community and is the co-founder and co-leader of the PASS Healthcare Virtual Chapter and the Atlanta Modern Excel User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@nealwaterstreet</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/nealwaterstreet</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.nealwaterstreet.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@nealwaterstreet</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84545</importID>
      <name>Andy Leonard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andy Leonard is founder and Chief Data Engineer at Enterprise Data  Analytics, Microsoft Data Platform MVP, creator of the DILM (Data Integration Lifecycle Management) Suite, an SSIS trainer, consultant, developer, Business Intelligence Markup Language (Biml) developer and BimlHero, SQL Server database and data warehouse developer, community mentor, engineer, and farmer. He is a co-author of "The Biml Book and SQL Server Integration Services Design Patterns" and author of "Managing Geeks - A Journey of Leading by Doing", "Data Integration Lifecycle Management with SSIS", "Building Custom Tasks for SSIS", and the "Stairway to Integration Services". Andy blogs at andyleonard.blog where you can learn more on the About Andy page.</description>
      <twitter>AndyLeonard</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/AndyLeonard</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://andyleonard.blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyLeonard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85336</importID>
      <name>Stephen Muliokela</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been a DBA for many years now and currently hold multiple SQL Server certificates.
In addition, I am also a Six Sigma Blackbelt.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/stephen-muliokela/32/a45/830</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85579</importID>
      <name>Frank Henninger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Frank has been a database adminstrator most of the last 10 years. In that time he's managed Oracle on Linux, DB2 on AIX and SQL Server on Windows.</description>
      <twitter>osirisdba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/fhenninger/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://osirismedia.biz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=osirisdba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83998</importID>
      <name>Ramu Pulipati</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ramu is the CTO/CoFounder of botsplash, an omni-channel platform to engage customers over messaging. At botsplash, Ramu focuses on building solutions that utilize open source technologies, including Postgresql and Clickhouse to enable communication choices for mid to large enterprises.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ramu_pulipati</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pulipati/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ramu_pulipati</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84409</importID>
      <name>Zach Maddigan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a current data solutions consultant passionate about using analytics and data science to translate raw data into actionable, meaningful and insightful information that businesses can use to solve their data driven business questions. I believe there is a plethora of data available for companies to harvest and interpret in order to improve the way they strategically look at the marketplace. I am continuing to learn about the field by pursuing a Masters of Science in Analytics from The Kogod School of Business at American University.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/zachmaddigan/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84040</importID>
      <name>Brian Carrig</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brian Carrig is a Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server and is currently a Senior Program Manager on the SQL Server Tiger Team at Microsoft focusing primarily on persistent memory technology and replication. In a previous life, Brian spent some time as an academic and holds a PhD in Computer Science. He is a native of Dublin, Ireland but now lives with his wife and two daughters in Redmond, Washington. If he is not talking about, thinking about or working with technology you will usually find him watching Chelsea FC.</description>
      <twitter>@briancarrig</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@briancarrig</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84096</importID>
      <name>Andrew Kelly</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrew J. Kelly is a Senior Technical Subject Matter Expert with B3 Group Inc. and lives in Clarkdale, AZ. He has over 20 years experience with relational databases and application development, but his main focus now is SQL Server. In addition to general SQL Server training and mentoring, he specializes in performance, scalability, and maintainability of large-scale SQL Servers. He is a regular speaker at conferences and user groups and was a SQL Server / Data Platform MVP for 18 years.</description>
      <twitter>gunneyk</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/andrew_kelly/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=gunneyk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84525</importID>
      <name>Edward Roepe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ed Roepe is the founder and president of Perimeter DBA and lives in Atlanta GA. 
Along with a BSBA in Computer Science from the University of Florida, he holds certifications in just about every version of SQL Server since Version 4.2. His specialties include Performance Tuning, Health Checks, Security Checks, Virtualization, High Availability and Disaster Recovery. During his 25+ years of SQL consulting experience, he has taught DBAs the secrets of SQL success. He has managed many very large databases  in areas of healthcare, financial services, universities, and transportation.  Ed can be contacted at edward@perimeterdba.com</description>
      <twitter>None</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/eroepe</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://None</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=None</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85874</importID>
      <name>Kevin Kline</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Kline is a database and industry expert serving as Principal Program Manager at SentryOne, the industry leading SQL Server database tools vendor. A Microsoft SQL Server MVP since 2003, he is a founder and former president of PASS. Kevin is an author of many books, blogger, columnist, and popular international speaker. Kevin’s best known book is the best-selling SQL in a Nutshell and contributes monthly to Database Trends  Applications magazine. He tweets at @kekline and blogs at http://Blogs.SQLSentry.com/Author/KevinKline.</description>
      <twitter>kekline</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kekline/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.sentryone.com/author/kevinkline</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kekline</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86634</importID>
      <name>Thomas Norman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tom Norman is a Database Architect at KPA with a strong fervor to protect data. He works daily to review and improve data protection methodologies while reviewing governing laws affecting finance, healthcare, and personal data. His areas of expertise include encryption, auditing, data identification, and database object deployment. He is the current leader of the PASS Virtualization Group and Vice President of the TRIPASS user group. You can read his blog at https://armordba.com/ and reach him on twitter at @armordba. Tom speaks at a number of SQLSaturday events and SQL Server user groups.</description>
      <twitter>ArmorDba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armordba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://armordba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ArmorDba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84474</importID>
      <name>Maxwell Myrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Max Myrick is a SQL Server consultant whose experience includes 15 years at Microsoft with 5 years on the SQL Server development team where he ran the SQL Customer Lab and then the Sustained Engineering team. He was an founding member of Microsoft#39;s Mission Critical team where he worked with the largest SQL Server applications worldwide for almost a decade. Max was a regular speaker for Microsoft and has continued to speak at various PASS and other SQL Conferences since becoming a managing partner of SQLHA LLC.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLHA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/company/sqlha</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlha.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLHA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84794</importID>
      <name>Jared Poché</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jared Poche began working with SQL Server as an instructor for certification classes and has a passion for teaching and performance troubleshooting. Jared spent 10 years providing customer support at Microsoft, most recently as a Sr. Support Escalation Engineer. He is currently working as a Database Engineer for ChannelAdvisor and is blogging about his current experiences at sqljared.com</description>
      <twitter>sqljared</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jared-poche-51102797</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqljared.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqljared</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84678</importID>
      <name>Jeff Mlakar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeff Mlakar is a database professional specializing in Microsoft SQL Server. He has worked the past 15 years as a database developer and administrator (admini-loper or develo-strator…take your pick), analyst, and with Business Intelligence. A technology enthusiast – he is interested in data security and privacy topics. Jeff lives in the Raleigh-Durham area of NC.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/jmlakar</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeffmlakar/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mlakartechtalk.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/jmlakar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84598</importID>
      <name>Trey Johnson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A veteran of the SQL Server Business Intelligence community, Trey Johnson has been a senior board member of PASS, a global speaker and author and was an influencer for several years on Microsoft's Business Intelligence Partner Advisory Council.  Today, Johnson is the Chief Evangelist, a senior leader and technologist with ZAP, focused on bringing immense value from ZAP's Data Hub and the Microsoft SQL Server, Analysis Services and Azure platform.

Johnson enjoys communicating about his experiences over 25 years with the intersection of analytics, SQL and BI.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/treyjohnson</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/treyjohnson/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.zapbi.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/treyjohnson</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>84783</importID>
      <name>John Welch</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Welch joined SentryOne in spring 2018 as VP of Engineering with the acquisition by SentryOne of the software division of Pragmatic Works. John leads the development of a suite of products that make developing, managing, and documenting data solutions easier. John has been successfully delivering IT solutions to business problems since 1994, and has been focused on business intelligence and data warehousing technologies since 2001. He is a Microsoft Most Valued Professional (MVP), and a frequent presenter on SQL Server and data topics. He also contributes to several open source projects and community initiatives targeted toward making data professionals work more productive.</description>
      <twitter>@john_welch</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/johncwelch/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://agilebi.com/jwelch</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@john_welch</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>83983</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83983</id>
          <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Perform</track>
      <location>
        <name>H1-2105 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Collecting Performance Metrics</title>
      <description>Ever had a manager standing over your shoulder, wanting to know why an instance is running slow or if it can handle additional workload? What information would you use to answer these questions? If only you knew what performance metrics to collect and had them for your existing instances to answer these questions. 

In this session, we will be combining three open source tools - Telegraf, InfluxDB, and Grafana - into an inexpensive system that collects performance metrics you can use to troubleshoot issues and answer important questions about your SQL Server instances, including your Linux SQL Server instances. We will learn what metrics to collect, how to use the tools to collect performance metrics and then we'll put it all together in an interactive dashboard for easy visualization.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84016</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84016</id>
          <name>Jim Donahoe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Build</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2126 (45)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting started with SQL Azure Database: What you need to know</title>
      <description>Azure SQL Database offers a way quickly spin up new databases with minimal management requirements. However, the number of differences between on-premises SQL Server and Azure SQL Database can be overwhelming. Even worse, with DBaaS it’s not clear who is responsible for what anymore.
In this session, we will cover all the basic steps of getting your first Azure SQL Database instance spun up. We’ll cover common gotchas, like firewall settings and resource locks. We’ll also dive into some more advanced options with templates, allowing you to make your processes reproducible.
By the end of this presentation, you’ll understand if Azure SQL Database is the right choice for you and your needs. You’ll understand how it can simplify management and allow you to scale easily. Finally, you’ll have the confidence to go and create your own instance with ease.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83824</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83824</id>
          <name>Thomas Norman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Build</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2101 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>DevOps: Consistent Deployments / Team Development</title>
      <description>Unless you are developing code by yourself, you face challenges of working with several team members. Different people are changing code which affects the code someone else is working on. In addition, there will be teams working on different projects at the same time.  In the middle of the projects, an emergency fix needs to be deployed to Production. So where is the code, when do you shared it with others, when do you get the code that has been shared, where is the production code branch located.  How do I branch and when do merge? How do I get a release branch? Let me share with you how we are handling this area of DevOps.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84525</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84525</id>
          <name>Edward Roepe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Support</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2124 (45)</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Ultimate Maintenance Plan</title>
      <description>Is your SQL Server running slower and slower? Do you prefer a proactive rather than a reactive approach to managing SQL Server? Do you worry about being able to recover in an emergency? If you answer yes to any of the above this session is for you. 

We will start by exploring some of the maintenance options that are available. We will then explore the popular utility program by Ola Hallengren and how to implement. Next, we will explore the other areas of SQL Server that need to be maintained like history tables in MSDB. Finally, we will explore the different options when maintenance windows are tight. 

At the end of this session you will be able to: (1) Choose a maintenance program for your SQL Servers; (2) Program and schedule the maintenance programs; (3) Ensure that the SQL Server is running at optimum performance each day.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84474</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84474</id>
          <name>Maxwell Myrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Evolve</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2130 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Then and Now: Changing the State of Long-held Beliefs</title>
      <description>We’ve all heard the rules for SQL Server like separate your data from your log, watch for a disk queue length over 2, and a low Page Life Expectancy always means memory pressure. All of these used to be true, but on today’s hardware and SQL Server versions – they are dangerously outdated. In this session, we will take on a bunch of these old “givens” of SQL Server that everybody has heard and followed, the underlying technological reasons they were true then, how today’s technology has rendered them obsolete, and what the new rules are that you need to know. So whether you are one of the old guard looking to refresh your set of working SQL Server rules or a member of the up-and-comers looking for the facts to win over the old guard, this session is for you.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84678</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84678</id>
          <name>Jeff Mlakar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Support</track>
      <location>
        <name>H1-2105 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Corruption! Preventing Disaster to your Database.</title>
      <description>Every DBA should know about database corruption because it can be a resume generating event. A corrupt database can ruin your day, affect system stability, lead to unnecessary downtime, and possibly data loss. 

In this presentation we will explore database corruption, learn how to diagnose, and see what we can do to fix it. We will discuss the causes, dispel some myths, and learn what questions to ask. After this, we dive into discovering the root cause and putting a plan in place to stop it in the future. Demos will illustrate diagnosing, troubleshooting, and fixing database corruption. Prepare to break a database and go through the steps to return it back to a usable state. 

Beginners will benefit along with others who may one day find themselves with a corrupt database. By the end of the session, you will have the tools and understanding necessary to take corrective action and prevent your databases from corruption!</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84598</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84598</id>
          <name>Trey Johnson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Design</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2101 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Your BI Workloads and How They Change in the Cloud (Azure)</title>
      <description>Your organization has made a conscious choice that everything should move to the cloud! You own the current BI workloads for your business and you are not sure what that means? 

If so, this session is for you where we explore in depth the workloads around ETL/ELT, Data Management, Analysis Services to support BI for your users. We’ll also talk data security, governance  managing your data outside of your 4 walls.

With plenty of ground to cover and an expected level of participation from the audience, this will be a fast paced session with insights into how you can retain aspects of what you have while pursuing the greater opportunities delivering BI on the Cloud affords you.

Attendees will understand what workloads are similar as they move to the cloud
Attendees will develop an appreciation for the benefits the cloud can offer to their BI deployment
Attendees should have the confidence to map out their own plans for making the most of the workloads they’ll change when they move.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85645</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85645</id>
          <name>Sandra Peele</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Perform</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2125 (25)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Index Trek</title>
      <description>When learning something new, it’s helpful to have a foundation.  Yet, indexes are often taught with only one or two sentences of explanation before CREATE INDEX.  I recall a student, exasperated by the textbook definition saying, “Will someone just SHOW ME an index!”  The goal of this high level presentation is to do just that.  In this 50 minute mission, we’ll explore nonclustered and clustered indexes as well as the strange new world of columnstore indexes.  Rather than focus on space and time requirements of indexes and index maintenance, we’ll seek out new understanding:

•	Why well-designed indexes speed up queries.
•	Why queries must be engineered carefully to use indexes.
•	Why indexes have both benefits and drawbacks.

After the mission, you’ll be prepared to further explore the galaxy of indexes.  
  
This presentation was co-produced with Stéphane Faroult, author of Getting the Message Across: Using Slideware Effectively for Technical Presentations and The Art of SQL.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85523</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85523</id>
          <name>Jeff Renz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analyze</track>
      <location>
        <name>H1-2105 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to the R Programming Language for BI Professionals</title>
      <description>The modern BI professional is taking on the challenge of operationalizing data science. Most BI developers are very strong in TSQL but their exposer to advanced statistics and visualizations were limited by what is available in the TSQL language. The R programming language allows us to clean, visualize, and apply advanced statistical methods to data. 

In this session I will demonstrate how to use R Studio to generate and test R scripts; generate R visuals in PowerBI; call R code in machine learning workflows; and execute R code in SQL Server. Additionally, I will cover these R programming fundamentals: creating and assigning variables; performing simple calculations; understanding R data types; vectors; matrices; factors; lists; data frames; and ggplot2 graphics.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85534</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85534</id>
          <name>Meghana Vasavada</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Design</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2101 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Custom Auditing in SSIS</title>
      <description>In order to effectively monitor SSIS performance, troubleshoot errors and understand the data linage in the production environment one needs to implement the package logging and Data auditing. SSIS already contains an Audit Transformation Component that captures information about the package metadata and the environment in which the package runs.

However, what if you encountered an error, or a package failure?  Suppose, a Data warehouse developer is performing an ETL to load a Dimension of a Data mart and would like to track the Data being processed. Audit Transformation Component cannot perform the job effectively.

So lets have an insight of how Auditing can be done by designing an SSIS  package that captures the Error information, DML operation on the table (Inserts/Updates/Deletes) along with the package metadata.

We'll create a package with an event handler that loads Data from a Staging to Dimension and creates an Audit table to track information on Data processing.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83938</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83938</id>
          <name>Michael Wharton</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Support</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2125 (25)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting Started with PowerShell Basics for SQL Server Administration</title>
      <description>Overview of PowerShell Basics and how to manage SQL server using PowerShell scripts. In this session you will learn the basics on building scripts using PowerShell and then learn the basics of using PowerShell for SQL server administration.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85871</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85871</id>
          <name>Melissa Coates</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Design</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2130 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Architectures in Azure for Analytics  Big Data</title>
      <description>This session is a technical overview of data platform choices in Azure, with a focus on analytical and big data solutions. We will cover several reference architectures prevalent for cloud-based systems. Key criteria for selecting components of a multi-platform analytics architecture will be shared, such as: data latency, schema changes, data formats, data integration vs. data virtualization, scalability, and user tools/language support. Attendees of this session will become familiar with the most commonly used data services in Azure, including considerations for making sound decisions when designing a data architecture to support analytics and big data.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85874</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85874</id>
          <name>Kevin Kline</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Perform</track>
      <location>
        <name>H1-1120 Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>SentryOne Tools for Productivity and Performance</title>
      <description>Whether you are hosting in your office, in a data center, or in the cloud, SentryOne covers monitoring, alerting, and tuning to help you get the most out of your servers – including servers that aren’t running SQL Server. In this session, your hosts will guide you through time saving strategies for managing performance across hybrid environments - whether you are running physical or virtual servers, SQL Server, Azure SQL Database, APS, or Azure SQL Data Warehouse. You will see demonstrations of SentryOne software highlighting configuration and performance pitfalls and leave with a better understanding of performance problems you may be currently missing. SentryOne provides a unified management experience; it’s your ONE platform for physical, virtual, and cloud performance.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85336</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85336</id>
          <name>Stephen Muliokela</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Perform</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2123 (25)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Corruption</title>
      <description>Database corruption could happen to you. When it happens to you, do you know what to do? Will you realize quick enough that you have corruption?
The presentation begins by talking about how to detect the corruption and the different strategies for handling unique corruption issues.
Highlight of topics
1.	Why corruption occurs?
2.	Detecting corruption – how SQL Servers detects corruption at the page level.
3.	Different types of corruption- e.g. False alarms, memory corruption etc.
4.	Limitation of DBCC  how to speed the DBCC process.
5.	Undocumented DBCC commands.
6.	Monitoring I/O errors.
7.	Verifying backup for corruption.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85672</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85672</id>
          <name>Devin Knight</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analyze</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2124 (45)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Digital Storytelling with Power BI</title>
      <description>Power BI has many amazing features built in to help guide a user through understanding their data better. Some of the most recently added features like Drillthrough, Bookmarks, Spotlight and the Selection Pane have made digital storytelling even more exciting. 

In this session, you will learn how to leverage these features to tell a story with your own data.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83559</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83559</id>
          <name>Spencer Swindell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Design</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2125 (25)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Applying Data Warehousing Principles</title>
      <description>Many data analysts typically begin to work with data as a single flat table. While this works for small datasets, as the size of the data grows these naive methods do not scale. Processing records takes longer, queries become more complex, and introducing new datasets is inconsistent at best. In order to solve these problems, we must take into account the underlying architecture of our data and how it should be modeled. During this talk we will discuss key concepts, patterns, and techniques for designing a data model that is simple to query, scales with your data, and is extendable to new datasets.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85627</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85627</id>
          <name>Linda Groszyk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Evolve</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2125 (25)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Social Intelligence at Work: What it is, Why it Matters, and How to Improve it</title>
      <description>Do you or someone you work with demonstrate challenges in their social intelligence and social communication skills? Is this impacting their job performance and/or ability to effectively participate as a member of a team? For many people, “social” does not come naturally and has to be explicitly taught. In this presentation, you will learn how the social mind works and what the core challenges are of people exhibiting social difficulties.  We will explore behaviors that may directly affect career advancement as well as discuss evidence-based strategies to improve social competency skills.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85503</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85503</id>
          <name>Jamie Wick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Support</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2125 (25)</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Restore: Optimizing Your Data Recovery</title>
      <description>When disaster strikes, everyone's immediate question becomes: How long until the system is back online?  Whether it's a single database or the whole SQL environment, time is essential... As everyone waits on the restore to complete. 

How long will the restoration process take?  
Can it run faster? 

In this session, we'll answer these questions by looking at how to establish and maintain a Restoration Baseline and the options available for performance tuning database restores.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85685</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85685</id>
          <name>Mitchell Pearson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Build</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2130 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to DAX</title>
      <description>Data Analysis Expressions were specifically designed by Microsoft to be easy to learn and powerful, with just the basics of DAX you can significantly improve the analytical value of your data model. In this introductory to DAX session, you will learn the basics of using the DAX language to create calculated columns and calculated measures. In addition to the basics, this session will introduce you to creating aggregates, conditional functions, and time intelligence calculations.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85315</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85315</id>
          <name>Jeff Burns</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Design</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2126 (45)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Avoid Shiny Object Syndrome and Create Visualizations That Last</title>
      <description>You’ve spent days (or even weeks) getting the data perfect. After a few days, you've put together a dashboard that is so flashy it could be on display in Times Square. You check in with the stakeholders a month later only to learn they no longer use it. :(

Your diagnosis: Shiny Object Syndrome. It’s real. It’s prevalent. And almost completely preventable.

In this session you will leave with 5 field-tested rules to follow when creating visualizations that will make your users return to your dashboard over and over…and compel them to share it with others!</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84040</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84040</id>
          <name>Brian Carrig</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Design</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2124 (45)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Successfully Running SQL Server in AWS</title>
      <description>Amazon Web Services (AWS) is the world's largest public cloud hosting provider, with many companies successfully running SQL server on AWS infrastructure, but trying to make sense of the available options can be daunting. In this session, we will explore the options available for running SQL server in AWS, either as a managed service or using dedicated EC2 instances. We will document the different storage options, High Availability strategies, as well as important security and maintenance caveats. We will also cover various licensing approaches  available when running SQL server in AWS.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85579</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85579</id>
          <name>Frank Henninger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Support</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2126 (45)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Managing SQL Server on Windows Server Core</title>
      <description>Lately it seems more sysadmins are embracing Windows Server Core as the OS of choice for virtualized servers. SQL Server is (almost) perfectly happy to run in this environment but how do you manage on an OS without a full desktop.

We'll cover what versions and features are supported, how to install sql server via a configuration file,  and what common activities are changed when you move into a Core environment.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83996</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83996</id>
          <name>Brad Llewellyn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analyze</track>
      <location>
        <name>H1-1120 Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning: Four Tips from the Pros</title>
      <description>Azure Machine Learning Studio is one of the most intuitive and approachable machine learning tools in the market today.  In this intermediate session, we'll see four techniques for maximizing the power we get from it, building production-quality machine learning models in a fraction of the time it would take in other tools.  The best part...still no Ph.D. required!  Get ready to be inspired as we unleash the power of the cloud on our data to see what Azure Machine Learning Studio is truly capable of!</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84096</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84096</id>
          <name>Andrew Kelly</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Scale</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2101 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting your Database off to a Right Start</title>
      <description>When you create a new database do you ensure you have done everything you can to give it the chance to shine when things get tough? How many times have you seen a database created with all the defaults and down the road it becomes out of control due to the size, amount of data or even activity? If you really want to ensure your database can scale and perform well at all times you need to do the proper homework before you create the database. We will walk thru the various factors that affect performance and scalability under real life conditions and help you understand how to properly configure them up front to avoid issues down the road. Scalability is all about having a proper foundation to build on.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85607</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85607</id>
          <name>Justin Randall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Perform</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2130 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Improve Performance and Save Space with SQL Server Data Compression</title>
      <description>Your databases are growing and consuming ever-increasing amounts of storage. This rapid unceasing growth creates difficult challenges managing query response times, backups, recovery time, data transfer and essential maintenance. What's a DBA to do? SQL Server data compression is a proven option for saving storage space and improving performance.
In this presentation you will learn how data compression works, how to determine when data compression is the right option, and other planning and implementation considerations.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85625</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85625</id>
          <name>Aaron Bertrand</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Evolve</track>
      <location>
        <name>H1-1120 Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>New T-SQL capabilities in SQL Server 2016, 2017, and beyond</title>
      <description>Discover the ins and outs of some of the newest capabilities of our favorite data language. From SESSION_CONTEXT() to DROP IF EXISTS to CREATE OR ALTER to new query-level hints, you’ll walk away with a long list of reasons to consider upgrading to the latest version or moving to Azure SQL Database.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84100</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84100</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analyze</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2124 (45)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Grokking the Grammar of Graphics</title>
      <description>One of the most popular libraries in R is ggplot2, a graphics library built on a concept called the grammar of graphics.  In this example-heavy talk, we will learn about the grammar of graphics through ggplot2.  We will start by building a series of simple visuals using ggplot2.  Then, we will show how easy it is to add more and more complex functionality to our visuals, showing that we can incrementally add polish to our visuals.  By the end of the talk, you will have the tools to build professional-quality visuals in R.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84409</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84409</id>
          <name>Zach Maddigan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analyze</track>
      <location>
        <name>H1-1120 Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Keeping Data Science Simple in Azure Machine Learning Studio</title>
      <description>As data science becomes a key buzzword that attracts many ears, people often try to overcomplicate the field of Data Science with fancy visualizations, algorithms and terminology. In its most basic form, data science can be broken down into three equal parts that consist of:
1.	Addressing a business problem
2.	 Understanding the data
3.	 Conducting and executing a “science” experiment.  

In this session we will walk through how to approach a data science problem in various phases using predictive analytics in Azure Machine Learning Studio.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84783</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84783</id>
          <name>John Welch</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Build</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2126 (45)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automating the Data-Centric Deployment Pipeline</title>
      <description>Continuous integration, delivery, and deployment are common elements of modern DevOps practices. However, it’s rare to see these practices put into place for data-centric applications, like databases, ETL, data warehouses, or reports. In this session, we’ll cover why these approaches are beneficial for the data organization and the pieces you need to have in place to be successful. We’ll also cover some of the prime trouble spots that organizations run into, as well as some tools that can help jump start your efforts.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85688</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85688</id>
          <name>Mike Burek</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Build</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2123 (25)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Use Python to Make Better Email Reports With Graphs</title>
      <description>Email reports are common and useful for reporting when a process succeeded or failed. You might have also figured out how to make it easier to read with HTML content, and even HTML tables. Sometimes, it still needs more, and needs to be easier.

Come see how to use Python to add graphs of your data to emails as a picture. Plus, you'll see some easier ways to create HTML content for emails using Python.

You'll be surprised how little code is needed for this. It's simpler than you think!</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83998</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83998</id>
          <name>Ramu Pulipati</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Evolve</track>
      <location>
        <name>H1-2105 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting started with Postgresql</title>
      <description>Postgresql is an Open Source, Free, and a Popular alternative database for building software applications. In this session, we will look into Getting started with Postgresql, Review unique features that make it exciting to work with and wrap up the presentation with strategies to deploy and scale for on-premise and cloud deployments.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84545</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84545</id>
          <name>Andy Leonard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Innovate</track>
      <location>
        <name>H1-1120 Auditorium</name>
      </location>
      <title>Moving Data with Azure Data Factory</title>
      <description>Azure Data Factory - ADF - is a cloud data engineering solution. ADF version 2 sports a snappy web GUI (graphical user interface) and supports the SSIS Integration Runtime (IR) - or "SSIS in the Cloud."

Attend this session to learn: 
 - How to build a "native ADF" pipeline;
 - How to lift and shift SSIS to the Azure Data Factory integration Runtime; and
 - ADF Design Patterns to execute and monitor pipelines and packages.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84028</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84028</id>
          <name>Prabhaker Potharaju</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Support</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2101 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Administrating and Managing SQL Server on Linux</title>
      <description>This session covers administrating and managing SQL Server on Linux such as tools, backups  restores and configurations on Linux.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84208</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84208</id>
          <name>Leveat Ruse</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Evolve</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2123 (25)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Resume Tips-Go Beyond the Print Out</title>
      <description>From the basics to the advanced. From paper, to LinkedIn, to what happens when the hiring manager "googles" you. We will explore what makes a GREAT online presence!</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86634</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86634</id>
          <name>Thomas Norman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Design</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2123 (25)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Encrypting Data within SQL Server</title>
      <description>Data breaches abound!  SQL Server has several options to encrypt the data, Transparent Data Encryption, Cell Level Encryption and SQL Server 2016 Always Encrypted.  Let’s review each option to hide the encrypt the data and learn about my experiences implementing Always Encrypted.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86725</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86725</id>
          <name>Andy Leonard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analyze</track>
      <location>
        <name>H1-2105 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Get Management Buy-In for Compliant Provisioning Software</title>
      <description>How to Get Management Buy-In for Compliant Provisioning Software</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84054</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84054</id>
          <name>Michael Moen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Design</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2126 (45)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Models, Productivity, and NODE.JS</title>
      <description>Using a simple dataset construct a model via the POWER BI desktop tool. Create a basic report and start to enhance the report with Measures and Columns. Then move that model into a tabular format and demonstrate the value of Live connect versus In tool design. 

After those demos, use NODE.JS to bring all sorts of data into Power BI. This will conclude with QA on PBI and NODE&gt;</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>84794</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>84794</id>
          <name>Jared Poché</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Perform</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2130 (35)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using DMVs for Performance Root Cause</title>
      <description>What are your first steps when you hear one of your SQL Servers is having a performance problem? In this demo-driven session, we will discuss key DMVs that can provide us data quickly. We will examine a number of example queries that can lead us to a quick root cause analysis in a number of different situations. This session will be kept at a very functional level, and should be accessible for anyone interested in SQL Server performance.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85034</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85034</id>
          <name>Neal Waterstreet</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Design</track>
      <location>
        <name>H2-2124 (45)</name>
      </location>
      <title>Master Data Management with SQL Server 2016 MDS</title>
      <description>Want to know the position Master Data Management and MDS play in an organization's overall data strategy? We'll review the key concepts and the different roles and responsibilities to help you get your organization moving forward with MDM. We'll then take a look at the features of SQL Server 2016 MDS that make it an excellent tool for MDM. This demo-packed presentation will cover architecture and installation, different ways of processing data, hierarchies, security and many other features that will get you up and running with MDS.</description>
      <startTime>10/20/2018 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/20/2018 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>