<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #479 - South Island NZ 2016</name>
    <startDate>4/16/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>100</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+12:00) Fiji, Kamchatka, Marshall Is</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat479</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>CPIT</name>
      <street>Madras Street</street>
      <city>Christchurch</city>
      <state>Canterbury, New Zealand</state>
      <zipcode>8001CPIT</zipcode>
      <longitude>172.6426849</longitude>
      <latitude>-43.5397491</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1591</importID>
      <name>Jade Software Corporation</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.jadeworld.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.jadeworld.com/themes/jadeworld/img/logo/jade-logo-landscape.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1544</importID>
      <name>Mettle Consulting Ltd</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.mettle.net.nz</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.nz-bi.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/mettle.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1115</importID>
      <name>SQL Sentry</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlsentry.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sentryone.com/Images/logos/sentryone-black.svg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1663</importID>
      <name>Datacom</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.datacom.co.nz/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.datacom.co.nz/Datacom/media/Digital-Assets/Logo/datacom-logo-refresh.png?width=183amp;height=56amp;ext=.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1653</importID>
      <name>Candle IT Recruitment</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://candle.co.nz/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.clarius.com.au/media/1256/candle_logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>297</importID>
      <name>SQL Services</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sqlservices.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/986/EventSponsor_14718.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1644</importID>
      <name>Christchurch Polytechnic Institute of Technology</name>
      <label>Personal Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.cpit.ac.nz/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.ara.ac.nz/__data/assets/image/0004/308749/Logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS USE ONLY</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42224</importID>
      <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warwick Rudd is a Data Platform MVP, Microsoft Certified Master, Founder and Principal Consultant at SQL Master Consulting. With 20+ years of experience beginning with the release of SQL Server 6.5, he has worked in both Australia and England from small start-ups to Multi-National Corporations. He hosts the PASS DBA Fundamentals Downunder Virtual Chapter, Organises the PASS SQL Saturday Brisbane event and has spoken at many SQL Server User Groups  SQL Saturday events globally. When not playing with the SQL stack, Warwick likes to get away to the cold and spend time snowboarding.</description>
      <twitter>warwick_Rudd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/pub/warwick-rudd/0/956/718</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmastersconsulting.com.au/Blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=warwick_Rudd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48224</importID>
      <name>Steve Knutson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve is a Microsoft MVP for Office Servers and Services based in Christchurch, New Zealand.

Steve brings more than 25 years of IT industry experience to clients’ projects. Past roles have included solutions architecture, systems engineering, business continuity, software development and IT planning and strategy in the local government, finance, legal, state owned enterprise, and education sectors.

Steve has a Computer Science degree from Massey University and is a Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer and Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist for SQL Server.

Steve is the Managing Director of Stratos Technology Partners and leads consulting work around SharePoint and Office 365.</description>
      <twitter>@nztechtweet</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/steveknutsonnz</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://onehundredwatt.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@nztechtweet</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45229</importID>
      <name>Simon Peck</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Simon is a MCSE in data analytics, certified Biml Expert (BimlHero) and co-author of "The Biml Book" he has been working with SQL Server since the 90's.  Simon is a director of Data Engineers a Christchurch based data solutions provider specialising in Microsoft based cloud and on-premise BI and Data Warehousing solutions.  Having worked for 50+ organisations worldwide over last 20 years he has a wealth of experience across many business sectors,  he is also a co-leader of the Christchurch SQL User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@BIGUYNZ</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/monchopper</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BIGUYNZ</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42486</importID>
      <name>Hamish Watson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hamish Watson is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware Expert with a passion for efficient database and application deployment using DevOps methodologies. 

He has 20+ years of IT experience in managing and deploying large scale databases on SQL Server technologies. 

He has been managing SQL Server since SQL Server 2000, and pragmatic approaches to delivering business value to clients is his career passion.

Educating and helping others learn is a driver for Hamish. He is a Director-At-Large on the PASS Board, international speaker, and a repeat guest lecturer at a local university.</description>
      <twitter>theHybridDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/in/hamishwatson8</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/the-hybrid-dbas-blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=theHybridDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48944</importID>
      <name>Darryl Wolfaardt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Darryl finds that his experience in business as an entrepreneur adds a richer perspective to any BI and data warehouse projects. The past six years in New Zealand has seen him involved in various industries including Utilities, Dairy, Media and Finance. While the consulting phases are typically technology agnostic, project delivery has been mainly on the Microsoft BI stack. Darryl is the founder of Mettle Consulting.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/in/darrylwolfaardt</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42357</importID>
      <name>Manohar Punna</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Manohar Punna is an Data Platform Geek and Vice President of DataPlatformGeeks by passion and a Data Platform Consultant by profession. He is a speaker at various conferences like PASS Summit, SQLBits, DPS. He has authored over 150 blogs and has written a One DMV a Day series which is a longest one day series on any topic on SQL Server till date.
Manohar is a product of this community and strongly believes in giving back to the community. So, ask him anything you would like to know and he is happy to learn it with you.</description>
      <twitter>ManuSQLGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/manohar-punna/15/153/508</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservergeeks.com/author/manoharpunna/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ManuSQLGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48152</importID>
      <name>Manjot Kaur</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working with SQL server for over 10 years. I have been an internal DBA and a consultant. 
I am passionate about automation, cloud technologies, performance tuning and learning SQL internals.
In my free time I love to read, playing with my toddler and trying my hands on new recipes.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>44767</importID>
      <name>John Martin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Martin is a Data Platform Engineer working in the financial sector, as well as Vice President Marketing for the PASS organization and currently a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Previously John has worked as a product manager for SentryOne and a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft UK.

John has over a decade of experience working with SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. Working as a DBA, developer and consultant for Microsoft, he has been lucky enough to see how best, and how not, to use SQL Server and the Data Platform effectively.</description>
      <twitter>SQLDiplomat</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/johnqmartin/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mssqltips.com/sqlserverauthor/291/john-martin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLDiplomat</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46843</importID>
      <name>Martin Catherall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin is a data consultant in Melbourne, Australia, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, and PASS Regional Mentor for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region.
Martin founded the Christchurch, New Zealand PASS Local Group and lead the group for a number of years before relocating to Melbourne.
He has been using SQL Server in various roles since 2000. In addition to anything data related, he enjoys playing the guitar and having fun with his family.</description>
      <twitter>MartyCatherall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/martincatherall</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://martincatherall.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MartyCatherall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46471</importID>
      <name>Reza Rad</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reza Rad is a Microsoft Regional Director, MVP, author, trainer, speaker and consultant. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for nine years from 2011.
Reza wrote many books on Power BI subjects including the Power BI from Rookie to Rock Star, and Pro Power BI Architecture.
Reza is the invited speaker at the world's well-known conferences such as Microsoft Ignite, Microsoft Business Applications Summit, Ignite Tour, PASS Summit, and many other conferences.
Reza is an active blogger and writes regularly about Power BI at https://radacad.com.</description>
      <twitter>Rad_Reza</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/in/rezarad/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://radacad.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rad_Reza</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48163</importID>
      <name>Rob Douglas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robs SQL history started as a remote DBA, branched into consultancy and now includes providing SQL Solutions to a variety of businesses, government departments and banks throughout Australia and New Zealand using a variety of native SQL solutions to meet their performance, higher availability and Disaster Recovery needs.</description>
      <twitter>Rob_DouglasNZ</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=AAMAAAoSId0BNgwoSf_o5y24oIW3PjEHbAmdY-camp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gumption.co.nz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rob_DouglasNZ</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42823</importID>
      <name>Leila Etaati</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leila Etaati is the First Microsoft AI MVP in New Zealand and Australia, as well as a Data Platform MVP. She has a Ph.D. from the University of Auckland and is the co-director and data scientist in RADACAD company with many clients around the world. Additionally, she is the co-organizer of Microsoft Business Intelligence and Power BI Use group in Auckland with more than 1300 members. Leila has also co-organized 3 main conferences in Auckland: SQL Saturday Auckland (from 2015), Difinity (from 2017) and Global AI Bootcamp. She is a data scientist, BI consultant, trainer, and speaker. She is a well-known International speaker to many conferences such as MS Ignite, SQL PASS, Data Platform Summit, SQL Saturday, Power BI World Tour and in Europe, USA, Asia, Australia, and NZ. She has over 10 years’ experience with databases and software systems. Leila is an active Technical Microsoft AI blogger in RADACAD.</description>
      <twitter>@leila_etaati</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/pub/leila-etaati/36/46/b03</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.radacad.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@leila_etaati</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48188</importID>
      <name>Chris Campbell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am Chris.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40558</importID>
      <name>Dave Dustin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With more than 35 years industry experience, Dave has worked with organisations and data systems of all sizes. He is currently Principal Engineer at Xero.</description>
      <twitter>venzann</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=venzann</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48465</importID>
      <name>Peter George</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter is an experienced consultant in the fields of Analytics and Business Intelligence. He has worked for specialist consultancies in NZ and the UK.  He has a wide range of professional interests, from traditional Business Intelligence (Data Visualisation, Data Modelling and ETL) through to more specialist modelling techniques in fields such as Capacity Planning, Finite Resource Scheduling and Discrete Event Simulation. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42333</importID>
      <name>Vijayakumar Thurupathan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thuru is a versatile technical person who has diversified experience in many areas of Information Technology for 6 years. Cloud computing, security, software development, business intelligence and databases are his most preferred technology areas. 

He is a frequent speaker in Sri Lanka .NET forum and Sri Lanka SQL Server Universe user groups. Thuru is the founder of Colombo Cloud Meet Up where he often talks about various cloud computing topics. Also he is a Microsoft MVP for Microsoft Azure.
</description>
      <twitter>thurutweets</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://lk.linkedin.com/in/thuru/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.thuru.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=thurutweets</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46844</importID>
      <name>Martin Catherall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin is a data consultant in Melbourne, Australia, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, and PASS Regional Mentor for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region.
Martin founded the Christchurch, New Zealand PASS Local Group and lead the group for a number of years before relocating to Melbourne.
He has been using SQL Server in various roles since 2000. In addition to anything data related, he enjoys playing the guitar and having fun with his family.</description>
      <twitter>MartyCatherall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/martincatherall</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://martincatherall.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MartyCatherall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>40559</importID>
      <name>Dave Dustin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With more than 35 years industry experience, Dave has worked with organisations and data systems of all sizes. He is currently Principal Engineer at Xero.</description>
      <twitter>venzann</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=venzann</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>43024</importID>
      <name>John Martin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Martin is a Data Platform Engineer working in the financial sector, as well as Vice President Marketing for the PASS organization and currently a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Previously John has worked as a product manager for SentryOne and a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft UK.

John has over a decade of experience working with SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. Working as a DBA, developer and consultant for Microsoft, he has been lucky enough to see how best, and how not, to use SQL Server and the Data Platform effectively.</description>
      <twitter>SQLDiplomat</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/johnqmartin/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mssqltips.com/sqlserverauthor/291/john-martin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLDiplomat</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>42486</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42486</id>
          <name>Hamish Watson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.69</name>
      </location>
      <title>Implementing DevOps methodologies to improve application deployment</title>
      <description>DevOps is a about aligning SQL Server DBAs and Development teams to utilise agile methodologies and continuous integration to optimise application rollouts.

Hamish will discuss the importance of DevOps in industry and how it is a method to leverage people, processes, and tools to remove barriers and improve service delivery. 

DevOps methodologies and culture can help teams to respond faster to competitive pressures by replacing error prone (human) processes with automation so that the experience of production deployments are more repeatable, more reliable and more robust.

In this session, we will look at continuous integration/delivery methods for both applications and databases. Hamish will use a live demo to illustrate the concepts of continuous integration  delivery and show the rewards of reliable production deployment.
</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42333</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42333</id>
          <name>Vijayakumar Thurupathan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.69</name>
      </location>
      <title>Protecting your data in the Cloud</title>
      <description>Are you concerned about moving to cloud, because of the safety of your data ? Organizations choose to go with the platform services of Azure using SQL Databases or they go with the Infrastructure services of Azure using virtual machines, in both cases security of your data is vital. This demo driven session will give you all the information you need to know about the security implementations available in SQL Databases in Azure and SQL Server. The session will cover the following topics with demos. Introduction to cloud adaptation of the organizations, - how enterprises adopt to the cloud and how startups are moving to the cloud. SQL relational store options in Azure. Security features of SQL Databases Cloud demanded security features of SQL Servers Using Azure Key Vault to secure data in SQL Server</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42823</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42823</id>
          <name>Leila Etaati</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Journey into Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <description>Machine learning provides a facility for companies and governments and not-for-profits companies to replace guesses with a valuable data driven predictive analysis. Azure Machin Learning is valuable tools that can be employed by all data scientist with different skill levels. In this session, a brief description about the azure machine learning, algorithms selection, importing data from different resources, creating web service, using the created web service in a .net project, calling the web service from Excel files, and comparison of the azure Machin Learning with SSAS mining structure approach will be presented. This session will be accompany with demos and provide a full process of data analytics using Azure Machine Learning.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42357</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42357</id>
          <name>Manohar Punna</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>N1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>DBA life made easier with SQL Server 2016 - Query Store and LQS</title>
      <description>DBA always faces challenges in troubleshooting live performance issues. In SQL Server 2016, the two new features introduced to help a DBA to be more productive. The Query Store is a feature that will help in visualizing what is happening with your executing queries, which otherwise is hard to collect with DMVs. The UI rich interface makes it easier to troubleshoot live scenarios as well has collect data for troubleshooting. Have you ever felt a need to see the execution plan when executing a query while troubleshooting? Live Query Statistics helps you view the live execution plan rather than waiting till end of the execution of query to see the actual execution plan. This session is recommended for advanced users as you will need basic understanding of troubleshooting using execution plans. </description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 3:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 4:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>44767</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>44767</id>
          <name>John Martin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>N1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>High Availability for SQL Server Standard Edition</title>
      <description>SQL Server High Availability is normally spoken about with Enterprise Edition features, however not all of us use Enterprise Edition, so what do we have in Standard Edition? In this session we will look at what options we have for building Highly Available systems in Standard Edition.

Looking at how to combine the different features such as clustering, mirroring and the new basic Availability Groups so that you can have much of the capability that you see in Enterprise Edition but without the high cost. I will demonstrate some of the ways that we can build solutions that are accessible to all with design patterns that you can upgrade to Enterprise at a later date if you upgrade your systems. </description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45229</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45229</id>
          <name>Simon Peck</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>Benefits of SSIS ETL automation with BIML</title>
      <description>Redefining business intelligence ROI is one of Varigences' (The creators of BIML) key headlines.  During this "from the field" session we will step through some real life scenarios where BIML was not only cheaper and faster but better than traditional methods of SSIS development.
We'll also explore some less obvious time savers I've discovered while using BIML for BI implementations.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48224</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48224</id>
          <name>Steve Knutson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>Business Intelligence for all with Power BI</title>
      <description>It’s a fact, we are now recording and storing more business data than ever before. Whether you are the CFO, Marketing Manager,  HR Manager, customer services representative or business owner, you are probably swamped with data that is meaningless unless you spend hours building the mother of all spreadsheets. Power BI allows you to visualise and analyse data from a wide variety of sources, both in-house and off the cloud quickly, easily and at a price everyone can afford.

Learn how Power BI improves your Business Intelligence. In this session Steve demonstrates Power BI dashboards, reports and natural language queries to answer real-world business questions.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 3:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 4:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46471</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46471</id>
          <name>Reza Rad</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>Incremental Load using CDC and Integration Service</title>
      <description>Incremental Load is one of the main challenges in loading data warehouse. SQL Server Integration Services 2012 comes with Change Data Capture (CDC) components that helps to improve incremental load. CDC can be used with Oracle or SQL Server database.
In this session a brief architecture design for solving incremental load will be discussed and then a real world sample of Incremental will be implemented through a demo with CDC components of SSIS 2012.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48152</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48152</id>
          <name>Manjot Kaur</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.69</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance Based Indexing</title>
      <description>SQL server indexes need to be effective so that data could be manipulated with minimum resource consumption. Having too few indexes will result in scanning full tables and having too many indexes will result in incurring un-necessary costs in keeping the index up-to-date. Even if the number of indexes "seem" sufficient, de-fragmenting is only one side of the story. In this session, we will cover index creation best practices and demo sql cache based index tuning, duplicate indexes, and more.
</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 3:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 4:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46843</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46843</id>
          <name>Martin Catherall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Lap Around Columnstore.</title>
      <description>Columnstore indexing was first introduced in SQL Server 2012.  
The technology was designed to give significant performance gains for datawarehouse queries. 
This initial version required some creative thinking to get all of the promised performance gains. This meant that adoption rates were not that high. 
However, SQL Server 2014 added significant functionality, which SQL Server 2016 builds upon. Come along and get a lap around this feature and find out how its adoption could help your organisation.
Attendees should leave this session will enough knowledge about the storage, architecture and query enhancements to implement a successful columnstore feature and administer it.
</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42224</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42224</id>
          <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>N1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>How Available is SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>Having your SQL Server databases not available for business to be making money is not a good way to stay employed. Do you understand what features and options can assist you with keeping SQL Server Databases Available?

In this session we will look at the options available to you currently to meet your Availability requirements using features being released in SQL Server 2016 to better provide high availability
</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40559</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40559</id>
          <name>Dave Dustin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>Managing and Monitoring SQL Server for $0 without sacrificing functionality, performance or data…</title>
      <description>One of the most important aspects of  DBAs role is making sure your servers and the databases housed on them are up and performing as expected.  Not only does this mean reacting if (when) something goes wrong. You need to be proactive and work towards identifying potential issues before they occur. In addition, with proper monitoring you can often identify ways to improve performance for "free"

This session covers using features built into Windows, SQL Server as well as extending with free 3rd-party components and solutions.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46844</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46844</id>
          <name>Martin Catherall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>N1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>Moving from Profiler to Extended Events.</title>
      <description>Profiler has been with us for a long time and it's pretty much the goto tool for a lot of performance related issues but there's been a new tool around for a few years now - actually since SQL SERVER 2008 - but there doesn't seem to have been a big uptake of it. Well, after this session hopefully that will all change for you...</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48188</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48188</id>
          <name>Chris Campbell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.69</name>
      </location>
      <title>Embracing Database Theft</title>
      <description>In a day and age where database theft is becoming increasingly more frequent, why do we continue to be negligent of our duty to protect user data? Why is it that we have a raft of security features made available to us within SQL Server, and strong cryptographic libraries and solid object-relational mapping frameworks at our disposal, but still opt for insecure alternatives? In this session we'll explore the consequences of directing application development down the better known and more convenient path, and why approaching it from the perspective that your data will inevitably be stolen is what will give you the best chance of surviving a breach.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>40558</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>40558</id>
          <name>Dave Dustin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>S1.69</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Window functions – reducing the need for cursors and other horrible stuff</title>
      <description>Window functions have been part of SQL Server since 2005.  In 2012, we got some new additions that make performing aggregations, running counts, n-1 / n+1, and much more that could previously only be done with RBAR loops.

This developer focused session describes and details usage of these features, covering theoretical and real world scenarios.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48163</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48163</id>
          <name>Rob Douglas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>N1.04</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hitting the SQL Server "Go Faster" Button</title>
      <description>Tuning individual queries is incredibly resource intensive.  Everyone wants a "Go Faster" button that will improve performance across the entire SQL instance.  While there is no sp_gofaster command to run, there are a bunch of magic knobs and switches that can quite often achieve the desired results.
  In this session we'll look at some of the things you can do to get the best performance out of your SQL Server workload.  You'll leave with a shopping list of things to check and options to try in your environments to get the performance you are after.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>