<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #563 - Dallas 2016</name>
    <startDate>9/24/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>750</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-06:00) Saskatchewan</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat563</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>University of Texas at Arlington</name>
      <street>416 Yates Street</street>
      <city>Arlington</city>
      <state>Texas</state>
      <zipcode>76019</zipcode>
      <longitude>-97.1132330596447</longitude>
      <latitude>32.7328138053417</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1742</importID>
      <name>Architecting Innovation</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.theaiteam.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://theaiteam.com/images/AI_Logo_FULL_ALT_sm.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1511</importID>
      <name>The University of Texas at Arlington (UTA)</name>
      <label>Venue Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.uta.edu/engineering</url>
      <imageURL>https://northtexas.pass.org/portals/316/Sponsors/UTA_COE2.gif</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>772</importID>
      <name>Kaminario</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.kaminario.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/39c8496e-246b-4f5a-a6ea-17eae02987fc.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>23</importID>
      <name>Pragmatic Works</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pragmaticworks.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/973/EventSponsor_14499.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>85</importID>
      <name>Pyramid Analytics</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.PyramidAnalytics.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://pages.pyramidanalytics.com/rs/pyramidanalytics/images/logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>607</importID>
      <name>DELL EMC</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.dellemc.com/en-us/index.htm</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/913/EventSponsor_14262.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>13</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/sqlsaturday/eventsponsors/Quest_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1503</importID>
      <name>Improving</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.improving.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.allenkinsel.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Improving_SQLSAT514.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1115</importID>
      <name>SQL Sentry</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlsentry.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sentryone.com/Images/logos/sentryone-black.svg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14586.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>299</importID>
      <name>SQLvariant</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://sqlvariant.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlvariant.com/BlogSupport/Images/SQLvariant_Logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52734</importID>
      <name>Trayce Jordan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Working with SQL Server for almost 20 years, Trayce is one of the first certified masters, holding an MCM for SQL 2005 and has been working at Microsoft since 2006.   Prior to joining Microsoft, he worked for a major online travel company as well as financial institutions and has served as a consultant working with companies in many different industries.  His specialties include database performance tuning, operations management and support, high availability and disaster recovery.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52987</importID>
      <name>Konstantin Melamud</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Konstantin has over 15 years of SQL Server experience and demonstrates his expertise and commitment to helping SQL Server DBAs succeed through his position as Director of Service Delivery at RDX.  In his role, Konstantin is responsible for designing and implementing RDX’s service delivery strategies, including those for SQL Server. Since joining RDX in 2009, Konstantin has proven to be a strong leader and expert in SQL Server database administration, architecture, performance tuning, and business intelligence. He is also a very active member of the SQL Server community and frequently presents at SQL Saturdays and user groups throughout the year. In addition, Konstantin presented during 24 Hours of PASS  and at the PASS Summits.</description>
      <twitter>@kmelamud</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@kmelamud</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52410</importID>
      <name>John Harp</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With 17 years in the technical support field and more than a decade working with Microsoft SQL Server, John has seen some of the weirdest errors and most spectacular failures SQL Server can generate. And he#39;s solved most of them, with a little help from his friends in the SQL Server Community. John is the Technical Support Manager for Idera#39;s SQL Server Products. </description>
      <twitter>@sekainohaten</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/john-harp/0/914/179</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sekainohaten</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52795</importID>
      <name>Rachael Martino</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rachael has been both an IT Executive and a Consultant. Systems training, data based application development experience and leadership training have prepared her to build stable. maintainable and successful solutions.

Rachael has been in the industry working with SQL Server since SQL 2000.  She started out her IT life as an application developer and lead a team of developers, creating data centric applications using SQL Server and Oracle.  She has worked in the Business Intelligence field using SSAS, multi-dimensional and Tabular, SSRS, SSIS, and PowerBI.  She has two Masters degrees from MIT, Systems Design and Management amp; Civil Engineering Information Technology.  Her interests surround the Big Data and Data Science areas.</description>
      <twitter>@RMartinoBoston</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rachaelmartino</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@RMartinoBoston</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52385</importID>
      <name>Bob Ward</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Ward is a Principal Architect for the Microsoft Azure Data SQL Server team, which owns the development for all SQL Server versions. Bob has worked for Microsoft for 26+ years on every version of SQL Server shipped from OS/2 1.1 to SQL Server 2019 including Azure SQL. Bob is a well-known speaker on SQL Server, often presenting talks on new releases, internals, and performance at events such as PASS Summit, Red Hat Summit, Microsoft Ready, SQLBits, SQLIntersection, Microsoft Inspire, and Microsoft Ignite. You can follow him at @bobwardms or linkedin.com/in/bobwardms. Bob is the author of the books Pro SQL Server on Linux and SQL Server 2019 Revealed available from Apress Media.
Twitter: http://twitter.com/bobwardms.</description>
      <twitter>bobwardms</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/bobsql</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bobwardms</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52777</importID>
      <name>David Stein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Stein - Agile Data Warehouse Architect and Independent Consultant - has more than a decade of experience working in SQL Server Business Intelligence. He’s designed multi-terabyte, multi-tenant Data Warehouses from scratch as well as saved projects in serious jeopardy.</description>
      <twitter>@Made2Mentor</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/david-stein/8/ba8/705</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.Made2Mentor.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Made2Mentor</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53005</importID>
      <name>Amy Herold</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Amy Herold is currently a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft, specializing in APS. Prior to this, she was a Sr. Database Administrator, focusing on PowerShell and automation. She is also currently the Director of Programs for the North Texas SQL Server User Group (NTSSUG). She frequently speaks at SQL Saturday and user group events across the United States and has also participated in numerous Women in Technology sessions as a panelist. Amy currently blogs at sqlkitten.com.</description>
      <twitter>@texasamy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aherold</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlkitten.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@texasamy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52544</importID>
      <name>Andy Tabisz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andy Tabisz is a Microsoft MVP and owner of WorkSmart Database Masters based in Grand Rapids, MI.  WorkSmart provides custom database and mobile solutions for small to mid-sized corporations using Access, SQL/Azure, ASP.NET, SharePoint, Power BI, Excel and integration with many technologies.  Through rapid application development, WorkSmart empowers organizations to work smarter and make better decisions by automating workflow, alerts and reporting capabilities.</description>
      <twitter>@AccessWisdom</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/andytabisz</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.worksmartdb.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@AccessWisdom</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52984</importID>
      <name>Lori Edwards</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lori Edwards currently holds the position of Solutions Engineer for SentryOne. Prior to working with SQLSentry, she spent 11 years working as a production DBA.  She also has volunteered for PASS since 2009 on the Program Committee, ERC, Nomination Committee and speaking at SQL Saturdays.</description>
      <twitter>www.twitter.com/loriaedwards</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/loriedwards/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservertimes2.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=www.twitter.com/loriaedwards</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50317</importID>
      <name>Ryan Casey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Public Speaker, and Group Moderator

SQL Saturday Speaker @
	• Houston, TX 2018
	• Dallas, TX 2018, 2017 (BI), 2016, 2015
	• Phoenix, AZ 2018, 2017 (BI)
	• Kansas City, MO 2017
	• Baton Rouge, LA 2017
	• Oklahoma City, OK 2016
	• San Antonio, TX 2016

SQL User Group Speaker @
	• NTSSUG, Dallas, TX
	• CACTUSS, Austin, TX
	• OKCSQL, Oklahoma City, OK
	• MSBIC, Dallas, TX
	• SALSSA, San Antonio, TX
	• FWSSUG, Fort Worth, TX

AIM Business Driven Data Solutions combines the collaborative and creative arts included in Technical Communication, the business acumen of a Harvard MBA program, and the technical discipline of object-oriented programming and business intelligence (data warehouses).</description>
      <twitter>@AimYourData</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryancaseymba/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.AimYourData.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@AimYourData</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50424</importID>
      <name>Mindy Curnutt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mindy Curnutt is a 5X Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Business Owner and Entrepreneur. Her specialties include SQL Server hardware, configuration, migrations, scalability, performance tuning.  She has been actively involved in the SQL Server Community for over two decades and has become a well known speaker within the SQL and Transportation Management communities. She is a two-time PASS Volunteer of the Month, has presented at 6 SQLPASS Summits, Live360, DevConnections, MVPMix and too many SQL Saturdays to count. She is currently the President of the North Texas SQL Server User Group out of Dallas/Fort Worth, TX.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mindycurnutt</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mindycurnutt.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50755</importID>
      <name>David Klee</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Klee is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware vExpert with a lifelong passion for technology. David spends his days focusing on the convergence of data and infrastructure as the Founder of Heraflux Technologies. His areas of expertise include cloud, virtualization, performance, and business continuity. David speaks at a number of national and regional technology related events, including PASS Summit, VMware VMworld, SQLBits, SQL Saturday events, and many SQL Server User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>kleegeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidaklee</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://davidklee.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kleegeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52418</importID>
      <name>Ginger Grant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ginger Grant manages the consultancy Desert Isle Group and shares what she has learned while working with data technology to people around the world.  As a Microsoft MVP in Data Platform, Microsoft Certified Trainer and an instructor on DataCamp, she focuses on guiding clients to create solutions using the entire Microsoft Data Stack, which includes SQL Server, Power BI, and Azure Data Cloud components. When not working, she protypes the latest pre-release data technologies, maintains her blog http://www.desertislesql.com, and spends time on twitter @desertislesql.</description>
      <twitter>desertislesql</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ginger-grant-3a177b157/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.DesertIsleSQL.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=desertislesql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52933</importID>
      <name>William Wolf</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bill is the Manager of SQL Server Performance Tuning for RDX.  He works with over 400 customers on solutions within the SQL Server environment and specialized in code tuning and mentoring the team within RDX. He has become a SQL Saturday veteran speaking at nearly 40 SQL Saturdays in the last 3 years.  He has also spoken at Summit and is an Idera Ace class of 2018. Bill is active in the Pittsburgh SQL Server User Group.  He is also the chapter lead for the DevOps Virtual User Group. He is passionate about educating users on SQL Server and mentoring others.</description>
      <twitter>sqlwarewolf</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamjwolf</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlwarewolf.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlwarewolf</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54265</importID>
      <name>Roberto Cavalcanti</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Roberto Cavalcanti is a Sr. Support Escalation Engineer with the Microsoft CSS Azure SQL Database support team. He is a database specialist with over 20 years working in the database industry. Since joining Microsoft CSS SQL Escalation team in 2008, Roberto has been passionate about customer support. He has been supporting Azure SQL Database since 2010, when it was still called SQL Azure. Roberto has written many articles about Azure SQL Database for MSDN/TechNet, SQL Magazine, and has been a speaker in internal and external events such as TechReady, Microsoft Insights/TechEd, and has delivered SQL training to many Microsoft SQL Support Engineers in multiple countries. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertocavalcanti</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50324</importID>
      <name>Steve Allison</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a long time IT person who started programming in 1976 with my father.  I started with Basic on a TI994A, TV on Channel 4 as the monitor and my cassette player as my hard drive.  I grew into Microsoft Basic and text files for data in the 80#39;s, ASP, Access, Excel, and Visual Basic in the 90#39;s, and in the 2000#39;s I did MySql and MSSql and moved the front end to Coldfusion platform.  I have moved my apps to web based and build most everything in JQuery, Coldfusion, Coldbox, and MSSql for the db.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://steve.evengame.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50319</importID>
      <name>Stacy Gray</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stacy is a leader of some of the best SQL Server  Azure SQL VM support engineers at Microsoft.  Her team troubleshoots and overcomes obstacles all day, every day, for the largest companies in the world.  She has worked with every version of SQL Server from SQL 6.5 to now, and recently certified to be a Microsoft Specialist: Design and Implement Cloud Data Platform Solutions. An experienced speaker, she's presented at the following SQLSaturdays:  Oklahoma City, Dallas, Houston  Baton Rouge.</description>
      <twitter>@stacylaray</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stacylaray</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://stacylaray.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@stacylaray</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50428</importID>
      <name>Kris Hokanson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kris has been building databases for over 20 years. Since SQL Server 7 he’s been looking for ways to shave a second (or an hour) off any query he comes across. His work experience ranges from small construction firms to fortune 200 Oil amp; Gas corporations.  He has designed and administered everything from 10 MB single user databases to enterprise data warehouses using SQL Server and SSIS to consolidate data from hundreds of disparate ERP systems.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54262</importID>
      <name>Rick Lowe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick is a Microsoft Certified Master with more than 20 years of SQL Server experience in a variety of roles. He currently lives in Washington state and works as an independent consultant providing remote performance DBA and performance tuning services for clients in the USA and Canada. His first exposure to SQL Server was as a database developer, but over time he became more and more interested in how the database engine operated... eventually specializing more on performance issues than code.

Rick will work with all things relational, but most enjoys helping smaller companies get better performance from MSSQL, as well as smoothing over relationships between DBA and development teams.</description>
      <twitter>DataFLowe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rick-lowe/a/228/441/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataflowe.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataFLowe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53018</importID>
      <name>Jared Nielsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rather than accepting the status quo, I believe in learning everything, and nothing, and mixing it all together until you have a strange, unique and ethereal blend of technology, marketing, knowledge, wisdom, creativity, passion, charity, caring, and humility. I think that being uncategorizable is the goal since life is the voyage, not the destination, so too should work be that extension of the undefinable so you </description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/FUZIONAgency</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/company/the-fuzion-agency</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.FUZIONAgency.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/FUZIONAgency</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50325</importID>
      <name>Sean Werick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been in the data industry for 15 years, specializing in Microsoft business intelligence for the last decade. I have architected, developed and integrated end to end solutions for customers in various sectors including finance, government, health care and retail. I am extremely passionate about data and the endless possibilities for companies utilizing it in the best ways. I enjoy data science and business intelligence because the possibilities and magnitudes of impact are immeasurable.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/seanwerick</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.seanwerick.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50540</importID>
      <name>John Sterrett</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Sterrett is a MCSE: Data Platform, Principal Consultant, and the Founder of Procure SQL LLC.  John has experience presenting at community events, including Microsoft Ignite, PASS Member Summit, SQLRally, 24 Hours of PASS, SQL Saturdays, PASS Chapters, and Virtual Chapter meetings. John is a leader of the Austin SQL Server User Group and is the founder of the HADR Virtual Chapter. John's community activities can be found at https://johnsterrett.com/community/</description>
      <twitter>JohnSterrett</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/johnsterrett</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://johnsterrett.com/community/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=JohnSterrett</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53036</importID>
      <name>Chris Shaw</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Shaw started his database career in 1993. Following the Marines, Chris continued working with databases for companies such as Wells Fargo, Pulte Mortgage, and Yellow Pages Inc. Chris has been writing and speaking about SQL Server for over 15 years at events such as SQL Connections, PASS Summit, and SSWUG Ultimate conferences. Chris received his 5th Microsoft MVP award.  </description>
      <twitter>@SQLShaw</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/christophershaw/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://chrisshaw.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLShaw</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50327</importID>
      <name>Bryan Smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bryan is a Data Solution Specialist with Microsoft Las Colinas, focused on data-driven solutions in the Azure cloud.  He also teaches analytics technologies within the MBA amp; MSBA programs at SMU Cox School of Business.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/bryan-smith/17/98b/161</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50627</importID>
      <name>Steven Ormrod</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steven Ormrod is a Database Administrator. He focuses on high-availability  and clustering, with a dash of performance tuning thrown in for fun. His environments consist of hundreds of servers spread across multiple countries. He is on the board of directors for the Austin, Texas PASS Chapter and speaks at user groups and SQL Saturdays. Steven holds a BS in Computer Science and a Masters of Education. He is a SQL Server MCM.</description>
      <twitter>@DBOrmrod</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://stevenormrod.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DBOrmrod</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54349</importID>
      <name>Russel Loski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Russ Loski is a SQL Server BI Developer based in Dallas-Fort Worth.  He current works as a Data Analytics Engineer for Navisite, a remote managed IT services company.   Twenty years ago, he began working with SQL Server 6.5. He has since continued to develop applications connected to all of the versions of SQL Server. He has worked with clients in industries from insurance to healthcare, from movie theaters to American football.  Russ is a regular speaker at SQLSaturday events, as well as the SQL Server Users Groups in the North Texas region. Russ likes working with data in various shapes.</description>
      <twitter>sqlmovers</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/russloski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmovers.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmovers</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52972</importID>
      <name>Louis Mangiacapra</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Louis Mangiacapra is a business intelligence consultant with a variety of experience in consulting and industry.  He has demonstrated the ability to incorporate business intelligence with enterprise architecture and integration.  With his diverse experience of both business and IT functions, he has a great ability to act as a liaison to understand business requirements and apply it to a technical audience.  Louis has worked in a variety of industries including insurance, banking/credit unions, retail, and education</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/tamulou24</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lmangiacapra</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/tamulou24</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53580</importID>
      <name>Latish Sehgal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Latish is a .NET Principal Consultant with Improving Enterprises and very passionate about software development and solving customer problems. He also created SqlSmash, a productivity plugin for SSMS. He can be reached via his blog at http://www.dotnetsurfers.com/ or twitter (http://twitter.com/latish).</description>
      <twitter>latish</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.dotnetsurfers.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=latish</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50316</importID>
      <name>Silvia Doomra</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Silvia is a Program Manager in Azure SQL Database Team. She has experience of over 8 years in Microsoft working on different technologies like Windows Server, Visual Studio, Mobile Operators. Currently she is working in Azure SQL Database team building scale-out database technologies.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/silviadoomra?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50396</importID>
      <name>Mike Byrd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Former rocket scientist and USAF Fighter Pilot -- now a SQL Server geek (24 years)! Past opportunities include free-lance technical writer for PC Magazine, Senior Software Manager for government sponsored munitions effectiveness committee, and insurance company CTO.  Currently senior database engineer consultant for several Austin companies.  

Presenter at many SQL Saturdays over last 6 years in United States, Europe, and Australia.

Specialize in SQL Server performance tuning; database (OLTP  OLAP) architecture; trouble-shooting; teaching TSQL (Basic through Advanced).

Video presentations (for local SQL Server user groups or SQL Saturdays) can be found at http://usergroup.tv/videos/category/speaker/mike-byrd</description>
      <twitter>ByrdNest_TX</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-byrd/1/aa0/bbb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://logicalread.solarwinds.com/?s=byrd, www.TSQLMentoring.com and SQLServerCentral.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ByrdNest_TX</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50639</importID>
      <name>Lance Tidwell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lance Tidwell, from the Austin, TX, area, has worked as a SQL Server DBA for the last 11 years. During his time as a DBA he has found his passion for all things SQL, but specifically for performance tuning. He has a life-long quest to always be learning new things; currently this quest has lead him to explore more about the Data Analytics/ Data Science areas.</description>
      <twitter>@Lance_LT</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://lancetidwell.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Lance_LT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52935</importID>
      <name>Ryan Adams</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ryan Adams is a Senior Premier Field Engineer for Microsoft.  He works directly with customers to help them realize their business potential and accelerate their digital transformation on premises and in the cloud.

Previously, Ryan was a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and spent 19 years working for a fortune 100 company.  His passion is the SQL Server Engine, High Availability, and Disaster Recovery. He also served on the Board of Directors for the North Texas SQL Server User Group, was President of the PASS Performance Virtual Chapter, was a PASS Regional Mentor, and served as a Director for the PASS organization.</description>
      <twitter>@ryanjadams</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanjadams</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ryanjadams.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ryanjadams</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53057</importID>
      <name>Chris Shaw</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Shaw started his database career in 1993. Following the Marines, Chris continued working with databases for companies such as Wells Fargo, Pulte Mortgage, and Yellow Pages Inc. Chris has been writing and speaking about SQL Server for over 15 years at events such as SQL Connections, PASS Summit, and SSWUG Ultimate conferences. Chris received his 5th Microsoft MVP award.  </description>
      <twitter>@SQLShaw</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/christophershaw/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://chrisshaw.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLShaw</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50310</importID>
      <name>Anthony van Gemert</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Anthony has more than 14 years in IT leadership positions, including 8 years of program management with Microsoft leading and managing diverse teams globally. He currently works with the SQL data systems engineering team on SQL Stretch database, part of the SQL Server 2016 release. His focusing on front end UX, customer engagement, and the upgrade experience.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52755</importID>
      <name>Michael Bourgon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Bourgon started his IT career by performing tech support and managing Sybase databases on Unix starting in 1995, before moving to SQL Server 7... continuing all the way to SQL Server 2017.  His focus on automation has led him to such diverse topics as Service Broker, WMI, Table Partitioning, Shell scripting, In-Memory Tables, and Powershell. He's currently a senior DBA with a large healthcare company, dealing with millions of transactions of day and managing hundreds of servers.  In his spare time he rides a bicycle, reads science fiction, blogs about SQL Server and Baking, and tries to raise his daughter to be a geek, too.</description>
      <twitter>@mbourgon</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelbourgon</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://thebakingdba.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mbourgon</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52999</importID>
      <name>Daniel Janik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Daniel Janik has been supporting SQL Server for 18 years. Six of those years were at Microsoft Corporation supporting SQL Server as a Senior Premier Field Engineer (PFE) where he supported over 287 different clients with both reactive and proactive database needs. Daniel has presented at many community events and SQL Saturdays.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLSME</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/daniel-janik/12/15b/606/en</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqltechblog.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLSME</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54263</importID>
      <name>Amy Herold</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Amy Herold is currently a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft, specializing in APS. Prior to this, she was a Sr. Database Administrator, focusing on PowerShell and automation. She is also currently the Director of Programs for the North Texas SQL Server User Group (NTSSUG). She frequently speaks at SQL Saturday and user group events across the United States and has also participated in numerous Women in Technology sessions as a panelist. Amy currently blogs at sqlkitten.com.</description>
      <twitter>@texasamy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aherold</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlkitten.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@texasamy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54412</importID>
      <name>George Govantes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Architect and Senior SQL Database Administrator with over 20 years of experience turned Chief Information Security Officer, Certified Information Security Manager, and Governance Risk and Compliance Certified Professional that helps organizations develop cloud and on-prem Identity and Information Security programs.  He also trains and consults in the area of IT leadership and the development of high-performance teams.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/georgegovantes/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54431</importID>
      <name>David Stein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Stein - Agile Data Warehouse Architect and Independent Consultant - has more than a decade of experience working in SQL Server Business Intelligence. He’s designed multi-terabyte, multi-tenant Data Warehouses from scratch as well as saved projects in serious jeopardy.</description>
      <twitter>@Made2Mentor</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/david-stein/8/ba8/705</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.Made2Mentor.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Made2Mentor</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54455</importID>
      <name>Craig Allen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Craig Allen is a Dell EMC mSpecialist (Microsoft Specialist). His role as a technical consultant is to help customers in understanding Dell EMC's products for the Microsoft platform. Craig can assist in the initial planning and evaluation of Dell EMC’s Proven Solutions for Microsoft, including requirements gathering, architectural guidance, and integration considerations. 
　
Craig is located in Dallas, TX and comes to Dell EMC with 25 years of experience in IT.</description>
      <twitter>@msftdude</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/craigdallen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.msftdude.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@msftdude</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>51047</importID>
      <name>Matthew Brimer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matthew Brimer has 10 years experience with SQL Server, 3 of which was spent as a Database Security expert for a Department of Defense Agency and 5 as the Database/Security Manager for a leading Pharmacy Services Company.  These days Matt can be found helping customers get the most out of the Databases/Servers/Networks as a Consultant for InterWorks.  Matt also holds several Security and Microsoft Certifications, is the President of OKC SQL PASS Chapter and is the former Event Chair for SQL Saturday Oklahoma City.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlcenturion</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlcenturion/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlcenturion.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlcenturion</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54471</importID>
      <name>Mark Wheeler</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working with SQL Server for 20+ years. SQL Server has come a long way in that time. My current role is helping clients implement solutions on various versions of SQL Server either as a BI or application database developer .  

In my off time, I enjoy the peace and quiet of scuba diving.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/markrwheeler</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>51147</importID>
      <name>Bala Shankar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bala is a Senior Escalation Engineer in the Microsoft Data Platform support team in Dallas, Texas.  Bala has worked 11 Years at Microsoft supporting SQL Server stretching back to SQL 7.0. He has interacted with many large SQL Server deployments on various component of SQL Server like the database engine, performance, replication and Azure. Bala is the lead for SQL Server on Azure Virtual Machine within Microsoft Support.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54343</importID>
      <name>Ryan Adams</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ryan Adams is a Senior Premier Field Engineer for Microsoft.  He works directly with customers to help them realize their business potential and accelerate their digital transformation on premises and in the cloud.

Previously, Ryan was a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and spent 19 years working for a fortune 100 company.  His passion is the SQL Server Engine, High Availability, and Disaster Recovery. He also served on the Board of Directors for the North Texas SQL Server User Group, was President of the PASS Performance Virtual Chapter, was a PASS Regional Mentor, and served as a Director for the PASS organization.</description>
      <twitter>@ryanjadams</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanjadams</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ryanjadams.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ryanjadams</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>51079</importID>
      <name>Rowdy Vinson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reformed SysAdmin with 15 years in IT. I'm a geek at heart and enjoy 3d printing, gardening, and Minecraft in my free time.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/RowdyVinson</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rowdy-vinson-0600024</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/RowdyVinson</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54513</importID>
      <name>Sri Sridharan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sri is the President of North Texas SQL Server User Group. Sri has been involved with SQL Server since version 4.2 and has held various roles developer/dba/ architect / pre-sales over the years. He is largely responsible for some of  few features in SQL 2008 like TDE and tools like MAPS. Sri holds a Bachelor's Degree in Physics , Masters in Computer Information Systems and an MBA in Finance. His wife Hema, made sure he got a 3rd Masters in parenting their 2 sons.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlrocks</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlrocks.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlrocks</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50334</importID>
      <name>Stan Geiger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data Architect and BI Architect.    Experience building Data Warehouse and ETL platforms, BI Analytics and OLTP systems.  He is currently a Director of Product Manager at Idera, responsible for the development of the multi-platform tools.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50636</importID>
      <name>Jamey Johnston</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jamey Johnston is a Senior Data Scientist/Engineer for a large independent OG company. For over 25 years, he has worked for Fortune 500 companies architecting successful platforms in the cloud, on the edge, and on-premises for BI reporting, statistical analysis, ML, and AI. Lately, he spends his time in Azure, Python, R, Power BI, MS SQL, and SAS JMP. He holds a BS in Spatial Analysis from LSU and a Masters of Science in Analytics from Texas AM. He is a professor at the Mays Business School at Texas AM in the MS Analytics program. He is active in his PASS Local Group in Houston, co-leader of the local Power BI users group and data analytics group. He regularly speaks and volunteers at PASS events. He is also a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>STATCowboy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jameyj</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://STATCowboy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=STATCowboy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54411</importID>
      <name>Mike Burek</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>He started by building a complete computerized inventory management system for a multi-state store. Next, he managed Texas Medicare and Medicaid claim data to keep it processing, and building new monitoring metrics. Afterwards, he processed and analyzed  marketing data on tens of millions of customers and sent hundreds of millions of multi-lingual marketing messages worldwide. Upgrading those marketing skills, he then worked to process and query tune marketing data for tens of thousands of worldwide enterprise customers, bringing in tens of millions of dollars per campaign. Now he monitors database servers to keep them running well, tunes queries, and helps businesses build new ETL processes. He also runs the Austin, TX user group.</description>
      <twitter>mikeburek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mikeburek</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tikiwiki.mikeburek.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mikeburek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50322</importID>
      <name>Simon Cho</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Simon Cho is one of the founders of SQLAngeles.com, which is a Los Angeles Korean Tech PASS community group.

As a Local Group leader, he is a Microsoft SQL community speaker. He has presented many times at SQLSaturdays and to PASS Local Groups.

He moved his passion to VISA Inc, the largest credit card provider in the world, where he used database technology to build a strong solution and a secure environment, with new strategies and features to maintain thousands of SQL Servers.

He has now joined the Nowcom Corp, as a Director of DevOps, where he leads the DevOps team and DBA team.

He is pretty much working on SQL server running on kubernetes.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/simonsql</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://simonsql.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50458</importID>
      <name>Naomi Williams</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Naomi Williams is a SQL Server professional working in the San Antonio area. Currently a seasoned Database Administrator  for both Oracle and SQL Server  doing database development, SSIS, SSRS and SSAS.  Naomi has been working with SQL Server for almost 15 years. Naomi is passionate about performance, high availability, and creative non standard solutions to complex problems</description>
      <twitter>naomithesqldba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nfwilliams</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=naomithesqldba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>51040</importID>
      <name>Bob Ward</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Ward is a Principal Architect for the Microsoft Azure Data SQL Server team, which owns the development for all SQL Server versions. Bob has worked for Microsoft for 26+ years on every version of SQL Server shipped from OS/2 1.1 to SQL Server 2019 including Azure SQL. Bob is a well-known speaker on SQL Server, often presenting talks on new releases, internals, and performance at events such as PASS Summit, Red Hat Summit, Microsoft Ready, SQLBits, SQLIntersection, Microsoft Inspire, and Microsoft Ignite. You can follow him at @bobwardms or linkedin.com/in/bobwardms. Bob is the author of the books Pro SQL Server on Linux and SQL Server 2019 Revealed available from Apress Media.
Twitter: http://twitter.com/bobwardms.</description>
      <twitter>bobwardms</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/bobsql</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bobwardms</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54470</importID>
      <name>Michael Minichino</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Minichino is a pre-sales SA supporting the TOLA region of the US for Kaminario. Michael has worked in Information Technology for over 23 years in both leadership and individual contributor roles. Prior to Kaminario he worked for Oracle in a pre-sales role in the Engineered Systems group serving as a database and storage specialist. He has also worked for the Oracle Platinum Partner Actifio as a database and DevOps pre-sales consultant.  Prior to Oracle and Actifio he worked for HP as a pre-sales Enterprise Architect.  However he has spent most of his career as a technology consumer in IT manager and director roles with both small and large organizations.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-minichino-6a71301</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>50317</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50317</id>
          <name>Ryan Casey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>110</name>
      </location>
      <title>Create a Data Loading Strategy</title>
      <description>Loading large amounts of data into SQL Server can be challenging. Many factors may challenge your goal for tuned performance. To make the decision making process more difficult, many of the choices listed below have both Pros and Cons to their implementation. For this reason, bulk loading large amounts of data requires a strategy.

Create a strategy to optimize your massive data loading processes.
•	High Performance Data Loading
•	Minimal Logging and Bulk Loading
•	Indexing Considerations
•	Delayed Durability
•	Eager Write

This session uses a Virtual Sandbox to demonstrate “real” data loads using these techniques listed above. We will look at the T-SQL used in these data loads. We will briefly discuss how the different settings and configurations effect the data loads. Power Point slides and sample SQL will be provided.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50316</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50316</id>
          <name>Silvia Doomra</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>111</name>
      </location>
      <title>Seamlessly Scaling Azure SQL DB with Elastic Database Tools</title>
      <description>Elastic Database Tools for Azure SQL DB offers a set of features that make it easier to build and manage a scaled-out data tier for cloud applications. With elastic database tools, applications can easily access data spanning multiple DBs, coordinate management tasks and manage how data is distributed among them. As part of the session, we explore workloads that are a natural fit for Azure SQL DB's elastic database tools. Patterns discussed in depth include multi-tenant applications created by cloud ISVs and SaaS vendors, and applications relying on temporal data distribution. The session will illustrate how easy it is now to build, scale and manage cloud applications in SQL DB when using elastic tools capabilities such as the elastic database client library for .NET.  </description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50424</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50424</id>
          <name>Mindy Curnutt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>109</name>
      </location>
      <title>Imposter Syndrome: Are You Faking It  Will they Find Out?</title>
      <description>Have you ever thought to yourself  “All these people think I’m smarter than I really am" or "I really don’t know what I’m doing, they're going to figure out I'm a fraud!”  If yes, then you suffer from the Impostor Syndrome. And despite all the accomplishments, awards and accolades, you still doubt yourself. It’s rampant in the modern day tech workplace, and the fear will make you shrink back from opportunities. You dismiss praise. You overcompensate by working harder, being charming and demanding perfection from yourself. What would happen if you were released from this bondage, and kicked your impostor to the curb? In this session, learn 3 powerful techniques that can help to improve your confidence and silent that annoying voice in your head!</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50396</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50396</id>
          <name>Mike Byrd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>105</name>
      </location>
      <title>Indexes: Everything You Wanted to Know -- Help or Hinder</title>
      <description>Indexes can be a boon or decrement for query performance. This presentation will present what they are (in layman’s terms) and how they may affect query performance – both from a read (SELECT) viewpoint as well as a data modification aspect (INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE).  This session will concentrate with a deep dive into clustered indexes and nonclustered indexes, their syntax and utilization, and their effect on performance in transaction and data warehouse databases.  Covering nonclustered indexes will also be examined in detail and the scenarios they should be applied.  There will be many query demos illustrating index utilization using statistics and query plans.  Attendee should have some TSQL and Management Studio experience.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50636</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50636</id>
          <name>Jamey Johnston</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>106</name>
      </location>
      <title>Code Like a Pirate ... Intro to R and Data Science Tools in MS</title>
      <description>R is the most popular statistics language used today. It is one of the most useful tools in the data scientist's tool belt. It is also integrated into the MS stack in tools like Azure ML, SQL Server and Power BI and can be used to take your data analytics to the next level.  
  
Come to this session to get an introduction to the R language including: 

  - Installing and Configuring R and RStudio 
  - RStudio Overview and Debugging
  - How to Access and Manipulate Data 
  - Install and Manage Packages 
  - Create and Use Variables 
  - Control Flows 
  - Functions 
  - Basic Graphing and Statistical Analysis 

We will finish with a brief introductions of how R integrates in Azure ML, Power BI and SQL Server 2016 using real demos.  
  
The focus of the session will be primarily on the introduction to the R language and getting attendees comfortable with using R to start the journey into Data Science! </description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50319</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50319</id>
          <name>Stacy Gray</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>106</name>
      </location>
      <title>Troubleshooting SQL Server Performance</title>
      <description>Microsoft SQL Support Engineers troubleshoot performance issues all day, every day.  They use a set of tools that not only gather all the data necessary to troubleshoot any performance issue, but the tools also analyze the data and generate visually attractive reports. These tools have been available to the public for free for years.  This presentation explains the tools, how to run them and how to interpret the results, including how to determine disk latency root cause, top reasons for high cpu, and what to do when you have excessive waits.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50428</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50428</id>
          <name>Kris Hokanson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>105</name>
      </location>
      <title>Random Acts of Senseless Databasing</title>
      <description>After years of snake oil salesmen and good-meaning but part-time developers, Acme Oil  Gas company’s databases have become something Rube Goldberg would be proud of and they've hired you to sort everything out. What are some of the things you can expect to find and how can you fix them? From spaghetti code that references views inside of views nested in other views, to overly indexed tables that generate 10x the disk IO and contention they should, we’ll talk about database development, administration, and plenty of things in between.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50310</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50310</id>
          <name>Anthony van Gemert</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>105</name>
      </location>
      <title>MICROSOFT: SQL Server 2016 Stretch Database </title>
      <description>Your SAN consumption is increasing faster than your budget, you have tables so big that you dread re-indexing, or your end-users demand their cold or archived data always be online. There’s a solution that lets you take advantage of the Cloud, on your terms, all without impacting your existing end-user applications or queries. 
 
Come and meet some of the SQL Server Stretch database product team, and find out how you can move your data securely and transparently, free up disc space and reduce your SAN consumption, while retaining full control from the on-premises SQL Server. You’ll reduce maintenance operations time and resources, plus lower overall cost. Learn how SQL Stretch database will simplify your journey to the Cloud!</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50334</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50334</id>
          <name>Stan Geiger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>110</name>
      </location>
      <title>Polybase and Time Travel (Temporal Tables)</title>
      <description>"With the release of SQL Server 2016, Microsoft has included two features that could fundamentally change the way we look at Data Warehousing.  The addition of Polybase for connecting to external data sources such as Hadoop and Azure Blob for native TSQL queries extends the reach of the DW.   The Temporal Table feature creates all kinds of possibilities for implementing Type 1 and 2 dimensions as well as time based reporting and logical data recovery.  In this session we will take an in depth lock at the features and scenarios for use.   We will also look at some actual demos of the technologies so you can get a feel for the technologies in action."</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50755</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50755</id>
          <name>David Klee</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>100</name>
      </location>
      <title>Objective SQL Server Performance</title>
      <description>“It’s slow! FIX IT!” is not a fun way to walk into the office on a Monday morning. However, putting objective metrics to the subjectivity of ‘slow’ is as much a science as it is art. Performance engineering takes effort well before an issue arises. Collecting the right metrics, trending and comparing against an established baseline, and identifying bottlenecks are all part of the performance process. This interactive session will help the DBA fine-tune their performance tuning approach so that the foundation for long-term proactive performance review is in place. The DBA can then shift the job responsibilities from a reactive response to a more predictive and proactive role.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52987</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52987</id>
          <name>Konstantin Melamud</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>111</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing your data warehouse for OLAP Processing</title>
      <description>Analysis Services have become a major part of upper management daily decision making activities.  However, with our DW sizes reaching multiple terabytes minimizing time required to process our data has become our top priority. In this session, we will cover the options we have as DBA’s to improve the performance of our DW processing time. We will look at features and general best practices available to us within SSAS and the database engine to ensure optimal performance, as well as enterprise level features within the database engine and SSAS available to us and how aligning those to work side by side would yield us significant improvement in our processing time. </description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53018</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53018</id>
          <name>Jared Nielsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>108</name>
      </location>
      <title>RESTful JSON API Microservices and SQL Server</title>
      <description>Transforming your enterprise or startup using micro services that rely on SQL Server data can be a challenge.  There are so many options out there.  I will introduce how you can jump into API driven develop with lightning fast frameworks that make your job easy and simple.  Explore how we leverage Entity Framework to quick start your data models with code-first prototyping.  Then we will explore how to transition back when you're ready for deployment.  SQL Server offers native tools for JSON support in the newest 2016 release but if you don't have that luxury we'll explore legacy versions as well.  API driven development can transform your software development lifecycle so join me as we get you going in the right direction with the latest frameworks and tools.  Source code will be provided of a standard API framework with a real data model to accompany your efforts.  We will also touch on OAuth 2.0, Unit Testing, and Continuous Integration (CI) for truly streamlined SQL powered apps.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52972</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52972</id>
          <name>Louis Mangiacapra</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>111</name>
      </location>
      <title>IoT – Particle Photon to Azure and PowerBI integration</title>
      <description>This session is an introduction into integrating the Particle Photon Wi-Fi development kit and Microsoft Azure to analyze, collect, and provide PowerBI reports on IoT data. 

Azure Event Hubs is a highly scalable publish-subscribe event ingestor that can intake millions of events per second to process and analyze massive amounts of data. Once collected into Event Hubs the data can be transformed and stored using any real-time analytics provider or a batching/storage adapters.

The Particle Photon has a simple but very robust development environment. When combined with Microsoft Azure using webhooks it is capable of ingesting millions of events per second using a remotely programmable Particle Photon. 

For this training we will specifically look at publishing data from a Particle Photon (equipped with a Photon Weather Shield) to an Azure Event Hub. Next we will store the data using blog storage, SQL database, and data lake storage to then graphically represent the IoT data in PowerBI. </description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52935</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52935</id>
          <name>Ryan Adams</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>111</name>
      </location>
      <title>Managing MSDB</title>
      <description>You put a lot of time into managing your databases, but MSDB often flies under the radar or only gets backed up. There are a ton of things that get stored in MSDB, so how are you supposed to know what all those items are? More importantly, how do you manage the data that is getting stored in there and keep it from growing out of control? We will take an in-depth look at all the SQL features that put data in MSDB and the best approach to managing that data.  You will walk away with scripts you can use to automate the grooming of MSDB.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53057</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53057</id>
          <name>Chris Shaw</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>111</name>
      </location>
      <title>Standardize Your Baseline</title>
      <description>The concept of baselines have been around for many years, yet all too often they are not executed on a regular basis and don't contain enough information, I believe this is because most DBA's don't have a standard baseline to execute. Baselines can tell you how the server should be performing under normal workloads with the configuration that is currently in place.  

During this session we will look at the kinds of data that you should be collecting while spending the majority of our time reviewing the methods on how this data can be collected, stored, automated and reported on.

These standardized baselines will give you a head start the next time you are looking to upgrade your server to new hardware, recover a server and performance troubleshooting.
</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52418</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52418</id>
          <name>Ginger Grant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>109</name>
      </location>
      <title>Developing R and SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>If you have heard about R and want to learn how to write it yourself and run it within SQL Server 2016 you will want to come to this session.  As Microsoft is now incorporating the R language into SQL Server 2016, the language is going to be a required skill for all data professionals in the near future.  SQL Server 2016 uses a non-open source version of R, and the benefits of using that version will be reviewed too.

Using SQL Server 2016, attendees will learn how to incorporate R in SQL Server as well write R code in Visual Studio which gets data from and runs on SQL Server.  The version of R which ships with SQL Server incorporates the ability to run with more data than can be loaded into memory, and attendees will learn the best use cases for it.   

Attendees will learn the setup requirements for running R from within SQL Server 2016, and learn how to run R code from within Server Management Studio. </description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52933</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52933</id>
          <name>William Wolf</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>100</name>
      </location>
      <title>Stop Doing That! 5 Common T-SQL Anti-Patterns</title>
      <description>There are several programming design patterns that work great in object oriented code but do not scale  inside SQL Server. Things like Scalar-Value functions, Unions, CTEs, and row by row processing can make for more work then you would expect.

In this session, we will focus on several anti-patterns like these and show how to rework them to improve scale in the database engine.   

By the end of the session, you will be able to quickly identify these common anti-patterns and analyze their sometimes unclear cost to the engine. Heading back to the office, you’ll be able to identify pain points in your longest running queries from a T-SQL perspective and become a code tuning rockstar!</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53036</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53036</id>
          <name>Chris Shaw</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>109</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tips for SQL Server Performance and Resiliency</title>
      <description>After working 20 years in the industry on hundreds of SQL Servers clear patterns emerge. These observations of patterns and best practices directly relate to the health of the server.#160; During this session we will review the patterns of healthy SQL Servers and identify unhealthy behavior that clearly shows servers that are at risk.#160;
We will review shared patterns, configuration and practices.#160;#160; Which of these repeating patterns represent healthy Servers and which of these patterns are#160; shared with servers that are having issues daily.#160;
These patterns are so clear in fact that I many SQL Servers will benefit from the application of at least one if not more of the tips we will cover.#160; At the end of this session attendees will have the tools to identify and correct common issues that impact SQL Servers Performance and Resiliency.
</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54431</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54431</id>
          <name>David Stein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>105</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dell EMC - Maximizing Microsoft SQL Server Storage Investments</title>
      <description>2016 is the year of All-Flash for primary storage and DELL EMC’s industry leading portfolio of All-Flash arrays unlock the speed, efficiency, and agility that your business stakeholders have been demanding. Whether supporting 1,000 or 10,000,000 IOPS, DELL EMC has a broad portfolio to ensure consistent sub-millisecond response time regardless of workload type.
 
Beyond just production database performance, DELL EMC provides robust database repurposing via our iCDM or Integrated Copy Data Management capabilities. Creating and maintaining test/dev, near real-time analytic, or sandbox environments has never been simpler. Join us and hear how we can address the needs of all of your Microsoft SQL Server instances.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 12:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54412</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54412</id>
          <name>George Govantes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>106</name>
      </location>
      <title>Agile Leadership Skills and Building High Performing Teams</title>
      <description>How do you build an environment that inspires innovation and individual ownership to deliver  operational excellence? How to move away from the Command and Control leadership style that is so pervasive within the IT culture? How do you move from Manager to Leader?  In today’s modern Enterprise, attracting and keeping talented employees is a challenge.  We’ll cover the importance of: Spirit of Service, Project Vision, Allowing Team Input, and Trust in Team Members, and the impact these areas make on both Individual and Team performance.  Thus altering how the organization is Managed/Lead from:  “How do I accomplish corporate goals?” to the more empowering:  “How do WE accomplish our corporate goals?”.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54455</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54455</id>
          <name>Craig Allen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>105</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dell EMC - Maximizing Microsoft SQL Server Storage Investments</title>
      <description>2016 is the year of All-Flash for primary storage and DELL EMC’s industry leading portfolio of All-Flash arrays unlock the speed, efficiency, and agility that your business stakeholders have been demanding. Whether supporting 1,000 or 10,000,000 IOPS, DELL EMC has a broad portfolio to ensure consistent sub-millisecond response time regardless of workload type.
 
Beyond just production database performance, DELL EMC provides robust database repurposing via our iCDM or Integrated Copy Data Management capabilities. Creating and maintaining test/dev, near real-time analytic, or sandbox environments has never been simpler. Join us and hear how we can address the needs of all of your Microsoft SQL Server instances.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 12:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50627</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50627</id>
          <name>Steven Ormrod</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>105</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Window Functions</title>
      <description>Window functions are a great TSQL tool that will allow you to write simpler, more elegant code. They were first introduced in SQL 2005, and then expanded in SQL 2012. By using TSQL Window functions you can simply your code and make it easier to understand. They allow you to see both aggregations and details all at the same time. In this demo-centric session we will begin with the basics introduced in SQL 2005, then move on to examine the new functions that were added with SQL 2012.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54349</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54349</id>
          <name>Russel Loski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>110</name>
      </location>
      <title>JSON in SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>There have been many data lingua franca over the years (EDI, CSV, XML).  Let's meet a new comer JSON (aka Jason).  JSON is the web developers new best friend, providing a schema free way to transmit and persist data.  SQL Server 2016 has provided new functionality to work with JSON.  In this session we will look at how to read a JSON document using the OPENJSON function.  We will also look at other methods for extracting information from JSON.  Finally, we will look at how to generate JSON documents from TSQL queries.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54263</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54263</id>
          <name>Amy Herold</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>110</name>
      </location>
      <title>WIT: Start 'em Young - Growing Women in IT</title>
      <description>Do an internet search on "Women in Technology" and you'll find lots of articles with surveys, graphs and percentages telling you that there are not enough women in technology related fields.  They'll give you just as many reasons why girls don't start in IT or women don't stay in IT.  Is this true? As women in technology, are we wired differently? Was there some lightbulb moment that to put us on the path to innovate with code? Why are you in technology in the first place? From Grace Hopper to that 6th grade girl gaming with people around the globe - while technology has changed and is more accessible, what makes women pursue IT careers hasn't. With opportunities now spanning a wide array of fields and technologies, what does it take to inspire the young girls of today? In this session we will try to cut through a lot of the noise and get down to what drives young girls who grow to be women in technology, how we can encourage them, and not get in their way.

Guest Speakers : Abha Jos</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52999</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52999</id>
          <name>Daniel Janik</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>100</name>
      </location>
      <title>A DBA's guide to whole stack performance troubleshooting</title>
      <description>Performance troubleshooting is a required skill for every DBA. Knowing the deep internals of how a query functions and why SQL Server chose to run it in a certain way is important. Knowing how to design a table or configure a database to squeeze every ounce of performance is our lifeblood. 

What if I told you that you may be doing this all wrong? What if all the work and laborious effort put into design or configuration don't improve the situation because the issue was never in SQL to begin with? Truth be told, the biggest differentiator between a good DBA and a great DBA is knowing the hardware and O/S; not just SQL.

Join me as I guide you through troubleshooting SQL Server performance from tip to toe to demonstrate the common performance problems you never knew you had.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>51047</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>51047</id>
          <name>Matthew Brimer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>110</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting Started With Your First SQL Server AWS RDS Migration</title>
      <description>Cloud Computing is all the rage but how do you get data from your on-premise SQL Server to your shiny new Amazon RDS instance? We'll go over the various iterations and offerings of AWS, proper sizing, cost, etc. and then we'll dive into the nitty gritty on how to migrate your data either in one shot or continuously over time.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54471</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54471</id>
          <name>Mark Wheeler</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>100</name>
      </location>
      <title>IA-Database Development using SQL Server Data Tools projects</title>
      <description>In this session we will use SSDT to create and deploy a database project that includes unit tests to validate the stored procedures and post deployment scripts to insert data. We will also look at the other capabilities of SSDT like being able to refactor columns and do a schema compare.
 
By the end of the session, you will have the working knowledge on how to use database projects to simplify your next development project. We will also look at the different methods for deploying your changes and why one may be better than the other.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 12:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>51079</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>51079</id>
          <name>Rowdy Vinson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>109</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Failover Clusters for High Availability</title>
      <description>As DBAs, we know that AlwaysOn AGs and Failover Cluster Instances are built on the foundation of Windows Server Failover Clustering and that HA is their goal, but have you ever seen it work? Are they a good solution for your org? Do you know if your SysAdmins can do their part? We’ll discuss these points and more, diving in under the hood of WSFC in demos and showing a few scripts to make support and troubleshooting a little easier. </description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54513</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54513</id>
          <name>Sri Sridharan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>110</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power Networking for Data Professionals</title>
      <description>In this session we will discuss  industry trends, career trends and just have a open dialogue with other Data Professionals, understand their wins, challenges and share ideas on how to navigate through them.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50540</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50540</id>
          <name>John Sterrett</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>108</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why Did My Execution Plan Change? Introduction to Query Store</title>
      <description>Join John Sterrett, Principal Consultant at Procure SQL LLC to learn how execution plans get invalidated and why data skew could be the root cause to seeing different execution plans for the same query. We will look at the options for forcing a query to use a particular execution plan. Finally, you will learn how this complex problem can be identified and resolved simply using a new feature in SQL Server 2016 called Query Store.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54343</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54343</id>
          <name>Ryan Adams</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>100</name>
      </location>
      <title>Detecting and Preparing for Corruption</title>
      <description>Corruption is a scary thing, so if it happens tomorrow are you prepared for it?  In this introduction we'll look at what causes corruption and the things you can do now to be able to detect it when it happens.  We'll even see how you can implement a self healing configuration.  You will also learn the different techniques for recovering from corruption.  Preparation is key and you'll be prepared to handle the situation without panic.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52795</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52795</id>
          <name>Rachael Martino</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>108</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Performance Tips</title>
      <description>It is quick and easy to build large, complex data models in Power BI (based on Power Pivot). However, building a model that performs well might seem hit or miss unless you are aware of how Power BI manages your data.  This session provides design techniques and tips that will have you building your own models to deliver solutions without those nasty performance surprises!
</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52984</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52984</id>
          <name>Lori Edwards</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>110</name>
      </location>
      <title>How To Plan Meetings That Work</title>
      <description>Too often we find ourselves in meetings that seem to have no purpose, that run long and we walk out with little more information than we started with.  In this session, you’ll learn how to organize meetings that are both efficient and effective from the start.  We’ll provide tips to help with participation, keeping the meeting rolling and even ending on time.   Be the person whose meetings people actually look forward to.  Both Lori and Allen have years of experience participating in and planning meetings both for work and volunteer settings including the PASS Board of Director, Election Review Committee and the Nominations Committee meetings.

</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52544</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52544</id>
          <name>Andy Tabisz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>111</name>
      </location>
      <title>Creating Access Web Apps with Power BI Integration</title>
      <description>In this session, you'll learn how to quickly build an Access Web App within SharePoint, tour the online development environment and see a real, live working app in action.   We'll discuss sharing the app and Power BI integration.  And lastly, you'll learn the pros/cons of Access Web Apps and hybrid solutions in a corporate environment as well as how to extend the data to iPhone and Android phones.  Presented by Andy Tabisz, Microsoft MVP, WorkSmart Database Masters (Michigan).
</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50325</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50325</id>
          <name>Sean Werick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>106</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016: Data Masking and Encryption</title>
      <description>Learn about data masking and encryption, the pros and cons of each, as well as when to use which.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52777</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52777</id>
          <name>David Stein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>109</name>
      </location>
      <title>Agile Data Warehouse and ETL Design with Biml</title>
      <description>Business Intelligence Markup Language is literally changing the way we think about Data Warehouse design and ETL. In this interactive presentation you'll see how you can rapidly iterate through the Data Warehouse Development Cycle and provide ROI almost immediately.  Learn how you can use BimlScript to automatically create staging tables, SSIS Packages, and other necessary objects during the modeling process. 
</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54262</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54262</id>
          <name>Rick Lowe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>108</name>
      </location>
      <title>Weird stuff I saw ... while supporting a Java team</title>
      <description>After spending more than a decade completely devoted to the Microsoft stack, over the last few years I've been getting pulled into work supporting Java teams. Yes, sure, Java is just another language so there aren't really and issues that are absolutely unique to the Java world. But it is a different stack, different culture, and different group of folks giving bad advice to developers ... just enough different to keep life interesting. Come hear about my misadventures with server side cursors, output parameters, integrated authentication, and NOCOUNT settings.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52734</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52734</id>
          <name>Trayce Jordan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>105</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to SQL Server 2016 - Always Encrypted, Masking  Row level security</title>
      <description>In this session we will go into depth of several new security features in SQL Server 2016:  Always Encrypted, Data Masking and Row Level Security just to name a few.   We will discuss how the features work and demonstrate how to implement.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50639</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50639</id>
          <name>Lance Tidwell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>106</name>
      </location>
      <title>Ways SQL Server Lies and the Performance Tuning Headaches It Can Cause.</title>
      <description>Have you ever tried to tune a query  or searched for a  performance bottleneck just to have SQL Server lead you down a rabbit hole?   In this session we will look at some common performance issues that can occur that might be masked or hidden by misleading information  you get from SQL Server.    We will also talk about why SQL Server gives you the information it does,  and how to see past this information and find the real issues causing your performance problems.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53005</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53005</id>
          <name>Amy Herold</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>108</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hi, my name is Powershell, let's be friends! An Intro to PoSH</title>
      <description>Powershell wants to be your friend - your very powerful friend. In this session we will go over some Powershell basics that will help get you started as well as some known "gotchas" when working in Powershell. This is a beginner session - no Powershell experience necessary. WARNING: You may get warm-fuzzies about Powershell by attending this session.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50324</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50324</id>
          <name>Steve Allison</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>108</name>
      </location>
      <title>Cursors temp tables and pivots oh boy</title>
      <description>Will do an overview of the PIVOT and UNPIVOT functions and how to manipulate your data in really cool ways.  Then we will move on to how to deal with Cursor functions and looping through data, then the joys of #tables vs @tables for your temporary table issues.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50327</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50327</id>
          <name>Bryan Smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>111</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Journey from Data to Insight</title>
      <description>Regardless of the tools and techniques we might employ, the fundamental task of the analyst is to turn data into business-relevant insight. This is not a simple task and not one that is fully under our conscious control.
In this session, we will discuss the our current understanding of how this process works and practices analysts can employ to improve the quantity and quality of insights they produce.  </description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52755</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52755</id>
          <name>Michael Bourgon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>106</name>
      </location>
      <title>Know what your machines are doing besides SQL Server! WMI,WQL,CIM and PoSH</title>
      <description>There's far more happening on your Windows servers than just SQL Server, and looking at ERRORLOG won't show you the whole story: other applications stealing your memory, OS issues, hardware errors, and more.  We'll start by looking at several different ways to collect Event Logs automatically.  From there we'll delve into WMI and WQL, which allow us to query servers (remotely or locally) to get information such as performance statistics, System and Event Logs, and even changes within SQL Server.

We'll finish it off with two immediately-usable implementations you can set up on Monday.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50322</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50322</id>
          <name>Simon Cho</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>110</name>
      </location>
      <title>Build ETL efficiently (10x) with Minimal Logging</title>
      <description>This session is designed to teach DBAs and developers the best strategy to transfer large data. 

We will first analyze how data gets accessed from the source and how data gets updated or inserted to the target server: index access patterns in read operation and minimal logging in wring operation. I will introduce TF610 and cover its benefit for minimal logging even in full recovery mode. </description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50458</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50458</id>
          <name>Naomi Williams</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>109</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Internals</title>
      <description>How does SQL do what it does? Take a look under the hood at how the SQL database engine works with the storage engine. What causes those waits and where do we look to resolve them!</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53580</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53580</id>
          <name>Latish Sehgal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>105</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSMS Tips and Tricks</title>
      <description>In this talk, we’ll go through tips and tricks to make you much more productive and efficient with SQL Server Management Studio, so that IDE does not get in your way and lets you focus on writing SQL.
</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>51147</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>51147</id>
          <name>Bala Shankar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>109</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deploy SQL Server with Microsoft Azure Virtual Machine</title>
      <description>Microsoft Azure  provides multiple options to migrate SQL  Server to the Cloud.  But migrating SQL Server requires good understanding of the different options and the constraints.  This session focuses on Microsoft Cloud option for SQL Server, how to deploy SQL Server on Azure Virtual Machine,  how  SQL Licensing works on Azure Virtual Machine, deploying Alwayson AG and Hybrid Cloud Scenarios.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52410</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52410</id>
          <name>John Harp</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>108</name>
      </location>
      <title>The AG-ony of Defeat: Let's Break Some SQL Server Availability Groups!</title>
      <description>Some database administrators create availability groups. Some database administrators have availability groups thrust upon them. Whether you're just starting to investigate SQL Server's own high availability solution, or if you've become responsible for an Always On Availability Group that's already been built, come get a glimpse of what can/will go wrong in an Availability Group implementation, from the commonplace to the spectacular. </description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54265</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54265</id>
          <name>Roberto Cavalcanti</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>111</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Database v12 - Lessons learned from the trenches</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn the best practices, tips and tricks on how to successfully use Azure SQL Database on production environments. You will learn how to monitor and improve Azure SQL Database query performance. I will cover how Microsoft CSS has been using Query Store, Extended Events, Azure SQL Database Advisor and PerfStat Scripts with SQL Nexus to help customers monitor and improve query response times when running their databases in the Microsoft Azure cloud. These learnings are all fruit of CSS support cases, and customer field engagements. This session includes several demos.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52385</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52385</id>
          <name>Bob Ward</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>100</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding SQL Server R Services</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 introduces a new platform for building intelligent, advanced analytic applications called SQL Server R Services. This session is for the SQL Server Database professional to learn more about this technology and its impact on developing and managing a SQL Server environment. We will cover the basics of this technology but also look at how it works, troubleshooting topics, and even usage case scenarios. You don't have to be a data scientist to understand SQL Server R Services  so come upgrade you career by learning more about SQL Server and advanced analytics</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>51040</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>51040</id>
          <name>Bob Ward</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>100</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016: It Just Runs Faster</title>
      <description>Join me in taking a deep dive and a behind the scenes look at how SQL Server 2016 ‘It Just Runs Faster’, focused on scalability and performance enhancements. This talk will discuss the improvements, not only for awareness, but expose design and internal change details. The beauty behind ‘It Just Runs Faster’ is your ability to just upgrade, in place, and take advantage without lengthy and costly application or infrastructure changes. If you are looking at why SQL Server 2016 makes sense for your business, you won't want to miss this session.</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54470</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54470</id>
          <name>Michael Minichino</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>106</name>
      </location>
      <title>Kaminario - Pushing the SQL Turbo Button with All Flash Storage</title>
      <description>TBD</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 12:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54411</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54411</id>
          <name>Mike Burek</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>105</name>
      </location>
      <title>Step by Step SSIS Import Package Creation</title>
      <description>Go step by step to create an SSIS package to import files. This will use SSIS variables, loops, expressions, and passing variables to SQL Server. The 6 objectives covered are:
1 - Read multiple files from a folder with changing file names
2 - Import to a Raw table
3 - Include a step to clean data into a Staging table
4 - Log the file name and the number of rows imported
5 - Move the imported file to a Done folder
6 - Send an email report for each file imported</description>
      <startTime>9/24/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/24/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>