<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #822 - Spokane 2019</name>
    <startDate>3/23/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>100</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-08:00) Pacific Time (US and Canada); Tijuana</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatSpokane</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>EWU Computer Science and Engineering Building</name>
      <street>837-979 Washington St.</street>
      <city>Cheney</city>
      <state>Washington</state>
      <zipcode>99004</zipcode>
      <longitude>-117.5757622</longitude>
      <latitude>47.4873895</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/972/EventSponsor_14605.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2376</importID>
      <name>IntelliTect</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.intellitect.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://intellitect.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IntelliTect_BlueBlack.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2043</importID>
      <name>Eastern Washington University Computer Science Department</name>
      <label>Venue Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.ewu.edu/cstem/departments/computer-science</url>
      <imageURL>https://web.ewu.edu/groups/urmgr/images/EWU_Logo_240x76.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2274</importID>
      <name>Red Gate Software</name>
      <label>Raffle Item</label>
      <url>http://www.red-gate.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1020/EventSponsor_14938.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2325</importID>
      <name>RevDeBug</name>
      <label>Raffle Item</label>
      <url>https://revdebug.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/952/EventSponsor_14374.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86889</importID>
      <name>Joseph Yeates</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joseph is a data enthusiast and blogs about all things Power BI on Feathers Analytics. He has a passion for crafting compelling data narratives and making insights accessible to a wider range of users through visualization. He holds the Certified Analytics Professional designation as well as a DBA certification with a focus on SQL Server Analysis  Reporting Services. He uses R Studio, Power Query and Power BI to model, manipulate, analyze, and visualize data. He integrates R into Power BI to bring the power of predictive analytics into reports and dashboards. He is a member of the Vancouver Power BI User Group and has presented on Power BI Tips  Tricks and Predictive Analytics with R in Power BI.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/FthrsAnalytics</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-yeates-bba5663a/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.feathersanalytics.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/FthrsAnalytics</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87110</importID>
      <name>Steve Stedman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Stedman is the Leader of a PASS Local Group in Bellingham WA USA. Steve runs his own SQL consulting firm Stedman Solutions, LLC. He has 29 years of programming and SQL experience.  He has written the book on SQL Common Table Expressions.  He teaches, speaks at conferences, writes, and has taught SQL server classes at Western Washington University.  Steve has previously spoken at PASS Summit, TechEd, DevTeach Vancouver, many SQL Saturdays, and more.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlemt</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stevestedman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SteveStedman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlemt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86740</importID>
      <name>Hamish Watson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hamish Watson is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware Expert with a passion for efficient database and application deployment using DevOps methodologies. 

He has 20+ years of IT experience in managing and deploying large scale databases on SQL Server technologies. 

He has been managing SQL Server since SQL Server 2000, and pragmatic approaches to delivering business value to clients is his career passion.

Educating and helping others learn is a driver for Hamish. He is a Director-At-Large on the PASS Board, international speaker, and a repeat guest lecturer at a local university.</description>
      <twitter>theHybridDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/in/hamishwatson8</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/the-hybrid-dbas-blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=theHybridDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87093</importID>
      <name>Alex Yates</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alex Yates has been helping organisations to apply DevOps principles to relational database development and deployment since 2010. He’s most proud of helping Skyscanner develop the ability to deploy 95 times a day. Originally for Redgate, later for DLM Consultants, Alex has worked with clients on every continent except Antarctica – so he’s keen to meet anyone who researches penguins. 

A keen community member, he co-organises SQL Relay, is the founder of www.SpeakingMentors.com and has been recognised as a Microsoft Data Platform MVP since 2017.</description>
      <twitter>@_alexyates_</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/alexanderyates</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.workingwithdevs.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_alexyates_</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88476</importID>
      <name>Ben Miller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben has been a member of the SQL Server Community since 2000. He loves a challenge and has fixed many SQL Servers and helped hundreds of people get more out of their DBA jobs.  He is a Data Platform MVP a SQL Server Certified Master (MCM). He has worked at various companies throughout the USA, as well as at Microsoft for 7 years. He is passionate about SQL Server Infrastructure, High Availability, Automation and Integration using SMO and PowerShell. He teaches DBAs how to use PowerShell to do their job and teaches SQL Server Internals. He is @DBAduck all around the web (Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, Blog) so let's catch up.</description>
      <twitter>DBAduck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dbaduck/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbaduck.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAduck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89701</importID>
      <name>Konstantin Kosinsky</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Konstantin is an industry expert who loves optimizing the performance at least in 10x. More data - more fun. 
 
Konstantin is a Principal Software Engineer at Azure DevOps Services, where he works on moving the Analytics for software engineering to a completely new level.

Konstantin was born and had been working in Ukraine for a long time, passionately sharing his knowledge with Ukrainian and other European data communities. Before joining Microsoft in 2012, he was a Data Platform MVP for many years.</description>
      <twitter>kkosinsky</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kosinsky/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kkosinsky</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86688</importID>
      <name>Reid Havens</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reid Havens is the founder of Havens Consulting Inc. He has a formal background in technology and organizational management, having obtained separate Master's Degrees in Organizational Development and Business Analytics. Reid has experience working with many of the Fortune 50, 100, and 500 companies. Reid is also an avid content developer, having authored numerous articles and videos on various blog sites and video platforms. He's also written multiple training curriculums, online video courses, and college level classes. Additionally, he guest lectures at the University of Washington and other universities, teaching Business Intelligence, Reporting, and Data Visualization.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/HavensBI</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/reidhavens/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.havensconsulting.net/blog-and-media/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/HavensBI</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89331</importID>
      <name>Michael Wall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Wall has been an IT professional going back to when he had his own software store and worked with his customers with their “dose” problems.  Originally hired by a small consulting firm to write web pages, he was thrust into the SysAdmin world when their lead consultant changed the passwords of all of the servers at a major pulp and paper company’s systems to 100%s$%t and walked out the door.  He was sent down with a copy of UNIX for Dummies and 50 cents for the bus ride back.  Fast forward a few years, he was asked if he wanted to be a DBA after successfully managing a fifty server Y2K upgrade.  Since then, he’s never looked back and has survived a number of data and system challenges.
When not wrangling cats at home, he currently</description>
      <twitter>michaelDwall1</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-wall/b/110/9a</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.becomingamaster.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=michaelDwall1</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86535</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88750</importID>
      <name>Gail Shaw</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gail Shaw is a Database Specialist focusing on database performance tuning and database recovery, with a particular interest in topics such as indexing strategies, execution plans, and writing T-SQL code that performs well and scales gracefully. Gail holds a Microsoft Certified Master certification for SQL Server 2008 and is a Data Platform MVP. She's a frequent poster on the SQLServerCentral forums, a Pluralsight author, writes articles for both SQLServerCentral.com and Simple-Talk.com, and has spoken at SQLSaturdays, SQL Bits and at the PASS Community Summit. Gail has been responsible for extending the lifespan of many an application, by performance-tuning their databases and providing technical guidance on all things SQL Server related.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLInTheWild</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlinthewild.co.za</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLInTheWild</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90611</importID>
      <name>Philip Spokas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vice President of Professional Services for IntelliTect with extensive executive management and leadership experience.  Accomplishments include strategy, architecture and design of several innovative data driven Software as a Service solutions, development of agile management practices, enterprise data architecture solutions, and the original design, architecture and development of the OnTrack Manufacturing Execution System. Holds Scrum, DevOps and Cloud Services industry certifications.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/philspokas</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/philspokas</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://intellitect.com/phil</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/philspokas</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88061</importID>
      <name>Rob Sewell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob was once a production SQL Server DBA, but is now generally found automating the Data Platform and providing training for clients. He has a passion for PowerShell, Data, and DevOps. He is an MVP, an officer for the DevOps PowerShell VG, and has spoken and volunteered at many PowerShell and Data events. He is a member of the committee that organises Data In Devon and the European PowerShell Conference. He is a proud supporter of the Data and PowerShell communities. 
 
He relishes sharing and learning and can be found doing both via Twitter @sqldbawithbeard and his blog sqldbawithabeard.com. He spends most of his time looking at a screen and loves to solve problems.</description>
      <twitter>sqldbawithbeard</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/robsewellsqldba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldbawithabeard.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqldbawithbeard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87795</importID>
      <name>josh smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Josh Smith is the senior-most DBA at a mid-sized credit union and leader of the Spokane Area SQL Server Users Group. He is not the most fond of writing about himself in the third person but attempts to be good natured about it. He believes strongly in participating in and contributing to the SQL Server community as much as possible.</description>
      <twitter>sqldeployhelmet</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/toosuto/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://accitentionaldba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqldeployhelmet</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89692</importID>
      <name>Rebecca Long</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rebecca Long is a software engineer with 15 years experience focusing on quality assurance and DevOps at a cyber-risk assessment company in Spokane, Washington. She holds undergraduate and master’s degrees in computer science with her thesis on social engineering and phishing within a financial institution.

While having been a leader in the Spokane tech community for most of the last decade, in 2018 she finally launched her dream of a non-profit called Future Ada which supports and advocates for women and non-binaries in STEAM (science, technology, engineering, art, and mathematics).

She lives with two cats, who are the true masters of the household.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/amaya30</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/amaya30/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://medium.com/@amaya30</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/amaya30</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88514</importID>
      <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server DBA with over 10 year's experience. Originally from Wales but now living in Ireland</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewpruski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbafromthecold.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86396</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87918</importID>
      <name>Melody Zacharias</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Melody is the Sr. Microsoft Solutions Manager at Pure and has been in love with data since 1991. She has been sharing her passion with the community in technical sessions and blogs since 2014. She has been a Microsoft MVP since 2016, including winning Rookie of the year for Canada that year. This last year, she was elected to the board of directors for PASS.org, the professional association for SQL Server and was awarded Regional Director by Microsoft. She has co-authored 3 books, including, SQL Server 2019 Administration inside out by Microsoft Press.</description>
      <twitter>SQLMelody</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/melodyzacharias</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlmelody.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLMelody</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86970</importID>
      <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Over 30 years in the computing field as a developer and system integrator; over 20 years working with SQL Server since version 6; cross platform experience with Oracle and IBM SQL/DS and DB2; Microsoft Certified Trainer for over 20 years.</description>
      <twitter>arlacerda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armando-lacerda</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arlacerda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87210</importID>
      <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erland Sommarskog is an independent consultant based in Stockholm, working with SQL Server since 1991. He was first awarded SQL Server MVP in 2001, and has been re-awarded every year since. His focus is on systems development with the SQL Server Database Engine and his passion is to help people to write better SQL Server applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sommarskog.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89121</importID>
      <name>Swagatika Sarangi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>*** AWS - SA  Informatica - MDM Certified, Solutions Architect ***

I have had nearly a decade of experience in leading Data Governance, Master Data and Data Quality oriented efforts, strategizing business plan, implementing all phases of SDLC and Agile for clients/projects including Telecommunication, Oil  Gas, Sporting goods, Logistics, Consulting, Insurance, Restaurant  Education etc. domain. I have extensive experience with developing effective business roadmaps and business models across E-Commerce, B2C, B2B, B2B2C with a major focus in effectively evaluating/and aligning Business Intelligence Analytics  Data Warehousing with the appropriate KPI's.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/GatorJazz12</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarangiswagatika/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.jazzintelligence.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/GatorJazz12</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87192</importID>
      <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kellyn Pot’Vin-Gorman is a member of the Oak Table Network and an Idera ACE and Oracle ACE Director alumnus. She is a Data Platform Architect in Power BI with AI in the EdTech group at Microsoft. Kellyn is known for her extensive work with multi-database platforms, DevOps, cloud migrations, virtualization, visualizations, scripting, environment optimization tuning, automation, and architecture design. 

Kellyn has spoken at numerous technical conferences for Oracle, Big Data, DevOps, testing, and SQL Server. Her blog (http://dbakevlar.com) and social media activity under her handle, DBAKevlar, is well respected for her insight and content.</description>
      <twitter>DBAKevlar</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellynpotvin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dbakevlar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAKevlar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>86396</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86396</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB205</name>
      </location>
      <title>2,4,8  16 - Visualise your data platform upgrade journey with SQL Server</title>
      <description>2,4,8  16 - these aren't just numbers to count or calculate. These are years that how SQL Server evolved as number of years!

Why Upgrade? 
Data Platform Upgrade topic has been a popular session that I've presented in major conferences like Microsoft Tech-Ed (North America, Europe  India) and SQLbits since 2008. 

In this session, we will overview in depth end-to-end upgrade process that covers the essential phases, steps and issues involved in upgrading  SQL Server (2000 to  2012),  SQL Server 2014 (with a good overview on 2016 too) by using best practices and available resources. 

What to-do and what not-to-do?

A popular session that I have been presenting since the year 2008, in MS Tech-Ed, SQL Saturday  SQLbits UK.
We will cover the an end-to-end upgrade cycle, including the preparation tasks, upgrade tasks, and post-upgrade tasks. Real-world data store and examples from my Consulting experience expanding on why  how such a solution.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87093</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87093</id>
          <name>Alex Yates</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DevOps/DataOps</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB105</name>
      </location>
      <title>DevOps 101 for Data People</title>
      <description>In 2009 John Allspaw and Paul Hammond delivered the session "10 deploys per day - Dev  ops cooperation at Flickr." In forty six minutes they changed the way millions of people would think about the software delivery process for years to come. It didn't have a name yet, but DevOps was born. DevOps folk preached about the cloud, automation, rapid delivery and any database technology that wasn't relational.
 
In 2013 Kenny Gorman declared "The DBA is Dead".
 
For the record, I don't believe that, but a lot of people do. What is certain is that the world of IT is changing and traditional roles are changing with it. We all need to adapt.
 
In this interactive talk I'll explain what DevOps is, where it came from, and its implications for SQL Server. I'll demo example solutions to some of the foundational technical challenges (source control and test/deployment automation) and will leave plenty of time at the end to answer your questions.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86740</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86740</id>
          <name>Hamish Watson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB105</name>
      </location>
      <title>Test Driven Development in SQL Server – how to deploy code safer</title>
      <description>Test Driven Development (TDD)  is a design approach which has enabled application developers to write cleaner code. 
It is relevant for database development as it ensures that code produced using TDD and unit tests will be of higher quality which means interactions with data will be safer. 
TDD is not a new method of unit testing, it is an essential design practice for improving the quality of your deployed code.
In this session it will be shown how we can use TDD to design and write better unit tests using open-source frameworks and industry standard tools. These tools can be run within SQL Server Management Studio which means DBAs can also take advantage of TDD and unit test, to ensure more reliable code is deployed to databases. 
TDD can result in code that can be deployed more reliably and faster when using DevOps processes such as Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery. 
A comprehensive DEMO will reveal how Test Driven Development can help you deploy database code safer.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87192</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87192</id>
          <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence/Machine Learning</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB104</name>
      </location>
      <title>Taming of the Shrew - Optimizing Power BI</title>
      <description>No one wants to tell a report user that while running a report in Power BI they have time to go get a cup of coffee…in another town.  Although data sets will often be the focus of performance issues, it’s important to know how to locate performance problems in Power BI and how to eliminate them.  

This session will take the Power User through how to identify time consuming processing in Power BI and how to address it through step-by-step and proven methods used to optimize in multi-tier environments.  This method removes frustration and finger-pointing and gets to the heart of the problem with a goal of correcting performance challenges.  The results are satisfied end users who get the information they need, when they need it.

Take Aways:
Learn how to identify what is taking the time in a Power BI data set and report.
Understand the logging and tracing mechanisms and capabilities in the environment.
Understand when a problem is really a problem.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87918</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87918</id>
          <name>Melody Zacharias</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence/Machine Learning</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB106</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Azure AI - The Art of the possible</title>
      <description>According to the Economist magazine, data is the world’s most valuable resource.  So, it makes sense that Data Science, Azure Machine Learning, and Analytics are all becoming core pieces to the success of every business.  As data professionals, we need to know how these core pieces will affect what we do, and how we can use the Azure AI suite to help our clients.  Microsoft’s AI suite is the central hub for learning and implementing each of these core pieces.  Using an easy to follow example, I will show the flow from problem to solution.  Multiple demonstrations of the different pieces will show use cases of the AI suite.  This overview of Azure AI will use the various pieces like a puzzle which, when brought together, will form a seamless picture of the whole so that participants can see that the individual pieces were meant to work together.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86889</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86889</id>
          <name>Joseph Yeates</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence/Machine Learning</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB104</name>
      </location>
      <title>Predictive Analytics with R in Power BI</title>
      <description>Power BI reports are typically used for descriptive analysis: a historical look of what has happened. But what if your report could visualize what is likely to happen and recommend what you can do about it now? This session will cover how to shift from descriptive to predictive analysis and leverage the power of machine learning to enhance your business intelligence solutions. The basics and best practices of predictive modeling will be introduced, and these concepts will be applied to create three predictive models in R using three different techniques. We will then walk through the three different ways to integrate the predictive power of these models into a Power BI report.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89121</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89121</id>
          <name>Swagatika Sarangi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence/Machine Learning</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB104</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why Solidity is Solid – Basics of Ethereum, Smart Contracts, and Blockchain.</title>
      <description>If you are into Ethereum or any latest Blockchain platform you may know the availability of “smart contract language (SCL)” comes easily. In this foundational quick talk, I will be introducing my audiences to a newer coding platform in Blockchain. We know that any RELATIONAL language/platform is legacy and solid when it comes to prevalence. But if you are open to experiment and broaden your understanding to a Blockchain world with the new-cutting-age-y languages, feel free to join my session. 
Topics that I will cover in this session – 
1.	What is Ethereum Blockchain (A, B, Cs of it.)
2.	Overview of NEO platform  Solidity language
3.	What are ‘Smart Contracts’
4.	Python, C++ Vs Solidity, Language of Smart Contract
5.	Last but not least, if you attend my session and do NOT understand ‘a thing’ I am speaking; you will still get a ton of ‘reference materials’ that I have been gaining from many over-priced Blockchain courses conducted by multi-millionaires, geeks.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 1:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89701</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89701</id>
          <name>Konstantin Kosinsky</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB106</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Columnstore indexes in Azure DevOps Services. Lessons learned</title>
      <description>The Analytics service in Azure DevOps Services provides all-over insights to your DevOps data: work item tracking, CI/CD pipelines, testing process etc. 
	 
Built on top of columnstore indexes, the Analytics service has to deal with 100s of millions records and daily growth in 10s of millions, only a few minutes delay from operation store, sub second query performance for in-product experiences as well as 3rd party extensions, Power BI integration and ad-hoc queries.
	 
Working on it, I've learned a lot of DOs and DON'Ts about columnstore indexes. Session covers how to:
* partition columnstore indexes in a multitenant environment
* maintain columnstore indexes in case of updates and/or purge to keep segment elimination possible
* evolve database schema without downtimes and maintenance windows
* design to benefit from predicate and aggregation pushdown
* deal with edge case like ad-hoc queries for raw data and paging
* choose between CCI and NCCI based on usage patterns</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86688</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86688</id>
          <name>Reid Havens</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence/Machine Learning</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB104</name>
      </location>
      <title>Demystifying Chart Types and Report Design Principles in Power BI</title>
      <description>Failing to deliver a well-designed Power BI Report is perhaps the most common reporting pitfall.  What good is quality data if it is not presented in a way that is meaningful or easily understood? Someone without any prior knowledge should be able to quickly understand a report without explanation and be quickly drawn to the key elements you want them to view.  This talk will walk through many elements of bad report design. Learn about visual cues and how certain chart types can convey data more accurately than others. Also, learn about the basic dos and don’ts of report design and layout, using easy-to-learn techniques that bring data to life.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88750</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88750</id>
          <name>Gail Shaw</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB205</name>
      </location>
      <title>On Transactions and Atomic Operations</title>
      <description>"If there’s one thing that we, as SQL developers don’t do, it’s use transactions as often as we should.

Transactions are critical when multiple changes need to be made entirely or not at all, but even given that it’s rare to see transactions used at all in most production code

In this session, we’ll look at what transactions are and why we should use them. We’ll explore the effects transactions have on locking and the transaction log. We’ll investigate methods of handling errors and undoing data modifications, and we’ll see why nested transactions are a lie.

1) Understand what transactions are and what they do.

2) Learn how to use transactions in combination with error handling to roll back changes on errors

3) Learn how transactions affect logging and locking.

"</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87795</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87795</id>
          <name>josh smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL 101</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB205</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL 101: A Very Good Place To Start</title>
      <description>We'll start with a quick tour of the Azure Data Studio before diving into the basics of T-SQL. In this interactive and demo heavy session we'll look at basic queries and filter operators as we build out some single table queries and multi table joins. We'll also cover some basic data aggregations and talk a little bit about what the SQL engine is doing under the covers to return your results as quickly as possible.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89692</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89692</id>
          <name>Rebecca Long</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DevOps/DataOps</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB205</name>
      </location>
      <title>Antipattern Assumptions in Data</title>
      <description>While we are engineers, we are still people full of assumptions, biases and unchecked preconceptions about society and other people.  This impacts our design patterns for software and databases. When we design architecture that is limited based on our assumptions, we can find our products limiting and creating user experience problems.  In this session, we will discuss common antipattern assumptions that cause these limitations in our architecture design.  We will also talk through the importance of creating a diverse team to help broaden perspectives and increase innovation which can help counter these antipatterns to pave the way for higher quality products.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87210</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87210</id>
          <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB106</name>
      </location>
      <title>Don't Use Cursors or Why You Maybe Should Use a Cursor After All</title>
      <description>You might have heard "don't use cursors, they are slow!". In this presentation, you will learn what this actually means: you should normally write set-based statements instead and I will explain why they generally are faster than writing your own loops. But I will also look at situations where using a loop for one reason or another is preferrable, and you will learn that the best way to run a loop in most cases is exactly a cursor, provided that you implement it properly. The presenation also gives some tips how you can troubleshoot performance problems with loops.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90611</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90611</id>
          <name>Philip Spokas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DevOps/DataOps</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB105</name>
      </location>
      <title>Continuously Deploy Azure Analytics Solutions using Azure DevOps</title>
      <description>This session will demonstrate deploying Azure Data Factory and Data Analytics solutions using Azure DevOps.

Using DevOps practices for ETL and analytics:
	• Eliminates manual and error prone steps increasing quality,
	• Reduces effort required to deploy,
	• Enables smaller and more incremental changes,
	• And a number of other advantages.

We'll cover practices required including configuration and testing to insure successful deployments.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89331</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89331</id>
          <name>Michael Wall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB105</name>
      </location>
      <title>PoSh on SSRS - Essential Skills to manage your RS with PowerShell</title>
      <description>Learn how powerful the new PowerShell tools for SSRS are and how they can help you administer your reporting environment!  This presentation will give a brief overview of the new tools that are being actively supported by Microsoft and then show many many ways to use them in your daily life.  Come away with scripts to help you implement the tools in any environment!</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88061</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88061</id>
          <name>Rob Sewell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB105</name>
      </location>
      <title>Administrating SQL Server with PowerShell dbatools</title>
      <description>Let me show you how easy it is to use PowerShell to accomplish many everyday tasks straight from the command line with the community developed module dbatools.

Afraid of PowerShell? 
Worried its too complicated?
Don't want to go through the learning curve?

Let me show you with plenty of demos how easy and straight forward it can be and I will save you time starting Monday

Want to restore an entire servers databases to the latest available point in time of the backups in just one line?
Be useful to know the Last DBCC Check for your entire estate in only one line of code?
Need to test your restores but its complicated?
and many many more
All this in a fast paced, fun session</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 1:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88476</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88476</id>
          <name>Ben Miller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB205</name>
      </location>
      <title>Be Friendly to SQL Server with TSQL Best Practices</title>
      <description>TSQL is a necessity when interacting with SQL Server so knowing can be half the battle. Performance is always good as the database starts to grow, but building in resilience when you begin is a greater advantage than refactoring. I will go over 5 key things to know when you write TSQL, use DataTypes and/or variables in comparisons and you will also learn about the procedure cache and how to avoid pitfalls there. This is a beginners session but the concepts in this session are a great foundation to begin with. If you are looking for a solid foundation to build on and need the basics to start, this session is definitely for you.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 1:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86535</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86535</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB104</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Cleansing With SQL And R</title>
      <description>On a given project, data scientists can spend upwards of 80% of their time preparing, cleaning, and correcting data. In this session, we will look at different data cleansing and preparation techniques using both SQL Server and R. We will investigate the concept of tidy data and see how we can use tools in both languages to simplify research and analysis of a small but realistic data set.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87110</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87110</id>
          <name>Steve Stedman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB106</name>
      </location>
      <title>TSQL User Defined Functions – Taboo or not?</title>
      <description>For years user defined functions (UDFs) have been the nemesis of the DBA focused on performance, but they have been loved by developers due to their ability to help with code re-usability and abstraction of business rules.
SQL Server 2019 introduces techniques that help eliminate some of the performance issues related to UDFs. Learn how and in what cases scalar UDF In-lining can improve your performance reducing the historic performance problems with UDFs.
We will explore how in-lining improves performance, along with what you can do and what prevents in-lining of UDFs.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88514</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88514</id>
          <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB106</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server  Containers</title>
      <description>This session aims to take attendees through what containers are and what benefits they bring.
After this demo based session, attendees will be able to go back to their respective companies and be able to evaluate container technology to determine whether or not it will be of benefit.

Attendees will be taken through the following: - 
The definition of containers
Virtual Machines vs Containers
Pulling SQL images from the docker hub
Running SQL Server containers 
Creating custom container images 
Sharing container images
Persisting data in SQL Server containers
A real world implementation of containers</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86970</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86970</id>
          <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>CEB106</name>
      </location>
      <title>CosmosDB - Understanding the main factors for successfull deployment</title>
      <description>Let's face it: Microsoft Data Platform is not just SQL Server anymore. Azure has added a dozen of other data related products to the menu. Being a cloud DBA means dealing with these new options when needed. 
In this session packed with demos you will see how to cross the bridge between SQL Server and Cosmos DB back and forth; how to related items from both sides and what is required to design a CosmosDB deployment.</description>
      <startTime>3/23/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/23/2019 1:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>