<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #665 - Bucuresti 2017</name>
    <startDate>9/16/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>90</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Harare, Pretoria</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatBucuresti</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Romania</name>
      <street>Piața Presei Libere nr. 3-5 Clădirea City Gate</street>
      <city>Bucuresti</city>
      <state>Bucureşti, Romania</state>
      <zipcode>013702</zipcode>
      <longitude>26.0714392662048</longitude>
      <latitude>44.4770856381306</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67307</importID>
      <name>Gheorghe-Bogdan SAHLEAN</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Yet another SQL Server enthusiast</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/bsahlean</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sahlean-gheorghe-bogdan-79a81648/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aboutsql.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/bsahlean</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67308</importID>
      <name>Cristian Lefter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cristian Lefter is Principal of Esential Training and one of the SQL Server MVPs. His primary competence is training. He is also a consultant, author, speaker and community leader. 
As his main expertise is Microsoft SQL Server, which resulted in founding an official PASS chapter, writing books and articles, contributing at the development of Microsoft Official Courseware, authoring certification exams, speaking at technical events and working as a Subject Matter Expert in various projects.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cristianlefter</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67300</importID>
      <name>Razvan Socol</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Software architect, database designer and application developer for business software, having more than 15 years of experience with Microsoft SQL Server. Former SQL Server MVP (July 2007-June 2010)</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/razvansocol</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69081</importID>
      <name>Octavian Cretu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Database Administrator, Database Developer, former Support Escalation Engineer at Microsoft</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69429</importID>
      <name>Alice-Lavinia Pasare</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>---</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69232</importID>
      <name>Liviu Ieran</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>More than 9 years of SQL Server experience working for Microsoft currently as a Support Escalation Engineer. 
My main area of expertise is SQL Server Performance where I helped optimize numerous query's and environments.</description>
      <twitter>@Liviu_Ieran</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/IeranLiviu</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Liviu_Ieran</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67713</importID>
      <name>Sorin Peste</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a Technical Evangelist @ Microsoft and passionate about all things software development.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66907</importID>
      <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Catalin Gheorghiu is a solution architect from Romania. He has more than 15 years of experience in developing solutions, especially on Microsoft technologies in very demanding environments. Is contributing articles and blogs to several user groups (MrSmersh), lecturing all over Romania and abroad, is also RONUA Timisoara (PASS Chapter) user group leader. Since 2011, every year he was awarded the Microsoft MVP Award.</description>
      <twitter>MrSmersh</twitter>
      <linkedin>?https://ro.linkedin.com/in/catalingheorghiu?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ronua.ro/author/catalin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MrSmersh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65058</importID>
      <name>Kaloyan Kosev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kaloyan Kosev is a SQL Server expert working with enterprise companies for the last 12* years. His daily work routine is a mixture of troubleshooting bugs and issues, consulting and advising clients and presenting to students. Within his free time he is trying to balance between SQL and x-sports.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/nosqltillcoffee</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://bg.linkedin.com/in/kosev</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/nosqltillcoffee</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64920</importID>
      <name>Mike Byrd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Former rocket scientist and USAF Fighter Pilot -- now a SQL Server geek (24 years)! Past opportunities include free-lance technical writer for PC Magazine, Senior Software Manager for government sponsored munitions effectiveness committee, and insurance company CTO.  Currently senior database engineer consultant for several Austin companies.  

Presenter at many SQL Saturdays over last 6 years in United States, Europe, and Australia.

Specialize in SQL Server performance tuning; database (OLTP  OLAP) architecture; trouble-shooting; teaching TSQL (Basic through Advanced).

Video presentations (for local SQL Server user groups or SQL Saturdays) can be found at http://usergroup.tv/videos/category/speaker/mike-byrd</description>
      <twitter>ByrdNest_TX</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-byrd/1/aa0/bbb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://logicalread.solarwinds.com/?s=byrd, www.TSQLMentoring.com and SQLServerCentral.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ByrdNest_TX</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69292</importID>
      <name>Andrada Nastasie</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am working for Microsoft Romania as a Premier Field Engineer since September 2015. My areas of interest are SQL Server High Availability solutions, Security and Configuration. Before Microsoft, I worked as a Database Administrator for 2 years in the banking environment. I studied Computer Science at the Polytechnic University of Bucharest.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64780</importID>
      <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr.SubraMANI Paramasivam is a Microsoft MVP, PhD, Microsoft Certified Trainer and Head of Data  AI at DAGEOP Ltd having 21 years of DB, BI, Analytics and AI experience. Mani has also spoken in various events like MS IGNITE, PASS Summit, MS Inspire, SQLBITS, Power Platform Summit, Global AI Bootcamp, Data  BI Summit, SQLRelay,  Power BI World Tour, Data Platform Summit, INSIDESQL UK, Global AI Nights, SQLServerGeeks Summit, MCT Global Summits, Data Day Events and various user group events. Mani also believes in Empowering Every Person in the planet and spreads the awareness on Global challenges via www.EmpoweringEveryPerson.com. He is also a co-owner of 1 Global AI Meetup and 3 Power BI PUG  PASS local / user groups.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dageop</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/dageop</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.yoursqlman.com/index.php/blogs</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dageop</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>64920</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64920</id>
          <name>Mike Byrd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown2</name>
      </location>
      <title>In-Memory Tables --Formula One Performance Unleashed, Part 1</title>
      <description>Query performance is what it is all about.  SQL Server 2014/2016 now has the new in-memory functionality that takes a completely different approach to data access and manipulation.  This session will consolidate the relevant information from all these sources so the production DBA/Developer will be able to understand, create, use, maintain, and trouble-shoot in-memory table functionality.  This session will also examine several demo scripts showing performance gains using the in-memory tables with and without columnstore indexes over equivalent disk based tables.  
This session is all about when and how to apply in-memory tables in a production environment.
After this session you will
1.	 Understand what in-memory tables are and how to create and maintain them including their limitations
2.	Be able to identify performance gains over equivalent disk back tables
3.	Comprehend the new data monitoring needed for in-memory table</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66907</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66907</id>
          <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cinema</name>
      </location>
      <title>IoT Circus –  deathmatch oops, datematch :) Power Bi vs Time Series Insights</title>
      <description>Or how to visualize your data and find insights for beginner IoT developer
If you create an IoT solution today, you have a variety of components available to mix and match to make your solution, akin LEGO.
You get your hardware and firmware right and you get data from the sensors, now what? Of course, you would like to have, some data visualization easy and fast, and of course you would like to learn something from that data easy and fast. And it would be nice to have the results available on mobile devices, yes, yes easy and fast.
Now enter our two titan technologies in a match to the death oops data  trying to achieve these goals, you guess it easy fast (and cheap). 
And we will see them clash, from real hardware, to the big Azure cloud, to mobile devices, trying to outmatch each other.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67308</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67308</id>
          <name>Cristian Lefter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cinema</name>
      </location>
      <title>Third Party Tools for SQL Server</title>
      <description>During of my work in the field (for more than 17 years) I noticed that very few people are aware that SQL Server has a great ecosystem of partners that come with functionality where Microsoft tools don't do it, or don't go in depth. Even more, some of the are offered for free and my session will expose as many as possible.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67713</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67713</id>
          <name>Sorin Peste</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Database - It's Just SQL Server Without the Headaches, Right?!</title>
      <description>The Azure SQL Database service's promise to us is simple: we get the nice features of SQL Server, with none of the management and operations hassle. But is it always that simple? Join this session for an overview about what this service really is, its strengths and weaknesses, and how to get the most bang for your database buck in the real world.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69429</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69429</id>
          <name>Alice-Lavinia Pasare</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cinema</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL XML unleashed</title>
      <description>This session covers XQuery implementation and XML index performance considerations.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64780</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64780</id>
          <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown2</name>
      </location>
      <title>PowerBI On-Premises Vs Cloud</title>
      <description>Microsoft initially released PowerBI online services which had restriction of developing dashboards and reports online only. Then came the PowerBI desktop for easy onsite development including the complex DAX logics.

PowerBI support to SQL Server 2016 Reporting Services is a major breakthrough for any dashboards without any need to host in the Cloud.

In this session, we will explore and compare the features availale on PowerBI Online Services and PowerBI On-prem SSRS 2016. This session also covers the PowerBI Roadmap for both on-prem and cloud solutions.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65058</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65058</id>
          <name>Kaloyan Kosev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Embrace the future: Running SQL Server in containers</title>
      <description>Well, the future is now. Join me in demo heavy session covering SQL server running in containers. Starting from scratch we will go through a complete container implementation.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67300</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67300</id>
          <name>Razvan Socol</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Graph tables in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2017 adds new features for storing data regarding graphs. In this session we will explore some of the details behind the implementation of these features, the advantages and drawbacks of the current implementation and evaluate the performance of various graph queries.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69081</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69081</id>
          <name>Octavian Cretu</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Distributed Availability Groups</title>
      <description>In this session we will look into detail behind the feature "Distributed Availability Groups". We will cover not only the advantages but also common issues encountered during the implementation and administration of the distributed availability groups.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69232</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69232</id>
          <name>Liviu Ieran</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 - Understanding Statistics</title>
      <description>When analyzing Query plans understanding statistics and what role they play is a very important part. 
The session will be mostly demo based and will show you how to interpret the stats histogram and how SQL estimates the rows returned from a given table.
It will also include a demo of the new query profile dmv.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67307</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67307</id>
          <name>Gheorghe-Bogdan SAHLEAN</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cinema</name>
      </location>
      <title>Custom Visuals in PowerBI</title>
      <description>This session will show how to create a custom PowerBI Visual using some basic knowledge about web development and how to integrate it into PowerBI reports or dashboards.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69292</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69292</id>
          <name>Andrada Nastasie</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server migration</title>
      <description>Best practices and recommendations for SQL Server migrations.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>