<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #336 - Holland 2014</name>
    <startDate>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Sarajevo, Skopje, Warsaw, Zagreb</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatHolland</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>University of Utrecht - Marinus Ruppert Building</name>
      <street>Leuvenlaan 21</street>
      <city>Utrecht</city>
      <state>Utrecht, Netherlands</state>
      <zipcode>3584 CE</zipcode>
      <longitude>5.173695</longitude>
      <latitude>52.086182</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>13</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/sqlsaturday/eventsponsors/Quest_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>388</importID>
      <name>ApexSQL LLC</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.apexsql.com/?utm_source=SQLSaturdaysutm_medium=sponsorlinkutm_campaign=%5BSQLSaturdays-Homepage%5D</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/864/EventSponsor_13700.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1300</importID>
      <name>XLCubed</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.xlcubed.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/61423e34-a7f4-4667-a024-98a0ee0d8f99.gif</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1115</importID>
      <name>SQL Sentry</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlsentry.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sentryone.com/Images/logos/sentryone-black.svg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>492</importID>
      <name>COEO</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.coeo.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/a60778e7-bdb6-4130-90a1-943b5d024d5d.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>8</importID>
      <name>FusionIO</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.fusionio.com/solutions/microsoft-sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/files/18b704b1-226d-48fe-b0b8-f7b4d3443b3d.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16243</importID>
      <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joseph D'Antoni is a Senior Consultant and Microsoft Data Platform MVP with over 20 years of experience working in both Fortune 500 and smaller firms. He is a Principal Consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates and lives in Malvern, PA. He is a frequent speaker at major tech events like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and Enterprise Data World. He blogs about all topics technology at joeydantoni.com. He believes that no single platform is the answer to all technology problems. Joseph holds a BS in Computer Information Systems from Louisiana Tech University and an MBA from North Carolina State University, and is the co-author of the Microsoft book "Introducing SQL Server 2016”.</description>
      <twitter>jdanton</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=3997984amp;trk=hb_tab_pro_top</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://joeydantoni.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jdanton</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13805</importID>
      <name>Enrico van de Laar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Enrico has been working with data in all kinds of formats and sizes for over 15 years. He is a Data  Advanced Analytics Consultant for Dataheroes where he helps organisations take their first steps in the world of Advanced Analytics. Enrico is a Data Platform MVP since 2014 and a frequent speaker on various data related events all over the world. He authored the book “Pro SQL Server Wait Statistics” and blogs about technologies like Microsoft SQL Server and Azure Machine Learning on his blog at www.enricovandelaar.com</description>
      <twitter>twitter.com/evdlaar</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/pub/enrico-van-de-laar/33/882/756/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.enricovandelaar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=twitter.com/evdlaar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18236</importID>
      <name>Kevin Kline</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Kline is a database and industry expert serving as Principal Program Manager at SentryOne, the industry leading SQL Server database tools vendor. A Microsoft SQL Server MVP since 2003, he is a founder and former president of PASS. Kevin is an author of many books, blogger, columnist, and popular international speaker. Kevin’s best known book is the best-selling SQL in a Nutshell and contributes monthly to Database Trends  Applications magazine. He tweets at @kekline and blogs at http://Blogs.SQLSentry.com/Author/KevinKline.</description>
      <twitter>kekline</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kekline/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.sentryone.com/author/kevinkline</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kekline</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21396</importID>
      <name>Neil Hambly</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Neil Hambly is a SQL Server consultant, founder and consultant at Datamovements, a Gold Microsoft Data  Analytics Consulting company.
Neil has 20+ years in a variety of SQL Server roles and is an MCT. He is a regular presenter (200+ events) at user groups, and PASS events, including PASS Summit and SQLSaturday, and many UK events (SQLBits, SQLRelay). Neil is the leader of PASS London (UK), a Professional Development VC, a Melissa Data MVP, and a SQL Cruise Technical Lead, who loves Guinness, whisky, and dancing.</description>
      <twitter>Neil_Hambly</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/neilhambly</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataidol.com/NeilHambly</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Neil_Hambly</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13159</importID>
      <name>Denis Reznik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denis Reznik is a Data Architect at Intapp, Inc. He has more than ten years experience in software development, database design, and performance tuning for cloud and on-premises solutions. In 2010 Denis became Microsoft Data Platform MVP and maintains MVP status today. Apart from his professional career, Denis actively participates in the development of the Ukrainian Data Community.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DenisReznik</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/denis-reznik/3/502/234</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://reznik.uneta.com.ua</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DenisReznik</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18516</importID>
      <name>Klaus Aschenbrenner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Klaus Aschenbrenner provides independent SQL Server consulting services across the United States and Europe, focusing on the .NET Framework and SQL Server 2005 and 2008. In 2004 and 2005, he received the Microsoft MVP award for his support of the .NET community. Klaus has also written a book, “Pro SQL Server 2008 Service Broker,” published by Apress (2008).</description>
      <twitter>@Aschenbrenner</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.SQLpassion.at/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Aschenbrenner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19156</importID>
      <name>Joost van Rossum</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I#39;m a Microsoft Business Intelligence consultant at ilionx with a focus on SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS). I started my career with some ASP, ASP.Net, MCMS and SPS assignments and made the switch to BI when Microsoft released SQL Server 2005.
I try to blog at least once a month about SSIS (and related stuff) and  try to answer questions on the SSIS forum on MSDN where I#39;m a moderator. And last year I wrote an SSIS Scripting book to show you how to use C# or VB.Net within SSIS.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ssisjoost</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/joostvanrossum</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://microsoft-ssis.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ssisjoost</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15114</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo is co-founder and RD lead of perFact BV, a Dutch company that improves analysis methods and develops computer-aided tools to generate completely functional applications from the analysis deliverable. The platform for this development is SQL Server. In his spare time, Hugo likes to share and enhance his knowledge of SQL Server by frequenting newsgroups and forums, reading and writing books and blogs, and attending and speaking at conferences.
Hugo is also a SQL Server MVP since 2006.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27079</importID>
      <name>Peter ter Braake</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter ter Braake, SQL Server MVP, co-founder of the Dutch PASS Chapter and organizer of the Dutch SQL Saturday, teaches SQL Server since 2002. Teaching is for Peter the perfect opportunity to share his SQL Server knowledge and his enthusiasm for the product. Since 2008 he works as an independent contractor giving him the opportunity to use his classroom experience in the real world and use his real world experience in the classroom. </description>
      <twitter>@pbraake</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nl.linkedin.com/pub/peter-ter-braake/1/b87/1aa?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@pbraake</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24804</importID>
      <name>Mladen Prajdić</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mladen Prajdić is a Data Platform MVP from Slovenia. He's been programming for 20 years, developing diﬀerent types of applications in .Net (C#) and SQL Server, ranging from standard line-of-business, image-processing applications to high performace and IoT applications. He's a regular speaker at various conferences and usergroup meetings, really likes to optimize slow SQL statements, analyze performance, and find unconventional solutions to difficult SQL Server problems. In his free time, he also develops a very popular add-in for SSMS, called the SSMS Tools Pack (www.ssmstoolspack.com).</description>
      <twitter>@MladenPrajdic</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mladenprajdic</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/mladenp</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MladenPrajdic</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13722</importID>
      <name>Edgar Walther</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Edgar Walther has been an independent  BI consultant for over 12 years and specializes in the Microsoft Data Platform. He runs a BI consulting firm, ITsmart, based in the Netherlands, and he is one of the founders of the Dutch Power BI User Group. With a background of both Business Economics and IT development the area of Business Intelligence is where he can bridge the gap between Business and IT. He is very eager to stay up to date with the latest developments in Microsoft BI products, and he likes to share them with other BI enthusiasts. He has been a speaker at several SQL Server and Power BI events.</description>
      <twitter>@edgarwalther</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/edgarwalther/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.itsmart.eu/Blog/tabid/180/Default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@edgarwalther</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12086</importID>
      <name>n/a n/a</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>
      </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18521</importID>
      <name>Klaus Aschenbrenner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Klaus Aschenbrenner provides independent SQL Server consulting services across the United States and Europe, focusing on the .NET Framework and SQL Server 2005 and 2008. In 2004 and 2005, he received the Microsoft MVP award for his support of the .NET community. Klaus has also written a book, “Pro SQL Server 2008 Service Broker,” published by Apress (2008).</description>
      <twitter>@Aschenbrenner</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.SQLpassion.at/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Aschenbrenner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22154</importID>
      <name>Pieter Vanhove</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pieter Vanhove is a SQL Server MVP and Database Consultant in Belgium and has been working with SQL Server since 2000. Performance tuning, SQL audits, migrations and training are part of the job. Pieter has also a profound knowledge in implementing HA/DR solutions and loves the new Azure stuff. Together with the SQLUG in Belgium, he helps organizing SQL Server Days and is also a regular speaker at Belgian and international events. Pieter recently won the Speaker Idol Contest at PASS Summit 2014.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://pietervanhove.azurewebsites.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17782</importID>
      <name>Justin Langford</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Justin Langford is a Principal Consultant for Coeo, a Microsoft Gold Partner providing SQL Server consulting services for platform, analytics and cloud consulting and support for SQL Server.   Coeo provide 24x7 Remote DBA services for mission critical SQL Server platforms.  Justin is an MVP and co-authored Wrox IT Pro: SQL Server 2012 Internals and Troubleshooting, as well as the same title for SQL Server 2008 and SQL Server 2005 Performance Tuning.</description>
      <twitter>@justinlangford</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@justinlangford</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14959</importID>
      <name>Henk Van der Valk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Henk is a TSP for SQL Server Parallel Data Warehouse at Microsoft covering Western-Europe and has been working on optimizing SQL Server based solutions for many years; he presented at several Pass events talking about his favorite topics: IT efficiency  performance optimizations. 
</description>
      <twitter>@HenkvanderValk</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://henkvandervalk.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@HenkvanderValk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21097</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denny Cherry is the owner and principal consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates Consulting and has over a decade of experience working with platforms such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Microsoft SQL Server, Hyper-V, vSphere, and Enterprise Storage solutions. Denny’s areas of technical expertise include system architecture, performance tuning, security, replication, and troubleshooting. Denny currently holds several Microsoft Certifications related to SQL Server 2000 through 2019, including being a Microsoft Certified Master, Microsoft MVP and VMware vExpert Award.</description>
      <twitter>mrdenny</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrdenny</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.dcac.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mrdenny</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16926</importID>
      <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Koesmarno, MCSE Data Platform, and MCSE Business Intelligence, MCT, is a Senior Program Manager at Microsoft, with a Bachelor’s degree in IT. She has over 10 years of experience working with SQL Server for large-scale and multi-million-dollar OLTP and ETL projects as a SQL Server developer and system analyst/designer. Her past projects include delivering a SQL Server 2012 data warehouse and BI solutions in the US and Australia. She now works with hybrid, cloud and on-prem SQL projects.</description>
      <twitter>@mssqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliekoesmarno</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mssqlgirl.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mssqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18936</importID>
      <name>Laerte Junior</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Laerte Junior is a  Windows PowerShell MVP Reconnect, PASS PowerShell VC Co-lead and, through his  simple-talk articles, an active member of the Microsoft Community  around the world. He also is a huge Star Wars fan (yes, he has the Darth Vader#180;s Helmet with the voice changer). He has a passion for DC comics and living the simple life.</description>
      <twitter>@laertesqldba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://br.linkedin.com/in/laertejunior/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/laerte-junior/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@laertesqldba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>35852</importID>
      <name>Sander van der hoeff</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With over 20 years of experience in automation Sander van der Hoeff knows his way around in the ICT business. Since 2000 Sander is Specialized in business intelligence and data warehousing using the full SQLServer Stack. In 2012 Sander founded his own BI-company: Du Sabot. Nowadays Sander spends his time on several BI- and DWH-projects as an independent professional. Sander combines deep technical knowledge with the capability to explain difficult BI- and DWH-concepts to the non-technical people</description>
      <twitter>shoeff</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/shoeff</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.du-sabot.nl</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=shoeff</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23357</importID>
      <name>Robert Hartskeerl</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With over 10 years of experience with SQL Server my knowledge goes a long way. But there is always room for more. That's the reason why I love to help people face and solve their everyday or incidental challenges. This helps me to get more out of SQL Server. My main role is as a DBA but I love to hang around in Visual Studio and not afraid to take you up on a discussion about ADO.NET or the Entity Framework.</description>
      <twitter>@rhartskeerl</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://robert.hartskeerl.nl</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@rhartskeerl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14801</importID>
      <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Grant Fritchey is a Data Platform MVP with over 20 years’ experience in IT, including time spent in support and development. He has worked with SQL Server since 6.0 back in 1995. He has also developed in VB, VB.NET, C#, and Java. Grant has written books for Apress and Simple-Talk. Grant presents at conferences and user groups, large and small, all over the world. He joined Redgate Software as a product evangelist in January 2011.</description>
      <twitter>@gfritchey</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/scarydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://scarydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@gfritchey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27022</importID>
      <name>Tomaž Kaštrun</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tomaž Kaštrun is BI developer and data analyst. His main focus are data mining, T-SQL development, programming and query optimization. He has been working with SQL server since version 2000. He is Microsoft Certified Professional, Microsoft MVP for data platform and Microsoft trainer.</description>
      <twitter>@tomaz_tsql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/tomaz.kastrun</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tomaztsql.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tomaz_tsql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16927</importID>
      <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Koesmarno, MCSE Data Platform, and MCSE Business Intelligence, MCT, is a Senior Program Manager at Microsoft, with a Bachelor’s degree in IT. She has over 10 years of experience working with SQL Server for large-scale and multi-million-dollar OLTP and ETL projects as a SQL Server developer and system analyst/designer. Her past projects include delivering a SQL Server 2012 data warehouse and BI solutions in the US and Australia. She now works with hybrid, cloud and on-prem SQL projects.</description>
      <twitter>@mssqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliekoesmarno</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mssqlgirl.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mssqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24744</importID>
      <name>Stacia Varga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stacia Varga is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and SSAS Maestro with a Bachelor’s Degree in Social Sciences. A consultant, educator, author, and principal of Data Inspirations, her career spans more than 30 years, with a focus on improving business practices through technology.

Since 2000, Stacia has provided consulting and education services for Microsoft's Business Intelligence technologies. As Stacia Misner, she also authored several books covering the Microsoft BI stack.</description>
      <twitter>@_StaciaV_</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/staciavarga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.datainspirations.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_StaciaV_</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14800</importID>
      <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Grant Fritchey is a Data Platform MVP with over 20 years’ experience in IT, including time spent in support and development. He has worked with SQL Server since 6.0 back in 1995. He has also developed in VB, VB.NET, C#, and Java. Grant has written books for Apress and Simple-Talk. Grant presents at conferences and user groups, large and small, all over the world. He joined Redgate Software as a product evangelist in January 2011.</description>
      <twitter>@gfritchey</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/scarydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://scarydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@gfritchey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16434</importID>
      <name>Jen Stirrup</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jen Stirrup, Microsoft Regional Director and MVP is a well-known Business Intelligence and Data Visualization expert, author, data strategist, and Master of Business Administration (MBA) student in London. Jen leads a boutique analytics consultancy, delivering strategic advice to companies large and small.

Jen has presented in Africa, India, Europe and North America. Jen has presented at Ignite, Techorama, TechEd, PASS Summit, SQLBits, and SQLSaturday events in Europe and the US. She also delivers the MAPA Azure Architects course worldwide with Microsoft team members. Jen was also featured on the Best of PASS Summit 2015 DVD as one of the top 10 speakers. Jen also was awarded PASS prestigious PASSion Award in 2012</description>
      <twitter>@jenstirrup</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/jenstirrup/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.jenstirrup.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@jenstirrup</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19477</importID>
      <name>Marco Russo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marco is a Business Intelligence consultant and mentor. He wrote several books about Power BI, Analysis Service, and Power Pivot. He also regularly writes articles and white papers that are available on sqlbi.com. Marco is a Microsoft MVP and an SSAS Maestro, the highest level of certification on Microsoft Analysis Services.
Today, Marco focuses his time with SQLBI customers, traveling extensively to train and consult on DAX and data modeling for Power BI and Analysis Services. Marco also teaches public classes worldwide.
Marco is a regular speaker at international conferences like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and SQLBits. He also enjoys delivering evening sessions at local user groups during his trips.</description>
      <twitter>marcorus</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlbi</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlbi.com/blog/marco</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=marcorus</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15109</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo is co-founder and RD lead of perFact BV, a Dutch company that improves analysis methods and develops computer-aided tools to generate completely functional applications from the analysis deliverable. The platform for this development is SQL Server. In his spare time, Hugo likes to share and enhance his knowledge of SQL Server by frequenting newsgroups and forums, reading and writing books and blogs, and attending and speaking at conferences.
Hugo is also a SQL Server MVP since 2006.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11575</importID>
      <name>Christian Bolton</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Christian Bolton is the Technical Director for Coeo Ltd, a leading provider of SQL Server managed support and consulting in the UK and Europe. Christian is a Microsoft Certified Architect, Microsoft Certified Master, and MVP for SQL Server, and an experienced technical author. He is particularly interested in SQL Server infrastructure, scalability, and high availability, and is a highly rated speaker at technical conferences worldwide.</description>
      <twitter>@christianbolton</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/christianbolton</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblogcasts.com/blogs/christian</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@christianbolton</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>14800</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14800</id>
          <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building a Database Deployment Pipeline</title>
      <description>The pace of business accelerates fairly continuously and application development moves right with it. But we’re still trying to deploy databases the same way we did 10 years ago. This session addresses the need for changes in organizational structure, process and technology necessary to arrive at a nimble, fast, automatable and continuous database deployment process. We’ll use actual customer case studies to illustrate both the common methods and the unique context that led to a continuous delivery process that is best described as a pipeline. You will learn how to customize common practices and tool sets to build a database deployment pipeline unique to your environment in order to speed your own database delivery while still protecting your organization’s most valuable asset, it’s data.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16243</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16243</id>
          <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Who Moved My Tuple--Columnstore Indexes in SQL Server 2014.</title>
      <description>
Data Warehouse workloads can be very large and taxing on your database server. With the modern demands of real-time analytics against growing volumes of data this challenge continues. When columnstore indexes and batch mode query processing were introduced in SQL Server 2012 were a performance game changer. In the 2012 implementation of columnstore, direct updating and inserting of data was not supported and other restrictions, such as data types limited the use of the feature. SQL 2014 removes those limitations—you can use a columnstore index as a clustered index, and more importantly directly perform DML against the index. Also, more query operators support batch mode, which means more of your queries can see performance benefits. You will understand the changes for 2014—and how having updateable columnstore indexes may cause changes to your process design. You will see the power of columnstore indexes in analytics, their limits, and how to include them into your system design.
</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16434</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16434</id>
          <name>Jen Stirrup</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>A One Hour Data Analysts Toolkit: using R and PowerBI</title>
      <description>If you want to conduct advanced Business Intelligence development and Business Analysis, then it is useful to understand data visualisation and have R as a tool in your toolset. In this intensive one hour session, we will look at the latest suite of Microsoft Business Intelligence tools - Microsoft Power BI in conjunction with R. The demos will be implemented in both tools in an end-to-end hour long session so that delegates can see when to use each technology in order to determine 'what to use' and 'when to use it', as well as seeing where the technologies complement each other. We will visualise the data according to data visualisation principles set out by Stephen Few amongst others.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16927</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16927</id>
          <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding Query Modes in Tabular Model</title>
      <description>SQL Server Analysis Services Tabular Model allows rapid and simplified data modelling of Business Intelligence solutions. An important aspect that is often overlooked when building a tabular model, is meeting real-time requirements. In this session you will learn how to tackle immediate (or close to) real time requirements using the different types of Data Access and Query Modes of Tabular Model and how your choice impacts your reporting options in the Microsoft BI stack.

Using live demo, this session will outline advantages and disadvantages between DirectQuery and In-Memory modes. We will also highlight impersonation and partitioning differences between the two modes. Finally, we will also cover the definition of a Hybrid Tabular Model solution.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16926</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16926</id>
          <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>From Impaired To Insightful Geospatial Reporting</title>
      <description>It is expected that business reports be insightful and engaging. Region based reporting can be transformed from boring grids to visually interactive maps. This session will describe how to embark upon self-service and mobile BI solutions that are available within the Microsoft BI stack for analytical geospatial reporting. You will learn the basics of geographical data, including GIS, Longitude-Latitude coordinates and free form text. Using these different data types, we will discuss SSRS 2012, Power View and Excel 2013 tools that can leverage insightful analysis. Finally and most importantly, attending this talk will get you started in learning the essential techniques to deliver geospatial reports that tell meaningful stories for users.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14801</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14801</id>
          <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting Started Reading Execution Plans</title>
      <description>The best way to understand why your query is running slow is to look at the execution plan. But, knowing how to get started in execution plans, what to look for, what's important, can all be terribly confusing. This session will provide you with a simple set of tasks to get you started reading execution plans. You'll learn where to start, what to look for first, and you'll be better prepared to tune your queries. We'll also look at some methods you can use to write queries against the plans themselves in order to more easily and quickly identify potential issues within your plans. The information presented will be immediately applicable on the queries you have running back in the office.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18236</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18236</id>
          <name>Kevin Kline</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Top 10 Admininistrator Mistakes on SQL Server</title>
      <description>SQL Server is easier to administrate than any other relational database on the market.  But “easier than everyone else” doesn’t mean it’s easy, nor does it mean is problem free. After all, many apps are growing from small, home-grown applications every year, with green IT professionals encountering issues that others had tackled and solved years ago.  Why not learn from those who first blazed the trails of database administration, so that we don’t make the same mistakes over and over again. There is a short list of mistakes that, if you know of them in advance, will make your life much easier. Once you apply the lessons learned from this session, you’ll find yourself performing at a higher level of efficiency and effectiveness than before.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19477</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19477</id>
          <name>Marco Russo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power Query in Modern Corporate BI</title>
      <description>In a Corporate BI environment, it is common having data available in controlled data sources such as Data Warehouse, relational Data Marts, and Analysis Services cubes. Consuming this data with self-service BI is very useful, but how do you manage and validate the access to corporate data sources? How do you share and validate new queries created by end users? How can users extract data at the right granularity level? Power Query bridges the gap between corporate and self-service BI. It empowers end-users so that they can extract and manipulate data from several data sources, inside and outside of the company. In this session, learn the Power Query best practices that enable the extraction of data from existing database and cubes, guided by an expert who understands both worlds (Corporate BI and Power Pivot data models).</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21396</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21396</id>
          <name>Neil Hambly</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Load Testing With SQL Server Tools</title>
      <description>It’s often difficult to know how your SQL Servers will perform under different loads. By performing load testing, we can gain these key insights, perform modifications to existing configurations, and understand the impact on performance levels.

Come learn about the native tools at our disposal for performing these important load tests and how we can identify when performance levels begin to drop. Using demos of these native tools – including Distributed Replay Utility (DRU), Database Tuning Adviser (DTA), Perfmon, Extended Events, and Profiler – we’ll see how to plan and perform a load test project, gain an understanding of SQL Server’s performance under varying load scenarios, and discover which tell-tale indicators can help alert us to performance degradation.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15109</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15109</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Improve your Database Performance in Seven Simple Steps</title>
      <description>You wrote the code, you tested it, it works, and it’s fast. So you deploy. And then those pesky users insist on entering not hundreds, not thousands, but millions of rows – and suddenly, you have performance problems.
What to do? Blaming SQL Server is a good start, but won’t solve the problems. You can of course hire a database consultant to make all your performance problems (and all your money) disappear - but why not first take a look yourself?
This session will show you seven simple things, that might alleviate most of your database related performance problems. Use these tricks at your workplace, and you can be the hero of the department!</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18516</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18516</id>
          <name>Klaus Aschenbrenner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Latches, Spinlocks, and Lock Free Data Structures</title>
      <description>You know locking and blocking very well in SQL Server? You know how the isolation level influences locking? Perfect! Join me in this session to make a further deep dive into how SQL Server implements physical locking with lightweight synchronization objects like Latches and Spinlocks. We will cover the differences between both, and their use-cases in SQL Server. You will learn about best practices how to analyze and resolve Latch- and Spinlock contentation for your performance critical workload. At the end we will talk about lock free data structures, what they are, and how they are used by the new In-Memory OLTP technology that is part of SQL Server 2014.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>35852</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>35852</id>
          <name>Sander van der hoeff</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Unlock the Power of Pivot Tables</title>
      <description>Your tabular model is done, approved and ready to be used by the user. By means of using Excel the user gets very excited about the use of tabular Models. For a while the user uses Excel as a self-service business intelligence tool. Then all of a sudden the user starts asking if they can use the program to extract more and other information from the tabular model by the use of Excel. Now it is up to you to familiarize the user with all the possibilities of working with the tabular model by means of Excel.
Given the small amount of documented knowledge about the use of tabular models by means of Excel, I will show you how to get the best of your tabular models by using Excel as a self-service business intelligence tool. Filters, named sets, and calculations in the pivot table: I will explain it all!</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22154</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22154</id>
          <name>Pieter Vanhove</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>1, 2, 3, … 100. How to manage many SQL Servers the easy way?</title>
      <description>Quote: “A good DBA is a lazy DBA”. When you have to manage a few SQL Servers, it’s not that hard to be a lazy DBA and to automate your day to day activities. But when you have to manage over 100 instances, it can become a tough job. Just imagine how you will deploy a new maintenance job on all your instances? Are you going to connect to each server one by one? Not really… Microsoft provides an enhanced set of multi-server management tools. The purpose of this sessions is to point out which SQL Server tools you can use for multi-server management. The session is bulk loaded with demos and it will give you a good idea what features can be helpful in your environment. </description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27079</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27079</id>
          <name>Peter ter Braake</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Top 10 issues for SQL Server Healthchecks</title>
      <description>Top 10 issues for SQL Server Healthchecks</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11575</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11575</id>
          <name>Christian Bolton</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding SQL Server Parallelism</title>
      <description>In this session you’ll learn how SQL Server chooses parallel operations, how to investigate what’s going on and whether your parallel query is running as efficiently as it could be.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27022</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27022</id>
          <name>Tomaž Kaštrun</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Usage of R in SQL Server for better data understanding</title>
      <description>Language R for Statistical computing is powerful language for data analysis with all great features for data import from SQL environment. Using R with SQL server data will help data scientists and data analysts prepare, explore and validate data much easier, as well as to use wide range of statistics; from uni-variate to multivariate.

Session will focus mainly on:
1) on connecting R Language with SQL server using standard ODBC connectors and T-SQL procedures. 
2) how to validate data with using classical statistical methods on SQL transactional data. 
3) how to use R output in SSRS and bring extra information to reports.
</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19156</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19156</id>
          <name>Joost van Rossum</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>How do you create nice/horrible packages?</title>
      <description>SSIS Development Best Practices:
I have seen my share of unreadable and unmaintainable SSIS packages. Last year I showed how to create faster packages, this time I want to show you how to create better packages with a list of do's and don'ts when creating packages and working in a project team. And how do you use/setup a product like TFS when working with SSIS? </description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18936</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18936</id>
          <name>Laerte Junior</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Writing your solutions using PowerShell</title>
      <description>Some frequently asked question of those who are starting out with PowerShell: 
Creating solutions that meet my needs? 
Script or function? When and why? 
I want to write codes thinking as PowerShell, but how? 
If you have these questions, this is the right session for you. In this session we will see a introduction to PowerShell, passing through some 
of its most important concepts and ending in your  first solution in the Shell.
It is time to you look at the future right ?</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13159</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13159</id>
          <name>Denis Reznik</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title> SQL Server Deep Dive</title>
      <description>How often do you wonder why SQL Server executes the query in such a way? Why is selecting few records from the table takes a long time? Why SQL Server eats lot of memory? etc. I invite you to join me in this session and look at the architectural components of SQL Server, look at the internal processes of SQL Server, and discuss how it affect performance of your queries.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13722</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13722</id>
          <name>Edgar Walther</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI: what, how, why?</title>
      <description>This talk is about the self-service BI products that Microsoft has to offer.  What is Power BI, how does it fit into a corporate BI environment with SQL Server and why do we want to use it? The Power BI products, Power Query, Power Pivot, Power View, Power Map, will also be shown in this demo-heavy session.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14959</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14959</id>
          <name>Henk Van der Valk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server PDW (APS) vs SQL Server, let's see the big differences</title>
      <description>In this session we will present a live comparison between the SMP and MPP versions of SQL Server, with a special attention to architecture, hadoop integration and Performance! The spirit of the session will be “Forget the slides… let’s just do live Demos!”</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13805</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13805</id>
          <name>Enrico van de Laar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>No more waiting – an introduction to SQL Server wait statistics</title>
      <description>When you are standing in line at the grocery store you know exactly what you’re waiting for, paying the things you intend to buy. In SQL Server things aren’t usually so simple and many times you have to wait for more than only the length of the queue or the speed of the cashier. Thankfully SQL Server gathers the exact time you have been waiting and what resource you have been waiting on. In this session we will take a look at how SQL Server gathers this information and how it can help you identify, troubleshoot and proactively solve performance issues.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21097</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21097</id>
          <name>Denny Cherry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Storage For the DBA</title>
      <description>One of the biggest issues in database performance centers around storage.  It’s also one of the hardest places to troubleshoot performance issues because storage engineers and database administrators often do not speak the same language.  In this session, we’ll be looking at storage from both the database and storage perspectives.   We’ll be digging into LUNs, HBAs, the fabric, as well as RAID Groups.  In addition to theory, we’ll be looking at an actual EMC SAN so that we can translate what we see in the Storage Array with what we see on the actual server.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24744</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24744</id>
          <name>Stacia Varga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building a BI Solution in the Cloud </title>
      <description>Office 365 Power BI offers new and exciting features that are leading a lot of companies into the cloud. However, there are several additional considerations that you must factor into deciding how to architect your overall BI solution. 

In this session, you will learn about the available Microsoft Azure components and services that support a BI ecosystem. In addition, you learn how to properly configure your solution, whether it’s a completely cloud-based solution or a hybrid solution that includes on-premises data sources and on-premises client tools. You will gain an overview of Azure networking, and how it works in Azure VMs as well as for Office 365.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23357</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23357</id>
          <name>Robert Hartskeerl</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Get ready, here is the cloud</title>
      <description>A few years ago we told you to learn PowerShell. At this moment Windows Server 2012 R2 ships with a couple of thousand PowerShell commandlets. Now we tell you the cloud is coming and it's called Microsoft Azure. In this session I will tell you what the cloud exactly is and what it not is. How safe is your data? And why should you consider moving to the cloud? Once you get a better understanding of the concepts of Microsoft Azure and cloud platforms in general you might change opinions on the future of the cloud</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>12086</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12086</id>
          <name>n/a n/a</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Session Details not available</title>
      <description>Session Details not available</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15114</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15114</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advanced Indexing</title>
      <description>So you know all about heaps, clustered indexes, and nonclustered indexes, but are still not satisfied? Then this is just the session for you!
Hugo will explore advanced features such as included columns, indexed views, and filtered indexes. You will find out how they are stored on disk, and how SQL Server uses them to satisfy queries. Then, you will see the tools SQL Server itself hands you to help identify just the right subset of indexes. And finally, you will get an stunning demonstration of just how bad you can hurt performance by following all those recommendations and creating too many indexes.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18521</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18521</id>
          <name>Klaus Aschenbrenner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Troubleshooting TempDb</title>
      <description>For most DBAs and DEVs the TempDb is a crystal ball. But the TempDb is the most critical component in a SQL Server installation and is used by your applications and also internally by SQL Server. TempDb is also one of the performance bottlenecks by design, because it is shared across the whole SQL Server instance. In this session we will take a closer look into the TempDb, how it is used by SQL Server, and how you can troubleshoot performance problems inside TempDb and how you can resolve them.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24804</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24804</id>
          <name>Mladen Prajdić</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Digging Into the .Net SqlClient</title>
      <description>The prevailing opinion is that the optimizations for SQL Server are usually only done on the server itself. But is there anything we can do on the client to gain more speed? In this session aimed at .Net and SQL developers, we'll dive into the workings of the .Net SqlClient and give you insight into way more than just SqlCommand.ExecuteReader() and SqlCommand.ExecuteNonQuery().</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17782</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17782</id>
          <name>Justin Langford</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Get started with troubleshooting SQL Server </title>
      <description>This session present key tools, methodology and approach for troubleshooting SQL Server.  Performance and availability of the database engine has a direct impact on user experience of applications.  As such, rapidly identify and resolving issues is important for many organisations.  The session will cover common issues, troubleshooting techniques and solutions.</description>
      <startTime>10/4/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/4/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>