<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #1018 – Atlanta BI – Virtual 2020</name>
    <startDate>12/5/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatATLBI</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft</name>
      <street>8000 Avalon Boulevard, Suite 900</street>
      <city>Alpharetta</city>
      <state>Georgia</state>
      <zipcode>30009</zipcode>
      <longitude>-84.2741601</longitude>
      <latitude>34.0704325</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1781</importID>
      <name>Microsoft</name>
      <label>SQL Saturday Partner </label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1018/EventSponsor_14902.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2689</importID>
      <name>Red Hat</name>
      <label>SQL Saturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://www.redhat.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1018/EventSponsor_14903.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2678</importID>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
      <label>SQL Saturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://cloud.google.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1018/EventSponsor_14904.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2696</importID>
      <name>Melissa</name>
      <label>SQL Saturday Supporter</label>
      <url>http://www.melissa.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1018/EventSponsor_14905.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108472</importID>
      <name>David Patrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave has been developing database applications for over 25 years. An MCT since 2001, he has taught many classes from Intro to Visual Interdev to Advanced SharePoint Development. Dave runs two user groups, the Maryland and Pennsylvania Microsoft Developers User Group, www.mapamdug.com, and MAD SharePoint, www.madsharepoint.com. Dave does SharePoint training and development for DSA, Inc., a DoD contractor that does great work for the Army over at Aberdeen Proving Ground. Dave is also an MVP.</description>
      <twitter>DavidEPatrick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidepatrick</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.madsharepoint.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DavidEPatrick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108573</importID>
      <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mihail Mateev is a technical consultant, community enthusiast, PASS Regional Mentor for CEE, chapter lead, Microsoft Azure MVP, Microsoft Regional Director. He works as a Senior Solutions Architect at EPAM Systems, focused on Data Platform, IoT and cloud related solutions. He also worked many years like a Technical evangelist in the Infragistics. Last years Mihail was focused on various areas related to technology Microsoft: Data Platform, Visual Studio, ASP.Net, Windows client apps, Data Platform, and Microsoft Azure. Michael also has a PhD in cloud computing area. He is a university lecturer on Smart Homes and Smart Energy IoT Solutions.</description>
      <twitter>mihailmateev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mihail-mateev/1/6b3/4b1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mmateev.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mihailmateev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108498</importID>
      <name>Benni De Jagere</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Benni De Jagere is a Senior Data Insights Consultant at Realdolmen, with a strong focus on the Microsoft (BI) Stack. 

On a daily basis he turns (large amounts) of coffee into insights for customers, and references witty British comedy way too often. Overly enthusiastic about anything data related, he’s trying hard to keep up with all things new and shiny.

Rumour has it that he's also involved with a ragtag band of data enthusiasts, enjoying themselves whilst organising cool community things. They go by the name of .. dataMinds!</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BenniDeJagere</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bennidejagere/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://bennidejagere.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BenniDeJagere</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>109023</importID>
      <name>Paul Turley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul is a Principal Consultant for Pragmatic Works, a Mentor and Microsoft Data Platform MVP. He consults, writes, speaks, teaches  blogs about business intelligence and reporting solutions. He works with companies around the world to model data, visualize and deliver critical information to make informed business decisions; using the Microsoft data platform and business analytics tools. He is a Director of the Oregon Data Community PASS chapter  user group, the author  and lead author of Professional SQL Server 2016 Reporting Services and 14 other titles from Wrox  Microsoft Press.  He holds several certifications including MCSE for the Data Platform and BI.</description>
      <twitter>paul_turley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pturley</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserverbiblog.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=paul_turley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108557</importID>
      <name>Edward Pollack</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ed Pollack has over 20 years of experience in database and systems administration, which has developed his passion for performance optimization, database design, and making things go faster. He has spoken at many SQLSaturdays, 24 Hours of PASS, and PASS Summit. This led him to organize SQLSaturday Albany, which has become an annual event for New York’s Capital Region. Sharing these experiences with the community is a top priority, and encouraging everyone to take the leap into public speaking and engaging others, a passion.
In his free time, Ed enjoys video games, traveling, cooking exceptionally spicy foods, and hanging out with his amazing wife and sons.</description>
      <twitter>EdwardPollack</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=81593638</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlshack.com/author/edward-pollack/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=EdwardPollack</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108900</importID>
      <name>Pedro Reis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pedro is a Microsoft BI Stack Professional and enthusiast, with a passion for Power BI, SSAS, Excel and DAX. During his career he has coordinated multiple teams, and the development of thousands of Power BI Reports.
He is the Leader of the Power BI Portugal Meetup group and the Porto Power BI User Group and an active Speaker at events like Power Platform World Tour, SQL Saturday, Porto Data, and meetups.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedrogoncalvesreis/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.meetup.com/Power-BI-Portugal</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108992</importID>
      <name>Melissa Coates</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Melissa Coates is a data architect with a background in data warehousing and business intelligence. Her current professional focus is enterprise-level Power BI governance, deployment, security, and administration. As the owner of Coates Data Strategies, Melissa produces training and consults to help companies strengthen and sustain their data-driven initiatives. Melissa is big supporter of the technical community, and has been a Microsoft Data Platform MVP since 2013. You can visit Melissa's website at CoatesDataStrategies.com, which includes community resources like diagrams, blogs, and videos.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLChick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/melissacoatesprofile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.CoatesDataStrategies/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLChick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108569</importID>
      <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wolfgang Strasser creates solutions based on the Microsoft Data Platform tools in his day-to-day job as Business Intelligence consultant. Either using SQL Server Database Engine, SSIS, reporting with SSAS and SSRS, implementing Power BI solutions or cloud tools for data analysis - the data-tools-landscape is broadening every day! Based on his professional careers as a software developer he likes to work on structured development processes.
Wolfgang shares his knowledge with the community at many national and international events. For his community work, Wolfgang has been awarded with the Microsoft MVP Award for Data Platform in October 2015</description>
      <twitter>wstrasser</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/wolfgang-strasser/7b/912/22b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://workingondata.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=wstrasser</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108927</importID>
      <name>John Miner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Miner is currently a Data Architect at Insight DI (BlueMetal) advising corporations on how to solve their business needs with data platform solutions.

He has over twenty five years of data processing experience, and his architecture expertise encompasses all phases of the software project life cycle, including design, development, implementation, and maintenance of systems.

He has an undergraduate and graduate degrees in Computer Science from the University of Rhode Island.  Other credentials include an up to date MCSE certificate and currently taking the Data Science program from EDX.

Before joining BlueMetal, John won the Data Platform MVP award in 2014 and 2015 for his outstanding contributions to the SQL Server community.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/JohnMiner3</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/minerjohn/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mssqltips.com/sqlserverauthor/154/john-miner/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/JohnMiner3</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108504</importID>
      <name>Nikola Ilic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I'm making music from the data! 

PowerBI and SQLServer addict, MCT, Pluralsight Author, blogger, speaker...Interested in everything related to data - always eager to extract valuable info from raw data in the most effective way. Multi-year experience working with (predominantly) Microsoft Data Platform (SQL Server, SSAS, SSIS, SSRS, and Power BI). Father of 2 and true football (and Barca) fan!</description>
      <twitter>DataMozart</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikola-ilic-data-mozart</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://data-mozart.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataMozart</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108603</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>109026</importID>
      <name>Chris Hyde</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Hyde is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and Microsoft Certified Trainer based in Albuquerque, New Mexico. He works as an independent SQL Server BI and DBA consultant, and is the leader of the Albuquerque PASS local user group. He is also part of the Friends of Redgate program and was a member of the Idera ACE class of 2018. He loves loud music and cricket, but usually not at the same time.</description>
      <twitter>ChrisHyde325</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/chris-hyde-3803706</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ChrisHyde325</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108513</importID>
      <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Over 30 years in the computing field as a developer and system integrator; over 20 years working with SQL Server since version 6; cross platform experience with Oracle and IBM SQL/DS and DB2; Microsoft Certified Trainer for over 20 years.</description>
      <twitter>arlacerda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armando-lacerda</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arlacerda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108727</importID>
      <name>Kevin Wilkie</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin has 15+ years experience with SQL Server and has worked with the product since version 6.5, although he remembers with distaste the early versions of the product. He started working with SQL Server as an "Accidental" DBA, and has moved up through the ranks as a SQL Developer, a BI Associate, and Production DBA at various parts of his career. Currently, he works as a Lead Data Analyst spreading the gospel of how great data can be to anyone and everyone who will listen.</description>
      <twitter>Oskaruth</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevinwilkie</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sherpaofdata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Oskaruth</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108869</importID>
      <name>Dennes Torres</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dennes Torres is a Data Platform MVP with more than 25 years of experience in the IT area. He improves Data Platform Architectures and turns data into knowledge. As a Brazilian living in Malta, Dennes works as a software developer and leads the Malta MDP User Group. Having the MCSE Data Platform, Business Intelligence, and Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) certifications, Dennes has been in love with database servers since he was  introduced to SQL Server 6.5, more years ago than he would like to admit.</description>
      <twitter>Dennes</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennestorres/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/dennes-torres/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Dennes</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108514</importID>
      <name>Thomas LeBlanc</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thomas LeBlanc (Microsoft Data Platform MVP) is a Data Warehouse Architect in Baton Rouge, and uses his 30+ years in IT to develop OLTP systems with normalized databases for high-performing T-SQL and dimensional data marts. Development is done in SSIS, SSAS, SSRS, Power BI, and Excel. As a PASS volunteer, he is past chair of Excel BI and Data Arch VCs and is active in the Baton Rouge Analytics and SQL Server User groups, as well as SQLSaturday in Baton Rouge.
You can find his blog at TheSmilingDBA.BlogSpot.com and website at Thomas-LeBlanc.com</description>
      <twitter>TheSmilingDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=29648544amp;trk=hb_tab_pro_top</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Thomas-LeBlanc.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TheSmilingDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108792</importID>
      <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warwick Rudd is a Data Platform MVP, Microsoft Certified Master, Founder and Principal Consultant at SQL Master Consulting. With 20+ years of experience beginning with the release of SQL Server 6.5, he has worked in both Australia and England from small start-ups to Multi-National Corporations. He hosts the PASS DBA Fundamentals Downunder Virtual Chapter, Organises the PASS SQL Saturday Brisbane event and has spoken at many SQL Server User Groups  SQL Saturday events globally. When not playing with the SQL stack, Warwick likes to get away to the cold and spend time snowboarding.</description>
      <twitter>warwick_Rudd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/pub/warwick-rudd/0/956/718</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmastersconsulting.com.au/Blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=warwick_Rudd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108488</importID>
      <name>James Serra</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>James Serra is a big data and data warehousing solution architect at Microsoft.  He is a thought leader in the use and application of Big Data and advanced analytics. Previously, James was an independent consultant working as a Data Warehouse/Business Intelligence architect and developer. He is a prior SQL Server MVP with over 35 years of IT experience. James is a popular blogger (JamesSerra.com) and speaker. He is the author of the book “Reporting with Microsoft SQL Server 2012”.</description>
      <twitter>www.twitter.com/JamesSerra</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/JamesSerra</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.JamesSerra.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=www.twitter.com/JamesSerra</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>109015</importID>
      <name>Marco Russo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marco is a Business Intelligence consultant and mentor. He wrote several books about Power BI, Analysis Service, and Power Pivot. He also regularly writes articles and white papers that are available on sqlbi.com. Marco is a Microsoft MVP and an SSAS Maestro, the highest level of certification on Microsoft Analysis Services.
Today, Marco focuses his time with SQLBI customers, traveling extensively to train and consult on DAX and data modeling for Power BI and Analysis Services. Marco also teaches public classes worldwide.
Marco is a regular speaker at international conferences like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and SQLBits. He also enjoys delivering evening sessions at local user groups during his trips.</description>
      <twitter>marcorus</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlbi</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlbi.com/blog/marco</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=marcorus</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108889</importID>
      <name>Michael McKinley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael McKinley is the founder of McKinley Consulting.  Michael has managed projects and workstreams in consulting for the last five years, in areas including data analytics, change management, operations excellence, and supply chain transformation.

Most recently, Mr. McKinley helped HCA build an enterprise-wide analytics model for their Human Resources Group, providing insights into how to retain and promote top talent.  He is currently engaged on his fourth project with HCA.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/Mike_L_McKinley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaellmckinley</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mckinley.consulting/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/Mike_L_McKinley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>109313</importID>
      <name>Eugene Meidinger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eugene Meidinger works as a BI consultant and full time Pluralsight author. He currently focuses on content on Power BI and related products. He also leads the Pittsburgh Power BI User Group. He is certified in querying and administering SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlgene</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlgene.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlgene</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>108488</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108488</id>
          <name>James Serra</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Three</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Synapse Analytics: A Data Lakehouse</title>
      <description>Azure Synapse Analytics is Azure SQL Data Warehouse evolved: a limitless analytics service that brings together enterprise data warehousing and Big Data analytics into a single service. It gives you the freedom to query data on your terms, using either serverless on-demand or provisioned resources, at scale. Azure Synapse brings these two worlds together with a unified experience to ingest, prepare, manage, and serve data for immediate business intelligence and machine learning needs.  In this presentation, I'll talk about the new products and features that make up Azure Synapse Analytics and how it fits in a modern data warehouse, as well as provide demonstrations.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 1:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 2:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108498</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108498</id>
          <name>Benni De Jagere</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Two</name>
      </location>
      <title>Designing impactful visualisations for your data</title>
      <description>As Data is key, visualising said data is even more important. We want our message to be understood with ease, and merely with a couple of glances. Hence making sure the receiving party can do so with ease will be vital to our success.

During this session, we'll go through some steps on how to maximise the potential of data visualisations. Starting at choosing the right types of visualisations, and which colour palettes are good matches for your message, we'll also make sure that our designs are as inclusive as we can possibly make them. Wrapping up with a few common use cases, you’ll definitely pick up a few new things to take home with you.

Walking out of this session, you can expect to have a decent understanding on a few common design principles for your data visualisations and reports.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 9:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 10:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108557</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108557</id>
          <name>Edward Pollack</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Two</name>
      </location>
      <title>Improving Analytics Performance With Columnstore Indexes</title>
      <description>Administrators and analysts often struggle with the storage and maintenance of reporting and analytics data.  Traditional rowstore tables do not scale well when data is measured in billions of rows.

Columnstore indexes provide a speedy and convenient way to store OLAP data within SQL Server.  Compression allows the data to be much smaller than other storage methods, allowing for faster reads.  Column metadata provides the tools needed for SQL Server to be able to service queries over massive data sets quickly and efficiently.

The basics of columnstore indexes allow an administrator to improve the performance of analytics, but there is much more to learn!  Understanding the internals of columnstore indexes allows querying to be even more efficient.

Columnstore indexes have evolved greatly since their introduction in SQL Server 2012.  This presentation explores this feature in SQL Server 2017 and SQL Server 2019 and how its newest features can turbo-charge your analytics workloads!</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108603</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108603</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Two</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting Started with Apache Spark</title>
      <description>As companies work to gain insight from ever-increasing amounts of data, data platform practitioners need tools which can scale along with the data. Early big data solutions in the Hadoop ecosystem assumed that data sizes overwhelmed available memory, emphasizing heavy disk usage to coordinate work between nodes. As the cost of memory decreases and the amount of memory available per server increases, we see a shift in the makeup of big data systems, emphasizing heavy memory usage instead of disk. Apache Spark, which focuses on memory-intensive operations, has taken advantage of this hardware shift to become the dominant solution for problems requiring distributed data. In this talk, we will take an introductory look at Apache Spark. We will review where it fits in the Hadoop ecosystem, cover how to get started and some of the basic functional programming concepts needed to understand Spark, and see examples of how we can use Spark to solve issues when analyzing large data sets.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 2:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 3:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>109026</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>109026</id>
          <name>Chris Hyde</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Two</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Engineering Brick-by-Brick: An Introduction To Azure Databricks</title>
      <description>Do you want to be a Data Engineer in the next step on your career path?  Maybe you're just getting started in the rapidly-growing Data Science and Analytics space?  Or perhaps you're already doing on-premises analytics and want to take things to the cloud?  Then come to this introductory session and see what Azure Databricks can do for you!

Azure Databricks provides a cloud-based Apache Spark environment that can be scaled up and out to tackle your big data analytics needs.  We'll look at how to set up your first Azure Databricks cluster, how to use shared notebooks in a collaborative environment, and how to leverage the integrated Azure Machine Learning capabilities.  We'll also discuss where Azure Databricks fits in the modern cloud data warehouse.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 1:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 2:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108472</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108472</id>
          <name>David Patrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Three</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to CDS inside of Power Automate (fka Microsoft Flow)</title>
      <description>The Microsoft Common Data Service lets you securely store and manage data that's used by business applications. Data within Common Data Service is stored within a set of entities. An entity is a set of records used to store data, similar to how a table stores data within a database.

Learn how the CDS ties into Power Automate (Flow), what Triggers and actions are available and how you can use this all.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108573</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108573</id>
          <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track One</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deep Dive on Embedded Analytics with Power BI</title>
      <description>Microsoft Power BI Embedded is a Microsoft Azure that enables developers to integrate Power BI reports into their web or mobile applications so they do not need to build custom solutions to visualize data for the users. 
Microsoft Power BI Embedded helps Independent Software Vendors to use Power BI data experiences within their applications. Customers, who use applications with Power BI Embedded, do not need to have a Power BI account or to know anything about this Azure service. 
This session covers the major concepts, related to Power BI Embedded Analytics: 
-	Use-cases
-	Architecture
-	Licensing
-	Application development
-	Application deployment</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108569</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108569</id>
          <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Two</name>
      </location>
      <title>Continuous Integration for the BI Developer</title>
      <description>In many cases and BI projects, the manual process of development and especially deployment of artefacts led to sleepless nights, emergency hotfixes, grey hair and many hours of stress.
Especially in BI development, the usage of database projects, unit testing, version control, continuous integration and deployment is an underrepresented area.
Join me in this demo-heavy session where I will guide you through the not-so-frightful jungle of continuous integration using SQL Server database projects, SSIS, T-SQLt and Azure DevOps etc.
After this 60 minutes you'll have the guidelines and some ideas how easy it is to change your manual BI development and deployment into a powerful and automated no-brainer that - just works!</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108514</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108514</id>
          <name>Thomas LeBlanc</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track One</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tabular Analysis Services 2019 from Start to Finish</title>
      <description>This is a start to finish session on developing an enterprise analytical database with Analysis Services 2017 (SSAS) Tabular Model. The session will provide an introduction to Analysis Services and why it should be used. The rest of the time will be spent in live demonstrations building an analytical database.  The session will start with a blank project and show the steps for data sources and data sets. The data modeling will include relationships and hierarchies. The DAX language will be used to create measures including a Key Performance Indicator. The more advanced examples will include a many to many relationship as well as a slowly changing dimension table. The reporting will be throughout the session using Excel PivotTables/Chart as well as Power BI.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 9:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 10:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108889</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108889</id>
          <name>Michael McKinley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track One</name>
      </location>
      <title>Basic Data Modeling for BI Reporting</title>
      <description>We all start using business intelligence tools by using a single dataset, like a flat file.  Then, we hit a plateau in our learning curve, or we add a second flat file into our BI product, and we get incorrect results.  One reason is that we haven't modeled our solution correctly.

In order to move to the next level of our journey along the BI learning curve, we need to understand how a tool like Power BI works.  Only then will we understand why we design our data models the way we do.

In this session, we will review how tools like Power BI work under the covers and how that impacts the way we construct our data models.  This is an introductory level course, so we will not get too technical, just enough to get us to the next level and moving back up that learning curve!</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>109015</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>109015</id>
          <name>Marco Russo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Three</name>
      </location>
      <title>Different Types of Many-to-Many Relationships in Power BI</title>
      <description>The new composite models in Power BI introduced a new type of relationship cardinality, called many-to-many. Nevertheless, despite their name, they are not many-to-many relationships, they are relationships between tables generated at a different granularity.

In this session, we clarify the purpose of the relationships with many-to-many cardinality, highlighting the significant difference with canonical many-to-many relationships. In the meantime, we show how and when to use the different kinds of many-to-many relationships with several practical examples.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108727</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108727</id>
          <name>Kevin Wilkie</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track One</name>
      </location>
      <title>Checking in on Tabular Models: Making Them Work Better</title>
      <description>We've all seen, and probably created, a few tabular models that are just plain slow. For the people just starting with tabular models to those who've been around the block a few times with them, we'll go over some ways in which I've sped up tabular models to be leaner and faster. So join me and learn (or remember) several different things to do with tabular models to make them better for everyone.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 10:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 11:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108927</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108927</id>
          <name>John Miner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track One</name>
      </location>
      <title>Exploring the Power BI Desktop Designer</title>
      <description>Learn why Microsoft Power BI is taking market share in the enterprise reporting tools area.

The desktop designer is an easy to use application that can mash up data from various sources and create visual reports that will dazzle your users.

Under the hood, the M-Language mashes up data from various sources into a relational data model; the x-velocity engine stores the data in an efficient column store format; and the DAX language can extend the model when necessary.

In short, the Power BI Desktop designer is a one stop place to turn mundane data into dynamic reports.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 2:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 3:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>109023</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>109023</id>
          <name>Paul Turley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track One</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Modeling Solutions for Challenging BI Data Modeling Problems</title>
      <description>Sorry to break the news but the world is not flat and neither is business data. Data modeling is an essential skill in Power BI design and hard problems require creative solutions. In this session, we will enumerate common challenges and demonstrate modeling techniques to resolve them. Session topics: implementing star and snowflake schema essentials, role-playing tables, many-to-many and bi-directional filters, working without relationships, disconnected lookup tables and calculation groups. We will also discuss the composite models and the future of BI data modeling.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 1:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 2:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108900</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108900</id>
          <name>Pedro Reis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track One</name>
      </location>
      <title>"DAX" the way to do it</title>
      <description>Love it or hate it, you just can't ignore DAX, the amazing language of Power BI. In this session, I'll show you it's true power and how knowing it can even make you completely rethink your data models.
No more hundreds of columns and weird aggregations in the database. With the Power of DAX, you can now achieve much more sophisticated and powerful calculations, while keeping it simple at its core.
I'll show you real-world applications of DAX and lots of tips and tricks that you will be able to use quickly and with little effort!</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108792</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108792</id>
          <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Three</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Studio - Above and Beyond</title>
      <description>The data platform environment is exploding so quickly and as a data platform professional how can you be productive and able to support your environments easily? 
In this session Warwick will introduce you to Azure Data Studio and take you on a demo rich journey on how, when, where and why Azure Data Studio can make your life easier in supporting your ever expanding data estate.
If you have not heard of or seen Azure Data Studio before, Warwick will introduce the tool, it’s history and introduce you to its continual enhancements to assist you.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108992</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108992</id>
          <name>Melissa Coates</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Three</name>
      </location>
      <title>Top Essential Actions for Governing Power BI</title>
      <description>In this session we will discuss the high-level goals for a well-governed Power BI environment, and why governance improves user experience when it's approached with user empowerment in mind. Practical and actionable suggestions for improving your Power BI implementation will be shared which you can use right away.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 2:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 3:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108513</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108513</id>
          <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Two</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Aggs</title>
      <description>Power BI was originally released as a fully cloud based, end user targeted data visualization tool. Now it is a powerful, scalable enterprise level BI ecosystem. Microsoft has increased its ability to deal with large volume of data both imported into it and hosted outside the service to implement semantic models.
In this session I will demo how to design and implement agg's and take advantage of this powerful feature that will allow you to report on virtually unlimited amount of data.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>109313</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>109313</id>
          <name>Eugene Meidinger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Two</name>
      </location>
      <title>An (Advanced) Introduction to DAX</title>
      <description>Coming from the Excel world, DAX can look like Excel formulas on steroids. However, to be successful with DAX and Powerpivot, you'll need a completely different mental model. In this introduction to DAX, we won't spend too much time on the basics. Instead, we'll focus the concepts that make DAX unique. This will help you avoid the stumbling blocks of working with DAX. We will cover calculated columns, measures, aggregations, filtering, and iterators.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 10:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 11:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108504</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108504</id>
          <name>Nikola Ilic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Three</name>
      </location>
      <title>Magnificent 7 - Simple tricks to boost your Power BI development</title>
      <description>Simple tricks are almost always the most efective.  Impress your users with some cool visualizations, using these 7 neat techniques: from taking buttons to the next level, through creating animated tooltips or using basic DAX calculations to enhance regular Power BI experience, this session full of demos will walk you through solutions to different use-case scenarios which can be applied in your day-to-day Power BI development.</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 9:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 10:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108869</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108869</id>
          <name>Dennes Torres</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track Three</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advanced ETL with Power Query</title>
      <description>The M language provides to Power Query a very powerful way to develop ETL, way beyond the basic features you know.

We can create functions, re-use funcitons, create loops, everything to turn our data transformations easier. During this session you will see many advanced techniques using M and Power Query</description>
      <startTime>12/5/2020 10:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>12/5/2020 11:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>