<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #712 - South Island NZ 2018</name>
    <startDate>5/26/2018 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>150</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+12:00) Fiji, Kamchatka, Marshall Is</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat712</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Ara Institute of Canterbury</name>
      <street>130 Madras Street</street>
      <city>Christchurch</city>
      <state>Canterbury, New Zealand</state>
      <zipcode>8011</zipcode>
      <longitude>172.64289</longitude>
      <latitude>-43.53824</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1103</importID>
      <name>SQL Masters Consulting</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlmastersconsulting.com.au</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/986/EventSponsor_14638.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1873</importID>
      <name>Ara IT</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.ara.ac.nz/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.ara.ac.nz/__data/assets/image/0018/406521/Ara-Landscape-Logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1551</importID>
      <name>RADACAD</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://radacad.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/982/EventSponsor_14808.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/908/EventSponsor_14257.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2179</importID>
      <name>Data Engineers</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dataengineers.co.nz</url>
      <imageURL>https://dataengineersmovetest.blob.core.windows.net/testowner/400dpiLogo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2002</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software</name>
      <label>Swag Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.red-gate.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/991/EventSponsor_14803.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>77366</importID>
      <name>Anupama Natarajan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Anu Natarajan is a Data and AI Consultant with 15+ years of experience working in design and development of Data Warehouse, Business Intelligence, AI enabled applications, and SaaS integrated solutions. Anu is a Microsoft MVP Data Platform, Microsoft Certified Trainer and passionate in sharing knowledge. She loves solving complex business problems with innovative solutions using technologies. 
Anu also speaks at conferences including PASS Summit, SQL Saturdays, Data Platform Summit, Difinity, and she organizes local user group meetups.</description>
      <twitter>@shantha05</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/in/anupama-natarajan-516a107</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.anupamanatarajan.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@shantha05</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70334</importID>
      <name>Phillip Seamark</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>An accomplished database and business intelligence (BI) professional with an in-depth knowledge of the Microsoft BI stack along with extensive knowledge of data warehouse (DW) methodologies and enterprise data modelling.

Expert knowledge in all facets of BI/DW including planning architecture, project management, dimensional modelling, performance tuning, ETL design, development and optimization, report and dashboard design as well as installation and administration.
Author of multiple books on DAX.

Over 27 years of commercial experience in delivering business applications across a broad range of technologies.</description>
      <twitter>PhilSeamark</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/seamark</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=PhilSeamark</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>78533</importID>
      <name>Reza Rad</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reza Rad is a Microsoft Regional Director, MVP, author, trainer, speaker and consultant. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for nine years from 2011.
Reza wrote many books on Power BI subjects including the Power BI from Rookie to Rock Star, and Pro Power BI Architecture.
Reza is the invited speaker at the world's well-known conferences such as Microsoft Ignite, Microsoft Business Applications Summit, Ignite Tour, PASS Summit, and many other conferences.
Reza is an active blogger and writes regularly about Power BI at https://radacad.com.</description>
      <twitter>Rad_Reza</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/in/rezarad/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://radacad.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rad_Reza</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>75787</importID>
      <name>Craig Bryden</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Craig has been working with SQL Server for over 20 years and currently holds several SQL Server based certifications. He has also previously held an MCT certification. Craig's contribution to the SQL Server community was recognised in 2018 with a Microsoft MVP award. He was involved with Microsoft Learning to set some of the current SQL server Exams. Craig is the Chief Data Strategist at BiTQ. Craig is an organiser of the QLD Power BI User Group</description>
      <twitter>@cbryden</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/craigbryden/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cbryden</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>81997</importID>
      <name>Hamish Watson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hamish Watson is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware Expert with a passion for efficient database and application deployment using DevOps methodologies. 

He has 20+ years of IT experience in managing and deploying large scale databases on SQL Server technologies. 

He has been managing SQL Server since SQL Server 2000, and pragmatic approaches to delivering business value to clients is his career passion.

Educating and helping others learn is a driver for Hamish. He is a Director-At-Large on the PASS Board, international speaker, and a repeat guest lecturer at a local university.</description>
      <twitter>theHybridDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/in/hamishwatson8</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/the-hybrid-dbas-blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=theHybridDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>77446</importID>
      <name>Vanessa Larsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>For over 6 years Vanessa has consulted on a wide range of solutions for clients in both Australia and New Zealand utilizing the features in SharePoint and Office 365. Vanessa specialises in maneuvering SharePoint and Office 365 to the business goals of her clients and is passionate about achieving a more productive digital workplace.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/vanessalarsen/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70391</importID>
      <name>Manohar Punna</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Manohar Punna is an Data Platform Geek and Vice President of DataPlatformGeeks by passion and a Data Platform Consultant by profession. He is a speaker at various conferences like PASS Summit, SQLBits, DPS. He has authored over 150 blogs and has written a One DMV a Day series which is a longest one day series on any topic on SQL Server till date.
Manohar is a product of this community and strongly believes in giving back to the community. So, ask him anything you would like to know and he is happy to learn it with you.</description>
      <twitter>ManuSQLGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/manohar-punna/15/153/508</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservergeeks.com/author/manoharpunna/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ManuSQLGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>77101</importID>
      <name>Martin Catherall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin is a data consultant in Melbourne, Australia, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, and PASS Regional Mentor for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region.
Martin founded the Christchurch, New Zealand PASS Local Group and lead the group for a number of years before relocating to Melbourne.
He has been using SQL Server in various roles since 2000. In addition to anything data related, he enjoys playing the guitar and having fun with his family.</description>
      <twitter>MartyCatherall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/martincatherall</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://martincatherall.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MartyCatherall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>78712</importID>
      <name>Leila Etaati</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leila Etaati is the First Microsoft AI MVP in New Zealand and Australia, as well as a Data Platform MVP. She has a Ph.D. from the University of Auckland and is the co-director and data scientist in RADACAD company with many clients around the world. Additionally, she is the co-organizer of Microsoft Business Intelligence and Power BI Use group in Auckland with more than 1300 members. Leila has also co-organized 3 main conferences in Auckland: SQL Saturday Auckland (from 2015), Difinity (from 2017) and Global AI Bootcamp. She is a data scientist, BI consultant, trainer, and speaker. She is a well-known International speaker to many conferences such as MS Ignite, SQL PASS, Data Platform Summit, SQL Saturday, Power BI World Tour and in Europe, USA, Asia, Australia, and NZ. She has over 10 years’ experience with databases and software systems. Leila is an active Technical Microsoft AI blogger in RADACAD.</description>
      <twitter>@leila_etaati</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/pub/leila-etaati/36/46/b03</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.radacad.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@leila_etaati</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>80494</importID>
      <name>Simon Peck</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Simon is a MCSE in data analytics, certified Biml Expert (BimlHero) and co-author of "The Biml Book" he has been working with SQL Server since the 90's.  Simon is a director of Data Engineers a Christchurch based data solutions provider specialising in Microsoft based cloud and on-premise BI and Data Warehousing solutions.  Having worked for 50+ organisations worldwide over last 20 years he has a wealth of experience across many business sectors,  he is also a co-leader of the Christchurch SQL User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@BIGUYNZ</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/monchopper</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BIGUYNZ</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71626</importID>
      <name>Dave Dustin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With more than 35 years industry experience, Dave has worked with organisations and data systems of all sizes. He is currently Principal Engineer at Xero.</description>
      <twitter>venzann</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=venzann</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>78720</importID>
      <name>Sudeep Ghatak</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working in the SharePoint, Office 365 and Azure space for close to 10 years now. Have spoken at some well known conferences including Digital Workplace Conference. I run the Christchurch Azure meetup.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sudeepghatak/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>80111</importID>
      <name>Amit R S Bansal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Amit R. S. Bansal is a SQL Server Specialist at SQLMaestros. He leads the SQL Server practice with a focused team providing consulting, training, and content development services to more than 160+ SQL customers globally. He frequently speaks at international conferences on SQL Server performance tuning, which is his core expertise. Amit is also honored with Microsoft Regional Director status, MVP award, and Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server credential. Amit has been working with SQL Server since 1999 and has been part of countless mission-critical SQL deployments. Performance Tuning in SQL Server is his core area of expertise. To learn more about Amit, visit http://sqlmaestros.com/amit-bansal.</description>
      <twitter>A_Bansal</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/AmitBansal2010</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=A_Bansal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>80613</importID>
      <name>Indira Bandari</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Indira is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP in New Zealand.  She has a Masters degree in Statistics and is passionate about data, analytics and Artificial Intelligence. She is a BI and SQL Lead, an international speaker, mentor and part time trainer with over 15 years of experience in designing and developing data warehouses and analytical solutions.  
Volunteering and sharing her knowledge is her passion. In her pass time, she runs free game development classes, database concepts and data visualization classes for 9-16 year old kids.
She is a Co-organiser for Data, Insights and Power BI User Group , Auckland AI Meetup Group and SQL Saturday Auckland. She speaks at various conferences, Virtual Webinars, PASS events etc</description>
      <twitter>indirabandari</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/indira-bandari/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mytechlearning.blogspot.co.nz/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=indirabandari</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>78623</importID>
      <name>Ginger Grant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ginger Grant manages the consultancy Desert Isle Group and shares what she has learned while working with data technology to people around the world.  As a Microsoft MVP in Data Platform, Microsoft Certified Trainer and an instructor on DataCamp, she focuses on guiding clients to create solutions using the entire Microsoft Data Stack, which includes SQL Server, Power BI, and Azure Data Cloud components. When not working, she protypes the latest pre-release data technologies, maintains her blog http://www.desertislesql.com, and spends time on twitter @desertislesql.</description>
      <twitter>desertislesql</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ginger-grant-3a177b157/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.DesertIsleSQL.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=desertislesql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>78176</importID>
      <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warwick Rudd is a Data Platform MVP, Microsoft Certified Master, Founder and Principal Consultant at SQL Master Consulting. With 20+ years of experience beginning with the release of SQL Server 6.5, he has worked in both Australia and England from small start-ups to Multi-National Corporations. He hosts the PASS DBA Fundamentals Downunder Virtual Chapter, Organises the PASS SQL Saturday Brisbane event and has spoken at many SQL Server User Groups  SQL Saturday events globally. When not playing with the SQL stack, Warwick likes to get away to the cold and spend time snowboarding.</description>
      <twitter>warwick_Rudd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/pub/warwick-rudd/0/956/718</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmastersconsulting.com.au/Blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=warwick_Rudd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>78534</importID>
      <name>Reza Rad</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reza Rad is a Microsoft Regional Director, MVP, author, trainer, speaker and consultant. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for nine years from 2011.
Reza wrote many books on Power BI subjects including the Power BI from Rookie to Rock Star, and Pro Power BI Architecture.
Reza is the invited speaker at the world's well-known conferences such as Microsoft Ignite, Microsoft Business Applications Summit, Ignite Tour, PASS Summit, and many other conferences.
Reza is an active blogger and writes regularly about Power BI at https://radacad.com.</description>
      <twitter>Rad_Reza</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/in/rezarad/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://radacad.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rad_Reza</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82955</importID>
      <name>Steve Knutson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve is a Microsoft MVP for Office Servers and Services based in Christchurch, New Zealand.

Steve brings more than 25 years of IT industry experience to clients’ projects. Past roles have included solutions architecture, systems engineering, business continuity, software development and IT planning and strategy in the local government, finance, legal, state owned enterprise, and education sectors.

Steve has a Computer Science degree from Massey University and is a Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer and Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist for SQL Server.

Steve is the Managing Director of Stratos Technology Partners and leads consulting work around SharePoint and Office 365.</description>
      <twitter>@nztechtweet</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/steveknutsonnz</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://onehundredwatt.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@nztechtweet</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82020</importID>
      <name>Heidi Hasting</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Heidi Hasting is a Business Intelligence professional and former software developer with over seven years experience in Microsoft products. She is an ALM/DLM enthusiast and Azure DevOps fan and co-founder and organiser of the Adelaide Power BI User Group. Heidi is a regular attendee at tech events including Azure Bootcamps, DevOps days, SQLSaturdays, Difinity and PASS Summit.</description>
      <twitter>heidihasting</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://au.linkedin.com/in/heidi-hasting-a068694</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=heidihasting</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72429</importID>
      <name>Gogula Aryalingam</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gogula is a data analytics professional from Sri Lanka, with 14+ years on the Microsoft data platform. He has worked with many aspects of data analytics and BI solutions from architecting, designing, developing and consulting across various industries and verticals. He is Regional Mentor for PASS South Asia, Data Platform MVP, MCSE, former MCT, and MSc in IT. Gogula's passion revolves data analytics and BI; hence enjoys writing, teaching and speaking about the things he works with. He was also involved as an SME for Microsoft certification development. He currently juggles his full time job as Lead Architect while speaking at local and foreign events, along with regular stints at the Sri Lankan Data Community which he co-founded.</description>
      <twitter>http://www.twitter.com/gogula</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/gogula</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datamaul.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://www.twitter.com/gogula</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71107</importID>
      <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Flynn is a Senior Database Administrator with 10 years experience in large 24 x 7 enterprise environments. He is a certified master for SQL Server and a regular attendee of the PASS Summit.

Has presented at SQLSaturday events in Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane and Auckland, Edmonton and Calgary, Oslo and Cambridge</description>
      <twitter>sqllensman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqllensman.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllensman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70222</importID>
      <name>Martin Cairney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin has 20 years’ experience in SQL Server technologies. His experience spans both the Database Engine and infrastructure requirements, and Data Warehousing and BI implementations. 
He has worked across many industry sectors including London’s global financial institutions and both State and Federal Government Departments. 
He is a SQL Server MVP, MCT and an experienced conference presenter, having presented at PASS Summit, SQLBits, and SQL Saturday events and User Groups round the world</description>
      <twitter>martin_cairney</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/in/martincairney</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=martin_cairney</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>70391</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70391</id>
          <name>Manohar Punna</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Real-Time Analytics with Power BI</title>
      <description>Power BI helps you build appealing visualizations of your data. With ever growing footprint of data it is equally important to get real-time insights into your data. It can be as simple as monitoring a single metric or viewing real-time sales performance across multiple locations. Power BI real-time streaming enables you to stream data and update dashboards in real-time. Any time sensitive data can be a source of streaming data set like IoT sensor devices, social media sources, service usage metrics etc.

In this session 
1. I will dive deep into real-time analytics with Power BI.
2. How to build streaming tiles in Power BI Dashboards.
3. Demo using Power BI REST APIs.
4. Demo using Azure Event Hub and Azure Stream Analytics.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>72429</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>72429</id>
          <name>Gogula Aryalingam</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Lake Analytics: Leveraging the Modern Data Warehouse</title>
      <description>What you feared has come upon you: You’ve been happily building business intelligence solutions the traditional way for years; Finally, the big data curse has caught up with you. Your organization wants to exploit their big data along with their day-to-day transactional data. You are now tasked with storing all this in one place and working your analytics magic on it. You start wondering how and where you would store this data, what kind of hardware you would need and and how you would learn everything from storing to processing to analysis in a short time – after all big data is a different type of beast from transactional data.
Fear not, all you need to do is look to the heavens; with Azure Data Lake and Azure Data Lake Analytics, you could get started quite fast. After an introduction to Azure Data Lake, we will dive into how you could perform simple yet power analytics using methods that are familiar with Azure Data Lake Analytics.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>77101</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>77101</id>
          <name>Martin Catherall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Privacy and the Data Professional.</title>
      <description>It’s almost a daily occurrence to hear about some sort of data breach. 
But what are the consequences of a data breach – for both the victims and companies involved – and what does that mean for you as a data professional.
As governments start to legislate more in an effort to protect the privacy of its citizens the entire concept of data storage become more complex.
Exactly what is legislation like the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and how will it affect around the world.
We’re seen Microsoft give us tools over the years – like Transparent Data Encryption and Dynamic Data masking - to help with this sort of thing – but is there a better answer?
Come along to this session and hear how you and your team can lessen your chances of being the ones responsible for the next data breach.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>78712</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>78712</id>
          <name>Leila Etaati</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Create Custom Visual using JSON and R</title>
      <description>Power BI visualization is a holistic visualization tool. You can draw most of the popular charts with it. However, there is always some needs for specific charts that may not be available in Power BI standard visualizations of the marketplace. There is a possibility to extend the visualization capabilities using R language. There are two ways to use R to extend the visualization possibilities. The approach was introduced in 2015 as “R” custom visual that you can draw chart by writing R scripts. The editor for writing R was not that was good and also the end-user able to see the R code behind the chart. The second approach for using R to have more chart in Power BI has been introduced in  2017 that is about creating Custom visual file (pbiviz file) using R and JASON language. In this seminar, I am going to show how you can create any custom visual by writing R codes. You able to create a custom visual that has a specific icon, name, and parameters.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>78534</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>78534</id>
          <name>Reza Rad</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Take Power BI Visualization to the Next Level</title>
      <description>Data Visualization is the front end of every BI system, and getting it right is one of the most important tasks in a BI application. Good visualization will affect tremendously on decision making process, bad visualization leads to wrong decisions. In this session, you will learn how to choose the right chart of visual with examples of Line chart, bar/column charts, and some other main charts in Power BI. You will also learn some tips and tricks to control interactivity of visuals in Power BI. You will learn about specific features in Power BI that helps empowering your visualizations. Session is full of demos, and through that you will learn tips and tricks for choosing best colors and best visuals for your solution.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71107</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71107</id>
          <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>DBATools! The reason to finally start learning and using Powershell</title>
      <description>Powershell has been part of Windows for &gt; 10 years and has been part of SQL Server since 2008.
In spite of this the adoption among Database Professionals for use in investigating and managing their environments has been low.

With the release of the open source DBA Tools module from DBATools.IO, with its 300+ commands, the time has arrived for Database Professionals to embrace PowerShell and upgrade their skills to support the modern Hybrid environment.

In this session we will look how to download, install and begin using the power within both this module and Powershell.

No prior experience with Powershell required!</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>78176</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>78176</id>
          <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room4</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQLOpsStudio Vs SSMS - There can be only one</title>
      <description>SQLOpsStudio is the new kid in town for the data professional. Is it a replacement for good old SSMS? 
In this session we will take you on a journey of comparing SSMS and SQLOpsStudio so that you can understand the ins and outs of both these tools, making it easier to know what each brings to the table. In this demo heavy session we not only hear about the differences but we match them up against each other to better learn what each can do.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>80494</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>80494</id>
          <name>Simon Peck</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Orchestration and data movement with Azure Data Factory v2</title>
      <description>As more and more businesses are looking to leverage cloud services to move and store their data we’ll take a look at how we can achieve that with ADF v2 and other Azure storage services.
For the SSIS developer, we’ll translate some ADF terminology to help get you started as well as demonstrate some real-life examples from our customer engagements.
And of course, being automation experts with Biml, we’ll demonstrate how we can automate the creation of ADF v2 assets.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>77446</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>77446</id>
          <name>Vanessa Larsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deciphering the Black Box - Why productivity projects crash and burn</title>
      <description>Like a building a bridge that collapses within days of its grand opening (if it even gets finished at all), sometimes our digital projects don't go the way we expect. Productivity initiatives are particularly fickle as we try to change the way that people work. So how do we make sure we can successfully become a digital workplace without it all coming crashing down around our ears?

In this session, we will share our stories from our time in the field experiencing the twists and turns that productivity projects take; how to have success in your internal project; and if you choose to bring in external parties, how to make the most of them.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71626</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71626</id>
          <name>Dave Dustin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Back to Basics – An overview of the internals of SQL Server</title>
      <description>What actually happens when you execute a query.
This session drills down into how SQL Server and other relational database systems work behind the scenes.
We’ll look at the interpreter, optimizer, estimator, storage, memory, locking, blocking, indexes, statistics and everything else that makes it all work.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>78720</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>78720</id>
          <name>Sudeep Ghatak</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Cloning the human brain - Cognitive Services</title>
      <description>Microsoft Cognitive Services enables developers to augment the next generation of applications with the ability to see, hear, speak, understand, and interpret needs using natural methods of communication. Hear from Sudeep and Amit on how Azure cognitive services is transforming the way we approach to problems.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70334</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70334</id>
          <name>Phillip Seamark</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advanced DAX for the SQL Professional</title>
      <description>Are you a whizz at SQL and curious about learning more about DAX?  This session will be aimed to share some helpful tips and tricks for creating beautiful DAX when building Power BI reports or Tabular Cubes.   Most people who learn DAX come from an Excel background, but this session will be tailored to those used to set based approaches such as SQL.

We will create data from thin air and show how you can shape your data model using DAX.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>80111</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>80111</id>
          <name>Amit R S Bansal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Troubleshooting SQL Server Memory Issues</title>
      <description>Welcome to the dungeon. Yes, SQL Server memory concepts are like entering a dungeon where you are guaranteed to get lost. It’s dark and complex out there and not many have come back alive. This session will help you find your way out of the dungeon. In this deep-dive session you will understand SQL Server memory architecture, how the database engine consumes memory and how to track memory usage. Complex concepts will be made simple and you will see some light beyond the darkness. Finally, you will learn how to troubleshoot common memory issues.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>75787</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>75787</id>
          <name>Craig Bryden</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSRS and Power BI Report Server - What's New</title>
      <description>In SQL 2016, SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) underwent massive changes with the addition of many new reporting features. Since that release, there have been many further developments, including the release of Power BI Report Server and SSRS 2017. In this demo laden session, Craig will recap the changes that SSRS has undergone from SSRS 2016 onwards, as well as look at and discuss Power BI Report Server.This session will be valuable for anyone new to SSRS, or anyone who has not had an opportunity to work with the latest versions of SSRS.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>77366</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>77366</id>
          <name>Anupama Natarajan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Modern Data Warehouse using Lambda Architecture and Azure</title>
      <description>Organisations capture huge volumes of data and they need actionable information to act on them proactively in real-time to stay competitive. This requires a different thinking from the conventional Data Warehouse Architecture to more Cloud based Data Processing Architecture where high volume batch and real-time processing can be achieved using optimal cost.

In this session you will learn about

1. Overview of Lambda Architecture
2. How Azure Services implement Lambda Architecture
3. Advantages of leveraging Azure for Lambda Architecture
4. Business Scenarios to consider Lambda Architecture
5. End to End Demo</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>78623</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>78623</id>
          <name>Ginger Grant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Implementing Python in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>Advanced data analytics does not live only in the realm of data scientists. The necessary tools now exist in SQL Server 2017 using the language which is number one on the list of most popular programming languages today, Python.  This session will provide and introduction to Python, cover how to integrate the language into SQL Server, demonstrate how to use Python in stored procedures and review how you can determine the resources that Python is using within SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>80613</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>80613</id>
          <name>Indira Bandari</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Google Forms meet Power BI via Reporting Services (SSRS)</title>
      <description>Are you interested in getting to know what your customers are thinking about your services? Empower your business with this end to end solution of creating feedback survey, sending and receving the responses and then finally analysing the same.

In this session I will show you how to 
•	Initiate customer feedback surveys using Google Forms.
•	Send the survey emails to the database contacts through data driven subscriptions of Reporting 
        Services (SSRS)
•	And finally analyse the customer feedback using Power BI</description>
      <startTime>5/26/2018 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/26/2018 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>