<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #932 - Croatia Virtual 2020</name>
    <startDate>9/19/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Belgrade, Bratislava, Budapest, Ljubljana, Prague</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatCroatia</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Hotel International</name>
      <street>Miramarska 24</street>
      <city>Zagreb</city>
      <state>, Croatia</state>
      <zipcode>10000</zipcode>
      <longitude>15.9740919306885</longitude>
      <latitude>45.7992727749775</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14261.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2678</importID>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://cloud.google.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14828.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2689</importID>
      <name>Red Hat</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://www.redhat.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14829.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2369</importID>
      <name>MOBILNA INFORMATIKA D.O.O.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.repsly.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14286.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2594</importID>
      <name>Plus-IT doo</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://plus-it.hr</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14287.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2656</importID>
      <name>KING ICT</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.king-ict.hr/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14672.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2368</importID>
      <name>SPAN d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://span.eu/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14317.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2373</importID>
      <name>Data Sense d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.datasense.hr</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14348.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2607</importID>
      <name>Infobip d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.infobip.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14362.jfif</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2672</importID>
      <name>HR Prodigy</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://hrprodigy.hr/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14749.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2579</importID>
      <name>Praxis Info d.o.o.</name>
      <label>Custom Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.firmoteka.hr/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14222.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2325</importID>
      <name>RevDeBug</name>
      <label>Custom Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://revdebug.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/932/EventSponsor_14375.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105224</importID>
      <name>Torsten Strauss</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Torsten (MVP, MCSE, MCT) has been working with Microsoft SQL Server since the turn of the millennium and is specialized in performance optimization for large SQL Server environments. He has been with bp as a database engineer for over two decades and collaborates closely with Sarpedon Quality Lab as a Principal Microsoft SQL Server Consultant. Torsten is the founder of inside-sqlserver.com and has given more than 120 presentations on Microsoft SQL Server performance optimization at national and international conferences and user groups. Torsten has been recognized as a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional for Data Platform since 2018.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105763</importID>
      <name>Sebastiano Galazzo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Passionate about Artificial Intelligence, Sebastiano @galazzoseba brings over 15 years of experience in AI and machine learning to his current position as CTO at Sistem-EVO srl.
Sebastiano has dedicated the last few years to designing and developing algorithms to tackle the challenges of Natural Language Processing, image recognition and predictive analysis through machine learning.
He is a Microsoft MVP and his work in AI has gained commendation in numerous publications and has received several national and international awards.</description>
      <twitter>@galazzoseba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://it.linkedin.com/in/sebastianogalazzo</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@galazzoseba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99699</importID>
      <name>Rudi Bruchez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>(same as before)</description>
      <twitter>nepasderanger</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://fr.linkedin.com/in/rudibruchez</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.babaluga.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=nepasderanger</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98829</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denny Cherry is the owner and principal consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates Consulting and has over a decade of experience working with platforms such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Microsoft SQL Server, Hyper-V, vSphere, and Enterprise Storage solutions. Denny’s areas of technical expertise include system architecture, performance tuning, security, replication, and troubleshooting. Denny currently holds several Microsoft Certifications related to SQL Server 2000 through 2019, including being a Microsoft Certified Master, Microsoft MVP and VMware vExpert Award.</description>
      <twitter>mrdenny</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrdenny</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.dcac.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mrdenny</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101212</importID>
      <name>Tomaž Kaštrun</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tomaž Kaštrun is BI developer and data analyst. His main focus are data mining, T-SQL development, programming and query optimization. He has been working with SQL server since version 2000. He is Microsoft Certified Professional, Microsoft MVP for data platform and Microsoft trainer.</description>
      <twitter>@tomaz_tsql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/tomaz.kastrun</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tomaztsql.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tomaz_tsql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101601</importID>
      <name>Gianluca Sartori</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gianluca Sartori is a Data Platform MVP, independent consultant and performance tuning specialist. He has been working in the software industry since 1999 and has been working with SQL Server ever since. He also works as a SQL Server trainer and in his spare time he writes technical articles and participates the SQL Server forums. Gianluca enjoys presenting SQL Server topics at conferences in Europe and in Italy in particular. He is currently working as lead DBA at a famous Formula 1 team.</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/#!/spaghettidba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://it.linkedin.com/pub/gianluca-sartori/23/50b/a12</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://spaghettidba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/#!/spaghettidba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107566</importID>
      <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Miloš Radivojević is a database consultant located in Vienna, Austria. He is Data Platform MVP and specializes in SQL Server for application developers and performance and query tuning. Currently, he works as a principal database consultant in bwin GVC (the largest regulated online gaming company in the world). He is co-founder of the SQL Pass Austria and speaks regularly at local and international database conferences. He is also co-author of the books SQL Server 2016 Developer's Guide, SQL Server 2017 Developer's Guide and Mastering SQL Server 2017.</description>
      <twitter>MilosSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://at.linkedin.com/pub/milos-radivojevic/1b/7bb/290/de</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://milossql.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MilosSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99720</importID>
      <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mihail Mateev is a technical consultant, community enthusiast, PASS Regional Mentor for CEE, chapter lead, Microsoft Azure MVP, Microsoft Regional Director. He works as a Senior Solutions Architect at EPAM Systems, focused on Data Platform, IoT and cloud related solutions. He also worked many years like a Technical evangelist in the Infragistics. Last years Mihail was focused on various areas related to technology Microsoft: Data Platform, Visual Studio, ASP.Net, Windows client apps, Data Platform, and Microsoft Azure. Michael also has a PhD in cloud computing area. He is a university lecturer on Smart Homes and Smart Energy IoT Solutions.</description>
      <twitter>mihailmateev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mihail-mateev/1/6b3/4b1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mmateev.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mihailmateev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99196</importID>
      <name>Magnus Ahlkvist</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Independent database consultant and certified trainer with a passion for chasing that extra millisecond.
20 years of database development and administration but trying to be humble enough to understand that I'm still learning.</description>
      <twitter>Transmokopter</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://se.linkedin.com/in/magnusahlkvist</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tsql.nu</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Transmokopter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>102846</importID>
      <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Catalin Gheorghiu is a solution architect from Romania. He has more than 15 years of experience in developing solutions, especially on Microsoft technologies in very demanding environments. Is contributing articles and blogs to several user groups (MrSmersh), lecturing all over Romania and abroad, is also RONUA Timisoara (PASS Chapter) user group leader. Since 2011, every year he was awarded the Microsoft MVP Award.</description>
      <twitter>MrSmersh</twitter>
      <linkedin>?https://ro.linkedin.com/in/catalingheorghiu?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ronua.ro/author/catalin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MrSmersh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108145</importID>
      <name>Nikola Ilic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I'm making music from the data! 

PowerBI and SQLServer addict, MCT, Pluralsight Author, blogger, speaker...Interested in everything related to data - always eager to extract valuable info from raw data in the most effective way. Multi-year experience working with (predominantly) Microsoft Data Platform (SQL Server, SSAS, SSIS, SSRS, and Power BI). Father of 2 and true football (and Barca) fan!</description>
      <twitter>DataMozart</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikola-ilic-data-mozart</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://data-mozart.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataMozart</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98600</importID>
      <name>John Martin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Martin is a Data Platform Engineer working in the financial sector, as well as Vice President Marketing for the PASS organization and currently a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Previously John has worked as a product manager for SentryOne and a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft UK.

John has over a decade of experience working with SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. Working as a DBA, developer and consultant for Microsoft, he has been lucky enough to see how best, and how not, to use SQL Server and the Data Platform effectively.</description>
      <twitter>SQLDiplomat</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/johnqmartin/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mssqltips.com/sqlserverauthor/291/john-martin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLDiplomat</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101663</importID>
      <name>Nicky van Vroenhoven</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nicky van Vroenhoven is a BI professional focused at the Microsoft stack. He mainly works with Power BI, Power Platform and T-SQL. After working 9 years in BI-consultancy jobs in several industries and companies, he is currently working as a Lead BI Developer at the DWH team at Van Lanschot Kempen in The Netherlands. Nicky has spoken at several User Groups, SQL Saturday Events, and the Power BI World Tour and is the co-founder of the Power BI Days Netherlands. In addition he enjoys tweeting and blogging about topics like Power BI and Power Platform at https://nickyvv.com.</description>
      <twitter>https://www.twitter.com/nickyvv</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nickyvanvroenhoven/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.nickyvv.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://www.twitter.com/nickyvv</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>102492</importID>
      <name>Gergely Csom</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data and AI expert with 15+ years of experience in various data warehousing, BI and AI projects in FSI, OilGas, Energy and Transportation. Experienced trainer, mentor, regular public speaker in various events. Nowadays building the best in class data team for helping our customers in their digital transformation journey in the super exciting Data  AI driven revolution. Running cloud  IoT pet projects nowadays in his free time:)</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/CsomGergely</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gergely-csom-27171670/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/CsomGergely</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98966</importID>
      <name>Vedran Kesegic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vedran Kesegic is a Microsoft Certified Master for SQL Server, with Oracle background. With 14+ years enjoyed in exploration of SQL Server depths, developing smart algorithms, optimizing SQL Servers and SANs. He is the author of XDetails, Addin for SQL Management Studio that shows detailed info about indexes and other objects. He likes to hang out, share knowledge, and talk about more or less important things in life.</description>
      <twitter>@VedranKesegic</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://hr.linkedin.com/in/vedrankesegic</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.sqlxdetails.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@VedranKesegic</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104353</importID>
      <name>Aleksandar Talev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Aleksandar Talev is Chief Development Officer in Semos  - Microsoft Gold Partner. He is professionally oriented to development of IT projects based on Microsoft technologies, primary SQL Server, Microsoft Power BI and Microsoft Azure. He has been working with SQL Server 6.5 since 1996. As a Microsoft trainer he is holding a Microsoft Curriculum courses focused on SQL Server as well as Power BI. As one of the founders of SQL Server User Group (PASS) Macedonia his free time he is engaged in developing the SQL Server community in Macedonia. He is a regular speaker on Microsoft conferences as well as local and global community events. In 2005 Microsoft awarded him with SQL Server MVP award.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/aleksandar-talev-95159187</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://Www.sqlpass.org.mk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98766</importID>
      <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dejan Sarka, MCT and Data Platform MVP, is an independent trainer and consultant that focuses on development of database and business intelligence applications. Besides projects, he spends about half of his time on training and mentoring. He is the founder of the Slovenian SQL Server and .NET Users Group. Dejan Sarka is the main author or co-author of eighteen books about databases and SQL Server. Dejan Sarka has also developed many courses and seminars for Microsoft, Radacad, SolidQ, and Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>DejanSarka</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/dsarka/Home.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DejanSarka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>98600</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98600</id>
          <name>John Martin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance Tuning with SQLDiag, the best free tool you never knew you had.</title>
      <description>Have you ever had the need to tune the performance of a SQL Server workload and got fed up with trying to line up all the data capture you need to get a picture of what is going on? What if I said that you have had a tool all along that can do this?

SQLDiag installs with SQL Server and is capable of coordinating the capture of trace data, perfmon data, and log files for you. Sounds great, "how do I use it?" I hear you ask.

In this session we will look at how to setup and run a data capture against SQL Server. We will then look at how to process the captured data into a format that we can use to troubleshoot performance problems. I will also showcase a number of additional tools such as Diag Manager, PAL, and Relog to help make sense of the data captured.

By the end of this session you will be in a position to start using SQLDiag to perform data catpure and have the toolset to process it to solve performance problems with your SQL Server systems.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98766</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98766</id>
          <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Science in Power BI Desktop</title>
      <description>Two of the most popular modern topics are data science and Power BI. The nice thing is that you can easily combine both of them by including data science analyses in Power BI. You can do this in numerous ways. Many Power BI visualizations already include the Analytics tab with plethora of intermediate-level analytical functions available. For example, you can add a trend line and many other lines to the Scatter chart. You can use R and / or Python script sources. You can do the whole analysis in R or Python, and then visualize the results in Power BI. You can also use the good old SSAS Multidimensional Data Mining as the source. You can include Azure ML predictions in a Power BI model. With R and Python visuals, you can add the impressive visualizations from these two languages in a Power BI report and dashboard. You can also use R and Python in Power Query for advanced data manipulation. There are also many custom visuals that include data science analyses. This session introduces all</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>102492</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>102492</id>
          <name>Gergely Csom</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building a modern data warehouse and BI solution in Microsoft cloud</title>
      <description>Data warehouse and BI market is evolving rapidly with the appearance of new cloud born technologies. We might assume, that moving an existing Microsoft based DWH to the cloud is an easy step, but when we dig a little bit deeper, we will see, there are many-many new technological choices and aspects on how to modernize an existing dwh/bi system in the cloud. Not to mention if we start everything from scratch in a new project designed specifically to the cloud to utilize cloud flexibility and innovation as much as possible. 
Which ETL tool should I use? Data factory v2 with SSIS and BIML, or Azure Databricks powered Dataflows? Or Power BI Dataflow? Which is the right decision to run OLAP workloads? Azure AS? Or simply Power BI? When do I need Azure SQL DWH?
In the last couple years I helped many customers to modernize their DWH landscape partially or fully in the cloud and during my presentation I will share my findings and recipes for the most common situation I met. You will have fun:)</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104353</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104353</id>
          <name>Aleksandar Talev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Implementing security in Azure Data Platform Solutions</title>
      <description>As computing environments is moving customer-controlled on premises data centers to cloud data centers, the responsibility of security also shifts. Security is nowadays a concern shared by cloud providers, organizations and individuals. For every solution, it's important to understand what's solution provider responsibility and what's Azure's responsibility.

In this presentation, attendees will see how Azure provides a multi-layered security model to protect customer data. I will show how security can range from setting up secure networks and access keys, to defining permission and to monitoring with Advanced Threat Detection across a range of data stores.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107566</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107566</id>
          <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Transact-SQL Performance Tips</title>
      <description>U ovoj populističkoj sesiji razmatraćemo kako način na koji je napisan upit može da dovede do sporog izvršenja uprkos povoljnom izvršnom okruženju (postoje dobri indeksi, server je rasterećen, nema mnogo konkurentnih sesija...)  i onemogući SQL Server da ga izvrši koristeći optimalni execution plan. 

Pokrićemo tipične greške koje programeri tom prilikom prave zbog nedovoljnog poznavanja funkcionisanja database engina.

Razume se, podelićemo savete u vezi sa pisanjem upita koji će svakako pomoći da se izbegnu tipične i najčešće greške u svakodnevnom radu sa SQL Serverom, a i elaboriraćemo šta bi to svaki programer trebalo da zna o SQL Serveru.

Session level: 200 - 300</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108145</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108145</id>
          <name>Nikola Ilic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Magnificent 7 - Simple tricks to boost your Power BI development</title>
      <description>Simple tricks are almost always the most effective. Impress your users with some cool visualizations, using these 7 neat techniques: from taking buttons to the next level, through creating animated tooltips or using basic DAX calculations to enhance regular Power BI experience, this session full of demos will walk you through solutions to different use-case scenarios which can be applied in your day-to-day Power BI development.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99720</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99720</id>
          <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Creating Custom BI Solutions with Power BI Embedded</title>
      <description>Microsoft Power BI Embedded is a Microsoft Azure that enables developers to integrate Power BI reports into their web or mobile applications so they don’t need to build custom solutions to visualize data for the users. 
Microsoft Power BI Embedded helps Independent Software Vendors to use Power BI data experiences within their applications. Customers, who use applications with Power BI Embedded don’t need to have a Power BI account or to know anything about this Azure service. 
This talk is a practical session on Microsoft Power BI Embedded concept with many examples how to create custom BI solutions using this technology.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 8:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 9:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105763</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105763</id>
          <name>Sebastiano Galazzo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Creating a photorealistic avatar using generative adversarial net</title>
      <description>Having an overview on how getting started with Microsoft Azure Machine Learning Studio we will start understanding generative deep learning algorithms.
Focusing on autoencoders, will be journey from the biginning (Of the speaker experience), mistakes and tips learned along the path showcasing several convolution flows. 
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pJ7VmOOMy4kfeature=youtu.be</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101663</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101663</id>
          <name>Nicky van Vroenhoven</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Folding in Power BI</title>
      <description>Power Query allows you to extract and transform data from a variety of data sources. Have you ever experienced that the importing of data is slower than you expected? In most of those cases, query folding is not happening fully optimized.
Query folding is important because it offloads data transformations to the source, instead of performing them in Power BI.
Attend this session to learn how to ensure that you get all the performance improvements possible within your reports! As a bonus, you will also learn in which cases query folding is not your best friend.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98829</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98829</id>
          <name>Denny Cherry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Table Indexing for the .NET Developer</title>
      <description>In this session we will be looking at the best and worse practices for indexing tables within your SQL Server 2012+ databases.  We will also be looking into the new indexing features that are available in SQL Server 2012+ (and SQL Server 2005-2008) and how you the .NET developer can make the best use of them to get your code running its best.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 8:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 9:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99196</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99196</id>
          <name>Magnus Ahlkvist</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Statistics, an unreliable friend.</title>
      <description>You learned that your statistics should be regularly updated. You even implemented Ola Hallengren's maintenance scripts. That should be enough, right? What if it's not?
Join me on some head-ache, a dive into statistics histograms, fun with flags and a praise to the evolution of SQL Server optimizer.
Much of this session is about the "ascending key problem", and how Microsoft have made shanges to the SQL Server optimizer to improve, but not completely eliminate the problem.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101212</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101212</id>
          <name>Tomaž Kaštrun</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Useful DAX and Power BI examples for everyday usage</title>
      <description>Session will cover many everyday useful DAX functions, and Power BI examples, that can help you build better and cleaner (slicers, forms, formulas) reports. With help of DAX -  powerful language to manipulate data in Power BI, handling hierarchies, data granulation, data aggregations and functions for date, time, text operations - session will walk you through many examples to help you prepare Power BI Reports for everyday usage.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99699</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99699</id>
          <name>Rudi Bruchez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Diagnosing performance problems on Azure SQL</title>
      <description>Dynamic Management Views, wait sats, executions statistics, Extended Events. Those are the tools you use on SQL Server on-prem to diagnose long running queries and server weaknesses. You use more or less the same tools on Azure SQL, but there are differences: permissions, database-specific views, XEvents ring buffer reading. In this session, we will address specific queries and views, and diagnosis steps specific to Azure SQL.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101601</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101601</id>
          <name>Gianluca Sartori</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Monitoring SQL Server without breaking the bank</title>
      <description>Monitoring SQL Server can become a very expensive business. Sure, the market offers countless paid solutions, but what if you have a large server estate and your budget is tight? 
In this session we will combine multiple open source tools (InfluxDB, Telegraf , Grafana, DbaTools and many more) to collect important performance metrics, analyze the data they collect, set up alerts for the critical events, troubleshoot issues and plan for the future. Join me and you will see how monitoring is not a business for billionaires.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105224</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105224</id>
          <name>Torsten Strauss</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Wait Statistics</title>
      <description>To understand the root cause of performance problems you need to have a good understanding about SQL OS and especially how connections, sessions, requests, tasks, scheduler, threads and wait statistics are working together.
In this session you will learn this understanding to identify common performance issues and find solutions to solve them.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>102846</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>102846</id>
          <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>“SQL-like” or query languages in Azure IoT</title>
      <description>If you are reading Azure IoT documentation you will stumble a lot on the “SQL-like query language” or “SQL-like language” syntagms.
In this presentation we will explore Azure IoT places where queries are used and see how to use them. And in the process to find out more about this “SQL-like” languages and how being a DB developer cam make you a IoT hero.
We will concentrate on the scenarios with the greatest impact, where a little SQL can solve you a lot of hassle.
So, we will leave no SQL query unturned  in Azure IoT Hub, Stream Analytics, Power Bi to name a few.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98966</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98966</id>
          <name>Vedran Kesegic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Logging Actual execution plans in SQL 2017 and 2019</title>
      <description>Actual execution plan gives us most comprehensive info for tuning a query, much more than estimated plan.
Now it also includes wait statistics, logical reads, and actual row numbers for that execution.
But there is a catch - it is traditionally very expensive to track plans for all executions, even if we filter for only slow ones.
We will see how new versions of SQL Server evolved to get us actual plans without sacrificing performance.
Let me introduce you to "Lightweight profiling" you can have enabled all the time on your server, with close to zero impact.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2020 8:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2020 9:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>