<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #696 - Redmond 2018</name>
    <startDate>2/10/2018 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>450</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-08:00) Pacific Time (US and Canada); Tijuana</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatRedmond</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Building 92</name>
      <street>15010 NE 36th ST</street>
      <city>Redmond</city>
      <state>Washington</state>
      <zipcode>98052</zipcode>
      <longitude>-122.137145996094</longitude>
      <latitude>47.6421012878418</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2002</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.red-gate.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/991/EventSponsor_14803.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>552</importID>
      <name>DB Best Technologies</name>
      <label>Platinum </label>
      <url>http://www.dbbest.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://i.piccy.info/i9/2c14fcfadc6ef0afae6a94278e068866/1563297673/47771/1328136/DBBest_logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1988</importID>
      <name>Rubrik</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.rubrik.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/945/EventSponsor_14614.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14586.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71821</importID>
      <name>Russel Loski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Russ Loski is a SQL Server BI Developer based in Dallas-Fort Worth.  He current works as a Data Analytics Engineer for Navisite, a remote managed IT services company.   Twenty years ago, he began working with SQL Server 6.5. He has since continued to develop applications connected to all of the versions of SQL Server. He has worked with clients in industries from insurance to healthcare, from movie theaters to American football.  Russ is a regular speaker at SQLSaturday events, as well as the SQL Server Users Groups in the North Texas region. Russ likes working with data in various shapes.</description>
      <twitter>sqlmovers</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/russloski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmovers.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmovers</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68854</importID>
      <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Over 30 years in the computing field as a developer and system integrator; over 20 years working with SQL Server since version 6; cross platform experience with Oracle and IBM SQL/DS and DB2; Microsoft Certified Trainer for over 20 years.</description>
      <twitter>arlacerda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armando-lacerda</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arlacerda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71718</importID>
      <name>Vern Rabe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vern Rabe is an independent SQL Server consultant and contract trainer in Portland, OR, and leader of the Oregon Data Community user group, formerly OregonSQL. He has attained MCSE, MCITP (both Administration and Development), and MCT certifications, among others. Vern has been passionate about databases since 1992 and has worked with SQL Server since version 4.21a. He provides broad technical SQL Server knowledge gained from the mixture of academic and practical experiences acquired from his classroom instructing and varied consulting contracts. Vern regularly presents technical sessions at SQL Server user group meetings, SQLSaturdays, and PASS Summit.</description>
      <twitter>@VernRabe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/vern-rabe/a/ba3/980</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.rabedata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@VernRabe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70006</importID>
      <name>Kun Cheng</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kun Cheng is a Program Manager at Microsoft working in the SQL Server Customer Advisory Team (SQLCAT). Focused on Enterprise customer and ISV application performance and scalability, he has more than 16 years of experience as a developer and consultant helping large SQL Server and SQL Database design and implementations across on-prem and Azure. His industry experience includes telecommunications, IT, and financial services.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70494</importID>
      <name>Yana Berkovich</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A people-oriented professional, aspiring Product Manager, with 11 years of process analysis, building solutions, customization, developing, managing and training experience. Working with Power Bi, Oracle SQL and SQL server for the past few years. Data enthusiast with international experience in many companies as a BA, Team Lead and everything SharePoint  Office 365.</description>
      <twitter>@Yana_Berkovich</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/yanaberkovich/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://yanaberkovich.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Yana_Berkovich</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70788</importID>
      <name>Rick Lowe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick is a Microsoft Certified Master with more than 20 years of SQL Server experience in a variety of roles. He currently lives in Washington state and works as an independent consultant providing remote performance DBA and performance tuning services for clients in the USA and Canada. His first exposure to SQL Server was as a database developer, but over time he became more and more interested in how the database engine operated... eventually specializing more on performance issues than code.

Rick will work with all things relational, but most enjoys helping smaller companies get better performance from MSSQL, as well as smoothing over relationships between DBA and development teams.</description>
      <twitter>DataFLowe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rick-lowe/a/228/441/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataflowe.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataFLowe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70088</importID>
      <name>Maxwell Myrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Max Myrick is a SQL Server consultant whose experience includes 15 years at Microsoft with 5 years on the SQL Server development team where he ran the SQL Customer Lab and then the Sustained Engineering team. He was an founding member of Microsoft#39;s Mission Critical team where he worked with the largest SQL Server applications worldwide for almost a decade. Max was a regular speaker for Microsoft and has continued to speak at various PASS and other SQL Conferences since becoming a managing partner of SQLHA LLC.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLHA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/company/sqlha</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlha.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLHA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70603</importID>
      <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kalen Delaney is a Data Platform MVP who has worked with SQL Server for more than 32 years. She has provided performance consulting services and taught advanced courses on SQL Server to thousands of people and organizations. In addition to her courseware development, Kalen has been writing about SQL Server for decades. She is the primary author of SQL Server Internals and the Inside SQL Server series. Kalen is also one of the primary editors for the Red Gate SQL Server Stairways tutorials.</description>
      <twitter>sqlqueen</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlqueen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69056</importID>
      <name>Simon Cho</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Simon Cho is one of the founders of SQLAngeles.com, which is a Los Angeles Korean Tech PASS community group.

As a Local Group leader, he is a Microsoft SQL community speaker. He has presented many times at SQLSaturdays and to PASS Local Groups.

He moved his passion to VISA Inc, the largest credit card provider in the world, where he used database technology to build a strong solution and a secure environment, with new strategies and features to maintain thousands of SQL Servers.

He has now joined the Nowcom Corp, as a Director of DevOps, where he leads the DevOps team and DBA team.

He is pretty much working on SQL server running on kubernetes.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/simonsql</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://simonsql.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69914</importID>
      <name>Janis Griffin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Janis Griffin has over 30 years of DBA/database experience including design, development and implementation of many critical database applications. Before coming to Quest Software, Janis primarily worked in the Telecom/Network Industry, working with both real-time network routing databases and OLTP business to business applications.  Janis also held positions as a Principal Architect and Senior Manager, mentoring other DBAs on best practices in database performance tuning.</description>
      <twitter>DoBoutAnything</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/janis-griffin/0/914/aba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DoBoutAnything</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71832</importID>
      <name>Davide Mauri</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data Platform MVP for almost 12 years, I love Data and Database in all their forms. Developer for passion (C# and Python), I've been working in the IT field since 1997. My focus has been databases and performance tuning since the start, focusing both on transactional and analytical workloads. I worked for more than 10 years on Business Intelligence and Data Warehousing, then moved to IoT and Big Data for a while. Now back to database space, injecting passion and innovation into Azure SQL as Microsoft Program Manager for Azure SQL Hyperscale, helping developers to re-discover SQL, which is now almost everywhere, and take advantage of all its amazing power!</description>
      <twitter>mauridb</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidemauri</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://medium.com/@mauridb</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mauridb</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69589</importID>
      <name>John Sterrett</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Sterrett is a MCSE: Data Platform, Principal Consultant, and the Founder of Procure SQL LLC.  John has experience presenting at community events, including Microsoft Ignite, PASS Member Summit, SQLRally, 24 Hours of PASS, SQL Saturdays, PASS Chapters, and Virtual Chapter meetings. John is a leader of the Austin SQL Server User Group and is the founder of the HADR Virtual Chapter. John's community activities can be found at https://johnsterrett.com/community/</description>
      <twitter>JohnSterrett</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/johnsterrett</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://johnsterrett.com/community/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=JohnSterrett</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72628</importID>
      <name>SQLSaturday Redmond</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Extended time slot</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71624</importID>
      <name>Joe Chang</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joe is a SQL Server Consultant specializing in seriously difficult performance issues. Root cause analysis of complex and vexing problems. Quick non-disruptive fixes for production systems when possible, and in-place re-architecture to correct deeply ingrained flaws when required. Prefers to be on the project from the beginning, but usually called as firefighter of last resort.
SQL ExecStats by Joe for automating SQL XML plan analysis, cross-referencing index usage to execution plans. He has models for predicting SQL Server performance early in the design phase, and taking the guess work out of performance tuning. 
He has built a more complete model than the SQL Server internal cost based query optimizer, including processor and system ar</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/joe-chang-174a451/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.qdpma.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69949</importID>
      <name>Arvind Shyamsundar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Arvind is a Principal Program Manager (Microsoft Azure Data) working on the Azure SQL DB and Hyperscale services. Arvind is passionate about sharing his knowledge and learnings - as well as automating troubleshooting and diagnostics as much as possible. Much of his work is available on GitHub (https://github.com/arvindshmicrosoft/) and his blog (http://aka.ms/arvindsh/). Arvind is also an #MCM4Life and has previously worked as a Principal PFE within Microsoft Services.</description>
      <twitter>arvisam</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://in.linkedin.com/in/arvindsh</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/arvindsh</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arvisam</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71897</importID>
      <name>Rick Lowe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick is a Microsoft Certified Master with more than 20 years of SQL Server experience in a variety of roles. He currently lives in Washington state and works as an independent consultant providing remote performance DBA and performance tuning services for clients in the USA and Canada. His first exposure to SQL Server was as a database developer, but over time he became more and more interested in how the database engine operated... eventually specializing more on performance issues than code.

Rick will work with all things relational, but most enjoys helping smaller companies get better performance from MSSQL, as well as smoothing over relationships between DBA and development teams.</description>
      <twitter>DataFLowe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rick-lowe/a/228/441/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataflowe.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataFLowe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71820</importID>
      <name>Russel Loski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Russ Loski is a SQL Server BI Developer based in Dallas-Fort Worth.  He current works as a Data Analytics Engineer for Navisite, a remote managed IT services company.   Twenty years ago, he began working with SQL Server 6.5. He has since continued to develop applications connected to all of the versions of SQL Server. He has worked with clients in industries from insurance to healthcare, from movie theaters to American football.  Russ is a regular speaker at SQLSaturday events, as well as the SQL Server Users Groups in the North Texas region. Russ likes working with data in various shapes.</description>
      <twitter>sqlmovers</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/russloski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmovers.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmovers</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72922</importID>
      <name>Paul Turley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul is a Principal Consultant for Pragmatic Works, a Mentor and Microsoft Data Platform MVP. He consults, writes, speaks, teaches  blogs about business intelligence and reporting solutions. He works with companies around the world to model data, visualize and deliver critical information to make informed business decisions; using the Microsoft data platform and business analytics tools. He is a Director of the Oregon Data Community PASS chapter  user group, the author  and lead author of Professional SQL Server 2016 Reporting Services and 14 other titles from Wrox  Microsoft Press.  He holds several certifications including MCSE for the Data Platform and BI.</description>
      <twitter>paul_turley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pturley</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserverbiblog.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=paul_turley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70779</importID>
      <name>Sourabh Agarwal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sourabh Agarwal is a Sr. Program Manager for the Microsoft Data Platform Group and owns the HADR components for the SQL Server In-Market release. In his decade-long stint at Microsoft, he has worked in different capacities and specializes in providing consulting services on SQL Server and other Data Platform technologies to Microsoft customers across business domains and geographies. His specialization includes designing and optimizing SQL Deployments, HADR, Microsoft Azure, and PowerShell scripting.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLSourabh</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqluninterrupted.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLSourabh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68905</importID>
      <name>Christian Wade</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Christian Wade is a Senior Program Manager for Analysis Services. His consulting experience includes data-warehousing, BI and application-development projects for numerous enterprise customers. Christian is the creator of the BISM Normalizer, which is a database comparison tool for Analysis Services tabular models. He is a frequent presenter at Microsoft conferences. You can find his blog at https://christianwade.wordpress.com/.</description>
      <twitter>@_christianwade</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://christianwade.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_christianwade</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71725</importID>
      <name>Ben Miller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben has been a member of the SQL Server Community since 2000. He loves a challenge and has fixed many SQL Servers and helped hundreds of people get more out of their DBA jobs.  He is a Data Platform MVP a SQL Server Certified Master (MCM). He has worked at various companies throughout the USA, as well as at Microsoft for 7 years. He is passionate about SQL Server Infrastructure, High Availability, Automation and Integration using SMO and PowerShell. He teaches DBAs how to use PowerShell to do their job and teaches SQL Server Internals. He is @DBAduck all around the web (Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, Blog) so let's catch up.</description>
      <twitter>DBAduck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dbaduck/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbaduck.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAduck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68811</importID>
      <name>Christopher Sims</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris is a software engineer and program manager with over 18 years of programming and 14 years of project management experience. Chris continually pushes his personal and professional boundaries by actively seeking out complex projects and applying innovative, sophisticated and elegant solutions to real-world problems. Chris is the technical principal of agile consulting firm, Sigao Studios. Sigao Studios specializes in offering modern responsive web solutions based on technologies that include Azure, CosmosDB and Azure Search. In addition to his technical pursuits, Chris enjoys stage acting and wood working in his free time.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sigaostudios</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopherpsims/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sigaostudios.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sigaostudios</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71678</importID>
      <name>Greg Larsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Greg Larsen has been working with SQL Server since 1999. He has authored 100's of articles related to SQL Server. He holds a MCSE Data Management and Analytics.  Greg also a SQL Server Consultant, adjunct professor and technical writer.</description>
      <twitter>GregoryALarsen</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/grlarsen/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=GregoryALarsen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74016</importID>
      <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sumit Kumar is a Program Manager in Microsoft Machine Learning team. He leads the Python and R integration in SQL Server as SQL Server Machine Learning Services. Before that Sumit was a Program Manager in Bing’s Intent Platform team. There he helped build Microsoft’s text understanding service using machine learning and NLP techniques, that powers many proactive experiences in Cortana and Outlook family of products. Prior to that he has worked for many years on Microsoft’s developer products, focusing mainly on Visual Studio features for C++ developers. Sumit has an MS degree in Computer Science from the University of Texas at Dallas.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73889</importID>
      <name>Scott Stauffer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Scott Stauffer (@SQLSocialite) is very PASSionate about data and enjoys meeting with like-minded data geeks. He started the Vancouver PASS Chapter in 2004. In 2008, Scott was recognized by Microsoft with a SQL Server MVP award. In 2009, Scott started a PASS BI Chapter in Vancouver, and was also at one time the PASS Regional Chapter Mentor for Canada. For over 10 years he has been an independent consultant working with clients to solve their data woes and extract insight from their business data.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLSocialite</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/scottstauffer</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://scottstauffer.ca</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLSocialite</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69286</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68856</importID>
      <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Over 30 years in the computing field as a developer and system integrator; over 20 years working with SQL Server since version 6; cross platform experience with Oracle and IBM SQL/DS and DB2; Microsoft Certified Trainer for over 20 years.</description>
      <twitter>arlacerda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armando-lacerda</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arlacerda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71719</importID>
      <name>Vern Rabe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vern Rabe is an independent SQL Server consultant and contract trainer in Portland, OR, and leader of the Oregon Data Community user group, formerly OregonSQL. He has attained MCSE, MCITP (both Administration and Development), and MCT certifications, among others. Vern has been passionate about databases since 1992 and has worked with SQL Server since version 4.21a. He provides broad technical SQL Server knowledge gained from the mixture of academic and practical experiences acquired from his classroom instructing and varied consulting contracts. Vern regularly presents technical sessions at SQL Server user group meetings, SQLSaturdays, and PASS Summit.</description>
      <twitter>@VernRabe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/vern-rabe/a/ba3/980</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.rabedata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@VernRabe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69385</importID>
      <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kellyn Pot’Vin-Gorman is a member of the Oak Table Network and an Idera ACE and Oracle ACE Director alumnus. She is a Data Platform Architect in Power BI with AI in the EdTech group at Microsoft. Kellyn is known for her extensive work with multi-database platforms, DevOps, cloud migrations, virtualization, visualizations, scripting, environment optimization tuning, automation, and architecture design. 

Kellyn has spoken at numerous technical conferences for Oracle, Big Data, DevOps, testing, and SQL Server. Her blog (http://dbakevlar.com) and social media activity under her handle, DBAKevlar, is well respected for her insight and content.</description>
      <twitter>DBAKevlar</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellynpotvin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dbakevlar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAKevlar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69289</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68927</importID>
      <name>Andrew Cook</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrew is a software development consultant in Seattle, WA focusing on development on the Microsoft Stack including Azure and Xamarin.
Andrew is a Xamarin Certified Developer, Microsoft Professional and Advanced Care Paramedic.</description>
      <twitter>@codingwcookie</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://codingwithcookie.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@codingwcookie</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71727</importID>
      <name>Ben Miller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben has been a member of the SQL Server Community since 2000. He loves a challenge and has fixed many SQL Servers and helped hundreds of people get more out of their DBA jobs.  He is a Data Platform MVP a SQL Server Certified Master (MCM). He has worked at various companies throughout the USA, as well as at Microsoft for 7 years. He is passionate about SQL Server Infrastructure, High Availability, Automation and Integration using SMO and PowerShell. He teaches DBAs how to use PowerShell to do their job and teaches SQL Server Internals. He is @DBAduck all around the web (Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, Blog) so let's catch up.</description>
      <twitter>DBAduck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dbaduck/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbaduck.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAduck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71286</importID>
      <name>Tim Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tim Gorman is a senior technical consultant for Delphix who securely enables masked data virtualization to increase the agility of IT development and testing while ending decades of security risk in SDLC.

Tim has co-authored six books on data warehousing and database administration, has performed technical review on eight more books, and has an author#39;s page on Amazon.com (http://www.amazon.com/Tim-Gorman/e/B00BKCTO5E).</description>
      <twitter>@TimGormanTech</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timgorman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://evdbt.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TimGormanTech</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71744</importID>
      <name>Michael Wall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Wall has been an IT professional going back to when he had his own software store and worked with his customers with their “dose” problems.  Originally hired by a small consulting firm to write web pages, he was thrust into the SysAdmin world when their lead consultant changed the passwords of all of the servers at a major pulp and paper company’s systems to 100%s$%t and walked out the door.  He was sent down with a copy of UNIX for Dummies and 50 cents for the bus ride back.  Fast forward a few years, he was asked if he wanted to be a DBA after successfully managing a fifty server Y2K upgrade.  Since then, he’s never looked back and has survived a number of data and system challenges.
When not wrangling cats at home, he currently</description>
      <twitter>michaelDwall1</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-wall/b/110/9a</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.becomingamaster.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=michaelDwall1</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73671</importID>
      <name>Arnie Rowland</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Arnie long ago realized that most issues between Developer and DBA comes from incomplete communication and a misunderstanding of each other's objectives. He is a frequent Trainer and Mentor for Developers and DBAs, bringing both sets of skills to better communicate  with teams to create a working solution. For over a decade, Arnie has been a SQL Server MVP, Certified Trainer, technical editor for several publishers, including MOC, and has served as University and Community College adjunct faculty. Clients include Fortune 500 and Multi-Nationals, Federal and State agencies, Foreign governments, and local enterprises –both public and private.</description>
      <twitter>@ArnieRowland</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/arnie</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/arnie_rowland/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ArnieRowland</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69384</importID>
      <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kellyn Pot’Vin-Gorman is a member of the Oak Table Network and an Idera ACE and Oracle ACE Director alumnus. She is a Data Platform Architect in Power BI with AI in the EdTech group at Microsoft. Kellyn is known for her extensive work with multi-database platforms, DevOps, cloud migrations, virtualization, visualizations, scripting, environment optimization tuning, automation, and architecture design. 

Kellyn has spoken at numerous technical conferences for Oracle, Big Data, DevOps, testing, and SQL Server. Her blog (http://dbakevlar.com) and social media activity under her handle, DBAKevlar, is well respected for her insight and content.</description>
      <twitter>DBAKevlar</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellynpotvin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dbakevlar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAKevlar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71285</importID>
      <name>Tim Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tim Gorman is a senior technical consultant for Delphix who securely enables masked data virtualization to increase the agility of IT development and testing while ending decades of security risk in SDLC.

Tim has co-authored six books on data warehousing and database administration, has performed technical review on eight more books, and has an author#39;s page on Amazon.com (http://www.amazon.com/Tim-Gorman/e/B00BKCTO5E).</description>
      <twitter>@TimGormanTech</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timgorman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://evdbt.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TimGormanTech</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>70089</importID>
      <name>Maxwell Myrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Max Myrick is a SQL Server consultant whose experience includes 15 years at Microsoft with 5 years on the SQL Server development team where he ran the SQL Customer Lab and then the Sustained Engineering team. He was an founding member of Microsoft#39;s Mission Critical team where he worked with the largest SQL Server applications worldwide for almost a decade. Max was a regular speaker for Microsoft and has continued to speak at various PASS and other SQL Conferences since becoming a managing partner of SQLHA LLC.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLHA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/company/sqlha</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlha.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLHA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>72627</importID>
      <name>SQLSaturday Redmond</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Extended time slot</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71491</importID>
      <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kalen Delaney is a Data Platform MVP who has worked with SQL Server for more than 32 years. She has provided performance consulting services and taught advanced courses on SQL Server to thousands of people and organizations. In addition to her courseware development, Kalen has been writing about SQL Server for decades. She is the primary author of SQL Server Internals and the Inside SQL Server series. Kalen is also one of the primary editors for the Red Gate SQL Server Stairways tutorials.</description>
      <twitter>sqlqueen</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlqueen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>71803</importID>
      <name>Davide Mauri</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data Platform MVP for almost 12 years, I love Data and Database in all their forms. Developer for passion (C# and Python), I've been working in the IT field since 1997. My focus has been databases and performance tuning since the start, focusing both on transactional and analytical workloads. I worked for more than 10 years on Business Intelligence and Data Warehousing, then moved to IoT and Big Data for a while. Now back to database space, injecting passion and innovation into Azure SQL as Microsoft Program Manager for Azure SQL Hyperscale, helping developers to re-discover SQL, which is now almost everywhere, and take advantage of all its amazing power!</description>
      <twitter>mauridb</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidemauri</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://medium.com/@mauridb</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mauridb</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69262</importID>
      <name>Amit Banerjee</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a data professional with over a decade of experience in Relational Database Management Systems. I lead Program Management for the SQL Server engineering team focusing on the SQL Server database engine (Windows and Linux) and Azure SQL Edge.

My past experiences include Program Management for Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery (HADR), Data Movement and Performance for SQL Server, Azure Database for PostgreSQL and Azure Database for MySQL.

I am an active blogger, co-author of Pro SQL Server on Microsoft Azure and Professional SQL Server 2012: Internals and Troubleshooting and a regular speaker at various community events like Microsoft Ignite, SQL PASS, TechEd, Virtual Tech Days, SQL Saturday and User Group meeting.</description>
      <twitter>banerjeeamit</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://in.linkedin.com/pub/amit-banerjee/20/64a/852</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.troubleshootingsql.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=banerjeeamit</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>70089</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70089</id>
          <name>Maxwell Myrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Nexus</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Consulting Dilemma:  Is Inside or Outside of the Corporation the Right Fit for You?</title>
      <description>Accomplished IT staff looking to make the next step in their career development are often tempted to abandon the traditional full-time employee role for that of a self-managed consultant. The biggest challenge is how to know which role is the best fit for you. This session will discuss the pros/cons of self-managed consulting with an eye to the skills it takes to really be successful on the outside. For those that fit, we will also cover several of the hidden traps of consulting, what you need to get started, and the six skills that you absolutely have to have (or rent) to make a go of it. Whether you are looking at this type of move near-term or just keeping your options open, this talk will give you the real-life lessons to make that next step with confidence.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69384</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69384</id>
          <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Trident</name>
      </location>
      <title>DevOps for the DBA</title>
      <description>DevOps came out of the Agile movement and the idea that operations needed to be part of the solution for agile development to be successful.  The DBA was often the most resilient and robust member of the operations team and most resistant to change.  This mentality was essential to the protection of company’s critical production data.

This session discusses common database challenges and how they can be minimized or solved with newer DevOps practices without impacting the DBAs “safe zone”.  We’ll discuss how to use these vital skills and motivate everyone towards solutions for more success in agile development environments. Development, testing, provisioning, patching, upgrading and managing will become easier with agile tools, virtualization and collaboration.  
The take-aways from this session are to embrace DevOps basics with a “DBA twist” such as:
•	Develop, Rinse, Repeat
•	Test Until Your Five Year Old Can Do It
•	Human Intervention Creates Human Error- Automate EVERYTHING.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69949</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69949</id>
          <name>Arvind Shyamsundar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Trident</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advanced SQL Server troubleshooting with SQLCallStackResolver</title>
      <description>Troubleshooting spinlock contention, strange wait types, AVs and asserts is no longer a black box. With the availability of SQLCallStackResolver (http://aka.ms/sqlstack) you can start uncovering the true reasons for a particular behavior within SQL Server, without having to open WinDbg! This tool can potentially save you a call to Microsoft Support (or at least go much better prepared to them!) In this session you will be presented live demos of how SQLCallStackResolver has helped in real-life cases, both for SQL Server on Windows and SQL Server on Linux. Latch contention, spinlock contention, AVs are no longer a mystery with this tool. Come and see how you can tackle the most difficult and advanced SQL Server troubleshooting scenarios yourself!</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70088</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70088</id>
          <name>Maxwell Myrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Origami</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Then and Now: Changing the State of Long-held Beliefs</title>
      <description>We’ve all heard the rules for SQL Server like separate your data from your log, watch for a disk queue length over 2, and a low Page Life Expectancy always means memory pressure.  All of these used to be true, but on today’s hardware and SQL Server versions – they are dangerously outdated.  In this session, we will take on a bunch of these old “givens” of SQL Server that everybody has heard and followed, the underlying technological reasons they were true then, how today’s technology has rendered them obsolete, and what the new rules are that you need to know.  So whether you are one of the old guard looking to refresh your set of working SQL Server rules or a member of the up-and-comers looking for the facts to win over the old guard, this session is for you.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69385</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69385</id>
          <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stinger</name>
      </location>
      <title>Oracle vs. SQL Server-  The War of the Indices</title>
      <description>This session is for the love of technology and learning.  Its based off research performed on objects, design and code built as similar as possible to see how Oracle and SQL Server compare in performance, usage and storage of indices.  Environments were built on-prem and in the cloud to view differences in different cloud support of database engines and based off trusted measurements in each platform so as to dig into how the use case was built, the similarities and the differences in each. 

Based off this use case, enhanced builds of more advanced index features and discussions of the advantages, reasons for the introduction and how it's effected the direction of each product, the DBAs who are responsible for them and resources. 

Takeaways are:
1.	Receive a strong education on platform differences between Oracle and SQL Server.
2.	Discover hidden insight on index storage and costs.
3.	Learn about great tips on maintaining index health</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69262</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69262</id>
          <name>Amit Banerjee</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Origami</name>
      </location>
      <title>Running applications on Azure Database for PostgreSQL/MySQL</title>
      <description>Azure Database for MySQL and Azure Database for PostgreSQL are managed database services built for developers using the community edition of MySQL and PostgreSQL. Learn how you can leverage these new choices of managed database services to build scalable, secure and intelligent apps. Using insights from current customer scenarios and through live demos, we walk through the service management capabilities, best practices to move your databases to the service, and also focus on how the Microsoft Azure ecosystem of app and data services is unlocking the potential of MySQL and PostgreSQL in the Azure cloud platform.

In this session, we will show you how you can develop on Azure and deploy solutions without having to worry about high availability, disaster recovery, monitoring and other common operational and administration tasks!</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69914</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69914</id>
          <name>Janis Griffin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Normandy</name>
      </location>
      <title>HiHo! HiHo! SQL Server on Linux, We Go!</title>
      <description>SQL Server has been running on Windows for years. Now Microsoft is making it available on Linux in order to provide a consistent database platform across Window and Linux servers, as well as on-premises and in the cloud. In this presentation, Janis Griffin, database performance evangelist at SolarWinds, will discuss the advantages of using SQL Server on Linux, comparing architecture, cost and performance. Several demonstrations on installing and maintaining SQL Server on Linux will be shown along with an introduction of several useful Linux commands.

The participant will learn:
1. The advantages of using SQL Server on Linux, comparing architecture, cost and performance to Window servers.
2. How to install, maintain and backup SQL Server on Ubuntu Linux systems 
3. Several useful Linux commands to monitor/manage SQL Server</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70779</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70779</id>
          <name>Sourabh Agarwal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Odyssey</name>
      </location>
      <title>Troubleshooting Always On Availability Group Failovers</title>
      <description>Unexpected failovers or Unsuccessful failovers are by far the most common problem sorrunding Always On Availability Groups. Troubleshooting failover related issues can be a challenge and time consuming. In order to effectively troubleshooting these issues data needs to be collected and analyzed from different servers and replicas. Things get further complicated by the fact that there are multiple logs which needs to be looked at and that these logs are in different time zone formats. In this session we will look at how to easily identify the reasons for failover of an Availability Group and what new capabilities are being introduced to help with the analysis of AG failovers.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71286</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71286</id>
          <name>Tim Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Utopia</name>
      </location>
      <title>Reducing The Surface Area Of Risk in Data Security</title>
      <description>Data obfuscation, also known as data masking, is soon a new legal requirement. Masking is the solution for non-production systems (i.e. DEV, TEST, etc) to greatly reduce the surface area of risk for data breach in your organization.  Masking should not be confused with encryption, which is an appropriate solution for production applications.  Those who believe that encryption solves all security problems are misled.

When done properly, masked data is not noticeable unless you look closely. Masking data well might still be usable for analytic reporting and aggregation, yet utterly useless for revealing confidential data. Masking is important enough that sophisticated software packages have become available.

Come learn about the right way to mask non-production data in order to allow the organization to limit possible exposure only to production.  Learn what techniques can be used, why, and what factors should be considered when deciding to secure confidential data.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71624</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71624</id>
          <name>Joe Chang</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Odyssey</name>
      </location>
      <title>Rethink Server Sizing</title>
      <description>Does it seem strange server sizing articles automatically assume that a 2-socket system, with some number of cores, is the right solution, excepting a 4-socket for extreme circumstances? Or is this accepted because that’s what everyone assumes absent rational technical explanation based on recent generation components? There were once valid reasons for multi-socket as the baseline system, but the world has changed since then. Were your database and application architected together to achieve high memory locality on a NUMA system? If this question cannot definitely be answered in the affirmative, then more than likely a single socket system is the best server platform for database transaction processing. This is not an option currently offered by the major cloud providers.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69286</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69286</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stinger</name>
      </location>
      <title>APPLY Yourself</title>
      <description>Microsoft introduced the APPLY operator in SQL Server 2005. This under-used, non-standard operator can help us solve a number of common (and not-so-common) problems with elegant code which performs well. We will look several problem spaces in which the APPLY operator shines, such as joining to table-valued functions, getting the top N child records for each parent record, string splitting, and word matching. With the use of these examples, we will gain a deeper understanding of when to use the APPLY operator.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71719</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71719</id>
          <name>Vern Rabe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stinger</name>
      </location>
      <title>Proper DataType Usage=Guaranteed Better Performance and Accuracy</title>
      <description>It’s an all too common occurrence to have table columns or variables that have been assigned less than ideal data types. 

In this demo-heavy presentation I will show you the importance of choosing the proper data type; show you some guidelines in determining what an appropriate data type would be; and once chosen, give you some tools for its usage and management. I will demonstrate several performance and accuracy issues, along with their possible solutions, caused by either the assignment of inappropriate data types or improper usage of them. In addition I will cover several data type related functions, and point out caveats in their usage. I expect even advanced T-SQL developers and DBAs to walk away with a useful nugget or two.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71744</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71744</id>
          <name>Michael Wall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Nexus</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Log Parser: Log What?</title>
      <description>Log Parser is one of Microsoft’s best and most under recognized tools.  Originally designed to read IIS and system logs, its simple complexity makes it a true “swiss army knife” of a tool.  With its ability to read multiple log and text formats and then spit them out in a myriad of formats, it can be used to quickly analyze large amounts of data and present them in a readable format.
This presentation will start with some basic uses of Log Parser, explain some of the core features, demonstrate some of the challenges, and finally focus on using Log Parser to decrypt SSRS logs.  These decrypted logs can then be used as a monitoring system.  
As with most things, there are multiple ways to accomplish a task.  Log Parser will be a welcome addition to your tool belt!</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71491</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71491</id>
          <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Nexus</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Look Inside SQL Server Distribution Statistics</title>
      <description>Where do the estimated rowcount values come from? Look inside SQL Server’s distribution statistics to see how they are used to come up with the estimates. We’ll also discuss changes in the cardinality estimator in recent versions and look at some new metadata that gives us more statistics information.

Goals:
•	Explore the output of DBCC SHOW_STATISTICS
•	Describe when the density information is useful
•	Look at some problem scenarios for which the statistics can’t give good estimates
•	Understand why cardinality estimation involves more than just the statistics</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71803</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71803</id>
          <name>Davide Mauri</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stinger</name>
      </location>
      <title>Serverless Computing: Azure Functions, Logic Apps and Azure SQL and CosmosDB</title>
      <description>Serverless is all about allowing us to focus only on the business problem we have to solve, removing all complexity related to infrastructure management, scalability and maintenance.
Azure offers many options in that space and two of them are particulary interesting: Azure Function and Azure Logic Apps. 
What are you needs? Hanlding data coming from a form? Invalidating cached data when a file changes? Responding to an external event like new customer added to your CRM?
Everything can be done very easily and with the language of your choice, or even via an easier workflow-like approach, that doesn't even require you to write code. 
No matter which approach you decide to take, you'll need to store data somewhere. Depending on the scenario you may want to use the new multi-API CosmosDB or the well established Azure SQL.
In this session we'll see how all the mentioned technologies can help us to have architectural choices to be more efficient and effective in our job.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71285</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71285</id>
          <name>Tim Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Utopia</name>
      </location>
      <title>Accelerating Development and Testing Using Data Virtualization</title>
      <description>Constraining everything in development and testing is database size.  Storage is a bottleneck, and while faster SSD/Flash is available, it is still too expensive due to the size of many databases, especially in DEV and TEST.  More to the point, it takes a lot of time to push terabytes around, and time itself is expensive.  The old joke about "good, fast, and cheap -- pick any two" is so true with data.

Providing full databases for each developer or tester on each task of each project seems unrealistic, when each copy might require terabytes of storage, so for decades everyone has limited themselves to working in shared dev/test environments that are refreshed only every few months, where conflicts occur,  quality suffers, and things move slowly.

Come learn why data virtualization is the solution to a problem everyone knows.

Good, fast, and cheap -- have all three with data virtualization.  Be able to clone data quickly, and remove the biggest constraint to development and testing.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71820</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71820</id>
          <name>Russel Loski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Utopia</name>
      </location>
      <title>Managing SSRS Reports using PowerShell and SSRS Web Services  (60 minutes)</title>
      <description>When you have to do something more than once, you should script it!  That’s true for SQL Server maintenance tasks.  It’s also important for Business Intelligence projects as well.  Microsoft has provided web services to manage your reporting service and to download reports in various forms.  In this session I demonstrate how to leverage these web services from PowerShell to handle common SSRS administrative tasks:  uploading and copying a report; checking the parameter values, setting the parameter defaults, scheduling a cache refresh.  I addition, I demonstrate how to download a report top PDF using PowerShell.  You will not only come away with a set of PowerShell scripts to manage your SSRS server, you will learn how to work around some of the less intuitive features of PowerShell to use and extend these scripts.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69289</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69289</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Origami</name>
      </location>
      <title>Securing SQL Server</title>
      <description>A default SQL Server installation is reasonably secure, but quot;reasonably securequot; doesn't cut it in an era in which one bad line of code, one weak password, or one open port can result in your customer database ending up on Pastebin. In this talk, we will look at different methods of securing a SQL Server instance, from venerable (principle of least privilege, Transparent Data Encryption) to novel (Always Encrypted, row-level security). These tools and techniques will show us ways for developers, database administrators, and network specialists to work together to secure SQL Server instances.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71725</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71725</id>
          <name>Ben Miller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Nexus</name>
      </location>
      <title>Gathering Trending Data with PowerShell</title>
      <description>Join me in the quest to become a PowerShell DBA! Learn how to improve your career by quickly accessing logistical information within a database rich environment. Discover how PowerShell tools can enable you to gather and store information in a functioning repository, placing views and functions from a day, a week, or even a year ago, right at your fingertips!</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71727</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71727</id>
          <name>Ben Miller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Trident</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Encryption</title>
      <description>Have you ever wanted to know how Transparent Database Encryption (TDE) works or how you set it up? What about encrypting your backups? This session will go over all the steps and caveats that go with this technology. TDE allows you to have your database encrypted on disk and the same Encryption Hierarchy allows you to back up your database and have it encrypt the contents in the backup file.  We will discuss the Encryption Hierarchy which is used for encryption in SQL Server and take you through keeping your secrets safe. We will also go over how Always Encrypted works as well. Master the concepts of SQL Server Encryption when you are done with this session.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71832</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71832</id>
          <name>Davide Mauri</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stinger</name>
      </location>
      <title>Back to the Roots: When indexes are not enough</title>
      <description>If you want optimum performance in SQL Server, you have to use indexes. But what if you already implemented indexes and your solution is still slow or it doesn’t scale like you want? Or, if you're on Azure, it is just requiring too much resources, which in turns means just more money to be spent on it? You may have to rethink the way you write your queries. How you write your queries is directly related to how you approach and solve your business problems, and more often than not thinking outside the box is the way to unlock incredible performances. But what this exactly means in a database? And how a developer can do that? In this session, you’ll see how using some lateral thinking and a set-based approach will open up a whole world of possibilities. Thanks to this demo intensive session, you'll never be the same after switching on this new mindset!</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71821</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71821</id>
          <name>Russel Loski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Utopia</name>
      </location>
      <title>Querying Semistructured Data in Azure Data Lake with USQL</title>
      <description>Data is exploding across enterprises.  Much of it is semi-structured junk.  Or is it junk?  What are you going to do with it until you can find out?  Microsoft’s Azure Data Lake is a cloud storage and analytical service for parking a variety of data.  When you are ready, you can query that semi-structured data using an ANSI SQL language called U-SQL.  In this session I will demonstrate the similarities and differences between U-SQL and T-SQL.  I will demonstrate how easy it is to build a query against 21 GB of CSV files. Such queries can help you determine whether you have a gold mine in your data or a bunch of garbage before investing in a full data warehouse build.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71897</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71897</id>
          <name>Rick Lowe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Nexus</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why should I care about ... the plan cache?</title>
      <description>SQL Server is a huge product, with many different places a DBA can go to look for information on how the server is performing. So many in fact that they can often overlap, which sometimes makes it hard to understand why tackling a new tool is worth the effort. In this installment of Rick's "Why should I care" series, he lays out a case for why working knowledge of the plan cache is critical for performance tuning efforts in real world environments. A review of relevant views and functions is included for the (newly?) motivated audience.

Perfect for those who are relatively new to performance tuning concerns, or advanced DBAs trying to figure out how to have a similar conversation with their less experienced peers, or developers who are curious as to why their DBAs drink in the morning (allegedly). This is not a deep dive into the cache, it really is primarily a session exploring _why_ these DMOs are worth slogging through.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>72628</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>72628</id>
          <name>SQLSaturday Redmond</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Origami</name>
      </location>
      <title>Five Lighting sessions (click here to see them)</title>
      <description>1. Temp Tables  Table Variables by Vern Rabe. 
    This talk will explain how to select between temp tables and table variables.

2. Why is my DBA So Grumpy ... When I Use NOLOCK and Other Query Hints by Rick Lowe
    Ever hear NOLOCK is bad? Ever use one (or a hundred) anyway? Come see some of the bad things that can happen when NOLOCK hints are abused.

3. Change Data Capture in SQL Server, SSIS, Master Data Services by Swagatika Sarangi.
    In This session, you will see a demonstration of implementing Change Data Capture in SQL Server 2017 and Master Data Services web UI 2017. 
   
4. A look at what is required to get an Alexa application up and running on Azure Functions where voice is the UI By Andrew Cook

5. 15 speaking tips in 15 minutes by Arne Rowland.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>72922</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>72922</id>
          <name>Paul Turley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Trident</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Nine Realms of Power BI</title>
      <description>Planning a Power BI solution  need to understand options  choices?  There is much to consider as you discover your inner Data Avenger.  Like the old story of the 4 Blind Men  The Elephant, if you ask 4 people to describe Power BI; you will likely get 4 answers.  Power BI solutions have 9 Realms.  It's easy to get started but things can get complicated quickly...  Should you import your data  use the cloud service? or keep your data on-premises using the gateway?  Should you use DirectQuery or direct access to Analysis Services, multidimensional or tabular, in Azure or on-prem?  What's the best method to secure data  control user access?  What to license?  How will users access dashboards  reports?  Can it be embedded?  A hammer or other tools?
From simple desktop  published reports, to enterprise-scale and highly-secured solutions; we will demystify all these options  provide a roadmap to conquer the Nine Realms; from Midgard to Asgard, and from Desktop to Power BI Avenger.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74016</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74016</id>
          <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Odyssey</name>
      </location>
      <title>Machine Learning Services in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>Machine Learning Services with Python and R support has transformed SQL Server into a powerful end to end AI platform. Come learn about the advantages of doing in-database machine learning using R and Python languages and get the latest in this technology.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71718</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71718</id>
          <name>Vern Rabe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stinger</name>
      </location>
      <title>It's Time for a Change: Temporal Table Support in SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>Without temporal tables (AKA history tables), we can only see the current version of data. We can’t see rows that have been deleted or rows as they existed before the latest update. The temporal table support in SQL Server 2016 gives us the ability to create system-maintained “history” tables to track all changes to the table data.

In this session we’ll discuss how you can benefit from temporal support in your tables, how to implement temporal tables in SQL Server 2016, and how to write “time travel queries” using the new FOR SYSTEM_TIME clause in a SELECT statement to easily query historical information.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73889</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73889</id>
          <name>Scott Stauffer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Origami</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI for the Faint of Heart - Building an Interactive Report</title>
      <description>You've heard about Power BI, and you've seen it, but you haven't yet rolled up your sleeves and got your hands dirty. It looks like it is really easy, but sometimes it helps to have someone step you through it the first time to help you hit the ground running. We will grab various public data sources, join them together in a model and build an interactive piece de ré·sis·tance on the visual design surface!</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>71678</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>71678</id>
          <name>Greg Larsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Trident</name>
      </location>
      <title>Blurring your Data with Dynamic Data Masking</title>
      <description>In this talk Greg will explore the new Data Masking feature, that came out with SQL Server 2016.  Greg will be discussing: 
•	Why you should mask your data
•	The 4 different masking functions
•	Security around Dynamic Data Masking
•	Benefits, drawbacks and programming considerations around Dynamic Data Masking
•	How to crack Dynamic Data Masking
Greg’s talk will also contain a number Dynamic Data Masking demos. 
After attending this session, Attendee will gain a solid understanding of Dynamic Data Masking and the considerations they should take into account when rolling out this new feature.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73671</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73671</id>
          <name>Arnie Rowland</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stinger</name>
      </location>
      <title>Prevent Presentation Paralysis</title>
      <description>Stop fretting about giving presentations -you CAN decide to become more confident, come across more polished, and actually present with authority. In this session, you will learn and pick up some great tips about how to better prepare, and then present, technical material. You WILL leave with an improved sense of possibility!

Arnie will guide you with techniques to better understand and match the audience's expectations to your presentation goals. You will gain a better understanding of how to prepare your presentation, as well as how to get, and hold the audience's attention. And even how to be more relaxed with the inevitable critique from colleagues. Ramp up your career. Don't miss this session!</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70006</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70006</id>
          <name>Kun Cheng</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Odyssey</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQLCAT: A customer story of Distributed AG strategy for Hybrid Architecture (Cloud agnostic)</title>
      <description>Come to learn how an enterprise customer moves from on-premises to cloud with hybrid design leveraging SQL Server Always-on and distributed availability group across cloud platforms (Azure  AWS).</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68905</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68905</id>
          <name>Christian Wade</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Normandy</name>
      </location>
      <title>Modeling and Analytics Features Coming in Azure Analysis Services</title>
      <description>Microsoft Azure Analysis Services  SQL Server Analysis Services help you build comprehensive, enterprise-scale analytic solutions that deliver actionable insights through familiar data visualization tools such as Microsoft Power BI and Microsoft Excel. Join this session for a look forward to what's coming in soon! The demos will cover new features to be announced for enterprise-grade BI models in the cloud.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>70494</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>70494</id>
          <name>Yana Berkovich</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Normandy</name>
      </location>
      <title>Enjoy Your Power Responsibly; Governance for PowerBI  O365</title>
      <description>PowerBI is used in many organizations, but how to govern it? this question is still a work in progress. All those features and capabilities and the limitless world of self-service BI, how are the users affected by that? How is IT? Some best practices, lessons learned and fun facts about the platform.
I will be talking about why do we need governance in Power BI? Groups and PowerB, permission management, limitations and how it correlates with other O365 applications.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69056</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69056</id>
          <name>Simon Cho</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Normandy</name>
      </location>
      <title>Build ETL efficiently (10x) with Minimal Logging</title>
      <description>This session is designed to teach DBAs and developers the best strategy to transfer large data. 

We will first analyze how data gets accessed from the source and how data gets updated or inserted to the target server: index access patterns in read operation and minimal logging in wring operation. I will introduce TF610 and cover its benefit for minimal logging even in full recovery mode.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68854</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68854</id>
          <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Odyssey</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Tricks for Storage and I/O Performance in the cloud</title>
      <description>SQL Performance strategies for on premises deployment don't translate straight through to the cloud. SQL Server 2016 brought much more integration and performance options for cloud database deployment. In this session we will see through multiple demos how to benefit from the storage options in Azure storage and make SQL Server break the sound speed!</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68811</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68811</id>
          <name>Christopher Sims</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Normandy</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting graphy with CosmosDB Graph API with Gremlin</title>
      <description>CosmosDB was announced at Build 2017 as an extension to Microsoft's DocumentDB offering and is positioned to be a key component of the Microsoft Data Platform. In this session, we will explore CosmosDB's graph API that is built using Apache's TinkerPop and Gremlin projects. Graph databases allow you to build a powerful data model that explores connections and paths between data. At the end of this session, attendees will have a solid understanding of what a graph database is and how you can use Gremlin and the .NET API to interact with a graph database.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68856</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68856</id>
          <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Odyssey</name>
      </location>
      <title>Unleashing Stretched Databases</title>
      <description>This is a deep dive session full of demos about SQL 2016 stretched databases feature. It will go from pre-reqs and blocking factor through deployment and disaster recovery. Everything you need to know and when to use this new cloud-based exciting capability.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68927</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68927</id>
          <name>Andrew Cook</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Utopia</name>
      </location>
      <title>Xamarin Data Syncing</title>
      <description>How can your users continue to use your mobile application while offline? A look into how and why to make a mobile app work where a data connection is not available and how to keep that data synchronized between the device, cloud and other devices. 

Offline sync allows users to interact with a mobile application, viewing, adding, or modifying data, even where there isn't a network connection. Changes are stored in a local database, and once the device is online, the changes can be synced with the web service.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69589</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69589</id>
          <name>John Sterrett</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Trident</name>
      </location>
      <title>An Introduction to Azure SQL Database for DBA's</title>
      <description>Are you interested in learning about Azure SQL Databases but are not sure where you should start learning?  Platform as a service (PaaS) databases are here and adoption is growing.  In this session, you will learn how to take your current DBA skills and utilize them with Azure Databases.  We will focus on getting started, migrating databases, disaster recovery, performance, and security.</description>
      <startTime>2/10/2018 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/10/2018 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>