<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #188 - Portugal 2013</name>
    <startDate>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT) Greenwich Mean Time : Dublin, Edinburgh, Lisbon, London</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatPortugal</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Portugal (Parque das Nações, (junto ao Oceanário))</name>
      <street>Rua do Fogo de Santelmo, Lote 2.07.02</street>
      <city>Lisbon</city>
      <state>, Portugal</state>
      <zipcode>1990-110</zipcode>
      <longitude>-9.09466</longitude>
      <latitude>38.761216</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>427</importID>
      <name>BI4ALL - Consultores de Gestão, lda</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.bi4all.pt</url>
      <imageURL>https://s16.postimg.org/hfkyap9sx/2015_logo_bi4all_sponsor_100x40px_01.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>161</importID>
      <name>Rumos - Formação e Comunicação, S. A.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://formacao.rumos.pt</url>
      <imageURL>https://s11.postimg.org/616v6rtmr/rumos.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>566</importID>
      <name>DevScope, S.A.</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.devscope.net</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/904/EventSponsor_14172.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>361</importID>
      <name>Actual Training, Lda</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.actualtraining.pt</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.actualtraining.pt/ATLogo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>903</importID>
      <name>Nikoport</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.nikoport.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlport.com/sql-server/sqlsat/niko_sqlsat_2013.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>566</importID>
      <name>DevScope, S.A.</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.devscope.net</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/904/EventSponsor_14172.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>854</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Portugal</name>
      <label>Diamond</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.pt</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlport.com/sql-server/sites/default/files/microsoft.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>83</importID>
      <name>PluralSight</name>
      <label>Swag Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pluralsight.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.srnimbus.com.br/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Pluralsight_logo_novo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Swag Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>345</importID>
      <name>Wintech</name>
      <label>Media Partner</label>
      <url>http://wintech.pt/</url>
      <imageURL>https://static.wintech.pt/fbicon.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>349</importID>
      <name>1stidea</name>
      <label>Media Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.1stidea.pt</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/043e7c50-0a06-4244-b54c-3755931ba37d.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20263</importID>
      <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mihail Mateev is a technical consultant, community enthusiast, PASS Regional Mentor for CEE, chapter lead, Microsoft Azure MVP, Microsoft Regional Director. He works as a Senior Solutions Architect at EPAM Systems, focused on Data Platform, IoT and cloud related solutions. He also worked many years like a Technical evangelist in the Infragistics. Last years Mihail was focused on various areas related to technology Microsoft: Data Platform, Visual Studio, ASP.Net, Windows client apps, Data Platform, and Microsoft Azure. Michael also has a PhD in cloud computing area. He is a university lecturer on Smart Homes and Smart Energy IoT Solutions.</description>
      <twitter>mihailmateev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mihail-mateev/1/6b3/4b1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mmateev.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mihailmateev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22412</importID>
      <name>Quilson Antunes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Quilson Antunes #233; DBA na hmR - Health Market Research, licenciado em Inform#225;tica de Gest#227;o pelo SLA Campus Lisboa - Laureate International Universities. No decurso do seu percurso profissional adquiriu experi#234;ncia na coordena#231;#227;o de recursos e compet#234;ncias em infra-estrutura e desenvolvimento de processos ETL. Cumulativamente possui s#243;lidos conhecimentos em administra#231;#227;o, desenho e desenvolvimento de bases de dados em SQL server desde a vers#227;o 7
</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pt.linkedin.com/in/quilson</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13973</importID>
      <name>Etienne Lopes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Etienne Lopes currently works as a SQL Server DBA at Celfinet.
Working with SQL Server since 1997, member of sqlport community (www.sqlport.com), regular speaker since 2012 at SQL Server events such as: SQL Saturday and 24 Hours of Pass.
Blog: http://sqland.wordpress.com/</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqland.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19549</importID>
      <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Broadbent is a Microsoft Certified Master in SQL Server, Chapter Leader, Virtual Chapter Leader, SQLSaturday Cambridge and SharePoint Saturday Cambridge founder (the UKs first SQLSaturday) and awarded Microsoft#39;s Community Contributor award in 2011 and the PASS Outstanding Volunteer award in 2012. Mark is a regular speaker at both International and National events and is an expert in HADR solutions, SQL Server migration, and SQL Server Concurrency control.</description>
      <twitter>retracement</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/retracement</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tenbulls.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=retracement</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11826</importID>
      <name>Pedro Correia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pedro Correia was born in 1976 on the 265th day of that year. He has been working with SQL Server for over 12 years, since the days of SQL Server 7.0, and his specialties are security and performance tuning. He is also a SQL Server trainer and teaching is one of his passions. 2012 was a year focused on the certification of competences and skills gained over the years, namely becoming one of the few Microsoft Certified Master - SQL Server 2008 (llt;100 worldwide).</description>
      <twitter>pjcorreiasql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pjcorreia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sql.pt</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pjcorreiasql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13952</importID>
      <name>Eladio Rincon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eladio es MVP en SQL Server desde el a#241;o 2002; es director de bases de datos relacionales de SolidQ en Espa#241;a donde dirige proyectos para clientes de SolidQ en todo el mundo. Ponente habitual en conferencias Microsoft MSDN/TechNet, SQLPASS o grupos de usuarios; participa con sus compa#241;eros en los blogs tecnol#243;gicos de su empresa http://blogs.solidq.com/bigdata-hadoop , http://blogs.solidq.com/elrincondeldba y http://blogs.solidq.com/bigdata-hadoop</description>
      <twitter>@erincon</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.solidq.com/blogs</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@erincon</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16567</importID>
      <name>Jen Stirrup</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jen is a database strategist, small business owner, SQLFamily and community advocate, public speaker and blogger. Jen was elected Director-At-Large (elect) for the Professional Association of SQL Server, responsible for the EMEA regions plus the Virtual Chapter portfolio.  Jen is passionate about all things data and business intelligence, helping leaders derive value from their Microsoft SQL Server, SharePoint and Office365 investments. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.jenstirrup.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11792</importID>
      <name>Constantin Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Constantin is working at Syntax Systems GmbH  Co. KG. He mainly deals with the design and development of solutions based on Microsoft products and technologies. Since 2010 he was each year designated Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for the Microsoft Data Platform. In addition he is member of the board of Just Community e.V. (http://www.justcommunity.de) and PASS Deutschland e.V. (http://www.sqlpass.de). He also leads the .NET User Group Frankfurt/Germany (http://dnug-frankfurt.de). Find his blog at: http://kostjaklein.wordpress.com</description>
      <twitter>KostjaKlein</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://kostjaklein.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=KostjaKlein</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21914</importID>
      <name>Pedro Lopes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pedro Lopes is a Principal Program Manager in the Microsoft Azure SQL Server team, based in Redmond, WA, USA. 

He is currently responsible for Program Management of database engine features for SQL Server and Azure SQL, with special focus on the Relational Engine (Query Processor, Programmability, Performance).
Regular speaker at conferences and user groups events, blogs about all things SQL at http://aka.ms/sqlserverteam, authored the book “Learn T-SQL Querying” (https://aka.ms/LearnTSQLQuerying), and tools in the TigerToolbox on GitHub: AdaptiveIndexDefrag (http://aka.ms/AID), BPCheck for SQL Best Practices and Performance checks (http://aka.ms/BPCheck), or usp_WhatsUp to get an instant view of perf issues (https://aka.ms/uspwhatsup).</description>
      <twitter>SQLPedro</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pt.linkedin.com/in/pedroazevedolopes/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/sqlserverteam</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLPedro</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23488</importID>
      <name>Ruben Pertusa Lopez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ruben is a Global BI/BigData Manager and Global Data Lead Architect at DUFRY HQ, member of PASS Spanish Group and founder of SQLSaturday Barcelona and Madrid. MCP and MCSA in SQL Server 2012 and also awarded with Microsoft MVP Data Platform. With more than 9 years of experience, he has been working in top projects for leading worldwide companies and teaching in the SolidQ BI Master. He has presented at the SQL Server 2008 R2 and 2014 Spanish launch event, PASS BA Chicago, TechNet Webcasts, Microsoft Partner Program and SolidQ Summit events.</description>
      <twitter>@rpertusa</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/ruben-pertusa-lopez/24/ba3/b0</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlpass.es</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@rpertusa</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23573</importID>
      <name>Rui Quintino</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior Architect amp; Data Fellow at DevScope. Rui works with Microsoft data related technologies since 1998 and currently leads Data Research amp; Advanced Analytics team at DevScope.

Beyond data techonologies, Rui also has strong background in web, mobile  amp; security and he likes to mix all of these to get the most out of Microsoft#39;s Data Platform and make the world a better place through the use of data.

Despite his assumed introversion he loves to learn amp; share his findings with developers, data lovers and microsoft platform communities on local amp; online events.</description>
      <twitter>rquintino</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pt.linkedin.com/in/rquintino</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://rquintino.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=rquintino</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19296</importID>
      <name>Luis Canastreiro</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>"Licenciado pela Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologia da Universidade Nova de Lisboa em Engenharia Informática e de Computadores desempenha desde 2006 funções de Premier Field Engineer na Microsoft, Actualmente as suas principais responsabilidades são: 
• Troubleshooting e Optimização de soluções com SQL Server, incluindo soluções de Failover Clustering. 
• Delivery de Risk Assesments Programs de SQL Server (SQL RAPs) na EMEA. 
• Desenvolvimento e apresentação de Workshops na área de SQL Server, Web (IIS) e Windows Powershell. 
• Participação no Blog da equipa Portuguesa PFE de SQL Server "
</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10992</importID>
      <name>Bruno Basto</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bruno Basto, senior consultant #160;and senior trainer #160;at Rumos. SQL certified since 6.5 version (1998). Work with MSFT tools and infrastructure since 1992 in the financial, banking and insurance areas. Responsible for several training projects for software solutions with MSFT infrastructure. Speaker at several MSFT and SQLPass events.
</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34574</importID>
      <name>André Kamman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>André is a freelance SQL Server specialist. In previous roles he’s done a lot of DBA work on 100’s of servers where he discovered his love for Powershell and automating processes in general. Today the better part of his day he’s building and tuning ETL processes.
André is a SQL Server MPV, Dutch PASS Chapter Leader and organiser of SQL Rally Amsterdam and SQL Saturday Holland</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://andrekamman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21528</importID>
      <name>Oliver Engels</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Oliver Engels is CEO of oh22data AG, a Microsoft Gold Partner in Germany specializing in CRM and BI. His special interests are Azure, Data Governance and Integration, Visualisation Tools like SSRS, Power BI, Tableau, R, and SharePoint. He has worked with SQL Server since version 6.5 and is a founder and Board member of PASS Germany, a PASS Regional Mentor, and runs the Frankfurt PASS Local Group. For more than seven years he is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a Microsoft pTSP.</description>
      <twitter>@oengels</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ssis-components.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@oengels</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13644</importID>
      <name>Enrique Catala</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Prácticamente toda aplicación utiliza por debajo un motor de base de datos para almacenar información. Entender lo que hace cuando le pedimos datos a SQL Server puede ayudar a cualquier desarrollador a entender por qué sus consultas van lentas. No se trata solo de abrir esa "caja negra" que es SQL Server, sino de entender lo que realmente tiene en su interior. En esta sesión aprenderemos a leer planes de ejecución y contaremos además, qué novedades hay en SQL Server 2014 con el nuevo cardinality estimator

</description>
      <twitter>@enriquecatala</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@enriquecatala</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16565</importID>
      <name>Jen Stirrup</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jen is a database strategist, small business owner, SQLFamily and community advocate, public speaker and blogger. Jen was elected Director-At-Large (elect) for the Professional Association of SQL Server, responsible for the EMEA regions plus the Virtual Chapter portfolio.  Jen is passionate about all things data and business intelligence, helping leaders derive value from their Microsoft SQL Server, SharePoint and Office365 investments. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.jenstirrup.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21531</importID>
      <name>Oliver Engels</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Oliver Engels is CEO of oh22data AG, a Microsoft Gold Partner in Germany specializing in CRM and BI. His special interests are Azure, Data Governance and Integration, Visualisation Tools like SSRS, Power BI, Tableau, R, and SharePoint. He has worked with SQL Server since version 6.5 and is a founder and Board member of PASS Germany, a PASS Regional Mentor, and runs the Frankfurt PASS Local Group. For more than seven years he is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a Microsoft pTSP.</description>
      <twitter>@oengels</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ssis-components.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@oengels</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19026</importID>
      <name>Leonard Lobel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leonard Lobel (Microsoft MVP, Data Platform) is CTO and co-founder of Sleek Technologies, Inc., a New York-based development shop with an early adopter philosophy toward new technologies. He is also a principal consultant at Tallan, Inc., a Microsoft National Systems Integrator and Gold Competency Partner.

Programming since 1979, Lenni specializes in Microsoft-based solutions, with experience that spans a variety of business domains, including publishing, financial, wholesale/retail, health care, and e-commerce. Lenni has served as chief architect and lead developer for various organizations, ranging from small shops to high-profile clients. He is also a consultant, trainer, and frequent speaker at local usergroup meetings, VSLive, SQL PASS, and other industry conferences.

Lenni has also authored several MS Press books and Pluralsight courses on SQL Server programming.</description>
      <twitter>@lennilobel</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/lennilobel</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://lennilobel.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@lennilobel</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22811</importID>
      <name>Regis Baccaro</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Regis has more than 15 years of experience with SQL Server, SharePoint and .Net as an architect and developer. R#233;gis is a SQL Server MVP since 2014 and a frequent speaker at SQL conferences, a PASS Regional Mentor and the founder of SQL Saturday Denmark community event. He is also a certified industry trainer on the APS/PDW platform. In his freetime he is an avid runner, cook and farmer.</description>
      <twitter>@regbac</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/regisbaccaro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://theblobfarm.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@regbac</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24153</importID>
      <name>Scott Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Scott Klein is a senior consultant with SQL Solutions Group with over two decades of experience working with Microsoft SQL Server. Prior to SSG, Scott spent almost 10 years at Microsoft, traveling the globe as a technical evangelist training and speaking about SQL Server and Microsoft’s Azure data services. Scott’s recent focus has been on advanced analytics, including big data and IoT, providing real-world training to help bring intelligence to your data. Scott has authored several books focusing on data and data analytics. Scott is continuously striving and looking for ways to help developers and companies grok the wonderful world of data.</description>
      <twitter>SQLScott</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/sqlscott</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLScott</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24154</importID>
      <name>Scott Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Scott Klein is a senior consultant with SQL Solutions Group with over two decades of experience working with Microsoft SQL Server. Prior to SSG, Scott spent almost 10 years at Microsoft, traveling the globe as a technical evangelist training and speaking about SQL Server and Microsoft’s Azure data services. Scott’s recent focus has been on advanced analytics, including big data and IoT, providing real-world training to help bring intelligence to your data. Scott has authored several books focusing on data and data analytics. Scott is continuously striving and looking for ways to help developers and companies grok the wonderful world of data.</description>
      <twitter>SQLScott</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/sqlscott</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLScott</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14677</importID>
      <name>Glenn Berry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Glenn works as a Principal Consultant for Dr. DMV, LLC in Elizabeth, CO. He was a Data Platform MVP from 2007-2017, and he has a whole collection of Microsoft certifications, including MCITP, MCDBA, MCSE, MCSD, MCAD, and MCTS, which proves that he likes to take tests. His expertise includes DMVs, high availability, hardware selection, performance tuning, and Azure SQL Database.  He is also an Adjunct Faculty member at University College - University of Denver, where has been teaching since 2000. He has completed the Master Teacher Program at Denver University - University College. He is heavily involved in the SQL Server community, and is a frequent speaker at user groups, SQL Saturdays, and the PASS Community Summit.</description>
      <twitter>GlennAlanBerry</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/public-profile-settings?trk=prof-edit-edit-public_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://glennsqlperformance.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=GlennAlanBerry</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9873</importID>
      <name>Artur Santos</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Artur Santos, is a trainer  consultant with more than 14 years of experience. Using SQL Server from 6.5, has created several workshops e sessions in SQL Server  SharePoint. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20746</importID>
      <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Miloš Radivojević is a database consultant located in Vienna, Austria. He is Data Platform MVP and specializes in SQL Server for application developers and performance and query tuning. Currently, he works as a principal database consultant in bwin GVC (the largest regulated online gaming company in the world). He is co-founder of the SQL Pass Austria and speaks regularly at local and international database conferences. He is also co-author of the books SQL Server 2016 Developer's Guide, SQL Server 2017 Developer's Guide and Mastering SQL Server 2017.</description>
      <twitter>MilosSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://at.linkedin.com/pub/milos-radivojevic/1b/7bb/290/de</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://milossql.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MilosSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17076</importID>
      <name>João Lopes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jo#227;o Lopes is a SQL Server MCP working as BI Consultant with over 10 years of experience, currently a member of the consulting team at BI4ALL delivering data solutions to global clients using Microsoft BI tools.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLSniper</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/joaolopes</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLSniper</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15391</importID>
      <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niko Neugebauer is a Data Platform Consultant. A SQL Server MVP with over 20 years of experience in IT, he is passionate about the Microsoft Data Platform and community. Founder of the Portuguese SQL Server User Group and the main organizer of the first SQLSaturday event outside of North America (#78 Portugal), Niko speaks regularly at events such as PASS Summit, SQLRally, SQLBits, and SQLSaturday events around the world. Niko loves sharing information and knowledge and has authored over 130 blog posts on Columnstore Indexes, and regularly contributes to the open-sourced CISL library focused on Columnstore Indexes.</description>
      <twitter>NikoNeugebauer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pt.linkedin.com/in/webcaravela/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.nikoport.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=NikoNeugebauer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21335</importID>
      <name>Neil Hambly</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Neil Hambly is a SQL Server consultant, founder and consultant at Datamovements, a Gold Microsoft Data  Analytics Consulting company.
Neil has 20+ years in a variety of SQL Server roles and is an MCT. He is a regular presenter (200+ events) at user groups, and PASS events, including PASS Summit and SQLSaturday, and many UK events (SQLBits, SQLRelay). Neil is the leader of PASS London (UK), a Professional Development VC, a Melissa Data MVP, and a SQL Cruise Technical Lead, who loves Guinness, whisky, and dancing.</description>
      <twitter>Neil_Hambly</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/neilhambly</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataidol.com/NeilHambly</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Neil_Hambly</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15055</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo is co-founder and RD lead of perFact BV, a Dutch company that improves analysis methods and develops computer-aided tools to generate completely functional applications from the analysis deliverable. The platform for this development is SQL Server. In his spare time, Hugo likes to share and enhance his knowledge of SQL Server by frequenting newsgroups and forums, reading and writing books and blogs, and attending and speaking at conferences.
Hugo is also a SQL Server MVP since 2006.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14678</importID>
      <name>Glenn Berry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Glenn works as a Principal Consultant for Dr. DMV, LLC in Elizabeth, CO. He was a Data Platform MVP from 2007-2017, and he has a whole collection of Microsoft certifications, including MCITP, MCDBA, MCSE, MCSD, MCAD, and MCTS, which proves that he likes to take tests. His expertise includes DMVs, high availability, hardware selection, performance tuning, and Azure SQL Database.  He is also an Adjunct Faculty member at University College - University of Denver, where has been teaching since 2000. He has completed the Master Teacher Program at Denver University - University College. He is heavily involved in the SQL Server community, and is a frequent speaker at user groups, SQL Saturdays, and the PASS Community Summit.</description>
      <twitter>GlennAlanBerry</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/public-profile-settings?trk=prof-edit-edit-public_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://glennsqlperformance.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=GlennAlanBerry</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9303</importID>
      <name>Allan Mitchell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Allan Mitchell is a SQL Server MVP and runs elastio, a small consultancy helping customers to make informed decisions about their data storage and integration.  His focus is on enterprise search as well as real-time data integration.</description>
      <twitter>@allanSQLIS</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://onlysearch.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@allanSQLIS</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>11792</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11792</id>
          <name>Constantin Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>StreamInsight: Complex Event Processing by MS</title>
      <description>The number of sensors is growing and growing and brings us closer to the "Internet of things". Applications, that have to process a big amount of data from event streams are a logical consequence. Some developers might have heard from Reactive Extensions (Rx) already, but Microsoft offers with StreamInsight (SI) another comprehensive platform for these scenarios.

In this session you will learn what a great addition for your toolbox StreamInsight is, if you have to develop applications, that have to handle complex events (CEP- Complex Event Processing). See how you can start with this technologie and how easy it is to jump in for .NET developers.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16565</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16565</id>
          <name>Jen Stirrup</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advanced Data Visualisation with Reporting Service</title>
      <description>As a report creator and designer, it's your role to make the message of the data come alive for data consumers and decision-makers. This requires a balance between conveying the 'truth' of the data across to the target audience, in addition to making the report look interesting that it will draw people's attentions in the first place.

SSRS is one of the most widely-used Business Intelligence products within the Microsoft stack. Come to this session to pick up some tips and tricks for advanced reporting writing, that is also  in accordance with thinking by Data Visualisation gurus such as Stephen Few and Edward Tufte.
This session will cover more advanced and less well-known features of reporting services with Data Viz in mind!</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13973</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13973</id>
          <name>Etienne Lopes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing implementation techniques</title>
      <description>This session describes some performance boosters as well as performance killers and some techniques that can lead T-SQL queries, functions and stored procedures to take a few seconds instead of lots of minutes to execute.

For instance: 
- What is best, CTE’s or Temporary Tables? When?
- When joining more than two tables (or intermediate result sets), should we still care about the join order?
- Did you ever expect to see an Index Seek in your execution plan but what you find is an Index Scan, although you took care of parameter sniffing and your statistics are updated?
- Do you care about what isolation level you use?

Using real life based demonstrations, this session will provide answers to these and other questions.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24154</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24154</id>
          <name>Scott Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Azure Scalability with Federations</title>
      <description>With more and more companies moving to a cloud solution, the necessity to easily and efficiently scale their database solution is critical. This session will discuss how to scale SQL Azure using SQL Azure Federations, a recent addition to SQL Azure that provides the ability to build scalable, elastic, and multi-tenant solutions in SQL Azure. SQL Azzure Federations bring the sharding pattern into SQL Azure as a first class citizen as a way to achieve greater scalability and performance from the database tier of your application through horizontal partitioning at the database level. This session will look at Federations from a real-world point of view, by applying Federations to a real-life database. We will also look at performance benefits.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14677</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14677</id>
          <name>Glenn Berry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hardware 201: Selecting Database Hardware</title>
      <description>The foundation of database performance is the underlying server hardware and storage subsystem. Even the best designed and optimized database application can be crippled by an inadequate hardware and storage infrastructure. Recent advances in new processors and chipsets, along with improvements in magnetic and SSD storage have dramatically changed the evaluation and selection process compared to the past. Many database professionals struggle to keep up with new technology and often simply let someone else make their hardware selection and sizing decisions. Don't let this happen to you! This session covers current and upcoming hardware from both Intel and AMD.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23573</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23573</id>
          <name>Rui Quintino</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>"Faster than the speed of light"... with #MSBI</title>
      <description>What-if insights from your business data were just a few seconds/clicks away? What-if we could instantly explore our data with rich  fully interactive dashboards using the amazing new features of Excel 2013, PowerPivot and PowerView? Without needing to build auxiliary reference tables, complex dax or powerpivot modelling? What-if instead self-service we could be "instantly-served"? </description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34574</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34574</id>
          <name>André Kamman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to outsource yourself with a Powershell script</title>
      <description>Well, kidding of course. Someone needs to maintain those scripts :-)
But there is a lot of repetitive work that can easily be scripted. 
And powershell is so versatile that it can be used to make scripts that "think" the way a DBA thinks. 
It will solve problems or complete a task for you that includes reacting to various (un)expected circumstances.
I will show you how to use some cool new features of Powershell 3,  like workflows and web access, and I'll use some of my own scripts to demonstrate how this all comes together.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23488</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23488</id>
          <name>Ruben Pertusa Lopez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Sentiment analysis using SSAS 2012</title>
      <description>We live in a world of social data. There are tweets, Facebook posts, updates, book reviews or forum discussions written in Social Networks. As an insight, we can find sentiment in all these social texts. This session reviews some text mining and integration techniques for extracting and incorporating these insights from Big Data into our analytical platform.
Real life samples and practical demos will be shown using Microsoft technologies.
Co-speaker: Javier Torrenteras (SolidQ BI Manager)
</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20746</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20746</id>
          <name>Miloš Radivojević</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Identifying and Solving Sort Warning Problems</title>
      <description>Sometimes SQL Server spills sort operation to tempdb although there is no memory pressure. Why and when it happens and why SQL Server raises a "Sort Warnings" event and what does it mean you can find in this session. We will see how to identify this problem in SQL Server 2008 and more elegant in SQL Server 2012 and of course we can discuss how to prevent this problem.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19296</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19296</id>
          <name>Luis Canastreiro</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Availability Groups- Performance e troubleshooting</title>
      <description>Nesta sessão o objectivo passa por detalhar que ferramentas estão disponíveis para a monitorização de uma solução de AlwaysOn Availability Groups e que tipo de troubleshooting poderá ser empregue tentar resolver alguns problemas que podem surgir durante a implementação e utilização de Availability Groups.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9303</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9303</id>
          <name>Allan Mitchell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2012 SSIS Change Data Capture</title>
      <description>We are storing more and more data FACT  
We have less time to move data around our environment FACT 
Businesses want close to real-time analytics FACT. 
We therefore need to plan our data movement strategy better.  In this session I will show you the improvements to CDC being made in SQL Server 2012 and suggest why this is something you will want to know.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14678</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14678</id>
          <name>Glenn Berry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dr. DMV: How to Use Dynamic Management Views</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2005 introduced Dynamic Management Views (DMVs) that allow you to see exactly what is happening inside your SQL Server instances and databases with much more detail than ever before. SQL Server 2008 R2 adds even more capability in this area. You can discover your top wait types, most CPU intensive stored procedures, find missing indexes, and identify unused indexes, to name just a few examples. This session (which is applicable to SQL Server 2005 through 2012), presents and explains over fifty DMV queries that you can quickly and easily use to detect and diagnose performance issues in your environment.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15055</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15055</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>UDFs, or: How to kill performance in one easy step</title>
      <description>User-defined functions in SQL Server are very much like custom methods and properties in .Net languages. At first sight, they seem to be the perfect tool to introduce code encapsulation and reuse in T-SQL. So why is this feature mostly avoided by all T-SQL gurus?
The reason is performance. In this session, you will learn how user-defined functions feed the optimizer with misleading and insufficient information, how the optimizer fails to use even what little information it has, and how this can lead to shocking query performance.
However, you will also see that there is a way to avoid the problems. With just a little extra effort, you can reap the benefits of SQL Server and still get good performance.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9873</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9873</id>
          <name>Artur Santos</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Scripting SQL 2012  SharePoint 2013 Installation </title>
      <description>Scripting an intire Instalation  Configuration through Scripts  PowerShell</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19026</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19026</id>
          <name>Leonard Lobel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Geospatial Data Types in SQL Server 2012</title>
      <description>The geospatial capabilities in SQL Server are not only powerful, but easy and fun to use! In this session, Lenni shows you how to integrate location-awareness into your own applications with the geometry and geography data types. We’ll explore the planar and geodetic spatial models, spatial markup languages such as WKT and GML, and then put these concepts to use as we build several useful demos, (e.g., Bing Maps integration). Demos show how to use the geospatial methods to easily calculate area, length, and distance, and project new shapes based on intersection and overlap. Attend this session and embrace spatial programming today!</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15391</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15391</id>
          <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Project Hekaton</title>
      <description>Microsoft is looking to bring a brand new type of database for the OLTP systems – in-memory, codename 'Hekaton'. Promising some of the before unseen speed improvements, the aim is to reach 100 times improvement over existing traditional OLTP performance. One of the most exciting and promising projects of the SQL Server history, Hekaton is a beginning of a new SQL Server era. 
Dive with me into review of the some of the already available architectural information, we will be looking into the differences with the traditional 8K pages, trying to understand this new 'native' way of functioning for the SQL Server.  </description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11826</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11826</id>
          <name>Pedro Correia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>CAST([Transaction Log] as T.SQL) </title>
      <description>The aim of this session is to take the audience in a quest for the original (or equivalent) T-SQL, that was in the origin of the different transactions recorded, by inspecting the transaction log records and dissecting its data. In a session that tackles several internals storage issues, needed to fulfill its objective, we will go in a travel that starts by the end of the log and will, hopefully, only end at the birth of the database.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22811</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22811</id>
          <name>Regis Baccaro</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database development with SSDT</title>
      <description>SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT) is a toolset that allows professional database and application developers to carry out all their database design work for SQL Server and SQL Azure within Visual Studio. SSDT provides a rich SQL Server development experience with first class language services and VS integration, as well as declarative, model-based tools that can be utilized for both online and offline development. In this session we'll dive into Online and Offline development as well as the Productivity and tools that the SSDT team keeps providing to us.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17076</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17076</id>
          <name>João Lopes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Travel from Relational to BI</title>
      <description>In this session we will travel through the basic concepts of BI, address the differences between relational modeling (OLTP) and dimensional (OLAP) and present the Microsoft BI platform from the perspective of those who live in the relational world and aims to explore the potential of BI. This session will be co-presented with Fernando Marçal</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24153</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24153</id>
          <name>Scott Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Azure - What is it and why do you need it</title>
      <description>This session will take an exploratory look at Microsoft's cloud-based relational database offering. We'll lift the hood and look at its many benefits and features, and how it easily fills the need for a highly available and scalable database service in the cloud. We'll discuss how SQL Azure helps ease provisioning and deployment, and how Microsoft takes care of the physical administration so that developers and DBA's alike can focus on the aspects of their job they really care about.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16567</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16567</id>
          <name>Jen Stirrup</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mobile Business Intelligence - Apprentice Style!</title>
      <description>It's Friday afternoon and your boss has just set you an 'Apprentice' style challenge: to implement mobile Business Intelligence, using Microsoft technologies. Budget: meager. Delivery date: yesterday. How do you start? What's available? What can you deliver?

We will look at the mobile roadmap, but we will also look at what you can do - right now

Using mobile technology, come to this demo-rich session to discover a number of novel ways to implement mobile Business Intelligence from the technical perspective. We will look at a variety of ways to deploy mobile Business Intelligence, including Azure, SharePoint and SSRS.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10992</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10992</id>
          <name>Bruno Basto</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Internal Storage – P1 </title>
      <description>This session describes how SQL Server internally stores table data. Although you can use SQL without understanding the internals of data storage, a deep knowledge of how data is stored will improve the development of efficient applications. This session explores the basic of metadata that keeps track of data and index storage information. </description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21914</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21914</id>
          <name>Pedro Lopes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanting Memory Pressure</title>
      <description>This 400-level session is a deep-dive on the various types of memory pressure a SQL Server may experience, how to identify this type of bottleneck, and how the database engine copes with these scenarios.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21531</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21531</id>
          <name>Oliver Engels</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Quality rulez! Integration and Performance be</title>
      <description>With the new Data Quality Services (DQS) Microsoft has an offering for Data
Quality Management. This session gives you insights how to use DQS efficiently.
In demos you will understand best practises in setting up a knowledge base,
correct matching rules and how to integrate DQS to your processes as DQS is
never an island solution. DQS performance aspects and how to report your
quality improvements will round up the session. The session assumes that you
have already tested DQS and want to get further with this toolset.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19549</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19549</id>
          <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>READPAST  Furious:Transactions,Locking,Isolation</title>
      <description>Mark Broadbent is a SQL Server specialist since 1998 and has worked with numerous HA solutions, is the SQLCambs Chapter Leader and held the UKs first ever SQLSaturday in Cambridge.

He has presented at numerous events around the globe such as SQLBits 7/ 8/ 9, X, SQLRally Orlando, SQLRally Dallas, SQLRelay, SQLPASS 2011/ 2012 and many international SQLSaturday events and was awarded the Microsoft Community Contributor award in recognition of his contribution towards the SQL Server Community.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13644</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13644</id>
          <name>Enrique Catala</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Parallelism in SQL Server</title>
      <description>In this session we will discuss about the parallelism in SQL Server. We will talk about configuration parameters, parallel execution plans, parallel operators and more. We also will talk about problems and best practices.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20263</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20263</id>
          <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Windows Azure SQL Reporting for App developers</title>
      <description>This talk is about how to deploy a report server project to Windows Azure SQL Reporting report server, and provide initial information for application developers who integrate reports hosted by Windows Azure SQL Reporting in their applications, as well as develop management tools against SQL Reporting report servers.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21528</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21528</id>
          <name>Oliver Engels</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Closed Loop in Enterprise Information Management</title>
      <description>This session shows via live demonstration the use of Integration Services, Data Quality- and Master Data Services to create a closed loop information management solution, which cleans, standardize, merge and purges data all with the new data curation tools of SQL Server 2012. The session will also cover principals and best practises for each of the technology used.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22412</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22412</id>
          <name>Quilson Antunes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Data Compression</title>
      <description>SQL Server Data Compression</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13952</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13952</id>
          <name>Eladio Rincon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Scale-out scenarios with Transactional Replication</title>
      <description>Transactional Replication exists in SQL Server since 1995; It's an stable solution, reliable and scalable 
if it's used properly. Obviously is not a solution for everything so you will have to decide wether this technology
fits for your needs or not. In this session we will introduce the main concepts about transactional replication and two real cases to show the scale-out benefits
of this technology. At the end we will talk about common best practices for transactional replication.</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21335</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21335</id>
          <name>Neil Hambly</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Extended Events – Effective Usage</title>
      <description>Extended Events is a replacement for profiler, it will become the premium tool for capturing diagnostic data within SQL Server with its advanced capabilities, however like any new feature it can take time to learn, becoming effective with the tool can be a hurdle to its usage
This session is specifically focused to make you effective with the Extended Events feature by demonstrating some common troubleshooting examples
</description>
      <startTime>3/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>