<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #963 – Denmark – Virtual 2020</name>
    <startDate>9/26/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>400</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Brussels, Copenhagen, Madrid, Paris</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatDK</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Danmark</name>
      <street>Kanalvej 7</street>
      <city>Kongens Lyngby</city>
      <state>Capital Region, Denmark</state>
      <zipcode>2800 Kongens Lyngby</zipcode>
      <longitude>12.5087</longitude>
      <latitude>55.77302</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>773</importID>
      <name>Kapacity A/S</name>
      <label>Premium</label>
      <url>http://www.kapacity.dk</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14529.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14435.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2696</importID>
      <name>Melissa</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>http://www.melissa.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14876.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2678</importID>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://cloud.google.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14831.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2689</importID>
      <name>Red Hat</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://www.redhat.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14832.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2690</importID>
      <name>Datheos</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.fortyplustwo.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14827.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1928</importID>
      <name>dbWatch</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://cilbuper.se/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14439.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1520</importID>
      <name>CatMan Solution A/S</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.catmansolution.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14575.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14518.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101154</importID>
      <name>Nicky van Vroenhoven</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nicky van Vroenhoven is a BI professional focused at the Microsoft stack. He mainly works with Power BI, Power Platform and T-SQL. After working 9 years in BI-consultancy jobs in several industries and companies, he is currently working as a Lead BI Developer at the DWH team at Van Lanschot Kempen in The Netherlands. Nicky has spoken at several User Groups, SQL Saturday Events, and the Power BI World Tour and is the co-founder of the Power BI Days Netherlands. In addition he enjoys tweeting and blogging about topics like Power BI and Power Platform at https://nickyvv.com.</description>
      <twitter>https://www.twitter.com/nickyvv</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nickyvanvroenhoven/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.nickyvv.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://www.twitter.com/nickyvv</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107901</importID>
      <name>Andreas Bergstedt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>24+ Years in the IT Sector, Last 12 years in the BI Space, Passionate about knowing and understanding data and what business actually want from their information.</description>
      <twitter>AndreasBergstedt</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://za.linkedin.com/pub/andreas-bergstedt/10/119/274/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blog.bi360.ml</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndreasBergstedt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101752</importID>
      <name>Rune Ovlien Rakeie</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rune Rakeie has been working with databases for over 20 years, primarily with Microsoft SQL Server. Throughout the years, Rune has had many roles, including developer, database designer, solution architect, and all the way to production DBA. Today Rune works for EVRY as a Principal Consultant "focusing" on the different cloud vendor's Data Platform Services.
Rune is very active in the Microsoft Data Platform community and has held a position on the board for the Norwegian user group. For the last 3 years he has been running the largest Microsoft Data Platform conference on Norwegian soil, SQLSaturday Oslo.
In his spare time you can find Rune in the woods of his hometown, Arendal, enjoying his new found hobby, single track bicycling.</description>
      <twitter>runeo34</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=runeo34</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101322</importID>
      <name>Dennes Torres</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dennes Torres is a Data Platform MVP with more than 25 years of experience in the IT area. He improves Data Platform Architectures and turns data into knowledge. As a Brazilian living in Malta, Dennes works as a software developer and leads the Malta MDP User Group. Having the MCSE Data Platform, Business Intelligence, and Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) certifications, Dennes has been in love with database servers since he was  introduced to SQL Server 6.5, more years ago than he would like to admit.</description>
      <twitter>Dennes</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennestorres/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/dennes-torres/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Dennes</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100954</importID>
      <name>Kevin Chant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior Database Architect originally from the UK and now living in the Netherlands. Data Platform MVP and MCT.

Over 23 years experience in the IT sector, and has supported databases for companies in the top 10 of the fortune 500 list.

In addition to a lot of SQL Server experience also has a fair few Microsoft Certifications. In addition, was probably the last ever person in the world to gain the MCSD Azure Architect certification and has gained the latest Microsoft DevOps Engineer Expert certification. 

Has real life experience with SQL Server and Azure Devops. Currently SQL Server Product Owner of around 1,900 instances. 

In addition, done various things over the years for the Data Platform Community.</description>
      <twitter>kevchant</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-chant/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.KevinRChant.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kevchant</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103577</importID>
      <name>Rob Sewell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob was once a production SQL Server DBA, but is now generally found automating the Data Platform and providing training for clients. He has a passion for PowerShell, Data, and DevOps. He is an MVP, an officer for the DevOps PowerShell VG, and has spoken and volunteered at many PowerShell and Data events. He is a member of the committee that organises Data In Devon and the European PowerShell Conference. He is a proud supporter of the Data and PowerShell communities. 
 
He relishes sharing and learning and can be found doing both via Twitter @sqldbawithbeard and his blog sqldbawithabeard.com. He spends most of his time looking at a screen and loves to solve problems.</description>
      <twitter>sqldbawithbeard</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/robsewellsqldba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldbawithabeard.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqldbawithbeard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101562</importID>
      <name>Daniel Otykier</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Daniel Otykier is a Principal Architect at Kapacity A/S - a Danish consulting company dealing mostly with Business Analytics on Microsoft technology. He has 12+ years on Microsoft SQL Server, the BI stack and C#/.NET development.
He is the author of Tabular Editor, a free alternative for developing Analysis Services Tabular models, and as of 2019 he is also a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>DOtykier</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-otykier-2231876/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://tabulareditor.github.io/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DOtykier</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100964</importID>
      <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Uwe Ricken is working with IT systems since the 90’s. The primary passion for developments with Microsoft SQL Server expanded in 2007 with his engagement as a DBA for Deutsche Bank AG in Frankfurt am Main. After 6 years of operational experiences as a DBA and over 14 years as a developer of complex database models he achieved the “Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008” certification which “was” the highest technical certification. In the same year he earned his first award as a Data Platform MVP for his support to the Microsoft SQL Server community in Germany and Europe. Uwe Ricken is a speaker on many international conferences and events and preferred topics are “Database Internals”, “Indexing” and “Development”.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dbBerater</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=270775013amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmaster.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dbBerater</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103284</importID>
      <name>Lorenzo Vercellati</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Graduated in Medieval History, I've been working with databases since 2000 and with Microsoft Data Platform since SQL Server 2005. I'm Senior Developer at SolidQ Italy and I love Data storytelling and visualization</description>
      <twitter>@supergimi</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lorenzovercellati/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@supergimi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101943</importID>
      <name>Asgeir Gunnarsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ásgeir Gunnarsson is a Data Platform MVP and Chief Consultant at Datheos in Denmark. He works on Business Intelligence solutions using the whole of the Microsoft BI stack. Ásgeir has been working in BI since 2007 both as a consultant and internal employee. Before turning to BI, Ásgeir worked as a technical trainer and currently teaches BI courses at the Continuing Education Department of the University of Iceland. 

Ásgeir speaks regularly at events both domestically and internationally, and is the group leader of the Icelandic PASS Group, as well as the Icelandic Power BI User Group. 

Ásgeir is passionate about data and loves solving problems with BI.</description>
      <twitter>bidgeir</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://is.linkedin.com/in/asgeirgun</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bidgeir</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101033</importID>
      <name>Gethyn Ellis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gethyn is a SQL Server consultant and trainer and has worked with SQL Server for nearly 20  years. He specialises in version mIgration,  performance, security, architecture and design including Azure and virtualisation solutions. He is working with private and public sector organisations in the UK, Europe and USA.

Gethyn delivers a range of SQL Server training, including the Microsoft Official Curriculum. He is the author of three training courses and two published books on SQL Server and Azure. You can find his blog at www.gethynellis.com</description>
      <twitter>gethyn_ellis</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/gethynellis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gethtynellis.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=gethyn_ellis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>102502</importID>
      <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>José Manuel Jurado currently works as SQL Escalation Engineer and Subject Matter Expert in Azure SQL Database at Microsoft Spain. With over 20+ years of experience in SQL Server environments (administration and database development), he is a speaker for internal events at Microsoft and for public events such as SQLSaturday, SQL Nexus, SQLBits, Pass Summit, SQL Server Konferenze, TechReady, DotNetConference, and Azure BootCamp. In the past, he worked as Project Manager for large global retail company for more than 10 years developing projects using different Microsoft Technologies.</description>
      <twitter>jmjuradodiaz</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-manuel-jurado-diaz-5a586014/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jmjuradodiaz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100916</importID>
      <name>John Martin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Martin is a Data Platform Engineer working in the financial sector, as well as Vice President Marketing for the PASS organization and currently a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Previously John has worked as a product manager for SentryOne and a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft UK.

John has over a decade of experience working with SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. Working as a DBA, developer and consultant for Microsoft, he has been lucky enough to see how best, and how not, to use SQL Server and the Data Platform effectively.</description>
      <twitter>SQLDiplomat</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/johnqmartin/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mssqltips.com/sqlserverauthor/291/john-martin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLDiplomat</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107523</importID>
      <name>Erwin De Kreuk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erwin de Kreuk is a passionate and very experienced Microsoft Solution Architect. 
Working as a Principal Consultant/ Lead Data and AI for InSpark, #1 Microsoft Partner of the Year in the Netherlands. Speaking at different national and international data community events.
He is working in the world of data on the Microsoft Platform for last 12 years and the last 4 years he has shifted his focus to the Azure Platform. 
Answering complex customer cases and technical issues are part of his day-to-day work. In addition to this work, he is a member of the Technology Board within InSpark and leads a team of highly experienced Data Expert in the field of Microsoft Data Platform.</description>
      <twitter>ErwindeKreuk</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nl.linkedin.com/in/erwindekreuk</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://erwindekreuk.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ErwindeKreuk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101013</importID>
      <name>Hylke Peek</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hylke is a BI and Data Analytics consultant. He delivers data and BI solutions for various organizations for more than 10 years. His focus is SQL Server, Azure, Power Platform and Python. But he founds everything interesting, as long as it involves data.

Hylke also provides training on these topics and speaks regularly on national and international events. The biggest fun of all this? Gaining new knowledge!</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/HylkePeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/hylkepeek/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/HylkePeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107466</importID>
      <name>Tariq Younas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tariq Younas (Azure MVP) is a senior technology specialist holding 14+ years experience in Microsoft technologies particularly Azure/ Azure Stack Hub (Hybrid Cloud)/ SharePoint / Office 365/ DevOps Automation and cloud-native architectures.

His areas of interest include Public/ Hybrid Cloud, IoT, Edge computing and Enterprise Architecture. He worked on application modernization and several IaaS/ PaaS migrations successfully. He is an international speaker/ author and member of (IASA Global) an Association for All IT Architects and AEA (Association of Enterprise Architects).

Recently he has been awarded by Microsoft (MVP) award for Azure. 

MVP public profile: MVP public profile: https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/PublicProfile/5003659</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/tariq_younas</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tariqyounas/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://TariqYounas.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/tariq_younas</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107465</importID>
      <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wolfgang Strasser creates solutions based on the Microsoft Data Platform tools in his day-to-day job as Business Intelligence consultant. Either using SQL Server Database Engine, SSIS, reporting with SSAS and SSRS, implementing Power BI solutions or cloud tools for data analysis - the data-tools-landscape is broadening every day! Based on his professional careers as a software developer he likes to work on structured development processes.
Wolfgang shares his knowledge with the community at many national and international events. For his community work, Wolfgang has been awarded with the Microsoft MVP Award for Data Platform in October 2015</description>
      <twitter>wstrasser</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/wolfgang-strasser/7b/912/22b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://workingondata.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=wstrasser</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100917</importID>
      <name>John Martin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Martin is a Data Platform Engineer working in the financial sector, as well as Vice President Marketing for the PASS organization and currently a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Previously John has worked as a product manager for SentryOne and a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft UK.

John has over a decade of experience working with SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. Working as a DBA, developer and consultant for Microsoft, he has been lucky enough to see how best, and how not, to use SQL Server and the Data Platform effectively.</description>
      <twitter>SQLDiplomat</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/johnqmartin/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mssqltips.com/sqlserverauthor/291/john-martin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLDiplomat</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>102806</importID>
      <name>Simon Whiteley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Simon Whiteley is the Director of Engineering for Advancing Analytics Ltd and a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Simon is a seasoned solution architect and technical lead with well over a decade of Microsoft Analytics experience. A deep techie with a focus on emerging cloud technologies and applying "big data" thinking to traditional analytics problems, Simon also has a passion for bringing it back to the high level and making sense of the bigger picture. When not tinkering with tech, Simon is a death-dodging London cyclist, a sampler of craft beers, an avid chef, and a generally nerdy person.</description>
      <twitter>MrSiWhiteley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/pub/simon-whiteley/32/994/aa8</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.adatis.co.uk/blogs/simonwhiteley/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MrSiWhiteley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107510</importID>
      <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen, as the founder of Savory Data, has a long history of providing customer solutions in the areas of data engineering, data science, and Business Intelligence. He is a certified software engineer, a graduated business educator, and professor of Databases  Project Management at HTL Leonding, and is certified as an MCSE  MCT. He is a published author and writes articles for well-known journals. He co-founded PASS Austria and organizes SQLSaturdays in Austria. Markus is a founding member of Power BI Usergroup Austria. Since 2017 Markus was awarded as an Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>MEhrenmueller</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markus-ehrenmueller/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.savorydata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MEhrenmueller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100922</importID>
      <name>Johan Ludvig Brattås</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Johan Ludvig Brattås is a managing consultant at Capgemini, and a dedicated community guy. He has worked with MS SQL server since late 1999, mostly with BI in one form or another. The last 6 years, most of his work has been in Azure working on data platforms, Power BI and the last three years expanding to Azure IoT and Stream Analytics.

Combining his passion for Microsoft SQL Server with his passion for sharing knowledge, he has spoken at various events in the SQL Community. This is also a way to give back to the community for all the things he has learned over the years. When not working, Johan Ludvig either spends his time with his kids, playing with new technology, or teaching coeliacs how to bake glutenfree food.</description>
      <twitter>intoleranse</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/johanludvig/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://brattas.org/sqlmusings</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=intoleranse</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>102871</importID>
      <name>Erik Svensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Microsoft MVP - Dataplatform
Leader of Denmark - Power BI Usergroup

Passionate about Power *, Excel , Analysis Services, Reporting Services.

CTO @CatManSolution - delivering a BI as service solution for suppliers to FMCG Retailers based on the Microsoft BI Stack</description>
      <twitter>@donsvensen</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/eriksvensen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://eriksvensen.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@donsvensen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107536</importID>
      <name>Marco Russo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marco is a Business Intelligence consultant and mentor. He wrote several books about Power BI, Analysis Service, and Power Pivot. He also regularly writes articles and white papers that are available on sqlbi.com. Marco is a Microsoft MVP and an SSAS Maestro, the highest level of certification on Microsoft Analysis Services.
Today, Marco focuses his time with SQLBI customers, traveling extensively to train and consult on DAX and data modeling for Power BI and Analysis Services. Marco also teaches public classes worldwide.
Marco is a regular speaker at international conferences like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and SQLBits. He also enjoys delivering evening sessions at local user groups during his trips.</description>
      <twitter>marcorus</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlbi</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlbi.com/blog/marco</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=marcorus</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107529</importID>
      <name>Marc Lelijveld</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Power BI enthusiastic, public speaker and passionated for everything which transforms data into action! Working at Macaw in the Netherlands as a Data  Analytics consultant.

What I like the most? Sharing my thoughts, experience, best-practices and enthusiasm about Power BI and related Microsoft Products with others. I mostly do this in public speaking for the user group, conferences, customer presentations and end-user training. But wouldn't it be great to cross borders and expand the community!</description>
      <twitter>@Marclelijveld</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://linkedin.com/in/marclelijveld</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://data-marc.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Marclelijveld</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100909</importID>
      <name>Chris Taylor</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris (@SQLGeordie) is a Principal Consultant working at Jarrin Consultancy providing SQL Server and Microsoft Azure consultancy to clients worldwide in a variety of industries ranging from Financial to Healthcare. He has been working with SQL Server since 2001 and during that time has become extremely strong in all areas of SQL Server but specialises in Security, System Optimisation and SQL Server Internals.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLGeordie</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/jarrinuk2000</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.chrisjarrintaylor.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLGeordie</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101091</importID>
      <name>Will Velida</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Will Velida is a Software Engineer working at ASB Bank in Auckland New Zealand. While at ASB Bank, he has worked in a variety of teams, including working in the Big Data team, Data Science and Analytics team and in the Payments team doing some awesome things in the cloud using Azure Functions and Cosmos DB! In his down time, he likes to hike around New Zealand and do the odd kayaking when the opportunity arises.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/willvelida/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107520</importID>
      <name>Hasan Savran</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hasan Savran is a BI Architect at Progressive Insurance Company. He spends his days architecting cutting edge business solutions by using the latest Web and Database technologies. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer.
Hasan has spoken at many SQL Saturdays, Code Camps and User groups. He is an active member of the HTML5 and WebAssembly W3C groups. He likes to write about SQL, CosmosDB, C#, and Front End development on his blog.</description>
      <twitter>Savranweb</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/hasansavran/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://h-savran.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Savranweb</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107462</importID>
      <name>Koen Verbeeck</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Koen Verbeeck is a Business Intelligence professional working at AE. He helps clients to get insight in their data and to improve their business intelligence solutions. Koen has a decade of experience in developing data warehouses, cubes and reports using the Microsoft Data Platform. Koen has a blog at sqlkover.com and writes articles for MSSQLTips.com. He has been awarded the Microsoft Data Platform MVP award in 2017.</description>
      <twitter>Ko_Ver</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://be.linkedin.com/in/kverbeeck</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlkover.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Ko_Ver</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107537</importID>
      <name>Dave Ruijter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave is Technology Consultant Data  Analytics and Microsoft MVP, bringing a decade’s worth of Microsoft Azure Data Platform and Power Platform experience to the table. He is a very passionate Power BI evangelist, eager to share his knowledge and experiences from the field.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/daveruijter</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/daveruijter</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://moderndata.ai</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/daveruijter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>100916</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100916</id>
          <name>John Martin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cloud Dev</name>
      </location>
      <title>Infrastructure as Code: An Introduction to Terraform</title>
      <description>Building reliable and repeatable infrastructure deployments thatcan be transitioned through Development, Test, and into production is becoming increasingly essential. There are many options including PowerShell, ARM, Cloud Formation and many more that you can use depending on your cloud of choice. But what if you want vendor lock in? Enter Terraform. An open source Infrastructure as code platform that works with Azure, AWS, and others as well as on-premises environments.

Together we will work through the what, why, and how of infrastructure automation with Terraform for building solutions. We will build a data platform solution and look at how we can transition through environments with VSTS and integrate this into development and operations processes that will let you concentrate on delivering more value to your users.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101154</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101154</id>
          <name>Nicky van Vroenhoven</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Power BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Form, a Flow and a Power BI Streaming Dataset Walk Into a Bar</title>
      <description>This is a live demo session that demonstrates the Microsoft Power Platform of products working together to create an interactive data application.

It's good to have some form of interactivity in your presentation. Whether it's by (live) polling your audience, telling a story, asking questions during your presentation or any other way to make your presentation more interactive, doesn't really matter.
The way I started doing this was by firing some questions at the audience after I introduced myself. Although that worked pretty well, I was asking closed questions with a show of hands. 
But as I work with the Power Platform suite of products I thought it was a good idea to use some of that Power! In this session I will show you:
- Create a form with Microsoft Forms,
- Create a Power Automate flow to get the answers,
- Push them into a Power BI streaming dataset,
- And finally create a Power BI report and dashboard on that dataset to get a live view of the answers of the audience.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101033</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101033</id>
          <name>Gethyn Ellis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure DB</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure DB</name>
      </location>
      <title>Top 5 Skills that a DBA will need in 2020</title>
      <description>It’s the year 2020 about ten years ago many people were writing about the demise of the DBA and how they won’t be around in ten years time. As we move into a new decade, and those ten years have passed the DBA role is still alive and kicking. Albeit, it has evolved in the last ten years and it has changed considerably since I started my career in the early 2000s.
In this session we will look at what skills you would expect a DBA to have in 2010 and compare it to what they will need in 2020. No doubt we will be covering:
•	New versions of SQL Server
•	Automation and PowerShell
•	Continuous integration
•	Cloud technology
•	Maybe some non-technical skills too
If you want to get my take on what skills a DBA needs to have in the Roaring 20s then this session is for you.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100909</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100909</id>
          <name>Chris Taylor</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Platform</track>
      <location>
        <name>Data Platform</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database CI/CD with Containers and Azure DevOps</title>
      <description>Containers are becoming ever popular but other than spinning one up to have a play around with the latest SQL Server 2019 CTP's new features, what else can they be used for?

In this demo heavy session we will show how Containers along with Azure DevOps can work for your CI/CD pipeline.

You will leave this session with the knowledge and ability to start creating your own bespoke SQL Server on Linux development / testing environments with automated image builds and releasing to Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) along with some of the issues / pitfalls of doing so. 

Pre-Requisite:
To get the most out of this session a basic understanding of what Docker/Containers are, is recommended.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101091</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101091</id>
          <name>Will Velida</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cloud Dev</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to building Machine Learning pipelines and models using ML.NET</title>
      <description>f you're a .NET developer, you may be forgiven for thinking that in order to build awesome machine learning applications, you'll have to brush up on your Python skills in order to use ML libraries.

With the release of ML.NET, this is no longer the case!

In this session, I'll cover what ML.NET is and how you can use it to add machine learning capabilities to your .NET applications. I'll cover the capabilities that the API offers in terms of preparing our data and evaluating our models. I'll also talk about the capabilities that the ML.NET Model builder and how that can simplify how we choose what type of model we want to build. I'll also talk about how we can deploy our models into production.

By the end of the session, you'll know how you can leverage your existing C# skills to use ML.NET to build machine learning applications!</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100964</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100964</id>
          <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Platform</track>
      <location>
        <name>Data Platform</name>
      </location>
      <title>Analyze and solve common wait stats scenarios</title>
      <description>SQL Server is a high frequently used piece of software which need to serve single requests and/or hundreds of thousands of requests in a minute. Within these different kinds of workloads Microsoft SQL Server has to handle the concurrency of tasks in a fashion manner. This demo driven session shows different scenarios where Microsoft SQL Server has to wait and manage hundreds of tasks. See, analyze and solve different wait stats due to their performance impact:
- CXPACKET: when a query goes parallel
- ASYNC_IO_COMPLETION: speed up IO operations (Growth / Backup / Restore)
- ASYNC_NETWORK_IO: What happens if your application refuses data?
- THREADPOOL starvation: crush of requests for Microsoft SQL Server
- PAGELATCH_xx: How does Microsoft SQL Server protects data?</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101943</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101943</id>
          <name>Asgeir Gunnarsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Power BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>What's Going On in My Power BI Environment?</title>
      <description>As Power BI is a self-service tool, it can be hard for administrators to monitor it. Power BI is fast improving in this context but there still isn’t a consistent way of monitoring it. There are compliance, governance, performance, and implementation questions to consider. Who is creating content, how is it being distributed, what data is being used, how long does the refresh take and how is it changing, who has a trial license, and what report is the most used? These are just some of the questions you as an administrator of Power BI might want to get answers to. 

In this session, we will look at how you can find those answers by monitoring Power BI. We will look at the Power BI Audit log for usage, license, and other audit information. We will look at what the Power BI API can show us about data sets, refresh history, Enterprise Gateway information, premium capacity, and artifact inventory. The audience leave the session ready to start their own monitoring of all or some of the topic</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101752</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101752</id>
          <name>Rune Ovlien Rakeie</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cloud Dev</name>
      </location>
      <title>Easing the pain of database migrations to the cloud - Planning, process and great tools!</title>
      <description>An essential part of migrating your application workload to the cloud is how to transfer your data securely to its new home. If you in addition want to change the underlying database system, for instance Oracle to SQL Server, it can quickly escalate to an overwhelming task. What if your application have a very high uptime requirement and your database is so large that you don’t not have a downtime window long enough to do a traditional backup/restore operation? In order to overcome these pain points we have now available, both in Azure and AWS, services and tools that alleviate these pains and brings your valuable data safely across with near-zero downtime.

In this talk we will:
- Guide you through how to set up a migration process with checks and balances
- Compare the schema analysis and conversion tools provided by AWS and Microsoft
- Compare the migration services provided by AWS and Azure
- Demonstrate near-zero-downtime migration for a live database on AWS and Azure</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>102806</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>102806</id>
          <name>Simon Whiteley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advancing Databricks - Next Level ETL</title>
      <description>Azure Databricks has been around for a while now, and Apache Spark since 2012. You've watched a couple of demos, got a brief overview of what Databricks does and you've got a rough idea of where it fits in… but where do you go from there?

This session is that next stop. We'll start by taking a deeper look inside the spark engine, understanding what makes it tick and how it talks to data. We'll then break down some of the key features that come together to build the kind of data processing task that's changing how we think about ETL.

We'll be looking at:
 - RDDs  How data is stored
 - Schema Inference
 - Storing Metadata
 - Parameters in Notebooks
 - Integration with Data Factory

Each of these features comes together to build a single, generic notebook that can validate the rows within a dataset that meet a specific structure, and it's all driven by metadata!

We'll be doing everything in python, so a light familiarity will help but is not mandatory</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100917</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100917</id>
          <name>John Martin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure DB</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure DB</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting Started with Azure SQL Database</title>
      <description>AzureSQL Database has gone from being a simple PaaS relational database to a more complex service with different service options. Selecting the right service option and tier for your need can be difficult.

In this session I will explain the differences between SQL Database, Managed Instance, and Serverless as well as the Hyperscale options. Together we will look at the use casses where these will fit best and when you should not use them in order to deliver the best results for your data driven applications.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107901</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107901</id>
          <name>Andreas Bergstedt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cloud Dev</name>
      </location>
      <title>Synapse Beyond the Data Warehouse</title>
      <description>In this session we discuss the future roadmap of the Azure data platform and how the Synapse Analytic Workspace 
plays a pivotal role in the modern data architecture.

We also demonstrate the public preview features and some of the coming capability at GA.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107462</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107462</id>
          <name>Koen Verbeeck</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Platform</track>
      <location>
        <name>Data Platform</name>
      </location>
      <title>The modern Cloud Data Warehouse - Snowflake on Azure</title>
      <description>The era of cloud data warehousing has finally begun. Gone are the days where you had to provision expensive servers and spend days configuring and tweaking to get the technical details right. Using cloud infrastructure, we can skip past the technical set-up and start loading data immediately.

Snowflake is a vendor offering a native cloud data warehouse, hosted on Azure. In this session, we'll introduce you to this new technology and explain the important concepts to get you started. Walking out of this session, you'll have all the knowledge you need to embark a project with Snowflake.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107537</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107537</id>
          <name>Dave Ruijter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Platform</track>
      <location>
        <name>Data Platform</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Battle of Modern Data Architectures: Databricks vs Synapse vs ADF</title>
      <description>Have you had that moment, in doubt of which Azure service to use for your 'Modern Data Architecture'? There are so many good options... Maybe go for Azure Synapse Analytics? Or the Azure Databricks route? Or stick to the familiar Azure Data Factory (in combination with...)? Let's line them all up and start **The Battle of Modern Data Architectures**! We'll compare them using real use-cases and demos, and you will learn how to choose the best fit for each scenario!</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107510</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107510</id>
          <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Platform</track>
      <location>
        <name>Data Platform</name>
      </location>
      <title>From SQL to R – Leverage Your T-SQL Knowledge to Learn R</title>
      <description>You are already familiar with T-SQL and are eager to learn R but do not know where to start? Start from what you already know: T-SQL. Both languages have many things in common on some levels, but are very different on others. You will learn how to begin your first steps in the new language and how to perform the most common tasks, typical for R: statistics, machine learning  data visualization.
This session will kick you off to the new language by using analogies from T-SQL. You will learn how to write your first R-scripts, make usage of packages and will leave this session with a basic understanding of typical use-cases of R and how to integrate that into your existing environment with SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107465</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107465</id>
          <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Continuous Integration for the BI Developer</title>
      <description>In many cases and BI projects, the manual process of development and especially deployment of artefacts led to sleepless nights, emergency hotfixes, grey hair and many hours of stress.
Especially in BI development, the usage of database projects, unit testing, version control, continuous integration and deployment is an underrepresented area.
Join me in this demo-heavy session where I will guide you through the not-so-frightful jungle of continuous integration using SQL Server database projects, SSIS, T-SQLt and Azure DevOps etc.
After this 60 minutes you'll have the guidelines and some ideas how easy it is to change your manual BI development and deployment into a powerful and automated no-brainer that - just works!</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100954</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100954</id>
          <name>Kevin Chant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cloud Dev</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure DevOps duet (90 minutes version)</title>
      <description>Welcome to Azure DevOps Duet, a tale about how a development team and an operations team have to bond together and start using Azure DevOps for SQL Server related deployments.

This session will cover the process of developing a CI/CD process starting at getting the team on board and ending with making an actual release.

We will discuss

- the challenges of implementing DevOps
- setting up a database solution project
- getting started with source control
- testing your database releases using tSQLt
- setting up your Azure Devops pipelines

After this session you will have the tools and knowledge to get started with DevOps and get your development process to the next level.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107520</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107520</id>
          <name>Hasan Savran</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure DB</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure DB</name>
      </location>
      <title>How does Azure Cosmos DB work under the hood?</title>
      <description>To master any technology, you need to understand the foundation of how it works on the backend first. We will explore Azure Cosmos DB's infrastructure, I will explain you how Azure Cosmos DB works in the backend in this session. We will cover the basics and some of the most misunderstood features like Partitioning, Multi-Model APIs and Consistency Levels of Azure Cosmos DB. 
Learning new technologies make you a better leader and collaborator. Join me to learn more about this new Cloud Database technology.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107523</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107523</id>
          <name>Erwin De Kreuk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Platform</track>
      <location>
        <name>Data Platform</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Key Vault, Azure Dev Ops and Data Factory how do these Azur</title>
      <description>Can we store our Connectionstrings or BlobStorageKeys or other Secretvalues somewhere else then in Azure Data Factory(ADF)? Yes you can! You can store these valuable secrets in Azure Key Vault(AKV).
But how can we achieve this in ADF? And finally how do we deploy our DataFactories in Azure Dev Ops to Test, Acceptance and Production environments with these Secrets ? Can this be setup dynamically?
During this session I will give answers on all of these questions. You will learn how to setup your Azure Key Vault, connect these secrets in ADF and finally deploy these secrets dynamically in Azure Dev Ops. As you can see a lot to talk about during this session.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101562</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101562</id>
          <name>Daniel Otykier</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>What's New in Tabular Editor</title>
      <description>If you're building Analysis Services Tabular models, you've probably already heard of a small tool called Tabular Editor. The tool was released to the public a little over 3 years ago, and a lot has happened since then! In this session, I'm going to demonstrate the newest additions to the tool. Regardless of your experience level with Tabular Editor, I promise that you'll find many of the new features interesting, and that you won't ever look back to Visual Studio/SSDT for Tabular model development.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100922</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100922</id>
          <name>Johan Ludvig Brattås</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Creating an modern data platform in the cloud</title>
      <description>Planning on creating a new data platform? Come join one of Norway's most experienced solutions architect to learn the Do's and Don'ts on cloud data platforms as well as design patterns and which services to choose where.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>102871</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>102871</id>
          <name>Erik Svensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Power BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Paginated Reports - How to and why should I care</title>
      <description>Power BI Report Builder is the tool to build paginated reports in Power BI and even though its a Power BI Premium feature - it could be a handy tool in your BI toolset that you should know about.

I will demo how you can build reports based on a Power BI dataset and how to parameterize the report.

I will also show how you can use paginated reports without having a Power BI premium capacity by using Power BI Embedded SKU's to create datadriven subscriptions.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101013</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101013</id>
          <name>Hylke Peek</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Common Data Service, why is it not common yet?</title>
      <description>Within the Power Platform, there's a data store called Common Data Service (CDS). But why would you use it? You've several hundred connectors allowing you to connect to almost every type of data storage. Well, CDS is an easy way to define and centralize business logic over multiple, interconnected applications handling various types of data.

In this session, we have a good look at CDS and find his strengths and weaknesses. We'll see how to build, ingest and extract data from CDS using demos. When you're using the Power Platform and/or curious about CDS but haven't used it yet, join me at this session.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107529</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107529</id>
          <name>Marc Lelijveld</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Power BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>External Tools for Power BI, how to create them!</title>
      <description>Power BI offers an add-in to work with 3rd party external tools like Tabular Editor, DAX Studio and ALM toolkit. The fact that you can use a tool of your own preference is already really cool! But did you know that you can build these tools yourself pretty easy? 

In this session I will show you how I build my model documentation external tool and how you can start doing this yourself!</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107536</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107536</id>
          <name>Marco Russo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Power BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using calculation groups in DAX</title>
      <description>Calculation groups are the most important feature introduced in DAX after variables in 2015. By using calculation groups, you can apply transformations to existing measures without having to create new measures in the model. For example, you can define the year-over-year calculation once and apply it to all the measures you want. Yet, calculation groups can do more than that.
This session introduces the syntax of calculation groups, when they should be used and several examples of use cases. You will also learn how calculation groups work internally and what are the limits of this amazing tool.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103577</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103577</id>
          <name>Rob Sewell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure DB</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure DB</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Notebooks in Azure Data Studio for the DBA</title>
      <description>An Azure Data Studio recent release introduced SQL Notebooks as a capability. While you might have read about notebooks being used for Data Science, this session is primarily for DBAs. 

We will cover installing Azure Data Studio.
What a SQL Notebooks is.
Using PowerShell in Notebooks in Azure Data Studio
Numerous use cases for you to use SQL Notebooks in your daily workload such as creating a Notebook for Glenn Berry's Diagnostic queries.

and some gifs ;-)
Prerequisites: Not having pogonophobia</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>102502</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>102502</id>
          <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure DB</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure DB</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to get the most from Azure SQL Database</title>
      <description>In this session we will show how to get the most advantages out from Azure SQL Database.
We will learn how to monitor the performance of our workload, how to improve it and how to secure it using the tools and features at our disposal on the Azure portal without having to install 3rd party tools.
We will also see some ways to lower the costs or increase performance without having to also increase costs.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103284</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103284</id>
          <name>Lorenzo Vercellati</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Power BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Power BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Datastorytelling  Visualization Best Practices with PowerBi</title>
      <description>What are the fundamental characteristics of Data Storytelling? How to use PowerBI not only as a data analysis tool but also as narrative data? During the session we will find out how the human brain reacts to what it sees and what are the most important best practices inherent in data visualization. We will also discover the main features of the most used visuals and when to use them or not to use them.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101322</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101322</id>
          <name>Dennes Torres</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure BI</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why Synapse Analytics is beyond Azure SQL Datawarehouse</title>
      <description>Synapse Analytics is being announced as the new name of Azure SQL Datawarehouse, but it's not only that. There is a broader view in Synapse analytics, beyond Azure SQL Datawarehouse. Let's see in this session what was improved, what changed, and how synapse analytics fits in the data platform.</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107466</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107466</id>
          <name>Tariq Younas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure DB</track>
      <location>
        <name>Azure DB</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL || SQL Server || Which one is right for me?</title>
      <description>While designing the solution or migrating to the cloud its important to consider the offerings of (Azure SQL vs SQL Server). In this talk, I will discuss the design and planning considerations for data services. This session will give understanding (IaaS) OR (PaaS) What to use When?</description>
      <startTime>9/26/2020 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/26/2020 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>