<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #921 – Pordenone – Virtual 2020</name>
    <startDate>5/30/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Sarajevo, Skopje, Warsaw, Zagreb</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat921</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Consorzio Universitario di Pordenone</name>
      <street>Via Prasecco</street>
      <city>Pordenone</city>
      <state>, Italy</state>
      <zipcode>33170</zipcode>
      <longitude>12.680547</longitude>
      <latitude>45.951774</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2678</importID>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://cloud.google.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14776.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14103.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2344</importID>
      <name>Wuerth Phoenix</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.wuerth-phoenix.com/it/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14565.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2342</importID>
      <name>Altitudo</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.altitudo.com/it/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14419.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2345</importID>
      <name>Fluentis</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.fluentis.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14421.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2353</importID>
      <name>palazzetti</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://palazzetti.it/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14423.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>422</importID>
      <name>Beantech</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.beantech.it</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14418.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>996</importID>
      <name>Realcomm Srl</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.realcomm.it/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14420.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1355</importID>
      <name>SolidQ</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.solidq.com/es</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14422.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105171</importID>
      <name>Fabrizio Saro</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>CEO e fondatore del gruppo Fluentis. 
Operativo nel mondo del software gestionale dal 1995 profondo conoscitore delle problematiche relative ai processi di business ed appassionato nell'evoluzione dei sistemi informativi azienali.
In azienda si occupa dell'analisi dei Trend tecnologici e continuamente impegnato nel deglinare gli stessi in soluzioni tangibili per i propri clienti e partner presenti nel territorio italiano ed internazionale.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.fluentis.com</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99544</importID>
      <name>Sergio Govoni</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Since 1999 Sergio Govoni has been a software developer; in 2000 he got a degree in Computer Science at "Università degli Studi" in Ferrara (Italy). He has worked for over 18 years in Centro Software, a software house that produces the best ERP for manufacturing companies that are export oriented. Now, he manages the development product team and he is constantly involved on several team projects, where he focues his attention on the architecture and the mission-critical technical details. Since 2016 he is the vice president of the UGISS (www.ugiss.org). For the provided help to technical communities and for sharing his own experience, since 2010 he has received the Microsoft Data Platform MVP award.</description>
      <twitter>@segovoni</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sgovoni</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mvp.microsoft.com/it-it/PublicProfile/4029181?fullName=Sergio%20Govoni</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@segovoni</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105135</importID>
      <name>Marco Giacomini</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Laurea in Scienze dell’Informazione e successiva Laurea in Informatica all’Università di Udine, Marco Giacomini è stato Professore di Sistemi Informativi Aziendali per cinque anni all’Università di Trieste presso la Facoltà di Ingegneria Industriale.
Ha percorso lo sviluppo professionale dell’ICT con particolare focus su temi quali le architetture software innovative, l’implementazione di servizi distribuiti, i servizi Cloud, e il software Industria 4.0.
E' presente dal 2014 nell’Albo degli Esperti in Innovazione Tecnologica del Ministero dello Sviluppo Economico (MISE), ed oggi è Innovation Manager.
È ideatore e progettista di software di livello nazionale, tra i quali IALMan, SmartMan, LabMan, HyperSCHED®, HyperMES® e ClincSmart.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/company/realcomm</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.realcomm.it/it/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98387</importID>
      <name>Gianluca Sartori</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gianluca Sartori is a Data Platform MVP, independent consultant and performance tuning specialist. He has been working in the software industry since 1999 and has been working with SQL Server ever since. He also works as a SQL Server trainer and in his spare time he writes technical articles and participates the SQL Server forums. Gianluca enjoys presenting SQL Server topics at conferences in Europe and in Italy in particular. He is currently working as lead DBA at a famous Formula 1 team.</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/#!/spaghettidba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://it.linkedin.com/pub/gianluca-sartori/23/50b/a12</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://spaghettidba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/#!/spaghettidba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101209</importID>
      <name>Tomaž Kaštrun</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tomaž Kaštrun is BI developer and data analyst. His main focus are data mining, T-SQL development, programming and query optimization. He has been working with SQL server since version 2000. He is Microsoft Certified Professional, Microsoft MVP for data platform and Microsoft trainer.</description>
      <twitter>@tomaz_tsql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/tomaz.kastrun</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tomaztsql.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tomaz_tsql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105150</importID>
      <name>Marco Pozzan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Consultant and trainer in business intelligence, analytics and data mining on Methode . Teacher for ITS courses of data warehouse at the University of Pordenone.</description>
      <twitter>@marcopozzan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://it.linkedin.com/in/marcopozzan</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.marcopozzan.it</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@marcopozzan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100192</importID>
      <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Martorana Tusa is a Business Intelligence Team Manager at Würth Phoenix,  the IT and consulting company of the Würth-Group. 
He is awarded as MVP in the Data Platform category

Former BI Specialist at Widex, a Danish manufacturing company, and BI Developer in the IT department of an Italian banking group. 20+ years of experience working with data. 
He is focused on the entire BI stack: database development, data warehousing, data analysis, reporting, etc. 
Andrea is a usual speaker at many events: SQLSaturdays, conferences in Europe and PASS Summit, and for PASS Virtual Groups. 

Andrea is an author for sqlshack.com, sqlservercentral.com, and UGISS (User Group Italiano SQL Server).</description>
      <twitter>bruco441</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bruco441</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101349</importID>
      <name>Kamil Nowinski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Blogger, speaker, #sqlfamily member. Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Data passionate, Data engineer and Architect.
Over 13 years of programming and experience with SQL Server databases, he worked both as developer and administrator big databases designing systems from the scratch. Passionate about tuning database engines, code transparency and maximising performance database engine.
Currently, he is expanding new horizons as a contractor in the UK market, making troubleshooting, prototyping BI and Big Data solutions, enhancing existing processes among Microsoft stuff environments, popularizing the DevOps approach and efficient solutions in the cloud.
An originator of the "Ask SQL Family" podcast and founder of SQLPlayer blog.</description>
      <twitter>@NowinskiK</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kamilnowinski/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlplayer.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@NowinskiK</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105120</importID>
      <name>Davide Cavalli</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>HR Recruiter in Consulcesi Tech, the ICT spin off of Consulcesi Group: the largest european network focused on services for professionals in the medical world.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://linkedin.com/in/cavallidavide</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100317</importID>
      <name>Riccardo Perico</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Back in 2010 I started working in Information Technology.
After a brief experience as ERP Consultant, I moved into Data Realm.

I spent these years exploring Data world from different points of view, both as DBA and Business Intelligence Specialist.

I'm a Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP), Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA) and Microsoft Certified Solution Associate (MCSA) in database, BI and Azure areas.

I'm one of the leaders of Power BI User Group in Milan and I'd been speaker during the Power Platform World Tour and Power Platform Bootcamp stops in Italy.

I'm also speaker during Azure Saturday and SQL Saturday events.

Last but not least, Hard Rock and Heavy Metal addicted!</description>
      <twitter>R1k91</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/riccardo-perico-8b942384/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://medium.com/riccardo-perico</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=R1k91</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101334</importID>
      <name>Riccardo Zamana</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I’m an accomplished, result driven management professional with 20 years of experience in both IT and business functions.
Proven history of managing complex IT operations and strategy for the development and delivery of high technological product and services.
I’m highly skilled in proposal development and delivering business results by creating tailor made Cloud and IOT based solutions around the specific customer needs. My passions are to architect and build up teams of qualified professionals, redesign and streamline of software processes integrating more departments, delivering perfectly governed eco-systems. Decisional trees based on microservices plots, especially in OSS sauce, represent my greatest fun. Even if I'm historically vot</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/riccardozamana/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.theazurefield.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105119</importID>
      <name>Dimitri Zornik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Solution Architect  Product Manager in beantech,
Planner and Data Analyst in LIDL  PBVi</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100223</importID>
      <name>Lorenzo Vercellati</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Graduated in Medieval History, I've been working with databases since 2000 and with Microsoft Data Platform since SQL Server 2005. I'm Senior Developer at SolidQ Italy and I love Data storytelling and visualization</description>
      <twitter>@supergimi</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lorenzovercellati/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@supergimi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98969</importID>
      <name>Marco Obinu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Curious by nature, talkative geek who can speak in front of a public or a camera, in love with technology, primarily SQL Server and Azure.
I'd like to understand how things work and to solve problems by myself.</description>
      <twitter>omegamadlab</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marco-obinu-omegamadlab/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.omegamadlab.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=omegamadlab</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105106</importID>
      <name>Dennes Torres</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dennes Torres is a Data Platform MVP with more than 25 years of experience in the IT area. He improves Data Platform Architectures and turns data into knowledge. As a Brazilian living in Malta, Dennes works as a software developer and leads the Malta MDP User Group. Having the MCSE Data Platform, Business Intelligence, and Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) certifications, Dennes has been in love with database servers since he was  introduced to SQL Server 6.5, more years ago than he would like to admit.</description>
      <twitter>Dennes</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennestorres/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/dennes-torres/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Dennes</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105131</importID>
      <name>Veronica Nuvolone</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Since graduating in Business Economics and Management, I understood that marketing would be my job vocation. At the beginning I had not considered Information Technology as the industry in which to express and improve my creative and communication skills. 
A bit by chance, I began my short work experience in this area and I was immediately fascinated. The data is "the new electricity" of every business and learning how to channel its value through social media was an opportunity that I could not lose. 
When I met SolidQ in 2016, I understood that it was my chance to learn from great experts and contribute to the creation and communication of the value of this company.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/veronica-nuvolone-b04820121/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100208</importID>
      <name>Mislav Karaula</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mislav is an experienced database developer, MCSE: Data Management and Analytics holder, has got a masters in mathematics and is a speaker at conferences. Works as a Senior Database Developer in Data Analytics Team in Span Plc. Designing, developing and optimizing enterprise data solutions with mathematical foundation rooted deep within the thinking process is what he does. Always striving for further challenges, passionate about all things data - databases, data warehouses, big data, data analytics, statistical data analysis, etc.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mislav-karaula/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100684</importID>
      <name>Francesco De Chirico</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Francesco De Chirico is a consultant, trainer and speaker specialized in modeling and developing complex BI solutions with the Microsoft BI stack. He has been working with SSAS since 2001 and has a strong knowledge of the MDX, DAX and M. He focused on all the Microsoft Data Platform especially on Power BI. Co-leader of the PASS Global Italian Virtual Group and Milan Power BI User Group, regular speaker at events like PASS SQLSaturday, Microsoft Certified Trainer for many years, Francesco holds several Microsoft certifications including the prestigious SSAS Maestro for BI certification (2012) and the Microsoft Professional Program Data Science certification (2017). He is the project creator of the Analysis Services Query Analyzer tool.</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/fdechirico</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/fdechirico</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://francescodechirico.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/fdechirico</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100683</importID>
      <name>Alessio Biasiutti</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have always been passionate about data and technology.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101101</importID>
      <name>Marco Pozzan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Consultant and trainer in business intelligence, analytics and data mining on Methode . Teacher for ITS courses of data warehouse at the University of Pordenone.</description>
      <twitter>@marcopozzan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://it.linkedin.com/in/marcopozzan</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.marcopozzan.it</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@marcopozzan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100674</importID>
      <name>Andrea Tosato</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior Software Developer at 4ward</description>
      <twitter>ATosato86</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/andreatosato/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.atosato.it</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ATosato86</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98621</importID>
      <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Martorana Tusa is a Business Intelligence Team Manager at Würth Phoenix,  the IT and consulting company of the Würth-Group. 
He is awarded as MVP in the Data Platform category

Former BI Specialist at Widex, a Danish manufacturing company, and BI Developer in the IT department of an Italian banking group. 20+ years of experience working with data. 
He is focused on the entire BI stack: database development, data warehousing, data analysis, reporting, etc. 
Andrea is a usual speaker at many events: SQLSaturdays, conferences in Europe and PASS Summit, and for PASS Virtual Groups. 

Andrea is an author for sqlshack.com, sqlservercentral.com, and UGISS (User Group Italiano SQL Server).</description>
      <twitter>bruco441</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bruco441</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99148</importID>
      <name>Rob Sewell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob was once a production SQL Server DBA, but is now generally found automating the Data Platform and providing training for clients. He has a passion for PowerShell, Data, and DevOps. He is an MVP, an officer for the DevOps PowerShell VG, and has spoken and volunteered at many PowerShell and Data events. He is a member of the committee that organises Data In Devon and the European PowerShell Conference. He is a proud supporter of the Data and PowerShell communities. 
 
He relishes sharing and learning and can be found doing both via Twitter @sqldbawithbeard and his blog sqldbawithabeard.com. He spends most of his time looking at a screen and loves to solve problems.</description>
      <twitter>sqldbawithbeard</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/robsewellsqldba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldbawithabeard.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqldbawithbeard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105176</importID>
      <name>Federico Favero</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Fondatore e CEO di Altitudo, Federico Favero ha una lunga esperienza nell’evoluzione delle soluzioni di business utilizzando le tecnologie Microsoft. Nella duplice veste di consulente e appassionato di innovazione tecnologica, lavora con l’obiettivo di tradurre le più recenti innovazioni tecnologiche in applicazioni concrete e fruibili dalle aziende. In Altitudo (www.altitudo.com), azienda Microsoft Gold Certified Partner che opera sul territorio italiano e all’estero, si occupa di soluzioni e progetti di Digital Transformation in cui l’intelligenza artificiale, i dati e le tecnologie di customer engagement sono utilizzate a supporto del miglioramento dei processi e della relazione con clienti e partner.</description>
      <twitter>federicofavero</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/federicofavero</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=federicofavero</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99593</importID>
      <name>Marco Dal Pino</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>He started working in IT in early '90.
Long experience in LOB application design and development for Retail, distribution and logistics market.
Trainer and Speaker in the main technical conference In Italy and overseas.
He is a staff member of DotNetToscana a community on Microsoft tech.
From 2013 Microsoft recognize him the title of MVP Most Valuable Professional
in May 2014 become Intel Software Innovator and later Intel Black Belt.
In 2017 joined Projest SPA as Senior Program Manager.
In 2020 he started working in Softjam SPA as Advisory Engineer and then in Microsoft as Cloud Solution Architect</description>
      <twitter>MarcoDalPino</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcodalpino/?locale=en_US</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mobileprog.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MarcoDalPino</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100693</importID>
      <name>andrea benedetti</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Benedetti è Architect SQL Server  BI nella divisione Servizi di Microsoft Italia dove ha la responsabilità dei progetti enterprise su tutta la data platform. SQL Server MVP dal 2004 a fine 2011, lavora con SQL Server fin dalla versione 6.5, è intervenuto come relatore in numerosi workshop, conferenze, seminari e roadshow. Appassionato di alpinismo (in solitaria) cura un blog in italiano. Scrive su Twitter come @anbenedetti.</description>
      <twitter>@anbenedetti</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/abenedetti</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.technet.com/b/andrea_benedetti_blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@anbenedetti</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100705</importID>
      <name>Gilberto Zampatti</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Time ago (a lot of time ago…) an excellent IT pro brought me with him and became my Mentor in the IT wonderland…it was a world full of mainframes…
I met the Relational theory when there were no commercial RDBMS, and I was spellbound by that “magic”. When Microsoft appeared in the IT market, I felt finally which trek I had to follow. I’m still walking on such road, and in my rucksack I’ve ben putting some other stuff (like SharePoint, for example). My sole regret:  I’ve left the College to consecrate all my time to my job; curiously, since then, I’ve never stop learning…</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105107</importID>
      <name>andrea benedetti</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Benedetti è Architect SQL Server  BI nella divisione Servizi di Microsoft Italia dove ha la responsabilità dei progetti enterprise su tutta la data platform. SQL Server MVP dal 2004 a fine 2011, lavora con SQL Server fin dalla versione 6.5, è intervenuto come relatore in numerosi workshop, conferenze, seminari e roadshow. Appassionato di alpinismo (in solitaria) cura un blog in italiano. Scrive su Twitter come @anbenedetti.</description>
      <twitter>@anbenedetti</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/abenedetti</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.technet.com/b/andrea_benedetti_blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@anbenedetti</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105132</importID>
      <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Martorana Tusa is a Business Intelligence Team Manager at Würth Phoenix,  the IT and consulting company of the Würth-Group. 
He is awarded as MVP in the Data Platform category

Former BI Specialist at Widex, a Danish manufacturing company, and BI Developer in the IT department of an Italian banking group. 20+ years of experience working with data. 
He is focused on the entire BI stack: database development, data warehousing, data analysis, reporting, etc. 
Andrea is a usual speaker at many events: SQLSaturdays, conferences in Europe and PASS Summit, and for PASS Virtual Groups. 

Andrea is an author for sqlshack.com, sqlservercentral.com, and UGISS (User Group Italiano SQL Server).</description>
      <twitter>bruco441</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bruco441</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98090</importID>
      <name>Gergely Csom</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data and AI expert with 15+ years of experience in various data warehousing, BI and AI projects in FSI, OilGas, Energy and Transportation. Experienced trainer, mentor, regular public speaker in various events. Nowadays building the best in class data team for helping our customers in their digital transformation journey in the super exciting Data  AI driven revolution. Running cloud  IoT pet projects nowadays in his free time:)</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/CsomGergely</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gergely-csom-27171670/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/CsomGergely</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100561</importID>
      <name>Danilo Dominici</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Danilo Dominici, lavora con SQL Server sin dalla versione 6.5. Si occupa principalmente di progettazione, implementazione ed ottimizzazione architetturale, monitoring e performance tuning.  Alterna le attivit#224; di consulenza a quelle di formatore, speaker ed autore. Microsoft Certified Trainer dal 2000 e SQL Server MVP dal 2014, #232; anche co-leader del PASS Global Italian Virtual Chapter, lo user group quot;virtualequot; in lingua italiana dedicato a SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>@danilo_dominici</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@danilo_dominici</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100914</importID>
      <name>Marco Parenzan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marco Parenzan is an independent Cloud and IoT Architect and .NET Developer. 
He has been awarded as a MVP on Microsoft Azure since 2014. 
He is a speaker in major community events in Italy about Azure and .NET development.
He is a community lead for 1nn0va, an official Microsoft community in Pordenone, Italy. 
He has written a book on Azure in 2016. 
He loves developing retrogames and reading comix.

Marco Parenzan è professionista per le architetture Cloud e IoT e lo sviluppo in .NET. 
Ha ricevuto il titolo di MVP su Microsoft Azure dal 2014. 
È uno speaker in Italia su Azure e lo sviluppo di .NET. 
E' un community lead per 1nn0va, una community ufficiale Microsoft a Pordenone, in Italia. 
Ha scritto un libro su Azure nel 2016.</description>
      <twitter>@marco_parenzan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://it.linkedin.com/in/marcoparenzan</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcoparenzan/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@marco_parenzan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100214</importID>
      <name>Danilo Dominici</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Danilo Dominici, lavora con SQL Server sin dalla versione 6.5. Si occupa principalmente di progettazione, implementazione ed ottimizzazione architetturale, monitoring e performance tuning.  Alterna le attivit#224; di consulenza a quelle di formatore, speaker ed autore. Microsoft Certified Trainer dal 2000 e SQL Server MVP dal 2014, #232; anche co-leader del PASS Global Italian Virtual Chapter, lo user group quot;virtualequot; in lingua italiana dedicato a SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>@danilo_dominici</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@danilo_dominici</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98904</importID>
      <name>Alessandro Alpi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alessandro lavora nell#39;IT dal 2000. La passione per l#39;informatica nasce ad 11 anni partendo dal C64 ed oggi #232; CTO di Engage IT Services srl dove si occupa della gestione del team di sviluppo e del contatto tecnico con i clienti.
Nel team si occupa anche dell#39;amministrazione e del ciclo di vita dei database. E’ MVP SQL Server dal 2008, #232; anche Microsoft Certified Professional, ed oltre ad essere speaker a diversi eventi Microsoft, segue due blog e risponde sui forum di StackOverflow e MSDN</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/suxstellino</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://it.linkedin.com/in/suxstellino</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://suxstellino.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/suxstellino</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100689</importID>
      <name>Luca Zavarella</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mentor  Technical Director at SolidQ Italy. He loves BI, Advanced Analytics and Machine Learning. He plays piano in the free time.</description>
      <twitter>@lucazav</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucazavarella/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/en/author/lzavarella/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@lucazav</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100736</importID>
      <name>Gianluca Hotz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gianluca Hotz is an independent consultant, trainer, speaker and Mentor specialized in architecture, database design, high availability, capacity planning, performance tuning, system integration and migrations for Microsoft SQL Server. He has been working as a consultant in the IT field since 1993 and with SQL Server since 1996. He is among the original founders of ugiss.org, where he served as vice-president from 2001 to 2016 and he is now serving as president, for his contribution to the community he has been a SQL Server MVP since 1998.</description>
      <twitter>glhotz</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://it.linkedin.com/in/ghotz</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ghotz.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=glhotz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101039</importID>
      <name>Francesco Milano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I've been working with Microsoft technologies since 2000, and I'm specialized in .NET Framework and SQL Server platform. I focus primarily on back-end development, integration solutions, relational model design and implementation. Starting from 2011 I'm also member of UGISS (Italian SQL Server User Group) and speaker at main italian SQL Server conferences and workshops.</description>
      <twitter>@_fmilano_</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://it.linkedin.com/in/fmilano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_fmilano_</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>98786</importID>
      <name>Marco Obinu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Curious by nature, talkative geek who can speak in front of a public or a camera, in love with technology, primarily SQL Server and Azure.
I'd like to understand how things work and to solve problems by myself.</description>
      <twitter>omegamadlab</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marco-obinu-omegamadlab/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.omegamadlab.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=omegamadlab</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100762</importID>
      <name>Marco Minerva</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marco Minerva si è dedicato a .NET fin dalla sua prima introduzione. Attualmente lavora come consulente freelance e si occupa di progettazione e sviluppo di applicativi basati sul Framework .NET, realizzando app per Windows, Xamarin e IoT, e soluzioni Web con ASP.NET, Web API e Azure. Organizza e tiene corsi di formazione. E’ co-fondatore e Community Leader di DotNetToscana. E' speaker ad eventi tecnici di livello nazionale e scrive articoli per riviste. E' Microsoft MVP per la categoria Windows Development.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/marcominerva</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcominerva</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://marcominerva.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/marcominerva</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>98621</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98621</id>
          <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Leverage Power BI automation using APIs and Flow</title>
      <description>Power BI is a cloud-based service; it means that it comes along with a standard set of APIs that provides access to its internal resources such as reports, datasets, rows.   
Using APIs gives more flexibility and allows to build custom dashboard applications either for administering or query the service.  
And if you combine the power of APIs with Microsoft Flow, you can automate some background processes such as adding users, granting rights, update or refresh datasets, ... 
The session is demo only. A complete walk-through to the process, will show you how to register an app, create a custom connector and leverage Power BI API actions by triggering a Microsoft Flow object. https://speakerscore.com/VK14</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 4:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 5:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101349</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101349</id>
          <name>Kamil Nowinski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</name>
      </location>
      <title>The databases in SSDT - a work with project and best practices</title>
      <description>A task seems to be easy. Maintenance a project of a database in the code repository, treat as master-version and do deployment evenly and frequently. Simple? Seemingly. The things become more complex as fast as a number of objects in database growing. While instead of one database, we have over a dozen. When databases have got the references to each other. And how about dictionary tables? Where to keep them and how to script? Additional issues are coming whilst we would like to control instance-level objects.
All these topics I will explain in the session focused on practical aspects of work with Microsoft Visual Studio Data Tools. https://speakerscore.com/25GX</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 11:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 12:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99544</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99544</id>
          <name>Sergio Govoni</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Processing improvements in the latest versions of SQL Server – IT</title>
      <description>How many times have you faced bad performances caused by incorrect rows-estimation or caused by multi-statement user-defined table valued functions? Have you ever seen a warning on Sort operator that spills data on tempdb caused by inadequate memory estimation? These are not the only problems we could have with queries optimization, but these are the three problems that SQL Server 2017 Adaptive Query Processing attempts to address. SQL Server 2019 introduces additional features and all of them are known with the name Intelligent Query Processing. This session will cover the Adaptive Query Processing first. Next we will cover, briefly, the features implemented in SQL Server 2019.
https://speakerscore.com/7QK2</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98090</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98090</id>
          <name>Gergely Csom</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building a modern data warehouse and BI solution in Microsoft cloud</title>
      <description>Data warehouse and BI market is evolving rapidly with the appearance of new cloud born technologies. We might assume, that moving an existing Microsoft based DWH to the cloud is an easy step, but when we dig a little bit deeper, we will see, there are many-many new technological choices and aspects on how to modernize an existing dwh/bi system in the cloud. Not to mention if we start everything from scratch in a new project designed specifically to the cloud to utilize cloud flexibility and innovation as much as possible. 
Which ETL tool should I use? Data factory v2 with SSIS and BIML, or Azure Databricks powered Dataflows? Or Power BI Dataflow? Which is the right decision to run OLAP workloads? Azure AS? Or simply Power BI? When do I need Azure SQL DWH?
In the last couple years I helped many customers to modernize their DWH landscape partially or fully in the cloud and during my presentation I will share my findings and recipes for the most common situation I met. You will have fun:) https://speakerscore.com/W9GC</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101039</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101039</id>
          <name>Francesco Milano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</name>
      </location>
      <title>A gentle introduction to Apache Spark for SQL Server people</title>
      <description>Lavorando con i dati, capita sempre più frequentmente di doversi confrontare con mondi che fino a poco tempo fa erano quasi estranei fra loro. 
SQL Server 2019, per esempio, introduce per la prima volta con i nuovi Big Data Cluster il supporto nativo ad Apache Spark, rendendo concreta la convivenza tra il carico di lavoro tipico di un engine relazionale e il calcolo distribuito.

Proveniendo da un ambiente SQL, l'approccio ad Apache Spark tramite il suo dialetto Spark SQL può sembrare molto naturale e poco ostico. La sensazione di "sentirsi a casa", però, non deve far dimenticare che l'engine sottostante ragiona in modo molto diverso da quello a cui siamo abituati.

In questa sessione proveremo ad avvicinarci ad Apache Spark partendo dalle sue basi, così da capire come ragiona e conoscerlo per affrontarlo al meglio. https://speakerscore.com/C4XR</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99593</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99593</id>
          <name>Marco Dal Pino</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Database EDGE, put your SQL wherever you want!</title>
      <description>Developing application for Smart city, Sensors, Industrial IoT increasingly need more affordable and powerful way to store data and manage it. 
Now we can also use the same approach we have in our client server distributed application even in remote deployed devices frquently not connected to internet.
Expand device architecture coverage to include ARM-based devices on top of x64-based architecture. Use Kubernetes to orchestrate your device infrastructure for better efficiency and automation. Run SQL Database Edge connected or offline to support various edge environments. https://speakerscore.com/NQXH</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101334</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101334</id>
          <name>Riccardo Zamana</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Moderm Data Science Lifecycle with ADX  Azure</title>
      <description>When you deal with data, you have to deal with many data sources and many data destinations too. Even Data science approach is changing, in terms of tools used for the various phases of work. Let's explore many use cases in which you have to use a time series database to explore data, retrieve insights and fill new databases. Azure Data eXplorer can be the ace up your sleeve with such situations. Let's have a deep dive into various Data science phases, and the correct approach tha must be done if you use ADX.
https://speakerscore.com/V5WR</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 11:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 12:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105106</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105106</id>
          <name>Dennes Torres</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Synapse Analytics: Beyond the Basics</title>
      <description>Let's discover how to configure Synapse Analytics in order to achieve better result from the MPP environment, going beyond the default configuration

Synapse Analytics, which is way beyond the former Azure SQL Data Warehouse, is focused on MPP, Multi Parallel Processing, being a very powerful environment for Data Warehouse processing. It's former name, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, usually pushed many DW and BI developers to use this powerful tool in order to build a Data Warehouse. However, just implementing the logical design of a Data Warehouse inside an MPP environment can be very deceiving, because many default settings for the MPP environment will not be at their best. On this session you will see how to configure the MPP environment to achieve it's best performance for your Data Warehouse. You will understand the importance to understand and control the distributions by compute nodes, how critical are the correct choice of resource classes and users, the benefits to correct manage.  https://speakerscore.com/Z111</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100192</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100192</id>
          <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advanced Analytics with Power BI</title>
      <description>Power BI makes advanced analytics handy for business users, allowing stakeholders to extract knowledge and insights from data, to solve business problems and make decisions.  
This session will introduce to the advanced analytics features of Power BI, showcasing some real word areas of application: forecasting, predictive analytics, machine learning algorithms, customer sentiment analysis.  
For every case it will also be covered the integration with all the complementary tools needed for building a working solution: Azure ML, Cognitive Services, R, Key influence visuals, ...
Discover how easy is using advanced analytics in Power BI to effectively address the business challenge and uncover new insights https://speakerscore.com/K866</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98969</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98969</id>
          <name>Marco Obinu</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Lift  Shift on Azure!</title>
      <description>Sempre più spesso le aziende migrano i propri datacenter, o parte di essi, in cloud. Quando si arriva alla componente SQL Server delle diverse isole applicative, ci si trova davanti alla possibilità di migrare il workload SQL su una pletora di servizi diversi, tra VM in IaaS e Azure SQL Database in PaaS. Analizziamo quali possono essere i driver che guidano la scelta di un percorso di migrazione verso Azure, quali strumenti usare e quali elementi possiamo andare ad introdurre nella soluzione affinché ci si possa avvalere dei benefici del cloud, evitando di fare l'ennesimo banale rehost che poco aggiunge rispetto a quanto avevamo on-premises. https://speakerscore.com/35R6</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 4:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 5:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98387</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98387</id>
          <name>Gianluca Sartori</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Monitoring SQL Server without breaking the bank</title>
      <description>Monitoring SQL Server can become a very expensive business. Sure, the market offers countless paid solutions, but what if you have a large server estate and your budget is tight? 
In this session we will combine multiple open source tools (InfluxDB, Telegraf , Grafana, DbaTools and many more) to collect important performance metrics, analyze the data they collect, set up alert for the critical events, troubleshoot issues and plan for the future. Join me and you will see how monitoring is not a business for billionaires. https://speakerscore.com/76VR</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 4:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 5:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100208</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100208</id>
          <name>Mislav Karaula</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</name>
      </location>
      <title>What can Azure do for your batch data analytics workloads?</title>
      <description>This session will cover developers' / architects' point of view towards what Azure data platform has to offer for batch data analytics workloads. The main focus is going to be on native Azure technologies, with a strong emphasis on how they can work in harmony to provide an on-demand scalable data collection, storage and analysis environment. Services such as Azure SQL Data Warehouse and Azure Synapse Analytics will be covered. https://speakerscore.com/S2G2</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 11:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 12:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105171</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105171</id>
          <name>Fabrizio Saro</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</name>
      </location>
      <title>IT market Clock for Database Management Systems</title>
      <description>IT market Clock for Database Management Systems</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 10:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 11:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100223</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100223</id>
          <name>Lorenzo Vercellati</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Datastorytelling  Visualization Best Practices with PowerBi</title>
      <description>Quali sono le caratteristiche fondamentali del Data Storytelling? Come utilizzare PowerBI non solo come strumento di analisi dati ma anche di data storytelling? Durante la sessione scopriremo come il cervello umano reagisce a ciò che vede e quali sono le più importanti best practices inerenti alla visualizzazione dati. Scopriremo inoltre le principali caratteristiche dei visual più usati e quando usarli o non usarli. https://speakerscore.com/81RK</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 11:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 12:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105119</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105119</id>
          <name>Dimitri Zornik</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</name>
      </location>
      <title>(Envisioning Beantech) A modern crystal ball to predict the future</title>
      <description>“SQL + R + Power BI = Demand Planning”</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 10:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 11:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101101</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101101</id>
          <name>Marco Pozzan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Microsoft Power BI fast with aggregation and composite model</title>
      <description>Il modello composito consente di avere tabelle enormi come origine DirectQuery e alcune tabelle più piccole in modalità di importazione. Quando parliamo di tabelle enormi le prestazioni sono sempre una sfida. In questa sessione, parleremo di come le aggregazioni possono essere utili per accelerare le prestazioni. Puoi vedere come gigabyte di dati possono essere analizzati e visualizzati in meno di un secondo. Scopri molti suggerimenti, trucchi e aspetti interni sulle aggregazioni in Power BI e sul loro utilizzo in un modello composito. https://speakerscore.com/MDN9</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105107</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105107</id>
          <name>andrea benedetti</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</name>
      </location>
      <title>(Envisioning Microsoft) "Move forward your data strategy"</title>
      <description>Envisioning Microsoft</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100914</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100914</id>
          <name>Marco Parenzan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</name>
      </location>
      <title>.net developer for Jupyter Notebooks and Apache Spark and viceversa</title>
      <description>Jupyter Notebooks and Apache Spark are first class citizens of the Data Science space, a truly requirement for the "modern" data scientist. But there was a requirement: being a python developer. Now Microsoft is investing on C# as another first class citizen in this space. Let's look what .net can do for notebooks and spark and what are notebooks and spark. https://speakerscore.com/Z2F6</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 4:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 5:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105131</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105131</id>
          <name>Veronica Nuvolone</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</name>
      </location>
      <title>(Envisioning SolidQ)</title>
      <description>(Envisioning SolidQ)</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100693</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100693</id>
          <name>andrea benedetti</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Modernizing your Data Warehouse with Azure Synapse Analytics</title>
      <description>Azure Synapse is Azure SQL Data Warehouse evolved—blending big data, data warehousing, and data integration into a single service for end-to-end analytics at cloud scale.
https://speakerscore.com/9SSC</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98786</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98786</id>
          <name>Marco Obinu</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server ed Azure: Disaster Recovery per tutti</title>
      <description>Grazie al Azure, oggigiorno è possibile disegnare soluzioni di Disaster Recovery affidabili e di facile implementazione anche per la media e piccola impresa.
Vediamo insieme quali sono le soluzioni suggerite da Microsoft, confrontandone pregi e difetti. https://speakerscore.com/H7FH</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 11:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 12:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100762</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100762</id>
          <name>Marco Minerva</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Sfruttiamo Dapper al 110%</title>
      <description>Dapper è il micro OR/M sviluppato e utilizzato da StackOverflow e rappresenta la soluzione ideale quando vogliamo avere il massimo controllo sulle query SQL che eseguiamo, mantenendo il mapping automatico dei parametri e dei risultati sulle classi di dominio. In questa sessione mostreremo come usarlo efficacemente nelle nostre applicazioni, come si rapporta con altre soluzioni di accesso ai dati e come integrarlo con librerie di terze parti, in modo da sfruttarlo davvero al 110%. https://speakerscore.com/QD9X</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100317</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100317</id>
          <name>Riccardo Perico</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI dataflows deep dive (IT) (https://speakerscore.com/SKKL))</title>
      <description>Power BI dataflows permette di centralizzare e standardizzare le fasi di data preparation nel cloud, sfruttando Power Query ed il linguaggio M. 
Quali sono gli scenari in cui utilizzarli? Quali sono le best practice da tenere a mente? 
Quali nuovi orizzonti offrono? 
Cerchiamo di rispondere a queste ed altre domande con esempi pratici.https://speakerscore.com/SKKL</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105120</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105120</id>
          <name>Davide Cavalli</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</name>
      </location>
      <title>(Envisioning Consulcesi)</title>
      <description>(Envisioning Consulcesi)</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101209</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101209</id>
          <name>Tomaž Kaštrun</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Applied data analytics with Azure Databricks</title>
      <description>Azure Databricks is an  Apache Spark–based analytics service for big data and data analytics on top.
In this session we will create Databricks scenarios for useful business scenarios.

Data engineers and business analysts (data scientists) can now work on RDD structured files using workbooks for collaborative projects, using ANSI SQL, R, Python or Scala, easily covering both analytical and machine learning solutions on one hand, and also giving the capabilities to use it as a datawarehouse. https://speakerscore.com/PHXH</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105176</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105176</id>
          <name>Federico Favero</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Quando i dati fanno la differenza (e quando un po’ meno)</title>
      <description>Quando i dati fanno la differenza (e quando un po’ meno)</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 10:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 11:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100214</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100214</id>
          <name>Danilo Dominici</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Usate SQL Server in containers: best practices</title>
      <description>I containers consentono una nuova modalità di distribuzione, gestione ed esecuzione di istanze SQL Server, in maniera molto più semplice ed efficiente rispetto ad esempio alle macchine virtuali. In questa sessione demo-oriented vedremo in dettaglio come funzionano i containers Docker, come SQL Server viene eseguito in essi e come utilizzarli on-premise ed in Azure. https://speakerscore.com/T4VC</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100683</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100683</id>
          <name>Alessio Biasiutti</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Custom Text Analysis with Azure Machine Learning Services</title>
      <description>Durante la sessione vedremo le tecniche di base per estrarre informazioni da testo scritto in linguaggio naturale, creare un semplice servizio e pubblicarlo come container attraverso Machine Learning Services.
https://speakerscore.com/KW22</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105132</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105132</id>
          <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</name>
      </location>
      <title>(Envisioning Würth Phoenix) Utilizzo di Power Platform per l’int</title>
      <description>Utilizzo di Power Platform per l’integrazione tra software: un esempio concreto</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 10:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 11:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100705</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100705</id>
          <name>Gilberto Zampatti</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance Monitoring in SQL Server 2019</title>
      <description>Some new object and configuration option of our databases can enhance the 
efficiency of our monitoring and tuning. This session will show some new 
object (DMO) introduced in the new platform and a couple of new options 
that can change our approach to the monitoring, maintenance and tuning activity. https://speakerscore.com/NGZM</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100689</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100689</id>
          <name>Luca Zavarella</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Walk-through of Azure Machine Learning Service new features</title>
      <description>La sessione consiste prevalentemente in una dimostrazione pratica che vi guiderà nel mondo del nuovo Azure Machine Learning Service, focalizzandosi sulle nuove funzionalità quali il Designer (ML senza codice), l'auto ML e l'interpretabilità di un modello.
https://speakerscore.com/ZGKX</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105150</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105150</id>
          <name>Marco Pozzan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI App per analisi di Bilancio da file XBRL</title>
      <description>Power BI App per analisi di Bilancio da file XBRL</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 3:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 4:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99148</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99148</id>
          <name>Rob Sewell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t3</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Notebooks in Azure Data Studio for the DBA</title>
      <description>An Azure Data Studio recent release introduced SQL Notebooks as a capability. While you might have read about notebooks being used for Data Science, this session is primarily for DBAs. 

We will cover installing Azure Data Studio.
https://speakerscore.com/7QK2
What a SQL Notebooks is.
Numerous use cases for you to use SQL Notebooks in your daily workload such as creating a Notebook for Glenn Berry's Diagnostic queries.

and some gifs ;-) https://speakerscore.com/7QK2</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100684</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100684</id>
          <name>Francesco De Chirico</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to M in Power BI</title>
      <description>Uno dei punti di forza di Power BI risiede nelle performance del suo engine di Power Query e nella capacità di semplificare lo sviluppo dell'intera fase ETL attraverso l'uso della sola interfaccia grafica. Ma dietro le quinte ogni nostro "click" si traduce in codice "M" e conoscere tale linguaggio consente di ampliare  ulteriormente le potenzialità di Power BI e quindi dei nostri modelli. In questa sessione introduttiva verranno descritti i principali costrutti e le regole base del linguaggio e si mostreranno alcuni esempi pratici di utilizzo all'interno dei modelli di Power BI. https://speakerscore.com/BQ76</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100561</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100561</id>
          <name>Danilo Dominici</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Ottimizzare SQL Server su VMWare: come si fa?</title>
      <description>Abbiamo installato SQL Server su una macchina virtuale VMWare seguendo (vero ?) tutte le best practices. Ma ancora non abbiamo le performance desiderate. Come si analizzano e risolvono le problematiche di performance su una VM? Quali sono le metriche da prendere in considerazione? E quali strumenti utilizzare? In questa sessione demo-oriented cercheremo di capire proprio questo.
https://speakerscore.com/4VJB</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105135</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105135</id>
          <name>Marco Giacomini</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</name>
      </location>
      <title>(Envisioning Real Comm): SmartMan: ERP Industria 4.0</title>
      <description>SmartMan: ERP Industria 4.0</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 10:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 11:20:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100736</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100736</id>
          <name>Gianluca Hotz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Data Virtualization with Polybase</title>
      <description>Polybase è la tecnologia introdotta con SQL Server 2016 per eseguire query distribuite in ambienti eterogenei. Inizialmente con un supporto di sistemi esterni limitato, in SQL Server 2019 è stato esteso per supportare non solo Hadoop e SQL Server in tutte le declinazioni, tra cui Azure SQL Data Warehouse, ma anche Teradata, Oracle, MongoDB e sistemi generici accessibili via ODBC. In questa sessione vedremo come funziona il meccanismo di integrazione dal punto di vista tecnico con qualche esempio pratico. https://speakerscore.com/8P1Q</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>98904</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>98904</id>
          <name>Alessandro Alpi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</name>
      </location>
      <title>"SQL Wars, l'attacco dei cloni e la resistenza dei container</title>
      <description>in questa sessione, Giuliano e Alessandro mostrano le tecnologie disponibili per trasportare velocemente dati di produzione in ambienti isolati da usare in: test di integrazione, emulazione di rilasci e controllo di anomalie. Dal cloning in Hyper-V ai container Docker, vedremo quanto è semplice fare provisioning di dati su Microsoft SQL Server per verificare la presenza di regressioni nell'integrare le modifiche prodotte dal Team di sviluppo
https://speakerscore.com/XJF3</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100674</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100674</id>
          <name>Andrea Tosato</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t4</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5 - https://bit.ly/sqlsat921t5</name>
      </location>
      <title>How scale SQL with Serverless</title>
      <description>Il serverless è la nuova frontiera dello sviluppo Cloud e le Azure Functions sono uno degli strumenti a disposizione per implementare questo nuovo paradigma. SQL Server è un componente importante nell'ecosistema Azure ma non esiste, al momento, un modo "chiavi in mano" per poterlo utilizzare all'interno delle Azure Functions.
In questa sessione vedremo come scalare correttamente una applicazione che ha la necessità di scrivere e leggere su SQL Azure e di come ridurre al minimo il codice applicativo. https://speakerscore.com/JTKD</description>
      <startTime>5/30/2020 4:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/30/2020 5:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>