<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #252 - Christchurch, NZ 2013</name>
    <startDate>8/10/2013 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>50</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+12:00) Fiji, Kamchatka, Marshall Is</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat252</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Christchurch Polytechnic Institute of Technology (CPIT)</name>
      <street>Madras Street</street>
      <city>Christchurch</city>
      <state>, New Zealand</state>
      <zipcode>8011</zipcode>
      <longitude>172.6426697</longitude>
      <latitude>-43.5358315</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>297</importID>
      <name>SQL Services</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sqlservices.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/986/EventSponsor_14718.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>83</importID>
      <name>PluralSight</name>
      <label>Friend of SQL Saturday #252</label>
      <url>http://www.pluralsight.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.srnimbus.com.br/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Pluralsight_logo_novo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Friend of SQL Saturday #252</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9777</importID>
      <name>Argenis Fernandez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Argenis is a Principal Architect at Pure Storage. He works with customers around the world to make sure they don’t have to worry much about their infrastructure for Data.
He is a former Data Platform MVP, former VMware vExpert, Microsoft Certified Master, and more recently worked in the Microsoft Azure Data/SQL Server engineering team as a Principal PM in the Tiger team.</description>
      <twitter>DBArgenis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/argenis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.purestorage.com/author/argenisfernandez/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBArgenis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10717</importID>
      <name>Brent McCracken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I've been working with SQL Server since v6.5 and nearly completed my MCM qualification. I am the technical lead for the database operations team in a nationwide bank in New Zealand.</description>
      <twitter>@sqldba_nz</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/pub/brent-mccracken/8/510/a34/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqldba.co.nz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqldba_nz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22625</importID>
      <name>Ray Bachert</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Business Intelligence and Data Quality Consultant | Founder The Data Quality Service
Ray has 20 years experience in business intelligence, data quality and project management at organizations of all sizes including Microsoft, SAP, City Care, University of Canterbury and Farmlands/CRT. His goal is to make it possible for companies of all sizes to improve the quality of their data without having to spend a lot of time or money to get results. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12234</importID>
      <name>Dave Dustin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With more than 35 years industry experience, Dave has worked with organisations and data systems of all sizes. He is currently Principal Engineer at Xero.</description>
      <twitter>venzann</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=venzann</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12911</importID>
      <name>David Curlewis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I'm the database team lead at Trade Me; New Zealand's busiest website.  I've been working with SQL for around 13 years now, and still learn something new every day (although I hope I've picked up enough tips  tricks along the way that I can show you something new). ;-)</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.curlewis.co.nz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19761</importID>
      <name>Martin Catherall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin is a data consultant in Melbourne, Australia, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, and PASS Regional Mentor for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region.
Martin founded the Christchurch, New Zealand PASS Local Group and lead the group for a number of years before relocating to Melbourne.
He has been using SQL Server in various roles since 2000. In addition to anything data related, he enjoys playing the guitar and having fun with his family.</description>
      <twitter>MartyCatherall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/martincatherall</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://martincatherall.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MartyCatherall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23237</importID>
      <name>Rob Douglas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robs SQL history started as a remote DBA, branched into consultancy and now includes providing SQL Solutions to a variety of businesses, government departments and banks throughout Australia and New Zealand using a variety of native SQL solutions to meet their performance, higher availability and Disaster Recovery needs.</description>
      <twitter>Rob_DouglasNZ</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=AAMAAAoSId0BNgwoSf_o5y24oIW3PjEHbAmdY-camp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gumption.co.nz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rob_DouglasNZ</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>12911</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12911</id>
          <name>David Curlewis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building to scale: Overcoming Performance Hurdles</title>
      <description>In this session I'll be using a fictional auction website's database (which I've created for demonstration purposes) to take an accelerated look at what a typical web-scale database application's performance pain points might be as it grows, both in size and load.  We'll simulate some users, monitor some stuff, see what breaks, and then fix it. 

This will include some basic design and indexing best practices to kick things off - but we'll quickly move on to more interesting options for getting the most out of SQL Server under load.  Time allowing, I'll also do some demo's on the impact that SQL Server 2014 In-Memory OLTP (i.e. Project Hekaton) tables have compared to our previous best efforts in 2012, and whether natively compiled stored procs will give us any additional zing as well!</description>
      <startTime>8/10/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/10/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23237</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23237</id>
          <name>Rob Douglas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Are you High?  Can you Recovery?</title>
      <description>A look at the High Availability and Disaster Recovery options available natively within SQL server.  Covering everything from backups alone to Mirroring, LogShipping and SQL Clustering.   Time permitting we'll delve into the advantages and disadvantages that SQL 2012 Availability Groups present and talk about how the HA and DR landscape is changed by the advent of cloud computing.</description>
      <startTime>8/10/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/10/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>12234</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12234</id>
          <name>Dave Dustin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Microsoft SQL Server – Project Hekaton</title>
      <description>The release of Hekaton, Microsoft’s In Memory OLTP enhancements for SLQ Server, promises to change the kind of high performance solutions that can be implemented using SQL Server. 
In this session we'll look at what Hekaton actually is, how it achieves the 10x-50x speed improvements on the same hardware and how architects and developers can start planning future application.
</description>
      <startTime>8/10/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/10/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9777</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9777</id>
          <name>Argenis Fernandez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Code-Less Securing of SQL Server</title>
      <description>Learn from a Microsoft Certified Master how to secure your SQL Server infrastructure and your Windows installations to enhance resiliency and minimize exposure to attacks—all without touching any of your code!</description>
      <startTime>8/10/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/10/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19761</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19761</id>
          <name>Martin Catherall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Saturday #252 - Keynote and Introduction</title>
      <description>Keynote and introduction to all sessions and tracks at SQL Saturday #252 Christchurch New Zealand. The event will run alongside events from the .NET group, Infrastructure group and Sharepoint / CRM group. There's a track for each so this is just to give people a taster for the rest of the day.</description>
      <startTime>8/10/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/10/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22625</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22625</id>
          <name>Ray Bachert</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>10 easy ways to improve data quality</title>
      <description>Learn 10 ways to dramatically improve your data quality using the tools you already own. This session is targeted for developers implemeting business intelligence, doing integration work or implementing new systems where data quality can make or break the success of your project.</description>
      <startTime>8/10/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/10/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10717</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10717</id>
          <name>Brent McCracken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Event Notifications with SQL Server</title>
      <description>Event Notifications are a great tool often not used by DBA's. I will show you how this is a good introduction into the world of Service Broker and why it is better than triggers or SQL Trace. I will demo a practical use of auditing that we use in Kiwibank that you can take away and use yourself.</description>
      <startTime>8/10/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/10/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>