<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #939 - Austin - BI Edition 2020</name>
    <startDate>2/8/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-06:00) Saskatchewan</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatBIATX</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>East Williamson County Higher Education Center</name>
      <street>1600 Innovation Blvd, Hutto TX</street>
      <city>Austin</city>
      <state>Texas</state>
      <zipcode>78634</zipcode>
      <longitude>-97.5736476</longitude>
      <latitude>30.5540901</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14327.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>5</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14572.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2626</importID>
      <name>SQLSaturday Baton Rouge</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlsatbr.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14497.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2624</importID>
      <name>CAPITOL TECHNOLOGY UNIVERSITY</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.captechu.edu/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14479.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1764</importID>
      <name>Procure SQL</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://procuresql.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14481.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2641</importID>
      <name>ZAP</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.zapbi.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14574.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>995</importID>
      <name>RDX</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.navisite.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14533.jpeg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2488</importID>
      <name>davebland.com</name>
      <label>SQL Saturday Evangelist</label>
      <url>http://www.davebland.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14371.PNG</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2141</importID>
      <name>Dallas DBAs</name>
      <label>SQL Saturday Evangelist</label>
      <url>http://www.dallasdbas.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14299.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2473</importID>
      <name>TidwellTidbits</name>
      <label>SQL Saturday Friend</label>
      <url>https://tidwelltidbits.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14464.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2008</importID>
      <name>Data Savvy</name>
      <label>SQL Saturday Friend</label>
      <url>https://datasavvy.me/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14573.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2623</importID>
      <name>SearchRPM Inc.</name>
      <label>SQL Saturday Friend</label>
      <url>https://www.searchrpm.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14465.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99470</importID>
      <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Feasel is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CTO at Envizage, where he specializes in data analytics with T-SQL and R, forcing Spark clusters to do his bidding, fighting with Kafka, and pulling rabbits out of hats on demand. He is the lead contributor to Curated SQL (https://curatedsql.com), president of the Triangle Area SQL Server Users Group (https://www.meetup.com/tripass), and author of PolyBase Revealed (https://www.apress.com/us/book/9781484254608). A resident of Durham, North Carolina, he can be found cycling the trails along the triangle whenever the weather's nice enough.</description>
      <twitter>feaselkl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-feasel/7/716/504</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.catallaxyservices.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=feaselkl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99228</importID>
      <name>William Assaf</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>William Assaf is a senior content developer on the SQLDocs team at Microsoft. Formerly a Data Platform MVP and a consultant for SQL Server, and before that a .NET developer, William currently works with Microsoft product groups on content related to the SQL database platform, specifically for SQL performance, Big Data Clusters, and Azure SQL DB. As a consultant for 13 years he worked with clients on SQL Server and Azure SQL platform optimization, management, disaster recovery and high availability, and led a crack multi-city team of consulting SQL DBA's. William has written for Microsoft SQL certification exams since 2011 and was the team lead author of the 2017 and 2019 editions of "SQL Server Administration Inside Out" by Microsoft Press. William is a past lead of the annual SQLSaturday Baton Rouge Planning Committee and supports the Baton Rouge User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>william_a_dba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamdassaf/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqltact.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=william_a_dba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99433</importID>
      <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tracy Boggiano is a Senior Database Administrator for DocuSIgn. She has spent over 20 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1999, and is currently certified as an MCSE Data Platform. Tracy has worked on SQL Server since 6.5. She has spoken at local user groups and numerous SQLSaturdays. She is currently a co-leader of a TriPASS Local Group in Raleigh, NC.   

Tracy also tinkered with databases in middle school to keep her sports card collection organized. She blogs at databasesuperhero.com. 

Her passion outside of SQL Server is volunteering with foster children as their advocate in court through volunteerforgal.org and being a mental health advocate as part of the PAIMI NC Advisory Council.</description>
      <twitter>TracyBoggiano</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyboggiano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://databasesuperhero.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TracyBoggiano</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101344</importID>
      <name>Russel Loski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Russ Loski is a SQL Server BI Developer based in Dallas-Fort Worth.  He current works as a Data Analytics Engineer for Navisite, a remote managed IT services company.   Twenty years ago, he began working with SQL Server 6.5. He has since continued to develop applications connected to all of the versions of SQL Server. He has worked with clients in industries from insurance to healthcare, from movie theaters to American football.  Russ is a regular speaker at SQLSaturday events, as well as the SQL Server Users Groups in the North Texas region. Russ likes working with data in various shapes.</description>
      <twitter>sqlmovers</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/russloski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmovers.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmovers</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100848</importID>
      <name>Wenbin Zhao</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wenbin Zhao is a Sr. Data Analyst and Tableau developer. He graduated from Brigham Young University and worked in the finance and data analytics field for the last 14 years. He loves everything data and business analytics, project management, and teamwork. He has been a Tableau user since 2013 and also participated in Tableau Hackathon in Austin. His team built a prototype embedded Tableau dashboard to track eye-movements by utilizing Tableau API and Python libraries to help ALS patients. His current focus at YETI is to help building consumer insights and predictive capabilities through visualization and data science. He’s also a teaching assistant of Data Analytics and Visualization program at University of Texas at Austin’s McCombs School</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/wenbin-billy-zhao/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99533</importID>
      <name>Derek Wilson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have successfully designed, installed and deployed data management and predictive analytics projects in a variety of industries. I enjoy working on data mining and predictive solutions to take historical data and apply adaptive learning technology to predict future outcomes.

We create project that provide the most value to the business through improving service, decreasing costs or increasing revenue through architecture, design, or technology solutions.</description>
      <twitter>@derekewilson</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/derekewilson/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@derekewilson</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101584</importID>
      <name>Christine Assaf</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Christine Assaf is an experienced HR pro who is passionate about the mental health of employees, leadership, and organizations. She is a leadership development professional with over 15 years experience in human resources and 20 years in business management. She holds a BS in Business Management, received her HRM certification at LSU, and is finishing up her master's degree at Colorado State University in Industrial and Organizational Psychology. She is a certified DDI Trainer, experienced public speaker, and is dedicated to teaching others about ways to support a culture of "expressiveness" in the workplace that creates connectivity.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/HRTact</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/christineassaf</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.hrtact.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/HRTact</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101996</importID>
      <name>Alberto Ferrari</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alberto Ferrari started working with SQL Server in 2000 and immediately focused his interest on Business Intelligence. He and Marco Russo created sqlbi.com, where they publish extensive content about Business Intelligence. Alberto published several books about Analysis Services, Power BI, and Power Pivot. He is a Microsoft MVP and he earned the SSAS Maestro title, the highest level of certification on Microsoft Analysis Services technology.

Today, Alberto's main activities are in the delivery of DAX and data modeling workshops for Power BI and Analysis Services all around the world. Alberto offers consulting services on large and complex data warehouses to provide assessments and validation of project analysis or to perform specific problem-solving activities.

Alberto is a well-known speaker at many international conferences, like PASS Summit, SQLBits, and Microsoft Ignite. He loves to be on stage both at large events and at smaller user groups meetings, exchanging ideas with other SQL and BI fans. When traveling for work, he likes to engage with local user groups to provide evening sessions about his favorite topics. Thus, you can easily meet Alberto by looking up local Power BI user groups during scheduled courses.
Outside of SQLBI, most of Alberto's personal time is spent practicing video games, in the vain hope of eventually beating his son.</description>
      <twitter>@FerrariAlberto</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlbi.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@FerrariAlberto</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99514</importID>
      <name>Meagan Longoria</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Meagan Longoria is a business intelligence consultant with Denny Cherry  Associates, and lives in Denver, Colorado. She is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Meagan spends a lot of time thinking about how to use data integration, DAX, and data visualization techniques to make data useful for people. She enjoys sharing her knowledge and experiences at conferences and user group meetings, as well as through her blog (DataSavvy.me).</description>
      <twitter>mmarie</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/meaganlongoria/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datasavvy.me</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mmarie</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101140</importID>
      <name>Matt Gordon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and has worked with SQL Server since 2000. He is the leader of the Lexington, KY PASS local group and a frequent domestic and international community speaker. He's an IDERA ACE alumnus and 2020 Friend of Redgate. His original data professional role was in database development, which quickly evolved into query tuning work that further evolved into being a DBA in the healthcare realm. He has supported several critical systems utilizing SQL Server and managed dozens of 24/7/365 SQL Server implementations. Following several years as a consultant, he is now the Director of Database Management for rev.io, where he is implementing data governance, DevOps, and performance improvements enterprise-wide.</description>
      <twitter>sqlatspeed</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlatspeed</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlatspeed.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlatspeed</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101582</importID>
      <name>Michael McKinley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael McKinley is the founder of McKinley Consulting.  Michael has managed projects and workstreams in consulting for the last five years, in areas including data analytics, change management, operations excellence, and supply chain transformation.

Most recently, Mr. McKinley helped HCA build an enterprise-wide analytics model for their Human Resources Group, providing insights into how to retain and promote top talent.  He is currently engaged on his fourth project with HCA.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/Mike_L_McKinley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaellmckinley</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mckinley.consulting/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/Mike_L_McKinley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100046</importID>
      <name>Ginger Grant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ginger Grant manages the consultancy Desert Isle Group and shares what she has learned while working with data technology to people around the world.  As a Microsoft MVP in Data Platform, Microsoft Certified Trainer and an instructor on DataCamp, she focuses on guiding clients to create solutions using the entire Microsoft Data Stack, which includes SQL Server, Power BI, and Azure Data Cloud components. When not working, she protypes the latest pre-release data technologies, maintains her blog http://www.desertislesql.com, and spends time on twitter @desertislesql.</description>
      <twitter>desertislesql</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ginger-grant-3a177b157/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.DesertIsleSQL.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=desertislesql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99606</importID>
      <name>Ganesh Lohani</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ganesh Lohani has 10 years of experience working with Business Intelligence platform and Data Analytics, with over 8 years of experience with MS BI tools and Business Intelligence processes. He is currently working for Stericycle as a senior Business Intelligence Developer. He also enjoy his evening and weekend time in providing online training, coaching and mentoring individuals who want to learn MSBI (T – SQL,  SSIS, SSRS, SSAS, and Power BI ) products. He holds MSIS degree from University of Texas at Arlington.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ganesh-lohani-6275a716</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101588</importID>
      <name>Alicia Moniz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alicia Moniz is a Microsoft AI MVP.  She authors the blog HybridDataLakes.com, a blog focused on cloud data learning resources.
Alicia has been in the Database/BI services industry for 14+ years and is an expert in T-SQL, Data Modeling, Database Administration, Analytics, Data Visualization, and Data Warehousing. Her skill set spans SQL Server 2005 through 2016 and Azure. She has hands on experience architecting, developing, and optimizing BI solutions in the Microsoft ecosystem.

Alicia holds certifications for both AWS/Azure Architect and AWS/Azure Big Data, and is a Microsoft Certified Solution Expert (MCSE): Data Management and Analytics.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/aliciamoniz</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101997</importID>
      <name>Alberto Ferrari</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alberto Ferrari started working with SQL Server in 2000 and immediately focused his interest on Business Intelligence. He and Marco Russo created sqlbi.com, where they publish extensive content about Business Intelligence. Alberto published several books about Analysis Services, Power BI, and Power Pivot. He is a Microsoft MVP and he earned the SSAS Maestro title, the highest level of certification on Microsoft Analysis Services technology.

Today, Alberto's main activities are in the delivery of DAX and data modeling workshops for Power BI and Analysis Services all around the world. Alberto offers consulting services on large and complex data warehouses to provide assessments and validation of project analysis or to perform specific problem-solving activities.

Alberto is a well-known speaker at many international conferences, like PASS Summit, SQLBits, and Microsoft Ignite. He loves to be on stage both at large events and at smaller user groups meetings, exchanging ideas with other SQL and BI fans. When traveling for work, he likes to engage with local user groups to provide evening sessions about his favorite topics. Thus, you can easily meet Alberto by looking up local Power BI user groups during scheduled courses.
Outside of SQLBI, most of Alberto's personal time is spent practicing video games, in the vain hope of eventually beating his son.</description>
      <twitter>@FerrariAlberto</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlbi.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@FerrariAlberto</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>101592</importID>
      <name>Brian Lee</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brian is the Global Power BI Enablement Lead at NXP Semiconductors, part the Enterprise Business Intelligence (EBI) organization in I.T. Brian leads the Enablement team’s effort in promoting Power BI across the corporation, providing Power BI training and consultation, user support, conducting POCs, pilot evaluation of new capabilities, hosting in-house Power BI User Group meetings, etc. Brian also leads the overall Power BI Roadmap, Governance and Security considerations and implementation. Working along-side embedded BI Partner Leaders and User Champions in organizations across the company, the Enablement team promotes and leads the implementation of Self-Service BI at NXP Semiconductors. NXP has &gt;30K employees in over 33 countries.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/briancclee/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99454</importID>
      <name>Leslie Andrews</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leslie Andrews is an IT professional with almost 20 years of experience working with databases, designing databases, as well as designing and developing applications against those databases. 2018-2019 Idera ACE.</description>
      <twitter>landrews5807</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/leslie-andrews-csm/9/491/b89</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.lace.technology/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=landrews5807</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99684</importID>
      <name>Mike Byrd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Former rocket scientist and USAF Fighter Pilot -- now a SQL Server geek (24 years)! Past opportunities include free-lance technical writer for PC Magazine, Senior Software Manager for government sponsored munitions effectiveness committee, and insurance company CTO.  Currently senior database engineer consultant for several Austin companies.  

Presenter at many SQL Saturdays over last 6 years in United States, Europe, and Australia.

Specialize in SQL Server performance tuning; database (OLTP  OLAP) architecture; trouble-shooting; teaching TSQL (Basic through Advanced).

Video presentations (for local SQL Server user groups or SQL Saturdays) can be found at http://usergroup.tv/videos/category/speaker/mike-byrd</description>
      <twitter>ByrdNest_TX</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-byrd/1/aa0/bbb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://logicalread.solarwinds.com/?s=byrd, www.TSQLMentoring.com and SQLServerCentral.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ByrdNest_TX</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99438</importID>
      <name>Matt Cushing</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt started out his career in Accounting and quickly realized he liked data a whole lot more!  Starting as a help desk associate, he's moved through support, development, data, and management positions before settling back to his passion for data.

Currently working for Applegate Farms in NJ, he loves the people he works with and for, and the company as a whole.  Thanks to the input and help from the SQL community, he was able to be ready for the right opportunity in his current position as a BI developer.  He also teaches a Database Management class at Rutgers University.

Ask him about the Red Sox sometime if you want your ear talked off ;).</description>
      <twitter>Sqlkohai</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mattcushing/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlkohai.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Sqlkohai</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99749</importID>
      <name>Jamey Johnston</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jamey Johnston is a Senior Data Scientist/Engineer for a large independent OG company. For over 25 years, he has worked for Fortune 500 companies architecting successful platforms in the cloud, on the edge, and on-premises for BI reporting, statistical analysis, ML, and AI. Lately, he spends his time in Azure, Python, R, Power BI, MS SQL, and SAS JMP. He holds a BS in Spatial Analysis from LSU and a Masters of Science in Analytics from Texas AM. He is a professor at the Mays Business School at Texas AM in the MS Analytics program. He is active in his PASS Local Group in Houston, co-leader of the local Power BI users group and data analytics group. He regularly speaks and volunteers at PASS events. He is also a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>STATCowboy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jameyj</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://STATCowboy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=STATCowboy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>99436</importID>
      <name>Bob Phillips</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am an independent consultant based in the UK, specializing in all things Excel, especially delivering BI within Excel. 

I came to appreciate the power and versatility of Excel as an enterprise tool in the mid-90s when managing the delivery of a data warehouse project. 

Now a freelance consultant, I specialize in Excel automation and BI delivered via Excel. An 11 year veteran of Microsoft#39;s MVP program, my life mission is to persuade small and medium corporates that data analysis and BI is important to them too, and that Power BI can help then find that information, in a straight-forward and cost-effective manner.</description>
      <twitter>@WessexBob</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/visibardd</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://wessexbi.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@WessexBob</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>100237</importID>
      <name>Matthew Floyd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>U.S. Air Force veteran with an Electrical Engineering degree who discovered a natural instinct working with databases and business intelligence. Love Microsoft products (especially Power BI, Power Query and SSAS Tabular Models) and learn something new everyday in order to share my knowledge with my colleagues. Happily married for 27 years to my wife Stephanie with two great sons, 18 and 10 years old. I am proud that my 18 year old is attending my alma mater, University of Texas at San Antonio, studying Mechanical Engineering.</description>
      <twitter>mattfloyd</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthewfloyd</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mattfloyd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>99749</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99749</id>
          <name>Jamey Johnston</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Modeling Techniques, Tools (ex Star vs Snowflake, Tabluar, Fact vs Dimmension)</track>
      <location>
        <name>4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Code Like a Snake Charmer - Introduction to Python!</title>
      <description>Python is the one of the most popular programming languages used today and one of the most useful tools in the data scientist's tool belt, especially for machine learning. Python is integrated into the Microsoft stack in tools like Azure ML, Databricks, and SQL Server.

This session will be an introduction to the Python language including: 
1) Installing and Configuring Python
2) Accessing and Manipulating Data
3) Installing and Managing Packages
4) Creating and Using Objects/Variables
5) Controlling Flows and Functions
6) Controlling Flows and Functions 6) Python in MS Power BI, Azure ML, MSSQL, and Databricks. 

Attend this session to learn how Python can take your data analytics to the next level. We will use Python, SQL Server, and the Anaconda distribution of Python to learn the basics of Python and how it is integrated in the Microsoft stack! We will walk through a simple deployment of a machine learning model to see how it all works together and learn some basic data science fun</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99470</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99470</id>
          <name>Kevin Feasel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Analysis / Cleaning Method and Tools / Data Demographics</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting Started with Apache Spark</title>
      <description>As companies work to gain insight from ever-increasing amounts of data, data platform practitioners need tools which can scale along with the data. Early big data solutions in the Hadoop ecosystem assumed that data sizes overwhelmed available memory, emphasizing heavy disk usage to coordinate work between nodes. As the cost of memory decreases and the amount of memory available per server increases, we see a shift in the makeup of big data systems, emphasizing heavy memory usage instead of disk. Apache Spark, which focuses on memory-intensive operations, has taken advantage of this hardware shift to become the dominant solution for problems requiring distributed data. In this talk, we will take an introductory look at Apache Spark. We will review where it fits in the Hadoop ecosystem, cover how to get started and some of the basic functional programming concepts needed to understand Spark, and see examples of how we can use Spark to solve issues when analyzing large data sets.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99436</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99436</id>
          <name>Bob Phillips</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Analysis / Cleaning Method and Tools / Data Demographics</track>
      <location>
        <name>4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Do I Need To M?</title>
      <description>Power Query is an powerful tool enabling the data analyst in creating usable data. It is one product that can truly claim to be user friendly, as so much of the functionality is available within the UI.

But, and there is always a but, sometimes you need to do things that are just not available through the UI. This is where you need to get down and get dirty, and manage the M code directly (M being the language that drives Power Query).

This session is all about the value of developing skills in M. Starting with a brief intro to M and some references to resources to help develop those skills further, we will then demonstrate a number of things you can do by directly coding in M, things that are not as simple or just can't be done through the UI.

The session will be using Power Query in Excel as Excel is still the most used BI delivery tool, but all of the techniques and code also apply to Power BI.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 2:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 3:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101140</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101140</id>
          <name>Matt Gordon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Make Your Company Conversational using Azure Cognitive Services</title>
      <description>Customers and users increasingly demand more personal and prompt communication from companies and brands with which they interact. How can data professionals help fill that need? The incredible power and instant accessibility of the Azure Cognitive Services Language and Speech APIs, combined with other Azure services, put the power in our hands. From translating between languages to make communication more efficient to analyzing support communications to ensure customers are happy, Azure Cognitive Services allows data professionals to enhance a brand's interaction with and impression in the customer community. This demo-heavy sessions walks through practical applications of these APIs that you can apply at home or at work immediately after the session.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101344</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101344</id>
          <name>Russel Loski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Importing Techniques and Tools (ex SSIS)</track>
      <location>
        <name>2</name>
      </location>
      <title>A metadata approach to fixed width files</title>
      <description>Face it, using SSIS to work with fixed width flat files is a pain.  The SSIS interface has you clicking around to mark each column. Then you use another interface to set each columns data types, etc.  And when you are done, you still need to document the file structure for your users.  What if you could simply document the file structure and then generate the ETL from the document?
To demonstrate such an approach, I build an Excel file describing US census data that has more than 300 columns of fixed width data.  After demonstrating how this file communicates to business users, I will generate an SSIS package from that metadata using BIML Script.  Then I will also look at how you can generate a SQL Server bulk insert format file from the same metadata.  A small amount of C# code can generate quite a large extract.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101592</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101592</id>
          <name>Brian Lee</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Presentation / Reports / Dashboards</track>
      <location>
        <name>4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Ecosystem and Use Models Overview</title>
      <description>While Power BI is often known as a BI tool or visualization tool, it is more appropriately viewed as an ecosystem, as it includes various tools, capabilities and integration with other Microsoft and 3rd party tools. 
	
This session will provide an overview of the Power BI ecosystem, look at various tools and key capabilities, their stand-alone functionalities, and how they can be integrated with other tools and environments. The intention of the session is for the attendee to walk away with a greater understanding and appreciation of Power BI's capabilities, what you can do with "it", and gain new ideas on how to leverage the capabilities in Power BI ecosystem in your data reporting and analytics journey.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100046</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100046</id>
          <name>Ginger Grant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Analysis / Cleaning Method and Tools / Data Demographics</track>
      <location>
        <name>4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting Started with Data Science and Databricks</title>
      <description>Databricks is a very popular environment for developing data science solutions.  More and more companies are interested in Databricks as it is very simple to set up and contains a collaborative workspace for working with a team of people. In this session you will see how to create Machine Learning Solutions with multiple workflows starting with ETL, to data exploration, model experimentation, and lastly to a production release of a data science solution. 

Today, more and more development is performed on very large datasets. Attendees will learn how to use Apache Spark, which is part of Databricks, to rapidly analyze lots of data.  Learn how to use Databricks to reduces operational complexity to create solutions which can be scaled up or down depending on the amount of data needed to process without having to change the underlying code. 
Python, Jupyter Notebooks, and Apache Spark are the technologies used to create solutions within this session.  No experience is required.
Agenda</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 9:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 10:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101588</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101588</id>
          <name>Alicia Moniz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>2</name>
      </location>
      <title>AI For Good: Cognitive Services Vision</title>
      <description>Are you curious about the role that AI will play in predictive modeling?  Are you wondering what the difference is between the Computer Vision API and the Custom Vision API?  Do you want a quick introduction to get you up to speed on both, so that you can quickly build and deploy a Cognitive Services model?

Join us for an introduction to the Cognitive Services Computer Vision and Custom Vision APIs on Azure.

In this session, we will look at the basics of Cognitive Services Vision.  First learn how to create your Cognitive Services model.  Then you can see how to train and improve accuracy.  Finally, we will step through python code in Azure Notebooks to call the APIs.

After this session, you will get up and running in Cognitive Services Vision in under an hour!

Prerequisites: Attendees should have an Azure account, as well as an account on Azure Notebooks.  Experience with coding in python is helpful, but not required.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 2:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 3:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99684</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99684</id>
          <name>Mike Byrd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Importing Techniques and Tools (ex SSIS)</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Change Tracking: A Near Bullet-Proof ETL Synchronization Control</title>
      <description>Change Tracking came out with SQL Server 2008, but SS2012 almost eclipsed it with Change Data Capture. Change Tracking is now the red-headed stepchild, but in many cases may be the best solution for data ETL movement from an SQL Server OLTP database to a data warehouse or reporting database. This session will provide a review of change tracking syntax and implementation with detailed demos. It will then dive into an actual ETL subset implementation from the AdventureWorks database to a data warehouse solution (modified AdventureWorksDW) with detailed code discussion and demos using TSQL only (no SSIS).  A variation of this implementation has run every 5 minutes with never a failure in over 7 years.  Come learn how you can adapt the supplied code to have near real-time in your data warehouse (or reporting database).</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99433</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99433</id>
          <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>More Common Than You Think: Mental Illness in Tech</title>
      <description>Mental illness is more common than you think.  One in four Americans suffers from a mental illness each year.  In the tech community, this is often not talked about.  Many times, people feel alone and isolated in the tech community with us mostly being introverted people.  It is time to start talking about mental illness out in the open and honestly about how it affects us and those around us.

In this session, we will talk about what mental illness is and what it is not.  How my mental illness has affected me.  How it effects the tech industry.  How mental illness can affect you and how you can tell if you are starting to have issues.  What to say and what not to say to people you know that are affected by mental illness.  Finally, how to get help and where reach out for help.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 2:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 3:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99228</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99228</id>
          <name>William Assaf</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Analysis / Cleaning Method and Tools / Data Demographics</track>
      <location>
        <name>2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Ethics in Data</title>
      <description>This session will explore a variety of considerations that modern data scientists and data practictioners must account for when gathering and presenting data, including topics on bias, construct analysis, and machine learning.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 9:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 10:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99514</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99514</id>
          <name>Meagan Longoria</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Presentation / Reports / Dashboards</track>
      <location>
        <name>2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Creating Accessible Power BI Reports</title>
      <description>Accessibility is catering for your whole audience, including those with disabilities. According to the US Census Bureau, 19 percent of the of the population had a disability in 2010. Do you know if your reports are designed in an inclusive way? In this session, we'll discuss accessibility standards and regulations of which you may want to be aware, how users with disabilities can consume Power BI reports, and guidance and pitfalls when designing inclusive reports.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99438</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99438</id>
          <name>Matt Cushing</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Networking 102: Getting Ready for a SQL Event</title>
      <description>Looking to get the most out of your SQL Saturday, PASS Summit, or local user group meeting? Plan ahead!  Events aren't just about learning new things, they're about meeting new people, networking with peers, and learning different approaches to common issues.

In this session, we'll go over steps you can take before, during and after the event to maximize the amount of great stuff you'll take away at the end (besides cool vendor swag).  Not just keeping up on new technologies, but meeting new people, getting leads on solutions/opportunities, and an appreciation for the community you're in and what it has to offer.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101582</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101582</id>
          <name>Michael McKinley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Modeling Techniques, Tools (ex Star vs Snowflake, Tabluar, Fact vs Dimmension)</track>
      <location>
        <name>2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Basics of Data Modeling for BI Reporting</title>
      <description>Come learn about the basics of data modeling for your business intelligence and reporting needs.  This course will cover several introductory modeling subjects, including:
  *  Transactional vs. Analytical models
  *  Kimball / Inman approaches
  *  The process for designing your data model
  *  Hierarchies / Parent-child relationships</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101996</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101996</id>
          <name>Alberto Ferrari</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Modeling Techniques, Tools (ex Star vs Snowflake, Tabluar, Fact vs Dimmension)</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>DAX Optimization Examples</title>
      <description>How do you optimize a DAX expression? In this session we analyze some DAX expressions and Tabular models and, through the usage of DAX Studio and some understanding of the VertiPaq model, we will look at how to optimize them.
As you will see, most optimizations are the direct application of best practices, but the session has the additional takeaway of understanding what kind of performance you should expect from your formulas, and the improvement you might expect from learning how to optimize the model and the code.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 9:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 10:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99606</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99606</id>
          <name>Ganesh Lohani</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building your Microsoft Business Intelligence (MSBI) Career</title>
      <description>Are you excited to know about the MSBI tools and work as a Business Intelligence Professional, a dynamic and rewarding career in Information Technology? If yes, this is the right time and place for you. In this session, I will give you the overview of the MSBI tools (SSIS, SSRS, SSAS, Power BI, Azure Machine Learning). I will also provide you some insights to build the MSBI career and to leverage the learning curve in Microsoft Data Platform, based on my knowledge and experience and the proven strategies and techniques.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99533</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99533</id>
          <name>Derek Wilson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Modeling Techniques, Tools (ex Star vs Snowflake, Tabluar, Fact vs Dimmension)</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Vault on SQL Server Tabular Model and Power BI</title>
      <description>In this session, you will learn the basics of building a data vault to organize and store your companies disparate data on SQL Server.  Learn how Hubs, Links, and Satellite tables create options for storing a variety of data from multiple systems.  The data vault structures will then be used as the data source to create views designed for SQL Server Analysis Services Tabular models.  Finally, Power BI will be used to visual the data for your end users.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100237</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100237</id>
          <name>Matthew Floyd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Presentation / Reports / Dashboards</track>
      <location>
        <name>5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Time Intelligence using a custom calendar</title>
      <description>Power BI time intelligence (Month to Date, Year to Date, etc) functions work great when you use the normal natural calendar. But what happens when you have a custom calendar where the month does not begin and end on the first and last days respectively of a month. Learn how to use Power Query (M) and DAX to create the time intelligence fields and measures needed to solve this problem.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 11:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 12:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>100848</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>100848</id>
          <name>Wenbin Zhao</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Analysis / Cleaning Method and Tools / Data Demographics</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>ETL Using Python, Pandas, and Jupyter Notebook</title>
      <description>ETL of large amount of data is always a daily task for data analysts and data scientists. While Excel and Text editors can handle a lot of the initial work, they have limitations. Python, in particular, Pandas library and Jupyter Notebook have becoming the primary choice of data analytics and data wrangling tools for data analysts world wide. 
In this 60 minute session, I will show you how to set up and get it running on your laptop for a jupyter notebook environment and start improve your ETL workflow.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 4:10:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101997</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101997</id>
          <name>Alberto Ferrari</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data Modeling Techniques, Tools (ex Star vs Snowflake, Tabluar, Fact vs Dimmension)</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using calculation groups in DAX</title>
      <description>Calculation groups are the most important feature introduced in DAX after variables in 2015. By using calculation groups, you can apply transformations to existing measures without having to create new measures in the model. For example, you can define the year-over-year calculation once and apply it to all the measures you want. Yet, calculation groups can do more than that.
This session introduces the syntax of calculation groups, when they should be used and several examples of use cases. You will also learn how calculation groups work internally and what are the limits of this amazing tool.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 2:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 3:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>99454</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>99454</id>
          <name>Leslie Andrews</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building a Strong Foundation for Data Analysis</title>
      <description>We are living in a world full of data but what we need is information.  What is required to transform data into information?  What are the foundational activities your organization needs to do in order to produce analytics that you are confident in sharing?  In this session we will discuss what is needed for your organization to convert data into information, the basics of: Data Governance, Data Modeling and how to have an immediate impact using tools like Power BI to deliver value; and, Data Visualizations and telling stories with the data.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 9:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 10:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>101584</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>101584</id>
          <name>Christine Assaf</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mastering your Resume  Interview: Tips to Get Hired</title>
      <description>Looking for a job? Learn trade secrets from an HR professional! Resume blunders and interview tips, this session will focus on the most important things you can do to get hired.</description>
      <startTime>2/8/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/8/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>