<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #758 - Montreal 2018</name>
    <startDate>6/2/2018 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>80</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatMontreal</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>MIcrosoft Montreal Offices</name>
      <street>2000 McGill College, 5e étage, Montréal</street>
      <city>Montreal</city>
      <state>Quebec, Canada</state>
      <zipcode>H3A 3H8</zipcode>
      <longitude>-73.573576911792</longitude>
      <latitude>45.5030134042437</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1988</importID>
      <name>Rubrik</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.rubrik.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/945/EventSponsor_14614.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>761</importID>
      <name>JetBrains</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.jetbrains.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://johnbulla.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/logo_jetbrains_31.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>558</importID>
      <name>Delphix</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.delphix.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://s1g.s3.amazonaws.com/8d76d3158dc5762281edd77ad20e50d4.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2203</importID>
      <name>Solution OMD INC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.solutionomd.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.solutionomd.com/images/solution-omd.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74174</importID>
      <name>Vitor Fava</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I'm a DBA with extensive experience in the areas of Database and Information Technology, working on planning, implementation, and maintenance of large corporate database servers. 
I have several professional certifications and good experience in development activities and management of entrepreneurial environments using SQL SERVER. 
I'm a speaker at various technology events such as SQL Saturday, The Developers Conference, InteropMix and also in various discussion groups focused on database technology.
I teach advanced training in SQL Server and Azure SQL Database and also acting as MCT in Microsoft official training.
I'm the Chapter Leader of SQLManiacs PASS chapter.</description>
      <twitter>sqlservermaniacs</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://br.linkedin.com/in/vitorfava</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.vitorfava.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlservermaniacs</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>78520</importID>
      <name>Franck Mercier</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Je suis arrivé chez Microsoft en 1999 en tant qu'ingénieur support sur la toute suite Office. En 2002, j'ai intégré l'équipe avant-vente sur la solution EPM (Enterprise Project Management). J'ai eu pour mission de promouvoir les solutions de gestion de projets, de programmes et d'innovation (IPM : Innovation Process Management). En 2010, j'ai radicalement changé de Technologie pour rejoindre l'équipe Avant-Vente Business Intelligence. En 2013, j’ai rejoint l'équipe des évangélistes IT Pro sur les technologies SQL, SharePoint et Office pour évoluer ensuite en tant qu'architecte Azure pour les ISVs. Depuis 2018, j'ai rejoint les équipes de Montréal pour prendre un rôle technico-commercial sur la plateforme de données de Microsoft.</description>
      <twitter>FranmerMS</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mercierfranck/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/franck</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=FranmerMS</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74200</importID>
      <name>Steve Simon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Simon is a Database Solutions Architect with Business Knowledge Services Inc. He has been involved with database design and analysis for over 35 years. Steve has presented papers at numerous PASS Summits and PASS SQL Rallies. He is also regular presenter on the SQL Saturday circuit and he is a contributor on SQLShack.com</description>
      <twitter>SQLServerBoffin</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stephenrsimon/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/simon_says/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLServerBoffin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74636</importID>
      <name>Dan Clark</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dan Clark is a senior data analytics consultant. He is focused on all things data analytics and training others how to get value from their data. Dan has published several books and numerous articles on .NET programming and data analytics. He is a regular speaker at various developer and database conferences and user group meetings and enjoys interacting with the Microsoft developer and database communities. His latest book Beginning Power BI published by Apress is a will get you up and running with self-service data analytics on the Power BI platform in no time.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dxclark/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://drclarkblog.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82361</importID>
      <name>Marco Russo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marco is a Business Intelligence consultant and mentor. He wrote several books about Power BI, Analysis Service, and Power Pivot. He also regularly writes articles and white papers that are available on sqlbi.com. Marco is a Microsoft MVP and an SSAS Maestro, the highest level of certification on Microsoft Analysis Services.
Today, Marco focuses his time with SQLBI customers, traveling extensively to train and consult on DAX and data modeling for Power BI and Analysis Services. Marco also teaches public classes worldwide.
Marco is a regular speaker at international conferences like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and SQLBits. He also enjoys delivering evening sessions at local user groups during his trips.</description>
      <twitter>marcorus</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlbi</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlbi.com/blog/marco</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=marcorus</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74364</importID>
      <name>Gregory Boge</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior SQL Server DBA
Kankuru creator
GUSS member (French SQL Server User Group)</description>
      <twitter>@kankurusql</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.kankuru.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@kankurusql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74212</importID>
      <name>Edward Pollack</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ed Pollack has over 20 years of experience in database and systems administration, which has developed his passion for performance optimization, database design, and making things go faster. He has spoken at many SQLSaturdays, 24 Hours of PASS, and PASS Summit. This led him to organize SQLSaturday Albany, which has become an annual event for New York’s Capital Region. Sharing these experiences with the community is a top priority, and encouraging everyone to take the leap into public speaking and engaging others, a passion.
In his free time, Ed enjoys video games, traveling, cooking exceptionally spicy foods, and hanging out with his amazing wife and sons.</description>
      <twitter>EdwardPollack</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=81593638</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlshack.com/author/edward-pollack/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=EdwardPollack</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74637</importID>
      <name>Dan Clark</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dan Clark is a senior data analytics consultant. He is focused on all things data analytics and training others how to get value from their data. Dan has published several books and numerous articles on .NET programming and data analytics. He is a regular speaker at various developer and database conferences and user group meetings and enjoys interacting with the Microsoft developer and database communities. His latest book Beginning Power BI published by Apress is a will get you up and running with self-service data analytics on the Power BI platform in no time.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dxclark/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://drclarkblog.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>80867</importID>
      <name>Denys Chamberland</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Graduated in Communications from Ryerson University in Toronto, Denys gained a solid background expertise
in digital audio video production before making the jump in computer programming. 
Since then, Denys has gained over 20 years of programming experience and has brought a significant collaboration in the creation,
the architecture and the development of several Web applications and software projects. Denys has also developed an expertise
in data visualization, notably the creation of custom 'on demand' BI visuals. 
A constant passion in exploring latest Microsoft Web and Azure technologies has brought him to play an active coaching role as Microsoft Community Contributor.</description>
      <twitter>@MawashiKid</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/denys-chamberland-08182922/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MawashiKid</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74278</importID>
      <name>Sophie Marchand</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Instigatrice du CFO masqu#233;, Sophie Marchand est d#233;tentrice d’une M.Sc. en finance corporative, d’un titre comptable CPA, CGA et d’un titre MVP (Most valuable professional) Excel  et d#39;un titre MVP Data Platform de Microsoft, et cumule de nombreuses ann#233;es d’exp#233;rience dans le milieu des affaires. Elle se sp#233;cialise particuli#232;rement en mod#233;lisation financi#232;re et en intelligence d’affaires. #192; ce titre, elle d#233;veloppe des mod#232;les financiers rigoureux, des tableaux de bord sophistiqu#233;s et des outils de gestion performants. Elle offre </description>
      <twitter>lecfomasque</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/marchandsophie</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.lecfomasque.com/accueil-mon-cher-watson/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=lecfomasque</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74195</importID>
      <name>Steve Simon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Simon is a Database Solutions Architect with Business Knowledge Services Inc. He has been involved with database design and analysis for over 35 years. Steve has presented papers at numerous PASS Summits and PASS SQL Rallies. He is also regular presenter on the SQL Saturday circuit and he is a contributor on SQLShack.com</description>
      <twitter>SQLServerBoffin</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stephenrsimon/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/simon_says/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLServerBoffin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82235</importID>
      <name>Jean Rene Roy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jean-Ren#233; Roy has been developing IT solution for large and small enterprises since 1987. In 1991 he founded the consulting firm Technologies SoftDesign Inc. 

Since that time he has worked on projects for House of Commons, Innovapost, Bell Canada, CGI, CNSC, Kraft, and many other clients assuming the responsibility of Business Analyst, Software Architect,ETL and BI Architect, Software Developers, Analyst, Team leader and mentor.  Jean-Ren#233; Roy is a SQL Server Microsoft MVP.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/#!/DevTeachConfere</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jeanreneroy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.softdesign.ca/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/#!/DevTeachConfere</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>77374</importID>
      <name>John Miner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Miner is currently a Data Architect at Insight DI (BlueMetal) advising corporations on how to solve their business needs with data platform solutions.

He has over twenty five years of data processing experience, and his architecture expertise encompasses all phases of the software project life cycle, including design, development, implementation, and maintenance of systems.

He has an undergraduate and graduate degrees in Computer Science from the University of Rhode Island.  Other credentials include an up to date MCSE certificate and currently taking the Data Science program from EDX.

Before joining BlueMetal, John won the Data Platform MVP award in 2014 and 2015 for his outstanding contributions to the SQL Server community.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/JohnMiner3</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/minerjohn/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mssqltips.com/sqlserverauthor/154/john-miner/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/JohnMiner3</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74166</importID>
      <name>Marcelo Adade</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marcelo is a Database Consultant at The Pythian Group. He has more than 10 years of experience in several Companies from different branches and sizes. Like financial companies, consultant shops, datacenters and e-commerce sites. Currently holds the MCSE, MCT and MCSA Microsoft Certifications and also the Oracle OCP. Loves technology and enjoys sharing his Database knowledge delivering presentations and official Microsoft Training Courses. Currently he is also the co-leader of the SQLMANIACS PASS User Group, based in Sao Paulo, Brazil</description>
      <twitter>@marceloadade</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://br.linkedin.com/in/marceloadade</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.dbbits.com.br</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@marceloadade</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>80497</importID>
      <name>Warner Chaves</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warner is a SQL Server MCM, Data Platform MVP and Principal Consultant at Pythian, a global Canada-based company specialized in DBA services. A brief stint in .NET programming led to his early DBA formation working for enterprise customers in Hewlett-Packard ITO organization. From there he transitioned to his current position at Pythian, building and managing data solutions in many industry verticals while leading a highly talented team of Data Platform consultants.</description>
      <twitter>@warchav</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/warnerchaves/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlturbo.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@warchav</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>77289</importID>
      <name>Mohamed Mawla</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Trilingual Principal Consultant amp; Team Tech lead at a global Tech Consulting Mohamed had worked with large SQL server environments such as financials and gov of hundreds of SQL server instances and enormous amounts of data. His favorite subjects are Cloud Analytics, performance tuning, High Availability, especially Replication and Disaster recovery. Certified Google Cloud and Azure Data Engineer.

When not working, Mohamed carries his cameras and takes a trip somewhere.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82362</importID>
      <name>Marco Russo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marco is a Business Intelligence consultant and mentor. He wrote several books about Power BI, Analysis Service, and Power Pivot. He also regularly writes articles and white papers that are available on sqlbi.com. Marco is a Microsoft MVP and an SSAS Maestro, the highest level of certification on Microsoft Analysis Services.
Today, Marco focuses his time with SQLBI customers, traveling extensively to train and consult on DAX and data modeling for Power BI and Analysis Services. Marco also teaches public classes worldwide.
Marco is a regular speaker at international conferences like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and SQLBits. He also enjoys delivering evening sessions at local user groups during his trips.</description>
      <twitter>marcorus</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlbi</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlbi.com/blog/marco</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=marcorus</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74237</importID>
      <name>Tim Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tim Gorman is a senior technical consultant for Delphix who securely enables masked data virtualization to increase the agility of IT development and testing while ending decades of security risk in SDLC.

Tim has co-authored six books on data warehousing and database administration, has performed technical review on eight more books, and has an author#39;s page on Amazon.com (http://www.amazon.com/Tim-Gorman/e/B00BKCTO5E).</description>
      <twitter>@TimGormanTech</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timgorman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://evdbt.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TimGormanTech</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>74639</importID>
      <name>Christophe Laporte</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Christophe Laporte is based in Toulouse, France and has worked with SQL Server since 1997, starting with SQL Server 6.5. Focusing on high availability, VLDBs, and virtualization, Christophe also delivers performance audits on SQL Server and helps companies in choosing the appropriate architectures (Cloud, OnPremise, or Hybrid). 
In addition to his MCM certification, Christophe is also a SQL MVP, speaker, and Microsoft Certified Trainer since 2000.</description>
      <twitter>conseilit</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://fr.linkedin.com/in/christophelaporte</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://conseilit.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=conseilit</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>76875</importID>
      <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kellyn Pot’Vin-Gorman is a member of the Oak Table Network and an Idera ACE and Oracle ACE Director alumnus. She is a Data Platform Architect in Power BI with AI in the EdTech group at Microsoft. Kellyn is known for her extensive work with multi-database platforms, DevOps, cloud migrations, virtualization, visualizations, scripting, environment optimization tuning, automation, and architecture design. 

Kellyn has spoken at numerous technical conferences for Oracle, Big Data, DevOps, testing, and SQL Server. Her blog (http://dbakevlar.com) and social media activity under her handle, DBAKevlar, is well respected for her insight and content.</description>
      <twitter>DBAKevlar</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellynpotvin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dbakevlar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAKevlar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>74200</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74200</id>
          <name>Steve Simon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>St-Laurent - 511</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Reporting Services 2017 on Steroids!!</title>
      <description>Reporting requests that are required ‘yesterday or sooner’, oft times necessitate working more efficiently and effectively. We have all been through this at one time or another.
In this hands on presentation we shall be looking some of the more challenging techniques of extracting our data from our Multidimensional and Tabular Models, in addition to our Data Mining Models. 
We shall be utilizing concepts of  ‘Openquery()’ and ‘linked servers’ as a means to extract data,  in addition to looking at the way that these two concepts can help us extract our data utilizing MDX, DMX and DAX expressions;  AND YET maintain the  flexibility and the ability to utilize all those wonderful techniques that may  be done with T-SQL.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 8:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 9:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74195</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74195</id>
          <name>Steve Simon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Laval - 510</name>
      </location>
      <title>An introduction to Data Mining  with SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>With the vast amount of changes that occur in our daily business environments, it becomes more and more difficult to achieve our corporate goals without some ‘lighthouse’ to guide our way. Data mining, (while not a panacea to resolve or ‘control’ the effects of these changes), can provide us with statistical trends by analyzing our data and highlighting probable outcomes.

In this hands on BEGINNERS presentation we shall be looking at Microsoft SQL Server’s Data Mining capabilities and we shall be discussing:

1)  Defining what questions we want answered and how to go about this in an effective and efficient manner.

2)  Creating the data model.

3)  How to gather the necessary data, discussing the training and testing aspect.

4)  Processing the model.

5)  Extracting information from our finished model, discussing the implications of this information.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74639</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74639</id>
          <name>Christophe Laporte</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database administration and performance management</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal A - 516</name>
      </location>
      <title>Les bases du dépannage SQL Server</title>
      <description>SQL Server, base de données la plus vendue en nombre de licences, reste relativement facile à administrer, tout en offrant un niveau de performance de premier ordre et une fiabilité excellente. Combien de "pannes" avec vous eu lors des 5 ou 10 dernière années ? Attention, ne me faites pas dire que l'on peut se passer des systèmes de haute disponibilité, FCI ou groupes de disponibilité. Il suffit de déterminer le RPO et le RTO et de monnayer l'indisponibilité du serveur pour déterminer si une stratégie de disaster recovery suffit, ou bien s'il faut prévoir la mise en haute disponibilité des ressources SQL.
Au final, le logiciel est fiable et ne provoque que très rarement des erreurs, des "plantages". 
Par contre, au quotidien, cela ne veut pas dire qu'il ne va pas y avoir de problèmes sur l'instance, principalement de connexion, d'autorisation ou de performance.
Au cours de cette session, nous allons aborder les bases du diagnostic et du dépannage SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74637</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74637</id>
          <name>Dan Clark</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal B - 517</name>
      </location>
      <title>Self-Service ETL with Power Query</title>
      <description>Before any significant data analysis can take place the data often needs to be transformed, aggregated, and combined. This is often referred to as the ETL (Extraction, Transform, and Load) process. Power Query is an excellent tool in the Microsoft self-service BI stack that allows business users to discover, combine, and refine data before loading it into a Power Pivot model for further analysis. In addition Microsoft has made connecting to a wide variety of sources including relational, structured, and semi structured data a consistent intuitive experience. This session guides you through using Power Query to extract, transform, and load data from various sources into a Power Pivot model. In addition we will look at the M language created by the tool and look at some advanced queries you can create using M.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74278</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74278</id>
          <name>Sophie Marchand</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>St-Laurent - 511</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI : Un tour complet de la solution</title>
      <description>Lors de cette session, nous survolerons l'ensemble des possibilités offertes par Power BI, de l'importation ou de la connexion aux données sources à la consommation de rapports sur le service web ou sur un serveur local (Power BI Report Server). Plus précisément, nous décortiquerons les options de:

 - importation et connexion aux données sources
 - transformation de données
 - modélisation de données
 - exploration de données
 - visualisation de données
 - publication et partage de rapports et de tableaux de bord
 - consommation de rapports et de tableaux de bord
 - analyse des données partagées 

En cours de présentation, nous allons également illustrer certains concepts par le biais de démos, de façon à ce que cette session, d'une durée d'une heure, propose un contenu à forte valeur ajoutée tout en étant dynamique et divertissante.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 2:25:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 3:25:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74212</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74212</id>
          <name>Edward Pollack</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database administration and performance management</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal A - 516</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Optimization Techniques</title>
      <description>How often have you been told that an application is running "too slow"?  This statement is the cause of a great deal of investigation, frustration, and dead-ends for database professionals.

The problem won't always be a bad query, but when it is, knowing how to dive in, diagnose its performance, and resolve the situation efficiently will turn a potentially frustrating situation into a fun one!  Using that knowledge in development to prevent future performance issues will improve script quality and application design, while making your future self less burdened by performance emergencies.

This is an opportunity to identify common query mistakes and learn a variety of ways in which we can solve them.  This discussion will include query rewrites, indexing, statistics, database design, monitoring, execution plans, and more!

Demos of poor-performing queries will be provided to illustrate key optimization techniques, design considerations, and the tools you need to fix them.  Fast.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 3:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 4:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>77289</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>77289</id>
          <name>Mohamed Mawla</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database administration and performance management</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal A - 516</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mapping SQL Server Expertise to Azure Cortana Intelligence - Cases and Scenarios</title>
      <description>Platform as Service offerings now enables developers to roll out their database infrastructure in minutes with minimal management overhead. However, this same amount of flexibility also comes with the challenges of picking the right tool, on the right provider and with the proper expectations. All of these are new challenges that are coming into the field of responsibility of the SQL DBA professional.

In this session, we'll map Cloud offerings, mainly Azure, that corresponds to the current features SQL Server DBAs use, their use cases for each one based on our client projects, and how they are different to the different SQL Server features we are familiar with. The goal is to get SQL Server DBAs on the latest Azure offerings and the echo of Cortana Intelligence.  If time allows, we will also show some offerings from Google Cloud.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 2:25:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 3:25:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74364</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74364</id>
          <name>Gregory Boge</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database administration and performance management</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal A - 516</name>
      </location>
      <title>J'ai migré un publisher sans réinitialiser la réplication</title>
      <description>Récemment, suite à une panne matérielle, j'ai du migrer les bases d'un publisher et la distribution sur un autre serveur. Puisque ces bases sont très volumineuses et que je n'avais pas à ma disposition de failover cluster sur le distributeur, je ne souhaitais pas devoir réinitialiser la réplication transactionnelle pour éviter les interruptions de service.
Dans cette session, je vais expliquer comment j'ai réalisé cette migration. Si vous ne connaissez pas la réplication, cette session vous permettra de comprendre comment elle fonctionne et les différents agents. Si vous maîtrisez la réplication, vous découvrirez peut être une nouvelle méthode de migration.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 9:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 10:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74237</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74237</id>
          <name>Tim Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database administration and performance management</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal A - 516</name>
      </location>
      <title>Accelerating Development and Testing Using Data Virtualization</title>
      <description>Constraining everything in development and testing is database size. Storage is a bottleneck, and while faster SSD/Flash is available, it is often too expensive due to the size of many databases, especially if not production. More importantly, it takes a lot of time to push terabytes around, and time itself is expensive. The old joke about "good, fast, and cheap -- pick any two" is very true with data.

Because providing full databases for each developer on each project seems unrealistic, when each copy might require terabytes of storage, for decades everyone has limited themselves to working in shared non-production environments that are refreshed only every few months at best. Conflicts occur,  quality suffers, and things move slowly.

Come learn why data virtualization is the solution to a problem everyone knows.

Good, fast, and cheap -- have all three with data virtualization.  Clone things easily and quickly, and remove the biggest constraint to development and testing.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>76875</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>76875</id>
          <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database administration and performance management</track>
      <location>
        <name>St-Laurent - 511</name>
      </location>
      <title>Screw DevOps, Let's Talk DataOps</title>
      <description>DevOps is the new hot topic for IT, but only answers part of the problem. This session and demo will discuss why data creates continual friction in the DevOps environment and how it must be incorporated into the solution.
Reasons for this solution is required: -Data is getting bigger and more complex -Security concerns around critical data is becoming more evident every day -Data is created in silos in many sources, yet consumed in just as many locations, including on-premises and in the cloud.

We'll discuss the tech, the politics and the challenges of bringing data into DevOps and how to do so more successfully with culture changes, tools, scripting, and virtualization.

Takeaways from this session:
1. Learn the five principles of Data Ops 2. How embracing a dynamic data platform can eliminate challenges and provide automation. 3. Learn the difference between containers, packages and data pods. 4. Learn how to bridge the gap between data and people, eliminating culture from the scene</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 3:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 4:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>77374</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>77374</id>
          <name>John Miner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>St-Laurent - 511</name>
      </location>
      <title>Effective Data Warehouse Storage Patterns</title>
      <description>Abstract:

Many companies start off with a simple data mart for reporting. As the company grows, users become dependent on the data mart for monitoring and making decisions on Key Performance Indicators (KPI).

Unexpected information growth in your data mart may lead to a performance impacted reporting system. In short, your users will be lining up at your cube for their daily reports.

How do you reduce the size of your data mart and speed up data retrieval?

This presentation will review the following techniques to fix your woes.

Coverage:

1 – What is horizontal partitioning?
2 – Database sharding for daily information.
3 – Working with files and file groups.
3 – Partitioned views for performance.
4 – Table and Index partitions.
5 – Row Data Compression.
6 – Page Data Compression.
7 – Programming a sliding window.
8 – What is different in Azure SQL database?</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>78520</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>78520</id>
          <name>Franck Mercier</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal A - 516</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Microsoft Azure Databricks</title>
      <description>Azure Databricks is a fast, easy and collaborative Apache® Spark™ based analytics platform optimized for Azure. Designed in collaboration with the founders of Apache Spark, Azure Databricks combines the best of Databricks and Azure to help you accelerate innovation with one-click set up; streamlined workflows and an interactive workspace that enables collaboration between data scientists, data engineers, and business analysts.
As a first-class Azure services, you automatically benefit native integration with other Azure services such as Power BI, SQL Data Warehouse, Cosmos DB as well as from enterprise-grade Azure security, including Active Directory integration, compliance, and enterprise-grade SLAs. 
Azure Databricks is well design to modernizing your existing data warehouse solutions for querying and reporting on data, capitalizing on Spark-based analytics for advanced analytics workloads, and real-time analytics on streaming data. 
During this presentation, you will discover what A</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 8:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 9:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>80867</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>80867</id>
          <name>Denys Chamberland</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Development and TSQL</track>
      <location>
        <name>St-Laurent - 511</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB + Gremlin API in Action</title>
      <description>Graph databases have been around in various
forms for a long time, in a wide range of data analysis from science technology
to business scenarios. However, there may still be a small pool of T-SQL
experts with graph experience, especially dealing with Gremlin traversal query language.
That's fully understandable. The session is not aimed on encouraging users to stop
using T-SQL, but rather giving them a new performing blade on their data analysis Swiss knife so to
speak. This session will start with a quick overview of new Azure Cosmos DB - Graph API options
It will then expose main comparaison between T-SQL vs Gremlin, and reasons why
graph may be more beneficial.
It will then give a basic introduction of Gremlin Transversal topology in real context.
Finally a demo will cover how to create a new Azure Cosmos DB - Graph API project
from Visual Studio Code. 
1.Generating Vertex and Edges through Core 2.0 Console Application +  
2.Consuming Graph API data query in Core .2.0 Web client.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 9:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 10:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>80497</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>80497</id>
          <name>Warner Chaves</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>St-Laurent - 511</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Data Warehouse for the SQL Server DBA</title>
      <description>The power of cloud storage and compute power has made data warehousing possible for businesses of all sizes. What was once a large capital expenditure and multi-year implementation can now be deployed and ready to use within minutes and allow any organization to collect, query and discover insights from their structured data sources. 

With a full T-SQL interface and compatibility with the rest of the Microsoft data stack, Azure Data Warehouse can fit transparently into your business data strategy and leverage already existing and familiar development and management skills.
 
In this session we will look at the main concepts of the Azure SQL Data Warehouse service, how it's different than SQL Server and the advantages it provides to an on-premises solution.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82361</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82361</id>
          <name>Marco Russo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal B - 517</name>
      </location>
      <title>My Power BI report is slow: what should I do?</title>
      <description>Abstract	You created a wonderful Power BI report, but when you open it you wait too much time. Changing a slicer selection is also slow. Where should you start analyzing the problem? What can you do to optimize performance?
This session will guide you in analyzing the possible reasons for a slow Power BI report. By using Task Manager and DAX Studio, you will be able to determine whether you should change the report layout, or if there is something in DAX formulas or in the data model that is responsible for the slow response.
At the end of this session, you will understand how to locate a performance bottleneck in a Power BI report, so you will focus your attention on the biggest issue.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74636</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74636</id>
          <name>Dan Clark</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal B - 517</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power Query Deep Dive</title>
      <description>Power Query is a great tool for extracting, transforming, and loading data.  It has an intuitive interface that allows you to create queries without having to worry about writing code. Under the covers Power Query is creating the M code that gets executed. In this session we will pull back the covers to reveal and understand the M code that is being created. This will give you greater insight into how to debug your queries. In addition, we will look at creating advance queries that go beyond what is available using the Power Query user interface.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 3:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 4:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82235</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82235</id>
          <name>Jean Rene Roy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Laval - 510</name>
      </location>
      <title>What Azure platform have to offer for your data</title>
      <description>The evolution of the Azure Platform is impressive. This sessions will provide you information on the long list of services you can use to create, manage and transform your data. From a operation application to Artifice Intelligence this sessions explain why the future of your data is in the cloud.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 2:25:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 3:25:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82362</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82362</id>
          <name>Marco Russo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal B - 517</name>
      </location>
      <title>Time intelligence and date tables in Power BI</title>
      <description>Every Power BI model has dates and the need of calculation over dates to aggregate and compare data, like Year-To-Date, Same-Period-Last-Year, Moving Average, and so on. Quick measures and DAX functions can help, but how do you manage holidays, working days, weeks based fiscal calendars and any non-standard calculation’
This session provides you the best practices to correctly shape a data model and to implement time intelligence calculations using both built-in DAX functions and custom DAX calculation for more complex and non-standard requirements.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 9:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 10:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74174</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74174</id>
          <name>Vitor Fava</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Data warehouse and BI delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Montreal B - 517</name>
      </location>
      <title>Implementing AI solutions using the cognitive services in Azure</title>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence (AI) is bringing big changes in the way people and businesses relate to technology.
As well as the arrival of the personal computer, the cloud computing and smartphones, the AI is the artificial technology that takes you to where you're going so much faster, intuitive and smart.
In this session we will discuss the basics of IA and how we can apply it in our business using the Azure Cognitive Services.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 8:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 9:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>74166</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>74166</id>
          <name>Marcelo Adade</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database administration and performance management</track>
      <location>
        <name>Laval - 510</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hybrid Theory - Synchronizing data between Azure SQL Database and  SQL SERVER Instances</title>
      <description>Would you like to use Azure SQL Database (PaaS) and keep its data in sync to your Datacenter? Then this session is for you! Let's walk thru the Database set up and how to use Data Sync to make sure data between your datacenter and Azure are synchronized. The Data Sync allows for bidirectional data transfer, meaning you can transfer data from your local Db to the Cloud and vice-versa.</description>
      <startTime>6/2/2018 9:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/2/2018 10:50:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>