<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #562 - Malaysia 2016</name>
    <startDate>9/10/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+08:00) Irkutsk, Ulaan Bataar</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatMalaysia</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Malaysia</name>
      <street>Level 26, Menara 3 Petronas, KLCC</street>
      <city>Kuala Lumpur</city>
      <state>Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia</state>
      <zipcode>
      </zipcode>
      <longitude>101.7108307</longitude>
      <latitude>3.15804</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor (500 USD)</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52606</importID>
      <name>Dinesh Priyankara</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dinesh is an experienced professional and database enthusiast with skills in database management systems and business intelligence. Possessing over 18 years of experience on data related technologies, he does training, consulting, and is a top contributor to the local SQL Server community. In recognition of his contributions and expertise he has demonstrated, he was awarded the Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) award for SQL Server for 13 consecutive years since 2006.
He is a Subject Matter Expert on SQL Server exams and has contributed for SQL Server 2012, 2016, 2017 and Azure Data Engineering exam development and Job Task Analysis (JTA).
Dinesh is the Founder/Principal Architect of dinesQL (Pvt) Ltd (http://dinesql.com). In his</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/dinesh_priya</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://lk.linkedin.com/in/dineshpriyankara/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dinesql.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/dinesh_priya</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53058</importID>
      <name>Gogula Aryalingam</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gogula is a data analytics professional from Sri Lanka, with 14+ years on the Microsoft data platform. He has worked with many aspects of data analytics and BI solutions from architecting, designing, developing and consulting across various industries and verticals. He is Regional Mentor for PASS South Asia, Data Platform MVP, MCSE, former MCT, and MSc in IT. Gogula's passion revolves data analytics and BI; hence enjoys writing, teaching and speaking about the things he works with. He was also involved as an SME for Microsoft certification development. He currently juggles his full time job as Lead Architect while speaking at local and foreign events, along with regular stints at the Sri Lankan Data Community which he co-founded.</description>
      <twitter>http://www.twitter.com/gogula</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/gogula</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datamaul.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://www.twitter.com/gogula</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52629</importID>
      <name>Nagaraj Venkatesan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nagaraj Venkatesan is a Data Platform MVP from Singapore and the leader of Singapore SQL PASS Chapter. As a SQL Server enthusiast, Nagaraj is a regular speaker in Asia Pacific region at Data Platform events like SQL Saturdays, SQL Server Geeks Summit, User group meetups etc.  Nagaraj shares his technical expertise at strictlysql.blogspot.com. Nagaraj also runs a YouTube channel called "DataChannel", which contains technical interviews with top Microsoft Data Platform experts in the world.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/arrnagaraj</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://in.linkedin.com/in/nagaraj-venkatesan-b6958b6</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://strictlysql.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/arrnagaraj</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53169</importID>
      <name>Dharmendra Keshari</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dharmendra Keshari has strong and in-depth experience in Database Management. Currently, working as Technical Specialist for Data Platform at Microsoft in Singapore and handling one of the most critical databases support for clients.

Dharmendra is an avid, regular mentor on social media, helping several enthusiast in solving their problems related to Database management. he is co-leader and regular speaker at Singapore SQL Server Pass Chapter (User Group). He has done certification for “Microsoft SQL Server#174; 2008, Implementation” and “Maintenance amp; Administering Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Database”.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://sg.linkedin.com/in/dharmendra-keshari-a7043398</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dharmendrakeshari.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53245</importID>
      <name>Dr. J. Joshua Thomas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr. J. Joshua Thomas, MSc, Ph.D., is currently a senior lecturer in department of computing at the School of Engineering, Computing and Built Environment, KDU Penang University College. He received his PhD in Intelligent Systems Techniques from University Sains Malaysia. He is currently work with machine learning (Deep learning) problems in computer vision, cross industry standard process for data science/mining (CRISP-DM) targeting manufacturing sensor dataset modelling, evaluation and deployment, Big data visual analytics and its applications. He has published academic articles from his research domain as book chapters, journal articles and conference proceedings. He has experience in Microsoft PowerBI, Azure Machine Learning studio.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50320</importID>
      <name>Manjot Kaur</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working with SQL server for over 10 years. I have been an internal DBA and a consultant. 
I am passionate about automation, cloud technologies, performance tuning and learning SQL internals.
In my free time I love to read, playing with my toddler and trying my hands on new recipes.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52486</importID>
      <name>Virendra Kumar Yaduvanshi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Competent, accomplished and result oriented information technology specialist with 20 years of experience, Dynamic leadership career, and demonstrated success in designing and implementing Database with emphasis on System Administration, Database Administration, Technologies deployment and technical analysis of multi-client operations, 
Innovative, result-driven leader with diverse IT experience emphasizing cross platform systems and network architecture, engineering, installation/implementation, integration, security and Administration for a VLDBs projects.
MCTS, MCITP and ITIL - applies broad technical expertise to resolve complex systems and DBs issues associated with progressive growth/expansion.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/v_yaduvanshi</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/virendrayaduvanshi</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://wikidba.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/v_yaduvanshi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53240</importID>
      <name>Ian Choy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ian Choy is Microsoft#39;s Technology Solution Professional for the data platform business, working with customers on Microsoft data platform adoption, architecture design decisions and best practices. His work and passion involves partner enablement on upcoming Microsoft technology and involvement community events. Prior experiences includes managing large scale data warehouse operations, business intelligence implementations and software development projects.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53861</importID>
      <name>Darien Nagle</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Darien has over 30 years of IT experience including former positions at TIBCO and Microsoft. Darien has worked across Australia and Southeast Asia including as Specialist Director at Microsoft Malaysia. An accomplished Cloud Computing seller and recognised best-practices global speaker, Darien is a believer in a future of Platform-as-a-Service-based cloud applications. His expertise includes establishing and embracing a customer's cloud journey and jointly developing a cloud technology roadmap incorporating some quick value-based wins up front. His current technologies and solutions expertise are too broad to mention here but include Linux and Windows virtual machines in the cloud, SAP on Microsoft Azure, SQL Server and BI, and many more.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53253</importID>
      <name>Chiu Kiang Phua</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chiu Kiang is the principal of PCK Consulting, a provider for SQL Server and Microsoft .NET development and consulting services. He works with customers and partners on technologies covering data management, business intelligence, performance tuning and enterprise integration.  He is currently in his 11th year in his role as a Microsoft MVP for SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>51070</importID>
      <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr.SubraMANI Paramasivam is a Microsoft MVP, PhD, Microsoft Certified Trainer and Head of Data  AI at DAGEOP Ltd having 21 years of DB, BI, Analytics and AI experience. Mani has also spoken in various events like MS IGNITE, PASS Summit, MS Inspire, SQLBITS, Power Platform Summit, Global AI Bootcamp, Data  BI Summit, SQLRelay,  Power BI World Tour, Data Platform Summit, INSIDESQL UK, Global AI Nights, SQLServerGeeks Summit, MCT Global Summits, Data Day Events and various user group events. Mani also believes in Empowering Every Person in the planet and spreads the awareness on Global challenges via www.EmpoweringEveryPerson.com. He is also a co-owner of 1 Global AI Meetup and 3 Power BI PUG  PASS local / user groups.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dageop</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/dageop</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.yoursqlman.com/index.php/blogs</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dageop</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53241</importID>
      <name>Deh Hui Chuan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Deh Hui brings with her a breadth of marketing, business and technology experience on the data platform, having started off as a Microsoft Certified Professional on SQL Server early in her career, having done business analysis with data tools - SAS/ SPSS and now marketing the data platform stack - SQL Server, Power BI, Datazen, Revolution Analytics. She is well recognized having won accolades such as NextGen Marketing Leader, Leadership Development and Talent Acceleration programs. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://my.linkedin.com/pub/dehhui-chuan/1/271/a66</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52339</importID>
      <name>Dinesh Asanka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dinesh Asanka MVP for more than 8 years and has experience over 15 years with SQL Server different versions. He has spoken in Sri Lanka as well as out side conferences.  Regular writer at SQL-Server-Performance.com and co-authored couple of books on SQL Server.  Visiting Lecturer at Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT), Sri Lanka on subjects such as Database Administration, Big Data Analytics, Data Security, Data warehousing amp; Data Mining at B.Sc and M.Sc level. 
Currently, reading for Mphil in the areas of data warehouse and fuzzy technology at University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka.</description>
      <twitter>@dineshasanka</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://lk.linkedin.com/in/dineshasanka</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://htttp://dbfriend.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dineshasanka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52605</importID>
      <name>Jason Aw</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A passionate IT leader with over 20 years of experience in in technology, infrastructure, cloud environments particularly with high availability and disaster recovery solutions for different architectures including SQL database applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/awjason</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sios-apac.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>53248</importID>
      <name>Juv Chan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Microsoft Azure MVP
https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/PublicProfile/5002031</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/juvchan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://my.linkedin.com/in/juv-chan-6104a540</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/juvchan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50440</importID>
      <name>Hamid J. Fard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am SQL Server Data BI Platform Expert with more than 9 years’ of professional experience, I am currently Microsoft Certified Master: SQL Server 2008, Microsoft Certified Solutions Master: Charter-Data Platform, Microsoft Data Platform MVP and CIW Database Design Specialist. After a few years of being a production database administrator I jumped into the role of Data Platform Expert. Being a consultant allows me to work directly with customers to help solve questions regarding database issues for SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://my.linkedin.com/in/hamidjfard</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>52629</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52629</id>
          <name>Nagaraj Venkatesan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Query Store - The Real "Deal"</title>
      <description>"Why my database performance has been suddenly slow? 
 Have my query plans changed? 
 Which plans have regressed and since when? 
 Is there any way I can control the plan change without changing the source code?"

If you have encountered any of the above situations, then query store is your remedy. SQL Server Query store is one of the path breaking features released in SQL Server 2016. The presentation will showcase how query store is a boon in handling sudden performance degradations, plan changes and analyzing query performance patterns over a period of time. Presentation will also demonstrate the power of query store in forcing query plans and compare it against   options available in earlier versions of SQL Server. Presentation will have interesting demos on tracking plan regressions and on scenarios the use force plans feature. At the end of the session, audience will have a clear understanding on how query store becomes their new important weapon in their arsenal, for performance</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52606</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52606</id>
          <name>Dinesh Priyankara</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Processing unstructured data</title>
      <description>Receiving imperfectly column-aligned data from applications is becoming a norm. However preparing this data for pre-defined relational structures using traditional methods is becoming significantly complex. Many implementations though, still handle this using traditional programming techniques - but isn't this still a database related task? And shouldn't the components of the Database Management Systems bear the responsibility of getting this done? With new features incorporated into modern database platforms, processing unstructured data is no longer a challenge, and can be performed easily. Let us take a sample data set and see how we do this the Microsoft way, of course using Microsoft SQL Server product suite including cloud offerings such as HDInsight.</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53245</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53245</id>
          <name>Dr. J. Joshua Thomas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Analytics: Drill, Hit, Predict and Visualize</title>
      <description>Data acquisition becomes extremely easier and companies start using huge amount of data to analyse customer behaviours, and to provide customers with more tailored service.  Data analytics is become progressively important in services organisations. Among various data processing approaches machine learning is predominantly imperative. According to user’s interests, automatically predict things that have the same feature to the users is also a crucial part of user personalised service. If sophisticated visual analyses generate immediate results presented in ways that shows patterns and allow exploration people across all levels to make effective decisions. This session will highlight on Microsoft’s Azure, Power BI tools to explore relevant data sources.
</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53169</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53169</id>
          <name>Dharmendra Keshari</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Troubleshooting Issues with Extended Events in real time</title>
      <description>Extended events to aid in performance tuning and in day to day administration specially when you don't have any benchmarking data for troubleshooting issues. In this session, we will see how the Extended Events streaming API can be used to process events in a near real-time. We will demonstrate how this feature enables new possibilities to capture real time problems without enabling any third party tools or inbuilt SQL Server features to capture issues like blocking,  deadlocks, high CPU and many more.
Extended Events were introduced in SQL Server 2008 but by SQL Server 2016, it has enhanced significantly. After this session, hopefully you will start using extended event, if you haven't started using till now.</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>51070</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>51070</id>
          <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hyperscale technology lets a DBA sleep, +30 minutes a day!</title>
      <description>Ease of access and easy life is now possible with On-premises and hybrid cloud technology within SQL Server 2016.

SQL 2016 Hyperscale technology gives us a huge relief in Backups, Disaster Recovery solutions, access resources no matter whether they are in on-premises, private or public cloud. New tools within SQL Server 2016 and Microsoft Azure has made every single DBA/Developers life much easier to scale to the cloud. 

This session will enable you to start working on scaling to the cloud and benefit from the SQL Server 2016's advanced new features.</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52486</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52486</id>
          <name>Virendra Kumar Yaduvanshi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Innovative Strategies for SQL Server Disaster Recovery</title>
      <description>Innovative Strategies for SQL Server Disaster Recovery</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53058</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53058</id>
          <name>Gogula Aryalingam</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI: The shift to business-led self-service analytics</title>
      <description>The recent past has shown us how the business intelligence landscape is shifting away from an IT-led paradigm to a business-led paradigm. This paradigm attempts to put the power of data in the hands of users for self-service. Power BI is Microsoft's self-service business intelligence offering, and is now standing out as a leader in self-service business intelligence. Join this session to learn what Power BI is all about and its capabilities. We'll then move over to various usage scenarios and how Power BI helps save the day. We will also take a look at how Power BI fronts the capabilities of advanced analytics on Azure, and brings it down to the end user.</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50440</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50440</id>
          <name>Hamid J. Fard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Database Backup Internals</title>
      <description>At this session, we will discuss about how SQL Server Database Backup works internally and why your database backup process takes long time to be completed! By attending this session, you will learn how to optimize SQL Server Database Backup process.</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52339</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52339</id>
          <name>Dinesh Asanka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Machine Learning  with SQL Server 2016 R Services</title>
      <description>Microsoft recently launched SQL Server 2016, which, in addition to many other great features, offers in-database advanced analytics with R Services, allowing users to combine the power of SQL Server and Microsoft R Server (or Open Source R), without data leaving the database.

With SQL Server R Services, users can develop analytic models in a local R IDE and it has it's own template as well for support different industry needs. </description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52605</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52605</id>
          <name>Jason Aw</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Practical Strategies For High Performance SQL Server High Availability</title>
      <description>High availability doesn't have to mean slow SQL server performance. In this informative webinar, Jason Aw, from SIOS Technology Corp. will share his practical strategies for boosting performance in these IO-intensive environments. He will also discuss the benefits of combining leading high performance storage platforms and high availability solutions to deliver continuous availability and faster application response times in SQL Server environments.</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53240</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53240</id>
          <name>Ian Choy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>instant Business Insight with Azure SQL and Power BI</title>
      <description>Start gaining the benefits of going to the Cloud for your Business Intelligence needs right now!
In this session we will explore how we can start implementing and using both Azure SQL and Power BI together.
The idea is to develop a demo template that audience can take away and start building their own real-world solution.
Heck, we may even implement some cool Azure SQL features like operational analytic if time permits. ;-)
</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50320</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50320</id>
          <name>Manjot Kaur</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance Based Indexing</title>
      <description>SQL server indexes need to be effective so that data could be manipulated with minimum resource consumption. Having too few indexes will result in scanning full tables and having too many indexes will result in incurring un-necessary costs in keeping the index up-to-date. Even if the number of indexes "seem" sufficient, de-fragmenting is only one side of the story. In this session, we will cover index creation best practices and demo sql cache based index tuning, duplicate indexes, and more.
</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53253</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53253</id>
          <name>Chiu Kiang Phua</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Top New Features in SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>This session covers the top new features in SQL Server 2016</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>53248</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>53248</id>
          <name>Juv Chan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building Multiclass Prediction Model  API with Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <description>Step-by-step walkthrough on how to use Azure Machine Learning to build a prediction model and API for a beginner's multiclass classification problem with sample dataset.</description>
      <startTime>9/10/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/10/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>