<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #587 - Sydney 2017</name>
    <startDate>2/18/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>180</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+10:00) Brisbane</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatSydney</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>UTS Building 4, Level 3</name>
      <street>15 Broadway, Ultimo</street>
      <city>Sydney</city>
      <state>New South Wales, Australia</state>
      <zipcode>2007</zipcode>
      <longitude>151.201131865082</longitude>
      <latitude>-33.8829624725239</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1589</importID>
      <name>Agile BI</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.agilebi.com.au/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.agilebi.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Agile-BI-Logo-3401.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1272</importID>
      <name>WARDY IT Solutions</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.wardyit.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/986/EventSponsor_14725.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>98</importID>
      <name>Angry Koala</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://angrykoala.com.au</url>
      <imageURL>http://angrykoala.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/ak_logo_250.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1870</importID>
      <name>ACS Foundation</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://acsfoundation.com.au/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.careersfortomorrow.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/acs-foundation-logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/908/EventSponsor_14257.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56693</importID>
      <name>Adam Gilmore</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adam Gilmore is a Data Warehousing and Business Intelligence Architect with 10+ years experience using Microsoft technologies to deliver BI and DW Solutions.  Adam is the Founder of Dimodelo Solutions, an Agile Data Warehousing and Business Intelligence consultancy. Dimodelo Solutions is the developer of 'Dimodelo Architect' an Agile Data Warehouse development tool built on the Microsoft Visual Studio platform.

Adam has presented at a number of SQL Server events in Brisbane including the SQL Server User Group and SQL Server Saturday.</description>
      <twitter>@dimodelo</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/adam-gilmore/3/902/576</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.dimodelo.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dimodelo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61595</importID>
      <name>Guy Glantser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Guy Glantser, Data Platform MVP, is the leader of the Israeli PASS Local Group, as well as the CEO and founder of Madeira Data Solutions. His career has been focused on the Microsoft Data Platform for the past 20 years, performing various database roles as either an on-site DBA, an external consultant, or a speaker. His main area of expertise is SQL Server development and optimization. Guy is involved in many activities in the Microsoft Data Platform community. He occasionally speaks at community events, such as PASS Summit, SQLBits, SQLSaturdays, and user groups around the world. He also co-hosts the SQL Server Radio podcast.</description>
      <twitter>guy_glantser</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/glantser</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.madeiradata.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=guy_glantser</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56996</importID>
      <name>Leila Etaati</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leila Etaati is the First Microsoft AI MVP in New Zealand and Australia, as well as a Data Platform MVP. She has a Ph.D. from the University of Auckland and is the co-director and data scientist in RADACAD company with many clients around the world. Additionally, she is the co-organizer of Microsoft Business Intelligence and Power BI Use group in Auckland with more than 1300 members. Leila has also co-organized 3 main conferences in Auckland: SQL Saturday Auckland (from 2015), Difinity (from 2017) and Global AI Bootcamp. She is a data scientist, BI consultant, trainer, and speaker. She is a well-known International speaker to many conferences such as MS Ignite, SQL PASS, Data Platform Summit, SQL Saturday, Power BI World Tour and in Europe, USA, Asia, Australia, and NZ. She has over 10 years’ experience with databases and software systems. Leila is an active Technical Microsoft AI blogger in RADACAD.</description>
      <twitter>@leila_etaati</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/pub/leila-etaati/36/46/b03</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.radacad.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@leila_etaati</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59912</importID>
      <name>Ajay Jagannathan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ajay Jagannathan is a Principal Program Manager Lead for Azure SQL Database and SQL Server Engine PM team, based in Redmond. He has an MS in Computer Science and over 20 years of industry experience. He is currently responsible for driving product strategy and roadmap for the database engine for SQL Server and Azure SQL Database to deliver breakthrough innovations and product experiences from inception to engaged customer usage that modernize database to handle the speed, variety and scale of today's data.  He partners closely with several customers to understand  product usage and feedback to drive improvements in the product. He has deep experience in various features of the database engine spanning over ten versions (SQL 6.5- SQL 2017).</description>
      <twitter>@ajaymsft</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/sqlserverstorageengine/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ajaymsft</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61594</importID>
      <name>Grant Paisley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Grant Paisley is a Data Platform MVP and founder of Angry Koala, a Microsoft Business Intelligence partner based in Sydney, Australia. Grant is president of the SQL Server Usergroup Sydney and created http://reportsurfer.com, a community built around reporting, where you can also run the reports. He was contributing author for quot;SQL Server 2008 Analysis Services with MDXquot; and quot;Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services Recipesquot;.</description>
      <twitter>@angrykoala</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@angrykoala</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56657</importID>
      <name>Kevin Boles</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Boles is a SQL Server expert, working exclusively with the product since v6.5. With over 25 years of database experience and over 45,000 man hours of SQL Server engine experience, he holds many related certifications, is an MCT and was a SQL Server MVP from 2007 to 2012. Kevin has been a very successful independent consultant for over 20 years. His passion is the relational engine, especially designing, building, analyzing and tuning high-performance database applications.</description>
      <twitter>@TheSQLGuru</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/thesqlguru</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TheSQLGuru</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56193</importID>
      <name>Victor Isakov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Victor Isakov (MCA, MCM, MCSM, MCT, MVP) is a Database Architect and trainer who provides consulting and training services to various organizations in the public, private, and NGO sectors globally. He regularly speaks at international conferences such as Microsoft TechEd/Ignite, PASS Summit, IT/Dev Connections, and SQLSaturdays.
Victor has written a number of books on SQL Server and has worked with Microsoft to develop the SQL Server exams and certification. In 2017 he authored "Exam Ref 70-764 Administering a SQL Database Infrastructure (1st Edition)".
He is one of only three non-Microsoft, Microsoft Certified Architects in the world.</description>
      <twitter>@victorisakov</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/victorisakov</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.victorisakov.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@victorisakov</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56978</importID>
      <name>Allen White</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Allen White is a Data Platform consultant. He has been both a developer and an administrator, so he understands both perspectives towards database technology. He loves sharing his experiences and helping people learn how to use SQL Server. Allen has spent over 40 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1992, and has been awarded Microsoft’s MVP Award for the last 13 years. Allen was a PASS Director from 2016 - 2018.</description>
      <twitter>SQLRunr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/allen-white-sql-server-mvp/5/784/b08/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataperfpro.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLRunr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61807</importID>
      <name>Grant Paisley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Grant Paisley is a Data Platform MVP and founder of Angry Koala, a Microsoft Business Intelligence partner based in Sydney, Australia. Grant is president of the SQL Server Usergroup Sydney and created http://reportsurfer.com, a community built around reporting, where you can also run the reports. He was contributing author for quot;SQL Server 2008 Analysis Services with MDXquot; and quot;Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services Recipesquot;.</description>
      <twitter>@angrykoala</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@angrykoala</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56412</importID>
      <name>Nagaraj Venkatesan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nagaraj Venkatesan is a Data Platform MVP from Singapore and the leader of Singapore SQL PASS Chapter. As a SQL Server enthusiast, Nagaraj is a regular speaker in Asia Pacific region at Data Platform events like SQL Saturdays, SQL Server Geeks Summit, User group meetups etc.  Nagaraj shares his technical expertise at strictlysql.blogspot.com. Nagaraj also runs a YouTube channel called "DataChannel", which contains technical interviews with top Microsoft Data Platform experts in the world.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/arrnagaraj</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://in.linkedin.com/in/nagaraj-venkatesan-b6958b6</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://strictlysql.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/arrnagaraj</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57192</importID>
      <name>Hamish Watson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hamish Watson is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware Expert with a passion for efficient database and application deployment using DevOps methodologies. 

He has 20+ years of IT experience in managing and deploying large scale databases on SQL Server technologies. 

He has been managing SQL Server since SQL Server 2000, and pragmatic approaches to delivering business value to clients is his career passion.

Educating and helping others learn is a driver for Hamish. He is a Director-At-Large on the PASS Board, international speaker, and a repeat guest lecturer at a local university.</description>
      <twitter>theHybridDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/in/hamishwatson8</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/the-hybrid-dbas-blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=theHybridDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>55126</importID>
      <name>Tobias Koprowski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Founder of Shadowland Consulting. In January 2015 decided to permanently leave Poland and discover new worlds. Actually settled in Hucknall (The Last home of The Byron Family). Community leader focused on SQL Server, SharePoint, security, collaboration and ITIL, DR, BCM, and SLA. Love licensing stuff. 

Microsoft Certified Trainer, freelancer, and consultant. Subject Matter Expert at Microsoft. Member of Microsoft Terminology Community, Friends of RedGate PLUS, PASS, ISSA, ACM and more. Since 1st July 2010 Data Platform MVP. Creator of SQLDAY Conference and Conference CEO 2009-2011. Co-Leader of PASS East Midlands Group. Speaker at group meetings and conferences. STEM Ambassador. 

Traveler. Coffee Addicted.</description>
      <twitter>@KoprowskiT</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/koprowskit</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://koprowskit.eu/geek/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KoprowskiT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>62426</importID>
      <name>Grant Paisley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Grant Paisley is a Data Platform MVP and founder of Angry Koala, a Microsoft Business Intelligence partner based in Sydney, Australia. Grant is president of the SQL Server Usergroup Sydney and created http://reportsurfer.com, a community built around reporting, where you can also run the reports. He was contributing author for quot;SQL Server 2008 Analysis Services with MDXquot; and quot;Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services Recipesquot;.</description>
      <twitter>@angrykoala</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@angrykoala</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56216</importID>
      <name>Matt Allington</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt is a BI Professional with over 30 years’ experience in the Consumer Packaged Goods industry. He has held senior job commercial and IT roles, always leveraging data to drive success.  Matt was the BI Director for Asia Pacific at The Coca-Cola Company before leaving to set up his own consulting business in 2014.

Matt is now the Principal Consultant at Excelerator BI and specialises in helping small, medium and large companies leverage Microsoft Excel, Power Pivot, Power BI and SharePoint to deliver rapid business value through Self Service Business Intelligence.</description>
      <twitter>@exceleratorbi</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://au.linkedin.com/in/mattallington</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://exceleratorbi.com.au/exceleratorblog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@exceleratorbi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57478</importID>
      <name>Marco Russo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marco is a Business Intelligence consultant and mentor. He wrote several books about Power BI, Analysis Service, and Power Pivot. He also regularly writes articles and white papers that are available on sqlbi.com. Marco is a Microsoft MVP and an SSAS Maestro, the highest level of certification on Microsoft Analysis Services.
Today, Marco focuses his time with SQLBI customers, traveling extensively to train and consult on DAX and data modeling for Power BI and Analysis Services. Marco also teaches public classes worldwide.
Marco is a regular speaker at international conferences like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and SQLBits. He also enjoys delivering evening sessions at local user groups during his trips.</description>
      <twitter>marcorus</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlbi</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlbi.com/blog/marco</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=marcorus</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54938</importID>
      <name>Manohar Punna</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Manohar Punna is an Data Platform Geek and Vice President of DataPlatformGeeks by passion and a Data Platform Consultant by profession. He is a speaker at various conferences like PASS Summit, SQLBits, DPS. He has authored over 150 blogs and has written a One DMV a Day series which is a longest one day series on any topic on SQL Server till date.
Manohar is a product of this community and strongly believes in giving back to the community. So, ask him anything you would like to know and he is happy to learn it with you.</description>
      <twitter>ManuSQLGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/manohar-punna/15/153/508</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservergeeks.com/author/manoharpunna/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ManuSQLGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56889</importID>
      <name>Reza Rad</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reza Rad is a Microsoft Regional Director, MVP, author, trainer, speaker and consultant. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for nine years from 2011.
Reza wrote many books on Power BI subjects including the Power BI from Rookie to Rock Star, and Pro Power BI Architecture.
Reza is the invited speaker at the world's well-known conferences such as Microsoft Ignite, Microsoft Business Applications Summit, Ignite Tour, PASS Summit, and many other conferences.
Reza is an active blogger and writes regularly about Power BI at https://radacad.com.</description>
      <twitter>Rad_Reza</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/in/rezarad/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://radacad.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rad_Reza</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56964</importID>
      <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Flynn is a Senior Database Administrator with 10 years experience in large 24 x 7 enterprise environments. He is a certified master for SQL Server and a regular attendee of the PASS Summit.

Has presented at SQLSaturday events in Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane and Auckland, Edmonton and Calgary, Oslo and Cambridge</description>
      <twitter>sqllensman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqllensman.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllensman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61597</importID>
      <name>Adam Cogan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I never follow a rule!</description>
      <twitter>AdamCogan</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.adamcogan.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AdamCogan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59615</importID>
      <name>Sunil Agarwal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A seasoned professional with 30+ years of industry experience in databases, Sunil has worked as a lead developer for relational database engine solutions, as a tool designer for backup and restore technologies and as a development manager for B2B commerce and e-learning solutions. He has been in his role as a Principal Program Manager for SQL Server for the last 12+ years. Sunil has authored many technical white papers and blogs, and has co-authored two books on SQL Server and has presented database technologies in numerous national and international conferences. He enjoys teaching and has taught introductory programming courses at the University of Rhode Island and the University of Colorado.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>62425</importID>
      <name>Iman Eftekhari</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Iman Eftekhari (MCSE BI, MCITP, CSP) has more than 15 years of experience predominantly in Microsoft BI space. He has been involved in many successful BI projects across the country mainly with financial services, health and the public sectors. He is the co-founder of Agile BI and is passionate about delivering BI projects using Agile methods.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://au.linkedin.com/in/ieftekhari</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.agilebi.com.au</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54833</importID>
      <name>Craig Bryden</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Craig has been working with SQL Server for over 20 years and currently holds several SQL Server based certifications. He has also previously held an MCT certification. Craig's contribution to the SQL Server community was recognised in 2018 with a Microsoft MVP award. He was involved with Microsoft Learning to set some of the current SQL server Exams. Craig is the Chief Data Strategist at BiTQ. Craig is an organiser of the QLD Power BI User Group</description>
      <twitter>@cbryden</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/craigbryden/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cbryden</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59340</importID>
      <name>Martin Catherall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin is a data consultant in Melbourne, Australia, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, and PASS Regional Mentor for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region.
Martin founded the Christchurch, New Zealand PASS Local Group and lead the group for a number of years before relocating to Melbourne.
He has been using SQL Server in various roles since 2000. In addition to anything data related, he enjoys playing the guitar and having fun with his family.</description>
      <twitter>MartyCatherall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/martincatherall</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://martincatherall.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MartyCatherall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61806</importID>
      <name>Bernard Spence</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a Senior Business Intelligence Consultant with 21 years experience with SQL Server. I work at Readify where I help clients improve the performance of their SQL Server instances, SSAS solutions, and SSIS packages</description>
      <twitter>TweetItReal</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TweetItReal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57789</importID>
      <name>Iman Eftekhari</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Iman Eftekhari (MCSE BI, MCITP, CSP) has more than 15 years of experience predominantly in Microsoft BI space. He has been involved in many successful BI projects across the country mainly with financial services, health and the public sectors. He is the co-founder of Agile BI and is passionate about delivering BI projects using Agile methods.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://au.linkedin.com/in/ieftekhari</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.agilebi.com.au</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61596</importID>
      <name>Matt Masson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt Masson is a  Program Manager in the Information Management and Machine Learning (IMML) organization. Matt has worked on multiple data integration products, including Power Query, SSIS, DQS, MDS, and the Data Management Gateway for Power BI. He has authored two books on SSIS (Apress, and MS Press), and is a frequent presenter at Microsoft conferences. You can find his blog at http://www.mattmasson.com/.</description>
      <twitter>@mattmasson</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mattmasson.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mattmasson</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56721</importID>
      <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warwick Rudd is a Data Platform MVP, Microsoft Certified Master, Founder and Principal Consultant at SQL Master Consulting. With 20+ years of experience beginning with the release of SQL Server 6.5, he has worked in both Australia and England from small start-ups to Multi-National Corporations. He hosts the PASS DBA Fundamentals Downunder Virtual Chapter, Organises the PASS SQL Saturday Brisbane event and has spoken at many SQL Server User Groups  SQL Saturday events globally. When not playing with the SQL stack, Warwick likes to get away to the cold and spend time snowboarding.</description>
      <twitter>warwick_Rudd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/pub/warwick-rudd/0/956/718</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmastersconsulting.com.au/Blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=warwick_Rudd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56253</importID>
      <name>Mike Byrd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Former rocket scientist and USAF Fighter Pilot -- now a SQL Server geek (24 years)! Past opportunities include free-lance technical writer for PC Magazine, Senior Software Manager for government sponsored munitions effectiveness committee, and insurance company CTO.  Currently senior database engineer consultant for several Austin companies.  

Presenter at many SQL Saturdays over last 6 years in United States, Europe, and Australia.

Specialize in SQL Server performance tuning; database (OLTP  OLAP) architecture; trouble-shooting; teaching TSQL (Basic through Advanced).

Video presentations (for local SQL Server user groups or SQL Saturdays) can be found at http://usergroup.tv/videos/category/speaker/mike-byrd</description>
      <twitter>ByrdNest_TX</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-byrd/1/aa0/bbb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://logicalread.solarwinds.com/?s=byrd, www.TSQLMentoring.com and SQLServerCentral.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ByrdNest_TX</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57513</importID>
      <name>Peter Myers</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Myers is a consultant, trainer and presenter, and has worked with Microsoft database and development products since 1997. Today he specializes in all Microsoft Business Intelligence products and also authors training course content for Microsoft products and services.

He has a broad business background supported by a bachelor’s degree in applied economics and accounting, and he extends this with extensive experience backed by current MCSE certifications. He has been a Data Platform MVP since 2007.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/peterjsmyers</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57763</importID>
      <name>Greg Low</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Greg Low is well-known in the SQL Server community as a mentor, trainer, author, and community leader. He is a certified master for SQL Server, was an instructor in that program, and holds a PhD in Computer Science. Microsoft often calls on Greg to develop data-related content, and to train their staff. He regularly speaks at tier-one conferences internationally. Greg is best known for his SQL Down Under podcast, SDU Tools, and his eBooks and whitepapers. He heads up a boutique consultancy called SQL Down Under in Melbourne Australia. Greg has been awarded as an MVP since 2001.</description>
      <twitter>greglow</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/greglow</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.greglow.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=greglow</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57142</importID>
      <name>Rob Douglas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robs SQL history started as a remote DBA, branched into consultancy and now includes providing SQL Solutions to a variety of businesses, government departments and banks throughout Australia and New Zealand using a variety of native SQL solutions to meet their performance, higher availability and Disaster Recovery needs.</description>
      <twitter>Rob_DouglasNZ</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=AAMAAAoSId0BNgwoSf_o5y24oIW3PjEHbAmdY-camp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gumption.co.nz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rob_DouglasNZ</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>62427</importID>
      <name>Sunil Agarwal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A seasoned professional with 30+ years of industry experience in databases, Sunil has worked as a lead developer for relational database engine solutions, as a tool designer for backup and restore technologies and as a development manager for B2B commerce and e-learning solutions. He has been in his role as a Principal Program Manager for SQL Server for the last 12+ years. Sunil has authored many technical white papers and blogs, and has co-authored two books on SQL Server and has presented database technologies in numerous national and international conferences. He enjoys teaching and has taught introductory programming courses at the University of Rhode Island and the University of Colorado.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54831</importID>
      <name>Manjot Kaur</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working with SQL server for over 10 years. I have been an internal DBA and a consultant. 
I am passionate about automation, cloud technologies, performance tuning and learning SQL internals.
In my free time I love to read, playing with my toddler and trying my hands on new recipes.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>56693</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56693</id>
          <name>Adam Gilmore</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>310 Agile BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automate Data Warehouse build and deployment (db,SSIS  SSAS) with Visual Studio 2015 and TFS</title>
      <description>See a demonstration of automated generation, build and deployment of a Data Warehouse (database, SSIS and SSAS) using Visual Studio 2015 and 'Visual Studio Team Services' Online.

It's not enough to 'do' Agile you must 'be' Agile...

This means  modifying, building and deploying your DW/BI solution, on a daily/weekly basis. Achieving this without automation is very difficult. 

Topics include:

1. Visual Studio 2015 and Visual Studio Team Services Online licencing for BI developers (things have changed).
2. A primer on setting up a project in 'Visual Studio Team Services'.
3. Automated Data Warehouse development (code generation) in Visual Studio 2015.
4. Using MSBUILD, Source Control and Build  Release functionality of 'Visual Studio Team Services' to automate the build and deployment of a Data Warehouse, SSIS and SSAS Cubes to multiple environments.

Grab a free script at the end to get you started.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56253</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56253</id>
          <name>Mike Byrd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>321 Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Rocket Scientist View on Indexes</title>
      <description>Indexes can be a boon or decrement for query performance. This presentation will present what they are (in layman’s terms) and how they may affect query performance – both from a read (SELECT) viewpoint as well as a data modification aspect (INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE).  This session will concentrate with a deep dive into clustered indexes and nonclustered indexes, their syntax and utilization, and their effect on performance in transaction and data warehouse databases.  Covering nonclustered indexes will also be examined in detail and the scenarios they should be applied.  There will be many query demos illustrating index utilization using statistics and query plans.  Attendee should have some TSQL and Management Studio experience.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56216</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56216</id>
          <name>Matt Allington</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>330 Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power Query is more than just a desktop BI ETL tool</title>
      <description>Power Query is a relatively new addition to Microsoft Excel that brings ETL to the self service BI user's desktop.  In this level 200 session I cover the basics of Power Query and how it can be used for desktop BI before quickly moving on to demonstrate how you can use Power Query for more advanced scenarios that you may not have thought of before, including:
	• Use Power Query as a data provider for traditional Excel Pivot Tables without using Power Pivot.
	• Building a Power Pivot calendar table from scratch using pure Power Query steps.
	• Add commentary to bank statements and make those comments "stick" using self-referencing tables.
	• Using Power Query as an auditing and exception management
        • Using Power Query as a pure ETL tool and exporting more than 1 m rows of transformed data to a file.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57192</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57192</id>
          <name>Hamish Watson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>320 Wardy IT</name>
      </location>
      <title>DevOPs and the DBA</title>
      <description>You may have heard the word "DevOps" and wondered whether it is just another buzzword and/or what it can do for you.
In this session I will demystify the concepts of DevOps and we will look at two aspects of DevOps - Continuous Integration  Continuous Delivery.

Continuous Integration is the practice in which software developers frequently integrate their work with that of other members of the development team.It also involves automating tests around the integrated work

​Continuous Delivery is the next step after Continuous Integration in the deployment pipeline and is the process of automating the deployment of software to  test, staging, and production environments.

Database migrations/changes are an area that may not be typically automated or utilise Continuous Delivery.

Through the use of a comprehensive live demo to a running production database the audience will learn the benefits and how to implement Continuous Delivery in their database systems deployment pipeline.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56193</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56193</id>
          <name>Victor Isakov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>321 Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Store: A (R)evolution in Query Tuning</title>
      <description>Fixing performance problems and detecting query regressions has never been easy in SQL Server as the database engine fundamentally does not capture the relevant information. With the release of SQL Server 2016, Microsoft has introduced a feature called Query Store that will help you capture vital query metrics that will help performance troubleshooting and regression detection. In this session we will examine Query Store and how it can be used in a myriad of use cases. We will examine its architecture, configuration and shortcomings. This session will help you build a monitoring solution that will help you detect and solve real-world performance problems across your entire SQL Server infrastructure. It will also substantially help de-risk upgrade projects, so there's no "excuse" not to upgrade to SQL Server 2016!</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56889</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56889</id>
          <name>Reza Rad</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>330 Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>10 Amazing Things About Power BI You Don't Know</title>
      <description>Have you use Power BI for a real-time dashboard? Have you looped through source files in your Power Query and applied custom functions on them? Have you changed your data model to help Power QA to respond intelligently? Have you head of structured columns in Power Query? Have you used Calculated Tables in DAX? Have you used Power BI Embedded? Have you done many other amazing things with Power BI?

In this session you can expect many live demos and to be impressed by the extraordinary things you can do with Power BI. You will learn tips and tricks to empower your Power BI solution. Tips and tricks that you learn in this session helps you to make your Power BI solution more scale-able, robust, and high performance.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57478</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57478</id>
          <name>Marco Russo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>330 Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>Handling Relationships in DAX</title>
      <description>The Tabular model in Power Pivot for Excel, Power BI and SSAS Tabular seems to offer only plain-vanilla one-to-many relationships, based on a single column. In 2015 there was the introduction of many-to-many relationships, yet the model seems somewhat poor when compared with SSAS Multidimensional. In reality, by leveraging the DAX language, you can handle virtually any kind of relationship, no matter how complex they are. In this session we will analyze and solve several scenarios with calculated relationships, virtual relationships, complex many-to-many. The goal of the session is to show how to solve complex scenarios with the aid of the DAX language to build unconventional data models.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59340</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59340</id>
          <name>Martin Catherall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>340 ACS Foundation</name>
      </location>
      <title>In memory OLTP - what can it do for me?</title>
      <description>In Memory OLTP came along in SQL Server 2014 along with several limitations.
It was still really useful – as long as your use case suited the limitations.
SQL Server 2016 removes several of these limitations and widens the use cases of in-memory OLTP.
For example, even if you are not taking advantage of in-memory tables, you can probably leverage performance improvements by replacing traditional table variables and both local and global temporary tables with in memory implementations. Now you’ll be able to say that table variable is truly in memory!
Come along to this session and learn about some of features of in memory OLTP  - or Hekaton as a lot of people refer to this -  and how you may be able to leverage these high performance features in both new and existing applications.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57789</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57789</id>
          <name>Iman Eftekhari</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>310 Agile BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Governance and Enterprise-wide Deployment Options</title>
      <description>Since release of Power BI many companies have started using it to leverage their data assets to profit from market opportunities. The ease of use and quick time-to-value were main elements to make Power BI a respected tool for every business from small to large enterprise. Many Business Users started using Power BI with minimum / no IT collaboration that started causing concerns especially within larger organisations. Now organisations have become increasingly aware of the need to put a governance and control process in place. 

In this presentation Iman will use his experience in implementing and rolling out Power BI for numerous organisations to share some tips and options for governance and deployment approaches at enterprise level.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61595</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61595</id>
          <name>Guy Glantser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>340 ACS Foundation</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Use Parameters Like a Pro and Boost Performance</title>
      <description>Parameters are a fundamental part of T-SQL programming, whether they are used in stored procedures, in dynamic statements or in ad-hoc queries. Although widely used, most people aren’t aware of the crucial influence they have on query performance. In fact, wrong use of parameters is one of the common reasons for poor application performance.
Does your query sometimes run fast and sometimes slow – even when nothing’s changed? Did it happen to you that a stored procedure, which had always been running for less than a second, suddenly started to run for more than 5 seconds consistently – even when nothing had changed?
In this session we will learn about plan caching and how the query optimizer handles parameters. We will talk about the pros and cons of parameter sniffing (don’t worry if you don’t know what that means) as well as about simple vs. forced parameterization. But most important – we will learn how to identify performance problems caused by poor parameter handling, and we will</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61594</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61594</id>
          <name>Grant Paisley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>310 Agile BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI for Enterprise, safely sharing your data | MS Dev Team</title>
      <description>Once you finish creating a compelling dashboard, what is the best way to share it with your organization? There are many options for dashboard distribution, getting alerts, getting updates, viewing it on various devices, and much more. Learn about Microsoft Power BI for the Enterprise. We talk about security, deployment, best practices, connecting data, hybrid, Gateway, solution templates and consuming everywhere (including mobile) scenarios. Join this session to learn about Power BI for the Enterprise. We will talk about security, deployment, best practices, connecting data, hybrid, Gateway, solution templates and consuming everywhere (including mobile) scenarios. Once you finish creating a compelling dashboard, what is the best way to share it with your organization? There are many options for dashboard distribution, getting alerts, getting updates, viewing it on various devices, and much more.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61806</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61806</id>
          <name>Bernard Spence</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>320 Wardy IT</name>
      </location>
      <title>Excel Tips and Tricks for the Data Professional</title>
      <description>Data is fast becoming the new currency of the 21 century as compute power increases whilst the cost of the storage decreases. Analysing data has never been easier with tools like Azure Machine learning (and R) which can provide powerful insights. Many data professions can only provide these insights if the has been cleaned beforehand. Microsoft Excel is one of the tools of choice for BI professionals and Data Scientists. This session will show a number of killer Excel tips and tricks that every data geek should be using in their career. This session will enable you to go back to the office and wow your boss and clients with cool and amazing techniques! Well ... only if they are also data geeks.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56964</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56964</id>
          <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>320 Wardy IT</name>
      </location>
      <title>Adding Power to the DBA toolkit!</title>
      <description>Interested in being able to manage, monitor and document your SQL Environment from a single location? Want to be able to produce modern interactive reports and dashboards that can be viewed on both desktop and mobile devices? 

By adding a little "Power" to your DBA toolkit you can!

By combining PowerShell and PowerBi with the more traditional DBA tools I will show how to query and document your entire environment and produce rich interactive reports that can be consumed by all levels of your organisation.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61597</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61597</id>
          <name>Adam Cogan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>330 Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI – Finally I can make decisions based on facts</title>
      <description>SSW’s Chief Architect, Adam Cogan, will take you through his personal journey of discovery into the world of Power BI.
 
Many companies have valuable data, but the challenge is being able to easily visualize it in a way that allows you to make decisions.
 
He will show in a live demo how Power BI allows even non-technical users to produce and share invaluable reports and dashboards.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59912</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59912</id>
          <name>Ajay Jagannathan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>320 Wardy IT</name>
      </location>
      <title>Become a Troubleshooting Ninja with PowerBI  SQL Extended Events</title>
      <description>New to Extended Events? Want to become a ninja in troubleshooting common SQL issues using extended events? This is a demo filled session that will show you how to troubleshoot several common issues in SQL server database engine and identify hotspots as well failures using only extended events. This session will showcase how extended events make scenario based troubleshooting easier using Power BI dashboards and without having to collect disparate sets of diagnostic data, gather memory dumps and comprise on performance. There have been a plethora of Extended Events which have been added to SQL Server recently based on customer feedback which deprecates the need to run profiler in many commonly encountered situations in production environments. This session covers the new enhancements and capabilities available for Extended Events.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57513</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57513</id>
          <name>Peter Myers</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>310 Agile BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Reports on the Run: Mobile Reporting with SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>Based on the acquisition of Datazen, Reporting Services now includes a new engine enabling the delivery of mobile reports. In this session you will learn about this new capability delivered with SQL Server 2016, including the architecture of the engine and the development of reports.

This session will describe and demonstrate how to prepare data for mobile reporting, and also how to develop and publish mobile reports. In addition, it will describe the architecture of the engine, and how to manage mobile reports.

This session will be of interest to a full range of professionals, including analysts, report developers, IT managers, and data architects.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57142</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57142</id>
          <name>Rob Douglas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>320 Wardy IT</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hitting the SQL Server "Go Faster" Button</title>
      <description>Tuning individual queries is incredibly resource intensive.  Everyone wants a "Go Faster" button that will improve performance across the entire SQL instance.  While there is no sp_gofaster command to run, there are a bunch of magic knobs and switches that can quite often achieve the desired results.
  In this session we'll look at some of the things you can do to get the best performance out of your SQL Server workload.  You'll leave with a shopping list of things to check and options to try in your environments to get the performance you are after.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59615</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59615</id>
          <name>Sunil Agarwal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>340 ACS Foundation</name>
      </location>
      <title>How SQL Server 2016 SP1 changes the game | Microsoft Dev Team</title>
      <description>Service Pack 1 for SQL Server 2016 was released to the market in November. It brings lot of enhancements and value for a customer that can greatly improve their experience with SQL Server. This session will cover some of the key enhancements that will entice a customer to upgrade to SQL Server 2016. In this session, we’ll also talk about several supportability and diagnostic improvements in the database engine and high availability technologies that will help customer and the field quickly identify and resolve issues in a mission-critical environment.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>62425</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>62425</id>
          <name>Iman Eftekhari</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>310 Agile BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Analytics in the Cloud: Real-life Examples</title>
      <description>See example solutions from the Agile BI team</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56996</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56996</id>
          <name>Leila Etaati</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>310 Agile BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Treasure Map: Choosing the Right Algorithm in Azure ML</title>
      <description>Data scientists uses various data-mining algorithms to do the prediction. Having a map on how to choose an algorithm, which is more appropriate for solving problems is always challenging. This session will provide an explanation of data mining algorithm with the Azure ML environment. The audience will see a couple of demos on each algorithm types. At the end of this session, they will be able to distinguish between each algorithm type. Moreover, the audience will be familiar with available algorithm specifications and usage.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>62427</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>62427</id>
          <name>Sunil Agarwal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>340 ACS Foundation</name>
      </location>
      <title>PANEL - "What's hot" for your  data career</title>
      <description>Panel discussion with many of the speakers including Microsoft Developers.  Will be a question and answer session around how to get into a career in data or grilling the leaders on what skills they think are going to be most in demand.   This is a great session to intend if you are a student, or looking for a change :)
SPEAKERS - Your are all invited</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56657</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56657</id>
          <name>Kevin Boles</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>321 Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>Common TSQL Mistakes</title>
      <description>We are going to examine a variety of oopsies MANY developers fall prey too - some obvious, some pretty subtle and some down right sneaky! Lots of code examples with the bad AND good code presented. I GUARANTEE that you will find things here that will either prevent you from getting bad data, throwing unwanted errors or vastly improving your database application's performance.  I have given this talk over SEVENTY times now and it is always very highly rated!</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54938</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54938</id>
          <name>Manohar Punna</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>340 ACS Foundation</name>
      </location>
      <title>Plan, Design and Implement a HADR Solution - a Journey</title>
      <description>Have you ever struggled to get a HA and DR solution for a single instance with more than 50 applications, 100 databases and 4 TB of data? 
Over the years, HA and DR has been a challenge with SQL Server. As the product evolved so did the options simplified for achieving a feasible HADR solution.
In this session I will walk you through various projects I have worked on in past 8 years. 
I will start with the basic DR solution built using Log shipping, an alternate to AGs in SQL 2008 using Powershell/.NET and SAN Replication and the latest 4 node, two site cluster built with Availability Groups.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56978</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56978</id>
          <name>Allen White</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>320 Wardy IT</name>
      </location>
      <title>Maintain SQL Server Performance Baseline w/PowerShell</title>
      <description>Maintaining a solid set of information about our servers and their performance is critical when issues arise, and often help us see a problem before it occurs.  Building a baseline of performance metrics allows us to know when something is wrong and help us to track it down and fix the problem.  This session will walk you through a series of PowerShell scripts you can schedule which will capture the most important data and a set of reports to show you how to use that data to keep your server running smoothly.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>62426</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>62426</id>
          <name>Grant Paisley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>321 Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>A three day Power BI strategic project - lessons learnt</title>
      <description>Come and see a solution created in three days created in Power BI desktop.  We will look at some design patterns for using Excel as an input mechanism and chat about how to control scope creep from our users.   This will be a quick informal session with plenty of audience interaction</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61596</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61596</id>
          <name>Matt Masson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>310 Agile BI</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Power of Power Query  | Microsoft Dev Team</title>
      <description>Microsoft Power Query started a revolution in self-service data transformation. First launched as an Excel add-in, this incredible product was soon integrated into Excel 2016, and became a core component of the wildly successful Power BI Desktop. This session provides an overview of the product, future integration plans, and a deep dive into the Power Query formula language. We’ll cover how to leverage some of the advanced features recently added to Power BI Desktop, such as function creation and query parameterization, and show you how to wrangle data like a pro.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56721</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56721</id>
          <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>340 ACS Foundation</name>
      </location>
      <title>2016 – The Rise and Fall of DBM</title>
      <description>With the release of SQL Server 2016, a true shift achieving and implementing High Availability and Disaster Recovery has come about. Database Mirroring has been the only option available to meet certain requirements. SQL Server 2016 now changes the game and in this session Warwick will introduce you to the replacement for DBM taking you through what there is, what it gives you and how you can move from DBM to AGs.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>55126</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>55126</id>
          <name>Tobias Koprowski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>330 Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>AD 2015. 2 AM. A Disaster just began...</title>
      <description>2AM. We sleeping well. And our mobile ringing and ringing. Message: DISASTER! In this session (on slides) we are NOT talk about potential disaster (such BCM); we talk about: What happened NOW? Which tasks should have been finished BEFORE. Is virtual or physical SQL matter? We talk about systems, databases, peoples, encryption, passwords, certificates and users. In this session (on few demos) I'll show which part of our SQL Server Environment are critical and how to be prepared to disaster. In some documents I'll show You how to be BEST prepared.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54833</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54833</id>
          <name>Craig Bryden</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>340 ACS Foundation</name>
      </location>
      <title>An Introduction to R and R Services</title>
      <description>R is the most popular programming language for advanced analytics today. With Microsoft's purchase of Revolution R, we are seeing native integration of R capabilities in the SQL Server 2016 database engine (R Services). We are also seeing R support in most of the Azure cloud products.
In this session I will provide an introduction to the R language as well as discuss how you go about using this inside SQL Server and other Microsoft provided tools.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54831</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54831</id>
          <name>Manjot Kaur</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>321 Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>DW SuperHero-Columnstore Index</title>
      <description>Columnstore indexes were introduced in SQL 2012. They have the superpower to boost SQL server performance by flipping row based indexing to column based indexing. In this session, we will cover basics of this technology, its usability, performance impact, implementation (through demo), access mechanism and what's new in SQL 2016.</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 8:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61807</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61807</id>
          <name>Grant Paisley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>321 Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 - What module to use and why</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 has many modules and in this interactive session you get to ask us what challenges you have and we will come up with options for what parts of SQL 2016 would best work.   We will look at the relational engine, Anaysis Server, Reporting Services, Integration Services, and Management Studio.  You should come along if you are relatively new to SQL Server or are not so new but not had time to look at some of the other data platform capabilities of SQL 2016.  Bring your questions!</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56412</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56412</id>
          <name>Nagaraj Venkatesan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>321 Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>R for Database Administrators</title>
      <description>"R", the latest buzzword in data platform, has all along been viewed as programming language for data scientists. However, "R" can be a handy tool for database administrators too. The presentation will show case how "R" can be used innovatively by Database Administrators to handle some of their common problems like tracking query regressions, capacity planning and detecting performance abnormalities. The session will introduce few algorithms of "R" and showcase how it can be used in DBA's world. The session would serve as a good starting point for DBA's exploring the world of "R"</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57763</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57763</id>
          <name>Greg Low</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>330 Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>What on earth are all the Azure* and Power* services and why would I want them?</title>
      <description>Don't know your Power Apps from your Power BI, Flow, etc.? In this session Greg will do his best to explain what on earth all the various services are, or at least the ones that he thinks are relevant to data people. Can't promise the final list until nearer the day but the aim at present would be a rapid fire discussion on each of: Power BI, Power Apps, Flow, Event Hubs, Stream Analytics, Azure ML, Cortana Intelligence Suite, Azure AD, SQL DB, SQL Data Warehouse, Elastic Database Pools, DocumentDB, Search, Storage, and more. (With demos on some but time wouldn't permit demos on all)</description>
      <startTime>2/18/2017 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/18/2017 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>