<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #206 - Madison 2013</name>
    <startDate>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-06:00) Saskatchewan</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatMadison</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Madison Area Technical College - Truax Campus</name>
      <street>3550 Anderson St</street>
      <city>Madison</city>
      <state>Wisconsin</state>
      <zipcode>53704</zipcode>
      <longitude>-89.327919</longitude>
      <latitude>43.121826</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1219</importID>
      <name>Tushaus Computer Services</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.tushaus.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.tushaus.com/Images/TushausLogo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1014</importID>
      <name>Rubix Consulting, LLC</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.rubixconsulting.net</url>
      <imageURL>https://rubixconsulting.net/Portals/0/Rubix_Images/rubix_rgb_image_on_top_no_line_with_url_3.gif</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>70</importID>
      <name>Tegile Systems</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.tegile.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/SQLSaturday/EventSponsors/Tegile_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1</importID>
      <name>Confio</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.confio.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/resized-confio_logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1213</importID>
      <name>Trek Bicycle Corporation</name>
      <label>Trek</label>
      <url>http://www.trekbikes.com/us/en/sitemap/</url>
      <imageURL>https://embed.widencdn.net/img/trek/ktjvponu9s/170x60px/2014_Trek_Color_Horizontal_on_white.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>83</importID>
      <name>PluralSight</name>
      <label>Swag</label>
      <url>http://www.pluralsight.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.srnimbus.com.br/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Pluralsight_logo_novo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>50</importID>
      <name>xSQL Software</name>
      <label>Swag</label>
      <url>http://www.xsql.com</url>
      <imageURL>
      </imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Swag</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27813</importID>
      <name>Wendy Pastrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wendy Pastrick is from Chicago, IL, and for the past 15 years has served as a Database Administrator supporting both development and production environments. Her many years of involvement with PASS include WIT Virtual Chapter and the Chicago Suburban User Group, serving as Regional Mentor, and as a PASS Board member since 2013. Wendy has organized several highly successful SQLSaturday events in Chicago.</description>
      <twitter>@wendy_dance</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://wendyverse.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@wendy_dance</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10588</importID>
      <name>Bob Pusateri</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Pusateri is a Microsoft Certified Master, DBA, and systems architect with over 10 years of experience on SQL Server. His interests involve internals, performance optimization, and cloud technologies. He is an active member of two Chicago-area PASS Local Groups, a community speaker, and maintains a web presence through both Twitter (@SQLBob) and his blog (bobpusateri.com).</description>
      <twitter>@SQLBob</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/bobpusateri</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.BobPusateri.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLBob</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19132</importID>
      <name>Leonard Murphy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leonard Murphy is a BI Business Analyst at Trek Bicycle Corporation in Waterloo, WI. Leonard works closely with business areas globally to help them maximize the value of Trek's Business Intelligence infrastructure. Leonard is experienced with cubes, data warehouses, Power Pivot and Power View and focuses on promoting self-service BI throughout Trek as well as in the wider community. Leonard is also on the organizing team for SQL Saturday Wisconsin. </description>
      <twitter>@phonetictalk</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/leonardmurphy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://leonardmurphy.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@phonetictalk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23656</importID>
      <name>Russel Loski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Russ Loski is a SQL Server BI Developer based in Dallas-Fort Worth.  He current works as a Data Analytics Engineer for Navisite, a remote managed IT services company.   Twenty years ago, he began working with SQL Server 6.5. He has since continued to develop applications connected to all of the versions of SQL Server. He has worked with clients in industries from insurance to healthcare, from movie theaters to American football.  Russ is a regular speaker at SQLSaturday events, as well as the SQL Server Users Groups in the North Texas region. Russ likes working with data in various shapes.</description>
      <twitter>sqlmovers</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/russloski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmovers.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmovers</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10027</importID>
      <name>Allen White</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Allen White is a Data Platform consultant. He has been both a developer and an administrator, so he understands both perspectives towards database technology. He loves sharing his experiences and helping people learn how to use SQL Server. Allen has spent over 40 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1992, and has been awarded Microsoft’s MVP Award for the last 13 years. Allen was a PASS Director from 2016 - 2018.</description>
      <twitter>SQLRunr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/allen-white-sql-server-mvp/5/784/b08/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataperfpro.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLRunr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16631</importID>
      <name>Jes Schultz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jes Schultz is a Software Engineer with Microsoft who has experience with a wide range of SQL Server features from version 2005 through 2019, and is on the cutting edge with Azure technologies. Since graduating Fox Valley Technical College with an IT-Programmer/Analyst degree, Jes has worked as an SSRS developer, DBA, and consultant. Before joining Microsoft, Jes was a six-time Data Platform MVP, recognized for her community work. Jes tackles every project and problem with tenacity and her enthusiasm is unmatched in the SQL Server community. In her free time, Jes never stops moving, and counts fitness, coffee, cooking, and travel as essentials in life.</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/grrl_geek</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jesborland</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blogs.lessthandot.com/author/jes-borland</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/grrl_geek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20445</importID>
      <name>Michael DeFehr</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael DeFehr is an independent SQL Server consultant based in Winnipeg, Canada. He is focused on database administration and development using Microsoft SQL Server.
A SQL Server MVP, Professional Engineer and MCITP in both Database Development and Administration, Mike has spent the past 15 years producing and maintaining database solutions. Mike specializes in the relational and storage engines and his solutions emphasize performance and simplicity.</description>
      <twitter>@mdefehr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/mdefehr</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mikedefehr.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mdefehr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18904</importID>
      <name>Kyle Neier</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kyle has been working professionally with computers since 1995, the past 10 years being dedicated to SQL Server. He currently works as an Engineer for Apparatus (apparatus.net) where he continues to chase his passion to automate DBA processes. He is a proud father of 5, a leader of the local PASS chapter (www.indypass.org), a Microsoft Certified Master (MCM), and enjoys sharing his passion for SQL Server with others by speaking and mentoring at local and regional events.</description>
      <twitter>@Kyle_Neier</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kyleneier</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldbamusings.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Kyle_Neier</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>28294</importID>
      <name>Zach Mattson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Zach Mattson is a reformed DBA turned BI Developer for Trek Bicycle Company in Waterloo, WI.  Zach has spoken at multiple community events and been published several times on using Powershell for SQL Server monitoring.  He now works from home full time, guarded full time by his yellow labs while developing solutions utilizing the full BI stack of Microsoft tools.</description>
      <twitter>@WIDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://widba.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@WIDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26089</importID>
      <name>Ted Krueger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ted Krueger has been working in development and database administration for over a decade. Ted currently works for a respected consulting company, Magenic Technologies as a valued Database Professional resource. He is a PASS Region Mentor, Friends of Red Gate member, SQL Server MVP and community mentor. Ted blogs and is also one of the founders of LessThanDot Technical Community</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.lessthandot.com/index.php/All/?disp=authdirauthor=68</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24582</importID>
      <name>Frank Gill</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Frank Gill is a Senior Data Engineer at Concurrency   With 21 years of IT experience, the first 8 as a mainframe programmer, he has developed a love of all things internal. Over the past several years, he has worked extensively with SQL Server solution in Azure, including Managed Instance.  When not administering databases or geeking out on internals, Frank volunteers at the Art Institute of Chicago and reads voraciously.</description>
      <twitter>skreebydba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=22766305amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://skreebydba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=skreebydba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16366</importID>
      <name>Jeff Prom</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeff Prom is a Data and BI Developer with over 15 years experience. From a wide variety of industries, he has worked at corportations both large and small including several global fortune 50 companies. Jeff is an active member in the SQL community and regularly speaks and attends user groups and conferences. He has earned MCTS certifications for Database Development, Administration, and BI. Jeff is currently employed at Silver Bay Realty Trust Corp as a Data Architect in Minnesota.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-prom/7/1b7/bb1/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://jeffprom.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14642</importID>
      <name>Gill Rowley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I#39;m a SQL Server DBA and Business Intelligence Consultant with over 10 years experience working with all versions of SQL Server dating back to SQL Server 7.0. When not playing with SQL Server I spend my time hunting, fishing, weightlifting, relaxing on my boat, playing men#39;s fast pitch softball, and playing with my rescued bull terrier Lola.</description>
      <twitter>@BadgerBully</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gillrowley?trk=nav_responsive_tab_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://gillrowley.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BadgerBully</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13886</importID>
      <name>Eric Selje</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eric Selje is a developer and consultant in Madison, WI who works on a wide variety of applications, from desktop to web to mobile - all of them requiring databases. Eric has for private businesses, non-profits, and is now working for the U.S. Courts. He has been a user group leader since 1995, and other than coding he loves playing Ultimate and baseball, doing crosswords and reading.</description>
      <twitter>@ericselje</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://saltydogllc.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ericselje</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24977</importID>
      <name>MIKE DONNELLY</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Donnelly has been working with SQL Server for 15+ years and holds the MCSE: Data Platform certification. He is an avid runner, blogger, and a wannabe gourmet chef. Currently living the SQL Life on the Jersey Shore.</description>
      <twitter>SQLMD</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/melsar93</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlmd.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLMD</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20057</importID>
      <name>Merrill Aldrich</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Merrill is a consultant with the national Digital and Technology Consultancy RBA. In past lives he was a SQL Server DBA for Financial Services and Real Estate Management organizations, a designer of buildings, an expert in three dimensional computer graphics and building information modeling, a speaker, teacher, and visiting lecturer.</description>
      <twitter>@onupdatecascade</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/merrill-aldrich/5/864/830</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/merrill_aldrich/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@onupdatecascade</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15711</importID>
      <name>Janis Griffin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Janis Griffin has over 30 years of DBA/database experience including design, development and implementation of many critical database applications. Before coming to Quest Software, Janis primarily worked in the Telecom/Network Industry, working with both real-time network routing databases and OLTP business to business applications.  Janis also held positions as a Principal Architect and Senior Manager, mentoring other DBAs on best practices in database performance tuning.</description>
      <twitter>DoBoutAnything</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/janis-griffin/0/914/aba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DoBoutAnything</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17517</importID>
      <name>Josh Fennessy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Josh Fennessy, Solution Architect at BlueGranite, has been building solutions with the SQL Server BI stack for 8 years. He is a Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert in Business Intelligence. Josh#39;s passions include manipulating data in novel ways to open analytic possibilities not before possible.

Josh is active in the SQL Server and Open Source communities. Beyond relational and OLAP data projects, Josh is also involved in projects using cluster computing platforms such as Hadoop.</description>
      <twitter>@joshuafennessy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuafennessy/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.joshuafennessy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@joshuafennessy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18848</importID>
      <name>Ken Stuber</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ken Stuber is the Data Architect at Jewelers Mutual Insurance in Neenah, WI as well as being an independent consultant with Drop Clean Buffers Consulting, LLC. Ken has been working with SQL Server since v6.5 in 1997 and has broad experience in the Microsoft Data Platform. His primary interests are in the performance tuning, enterprise architecture, DevOps, database design and database development. When not fighting the query optimizer, he can be found RVing around North America, backpacking, cooking, gardening, reading, and studying for whatever will replace the MCM program.</description>
      <twitter>@KenStuber</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/ken-stuber/9/b7b/2a0/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dropcleanbuffers.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KenStuber</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22665</importID>
      <name>Brian Davis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brian Davis is a Product Integration Engineer at SentryOne and has over 15 years in the IT field in multiple areas including software development, support, user training, and as a DBA. He has been working with SQL Server since 2003 and has hands-on experience with SQL Server 2000 through 2016. Brian is also a PASS Regional Mentor and an active member and leader of the Ohio North SQL Server User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@Brian78</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/briandavis78</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.sqlsentry.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Brian78</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14182</importID>
      <name>Farouq Abukhamireh</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Farouq Abukhamireh is a Microsoft Business Intelligence Architect and a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) who is focused on Microsoft’s Business Intelligence (BI) stack (Power BI, Azure, SSAS, SSIS, SSRS, MDX, DAX, Excel Services, PowerPivot, PowerView and SharePoint).  Farouq is a seasoned Information Technology professional with 21 years of experience developing innovative solutions using Microsoft technologies.  Farouq works as a consultant with Dicense LTD.</description>
      <twitter>@AskFarouq</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/farouq</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.blogger.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@AskFarouq</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17845</importID>
      <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kalen Delaney is a Data Platform MVP who has worked with SQL Server for more than 32 years. She has provided performance consulting services and taught advanced courses on SQL Server to thousands of people and organizations. In addition to her courseware development, Kalen has been writing about SQL Server for decades. She is the primary author of SQL Server Internals and the Inside SQL Server series. Kalen is also one of the primary editors for the Red Gate SQL Server Stairways tutorials.</description>
      <twitter>sqlqueen</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlqueen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16520</importID>
      <name>Jennifer Salvo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>***SESSION WITHDRAWN *** Jennifer Salvo is a Business Intelligence developer focusing on the Microsoft BI technologies (SSIS, SSAS, SSRS).  Her prior work experience includes software development, systems analysis, end-user support, training, and SharePoint administration.  She has worked in the IT field for over 10 years.  In her free time, she enjoys reading, biking, running and spending time with her family.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://salvoz.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9770</importID>
      <name>Argenis Fernandez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Argenis is a Principal Architect at Pure Storage. He works with customers around the world to make sure they don’t have to worry much about their infrastructure for Data.
He is a former Data Platform MVP, former VMware vExpert, Microsoft Certified Master, and more recently worked in the Microsoft Azure Data/SQL Server engineering team as a Principal PM in the Tiger team.</description>
      <twitter>DBArgenis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/argenis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.purestorage.com/author/argenisfernandez/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBArgenis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16252</importID>
      <name>Jim Dorame</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jim Dorame has been working with SQL Server for over 20 years. Over those years he has learned a great deal from the SQL community. He has also given back to the community in the hopes that he may help someone in their career. He is always looking for something to learn and luckily Microsoft keeps adding to SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>@DBAJD</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesdorame</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.jamesdorame.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DBAJD</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26858</importID>
      <name>Tim Ford</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tim Ford is a Data Professional, Author and Community Leader whose technical passions lie in creative solutions for managing and presenting data.  He#39;s been a healthcare DBA since 2000 and leads SQL Agent Man Consultancy and SQL Cruise.  He takes 25 students and leaders in the SQL Community and places them on cruise ships for technical and professional development training without the distractions of the office and internet twice a year on SQL Cruises (www.sqlcruise.com). Currently Tim serves on the Board of Directors for PASS and is passionate about taking fellow Data Professionals to the next level in their careers. He enjoys telling stories with data.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLAgentMan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothyford</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://thesqlagentman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLAgentMan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14105</importID>
      <name>Eddie Wuerch</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eddie Wuerch has 20 years of experience as a SQL Server specialist in a much-longer IT career. A Microsoft Certified Master, Eddie spends his days in the Salesforce Marketing Cloud, focusing on performance, scale, and uptime for the massive SQL Server backend. These SQL Servers churn billions of transactions daily against trillions of rows of data in a 24x7 continuously-available online system accessed by millions worldwide every day.</description>
      <twitter>@EddieW</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/eddiewuerch</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.indydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@EddieW</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26859</importID>
      <name>Tim Ford</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tim Ford is a Data Professional, Author and Community Leader whose technical passions lie in creative solutions for managing and presenting data.  He#39;s been a healthcare DBA since 2000 and leads SQL Agent Man Consultancy and SQL Cruise.  He takes 25 students and leaders in the SQL Community and places them on cruise ships for technical and professional development training without the distractions of the office and internet twice a year on SQL Cruises (www.sqlcruise.com). Currently Tim serves on the Board of Directors for PASS and is passionate about taking fellow Data Professionals to the next level in their careers. He enjoys telling stories with data.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLAgentMan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothyford</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://thesqlagentman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLAgentMan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15957</importID>
      <name>Jason Strate</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jason Strate is a SQL Server Solutions Architect with Pragmatic Works. He is also a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and MCM. He has over 15 years of experience developing, architecting, and managing data platforms. Jason writes, blogs, and presents on SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>@stratesql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonstrate/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.jasonstrate.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@stratesql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22389</importID>
      <name>Paul Timmerman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and the Lead SQL Server DBA at Hennepin County Medical Center in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Paul has fifteen years of experience in database administration and currently the Chapter Leader of the Minnesota SQL Server User Group, PASSMN. Paul is an active member of the PASS community and routinely speaks at user group meetings and SQL Saturday conferences.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.lessthandot.com/index.php/author/mndba/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21361</importID>
      <name>Neil Hambly</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Neil Hambly is a SQL Server consultant, founder and consultant at Datamovements, a Gold Microsoft Data  Analytics Consulting company.
Neil has 20+ years in a variety of SQL Server roles and is an MCT. He is a regular presenter (200+ events) at user groups, and PASS events, including PASS Summit and SQLSaturday, and many UK events (SQLBits, SQLRelay). Neil is the leader of PASS London (UK), a Professional Development VC, a Melissa Data MVP, and a SQL Cruise Technical Lead, who loves Guinness, whisky, and dancing.</description>
      <twitter>Neil_Hambly</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/neilhambly</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataidol.com/NeilHambly</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Neil_Hambly</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21149</importID>
      <name>Michael Steineke</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Steineke is a Windows Server Platform expert with an industry-wide reputation as an innovator in the areas of Windows Server, storage and network architecture, disaster recovery, datacenter configuration, and SQL Server. He is a Cloud and Datacenter Management MVP specializing in High Availability and has spoken on subjects like Windows Server, clustering, Storage, Hyper-V, SQL Server, and multi-site clusters at user groups and conferences of all sizes, including SQL Saturdays, SQL PASS Summit, Microsoft TechEd, and the Microsoft MVP Summit.</description>
      <twitter>@MSteineke</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelsteineke</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.michaelsteineke.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MSteineke</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12135</importID>
      <name>Derek Dai</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Over 10 years’ experience in database design, development, and administration using a wide variety of tools and technologies. Having focused on Business Intelligence using the SQL Server BI stack (SSAS, SSRS, SSIS, Power-pivot, Semantic Model and Data Mining) with solid knowledge on SQL Server DB Core engine. And extensive experience with Microsoft development tools.
PASS VC Leader; MCT; MSCE BI and Data Platform</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://derekdb.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>17517</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17517</id>
          <name>Josh Fennessy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 380</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Demystifying BISM and Tabular Mode SSAS</title>
      <description>With the release of SQL 2012, Analysis Services (SSAS) has seen some major changes.  An entire new method of modelling analytic data has emerged and it's called Tabular Mode Analysis Services.  In addition to that, a new semantic layer has been added to the tool, the Business Intelligence Semantic Model (BISM), which will help to bring the two modes -- Multidimensional and Tabular -- into one level playing arena.

In this session, attendees will gain understanding of what Multidimensional and Tabular modelling IS, as well as how the BISM layer helps to translate user requests to ensure no confusion is made. Attendees will also learn how to BUILD a Tabular model, and will help design a solution live during the presentation. </description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18848</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18848</id>
          <name>Ken Stuber</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 142B</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Development using SQL Server Data Tools</title>
      <description>In 2007, Microsoft introduced Data Dude for Visual Studio 2005 to help bring the processes, controls and tools for code management to Database Development that Application developers had been enjoying for ages.  It had its problems, but it mostly worked and was a welcome step in the right direction. Many versions later we have SQL Server Data Tools for Visual Studio 2012 (and 2010). A more mature product that finally brings database development up to par with traditional application development and has many features data geeks, like ourselves, will truly love. This talk will provide an overview of SSDT’s features and show you how to get started using it to save time, implement better code controls and be a better DBA or database developer.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>12135</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12135</id>
          <name>Derek Dai</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 384AB</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>“ColumnStore” Indexes for Fast EDW Query</title>
      <description>This session will introduce the new xVelocity Memory-Optimized Columnstore Index feature of SQL 2012. This presentation will describe what a column store index is, how this feature is used to store data by columns instead of by rows and compare the advantages and disadvantages between the two storage methods. Live demos will explore how to create columnstore indexes, when to create them, best practices for using them and typical data warehouse scenarios that can leverage the columnstore index to drastically speed up data warehouse queries, in many cases by a factor of 10 to 100, so you are equipped to start implementing this feature into your database environment.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24582</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24582</id>
          <name>Frank Gill</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 142B</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Interrogating the Transaction Log </title>
      <description>Without the transaction log, SQL Server would have no way of maintaining a consistent and durable view of its data.  It would be pandaemonium!!!  Think of the Stay-Puft Marshmallow Man!  Thankfully the transaction log is there and we can all breathe easier.
In this session, you will learn how SQL Server uses the transaction log to maintain the durability and consistency of its data, along with methods for reading the transaction log and identifying active transactions.
</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26858</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26858</id>
          <name>Tim Ford</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 142A</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Don't Box Me In:  Escape the Cubicle</title>
      <description>I've been telecommuting in some capacity or another since before I was a DBA.  For 13 years I've been able to be a productive, responsive, integral and valuable asset to my company without maintaining a physical presence within the confines of a corporate office.  Let's have a conversation and discuss what has (and has not) worked for me over the years.  Let's discuss the traits of a good telecommuter as well as those attributes that may not make this the right arrangement for everyone.  We will even discuss what my Managers have done over the years to not only acommodate telecommuting, but to embrace and succeed from having staff that work remotely!  

This session is aimed at staff and management alike.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15957</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15957</id>
          <name>Jason Strate</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 321</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Discovering the Plan Cache</title>
      <description>Execution plans are stored after execution in the plan cache. This metadata about how queries are executed can provide insight into how your SQL Server environment is functioning. By using XQuery to browse and search the plan cache you can find potential performance issues and opportunities to tune your queries. This information can be used to help reduce issues related to parallelism, shift queries from using scans to using seek operations, or discover exactly which queries are using what indexes. All of this and more is readily available through the plan cache. In this session we will explore the plan cache and start you on the road to discovery.
</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13886</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13886</id>
          <name>Eric Selje</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 322</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Unit Testing Fundamentals </title>
      <description>How can you be certain the "little change" you're about to make to that stored procedure isn't going to take down your whole company? Real developers use a technique called "Unit Testing" to minimize that risk, a concept that's also available to you. With unit testing you can quick ascertain whether the the changes to functions, stored procedures, and even other objects in your database had a negative unforeseen impact.

In this session we'll walk through the basics of what unit testing is, how to set up a simple Unit Testing project in SSMS, how we can tell whether something has negatively changed in our functions or procedures.  We'll also enumerate any 3rd party tools available to help us with Unit Testing our databases.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19132</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19132</id>
          <name>Leonard Murphy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 380</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power View Strengths  Weaknesses</title>
      <description>Power View is a visual data exploration tool that comes built into Excel 2013. With it you can build charts that seamlessly interact with each other and quickly map your data using Bing maps. In this session, you will learn where Power View shines and where it doesn't so you can maximize the value you get out of it in a minimum amount of time.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16631</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16631</id>
          <name>Jes Schultz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 142A</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Consulting: The Good, The Bad, The Ugly</title>
      <description>Ted Krueger and Jes will be presenting this session. Consulting is a mystical career path that is often questioned: should I do it, can I do it, and why should I do it? Come join us for a discussion of the pros and cons to consulting with an emphasis on SQL Server and Microsoft Technologies. We'll field questions with real world experiences. Once you leave this open floor session, you'll be able to make better choices in your own professional development and how consulting may or may not effect it.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14642</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14642</id>
          <name>Gill Rowley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 142B</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>You're the DBA.  Now What?</title>
      <description>Are you an accidental DBA trying to find your way through your new role? Are you an experienced DBA moving to a new position, team, or major application? This presentation is for you! In this presentation, we will review best practices for what to do when you're a brand new DBA. You will learn what to look for when you walk into a new environment, as well as pitfalls to avoid.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>28294</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>28294</id>
          <name>Zach Mattson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 384AB</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Powershell Driven Life</title>
      <description>Why are we here?  I have no idea, but I do know Powershell can probably help make it easier.  This session will be entirely demos hitting on a variety of different areas in the SQL Server stack.  Using plenty of SQL Server Management Objects(SMO), we will cover a variety of tasks for the data professional on both sides (OLTP / OLAP) of the house including working with SSAS, SQL Server , writing tests and automation.  The theoretical will be ignored as well as any common decency towards mass produced beer.  A Powerpoint free presentation.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26089</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26089</id>
          <name>Ted Krueger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 142A</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Upgrading to SQL Server 2012 with limited downtime</title>
      <description>With SQL Server 2012 released and going strong, we’re all wanting the latest and greatest, high performing, SQL Engine sitting on our servers.  How we do that is another question.  How do you get a weekend of downtime? Do you like convincing the business you need it?
I don’t and that is why we’re going to look at methods to upgrade or migrate SQL Server 2005, SQL Server 2008 and SQL Server 2008 R2 up to SQL Server 2012 with as little downtime as possible - minutes.  In this session, we’ll see how mirroring, log shipping and even replication, can make us look like DBA Rock stars at upgrade time. 
</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16366</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16366</id>
          <name>Jeff Prom</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 380</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Master Data Services</title>
      <description>Does your company have similar data in multiple locations? Not really sure which set of data is accurate? With MDS, Microsoft gives you the ability to have one accurate source of non-transactional data to use with your applications or send to other databases and ETL processes. Leverage data stewards to help manage the data repository to ensure it is up-to-date and accurate.

In this session we will cover MDS from start to finish including installation, creating models/entities, working with data, using the Excel 
add-in, security, hierarchies, views, versions, and business rules. After this session, you should have a good understanding of what MDS does, how to use it, and how to get started with your own MDS project.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10588</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10588</id>
          <name>Bob Pusateri</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 350</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Back It Up Faster!</title>
      <description>Backups: You can't live without them but want them to complete as quickly as possible. The faster they're done, the sooner your server's CPU and IO resources can get back to their normal job of servicing queries. 

Queries aren't the only part of SQL Server you can tune for maximum performance - backups fall under this category as well. This session will discuss how backups work and how you can capitalize on this knowledge to ensure they complete as quickly as possible. Cutting your backup (and restore) times by 50% or more is not out of the question when using these methods.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17845</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17845</id>
          <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 321</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>What’s Simple About SIMPLE Recovery?</title>
      <description>There is a common misconception that SIMPLE Recovery means no logging, and this is a very dangerous myth to propagate. SQL Server does log database changes in SIMPLE Recovery, but some (not all) operations are minimally logged. In this presentation, I'll tell you what minimal logging means in conjunction with each of the three different recovery models. In addition, I’ll describe the benefits and dangers of the SIMPLE Recovery Model. </description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22389</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22389</id>
          <name>Paul Timmerman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 384AB</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>An Optimistic Approach: Snapshot Isolation in SQL </title>
      <description>Until 2005, SQL Server was a very pessimistic RDBMS.  However with the introduction of the Read Committed Snapshot database option and the new Snapshot Isolation level, that is no longer the case.

After a high level look at all SQL Server isolation levels, we’ll spend the majority of this session discussing the implementation of optimistic concurrency control in SQL Server.  We’ll look at the benefits and drawbacks of using an optimistic isolation level and discuss use cases where it may or may not be appropriate.

Come learn how to put one of the more powerful, but least understood, aspects of SQL Server to work for you!</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26859</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26859</id>
          <name>Tim Ford</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 350</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>High IO, High IO, It's a Case Study Yo Ho!</title>
      <description>Confronted with the highest IO of any Windows server in our environment one intrepid DBA was able to reduce IO, space consumption, and blocking to new lows.  This is a case study, based upon actual events where the names of the innocent as well as the guilty are changed to protect the DBA.  Topics covered: DMVs, online operations, Filegroups, Page Compression, and disk formatting best practices.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15711</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15711</id>
          <name>Janis Griffin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 321</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Extend Your Knowledge with Extended Events!</title>
      <description>SQL Server Extended Events can be used to gather a wide range of performance information, and in troubleshooting in SQL Server.  Extended Events use less system resources and provide better information than SQL Profiler and they allow for correlation of SQL Server event data along side of OS or Application event data. This presentation will explore what Extended Events are, how to set them up and use them in several case studies.

</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20057</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20057</id>
          <name>Merrill Aldrich</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 142B</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Shoveling Frogs into a Wheelbarrow</title>
      <description>If you face managing over a hundred, or perhaps thousands, of databases, automation, standards and a "policy-based" mindset are critical. In this session we'll do a walk-through of a rules-based backup and index maintenance solution suitable for zillions of smaller databases, and talk at a high level about features and techniques for multi-server management including monitoring, performance data collection, jobs automation, PowerShell and PBM.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27813</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27813</id>
          <name>Wendy Pastrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 142B</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Navigating the Options for Data Redundancy</title>
      <description>SQL Server has so many options for data redundancy, how do you know when you should use replication, or log shipping or AlwaysOn, etc? We will use real world examples where data redundancy is needed and discuss which is the appropriate technology and why. This is more than just a high availability vs disaster recovery discussion. If you have ever been confused or overwhelmed by all of the options, they will be broken down and made clear in this session.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21361</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21361</id>
          <name>Neil Hambly</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 384AB</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Effective Index Partitioning, Compression Strategy</title>
      <description>We all know that ‘Indexing’ is KING when it comes to achieving high levels of performance in SQL Server. When Indexing also combines 2 of the Enterprise features: Partitioning  Compression, we can often see substantial gains.

Learn how to identify those objects that benefit greatly from being Partitioned or Compressed, OR combining both of these features to even greater effect.

Using Demos to illustrate the performance gains with real-world examples, Take away advanced scripts for use in your own environments.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14105</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14105</id>
          <name>Eddie Wuerch</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 142A</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Join Us! Getting Started as a Technical Speaker</title>
      <description>Have you ever thought about speaking at a user group or SQL Saturday, but weren't quite sure how to get started? If so, this session is for you! Technical speaking is loads of fun, great for your career, and you get to hang out with some terrific people. This session will provide the tools necessary to get your first session off the ground, and prep you to be a great speaker. Attend this session and you'll be able to: * Identify your topic and build a killer abstract for it, * Design and build the presentation, and * Prepare and deliver your first session</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18904</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18904</id>
          <name>Kyle Neier</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 350</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Throwing T-SQL 2012 Enhancements Against the Wall</title>
      <description>Just like your grandma tested spaghetti to tell if it was done, we'll be throwing several of the new T-SQL enhancements against the wall to see what's good and what falls off. We'll silence the lion's RaiseRror by throwing some meaty exceptions. We'll bring together the old lovers "Coalesce" and "+" for one last jaunt before they are banished by the Concat function. We'll even open the window on some of the new aggregate and analytical functions as well as some other t-sql enhancements introduced in SQL 2012. </description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22665</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22665</id>
          <name>Brian Davis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 322</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS Templates Can Make Your Life Easier</title>
      <description>How many times have you started a new SSIS project and added the same components that you’ve added to almost every other package you’ve created?  Components to handle logging and errors or even a standard workflow for loading data files.  In this session I’ll show you how you can create standard templates that already contain any and all of the common components you desire.  We’ll also look at how to implement and use these templates so that the next time you create a SSIS package you can spend your time on the work you actually need to do instead of implementing common components over and over again.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16520</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16520</id>
          <name>Jennifer Salvo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 380</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting Started with SSAS Tabular Cubes</title>
      <description>Prior to the release of SQL Server 2012, Business Intelligence Developers had a single option when creating cubes in Analysis Services, the Multidimensional Model.  Now, Microsoft has added the Tabular Model to Analysis Services which opens up many new and exciting possibilities.

In this session, we'll discuss the features and benefits of the Tabular Model and draw comparisons to the Multidimensional Model.  We'll also review scenarios when implementing a Tabular cube may be a better choice than Multidimensional.  The presentation will conclude with a demo of basic Tabular cube functionality.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10027</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10027</id>
          <name>Allen White</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 321</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Manage SQL Server 2012 on Server Core w/PowerShell</title>
      <description>Windows Server 2008 introduced Server Core, the operating system without the Graphical User Interface. SQL Server 2012 is the first version of SQL Server to support Server Core. To gain the maximum efficiency from your servers you want to make use of Server Core and with PowerShell you can effectively manage SQL Server in that environment. This session will demonstrate how to manage SQL Server 2012 on Windows Server Core and provide scripts to help you perform the common tasks you need to perform on that platform.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20445</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20445</id>
          <name>Michael DeFehr</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 350</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deadlocks: What to do about the dreaded 1205</title>
      <description>Deadlocks can be very tricky, unpredictable and generally nasty. Is all hope lost? This demo-intensive session will explore several types of deadlocks and give you some insight into how to track them down and prevent them. We wil start with a quick review of locking and blocking concepts, then take a deep-dive into deadlock demos.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9770</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9770</id>
          <name>Argenis Fernandez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 321</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Secret Life of an INSERT Statement</title>
      <description>Follow the life of an INSERT statement from the moment it is issued by the Client, through reception, parsing and execution by the SQL Server engine, until the operation is completed and a message is sent back.

This is an Internals session where we will touch on all the different components that comprise the SQL Server Database Engine involved in handling a single INSERT statement. Watch structures on memory and disk get updated, and geek out on details!</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21149</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21149</id>
          <name>Michael Steineke</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 350</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL 2012  Windows 2012 - Better Together</title>
      <description>Enhancements in Windows Server 2012 that give you more fexability and higher uptime with SQL Server 2012.  Including Quorum models, SQL over SMB, Large SQL in HyperV.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16252</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16252</id>
          <name>Jim Dorame</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 384AB</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>PowerShell and SQLPSX the Dynamic Duo for the DBA</title>
      <description>With PowerShell and SQLPSX your DBA life can be a lot simpler.
SMO is powerful, but can be difficult to use.  Enter SQLPSX.  Chad Miller put together a set of PowerShell functions that
streamline the use of SMO, easing management of a multi-server environment. 
Come learn when and how the addition of PowerShell and SQLPSX can benefit you.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24977</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24977</id>
          <name>MIKE DONNELLY</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 322</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Flipping Through the SSIS Catalag</title>
      <description>With the release of SQL Server 2012 one of the biggest changes for SSIS Administration was the addition of the Integration Services Catalog and using parameters. The Catalog is the storage and logging location for SSIS 2012. Parameters are the new configurations in SSIS 2012 and once you start using them you will never go back. Package Variables, Configuration Strings, Package properties can all be configured using Parameters. You will learn how to create the catalog, use parameters to deploy packages through different environments and use the built in reporting to monitor packages as they run.
</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23656</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23656</id>
          <name>Russel Loski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 322</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to BI Markup Language (BIML) and BIML</title>
      <description>Microsoft has provided some great tools for creating and editing SSIS packages.  First Business Intelligence Development Studio (BIDS) then SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT).  However, when creating an SSIS package you frequently repeat the same steps over and over.  BIML is an XML markup language designed for representing the structure of an SSIS package.  BIML Script takes that structure and generates an SSIS package.
In this session we will use BIDS Helper to create a simple SSIS package using BIML.  We will handle a couple SSIS scenarios with BIML and BIML Script.  </description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14182</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14182</id>
          <name>Farouq Abukhamireh</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Room 380</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Business Intelligence and Data Mod</title>
      <description>An introduction to Business (BI) Intelligence,  describing common BI scenarios, current trends in BI, and the typical roles that are involved in creating a BI solution. It also introduces the Microsoft BI platform and describes the roles Microsoft SQL Server 2012 and Microsoft SharePoint 2010 play in Microsoft BI solutions.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>