<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #830 - Colorado Springs 2019</name>
    <startDate>4/6/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>175</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-07:00) Mountain Time (US and Canada)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat830</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>CTU Colorado Springs</name>
      <street>4435 North Chestnut Street</street>
      <city>Colorado Springs</city>
      <state>Colorado</state>
      <zipcode>80907</zipcode>
      <longitude>-104.833023</longitude>
      <latitude>38.892986</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/972/EventSponsor_14605.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>74</importID>
      <name>Xtivia</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.xtivia.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.xtivia.com/media/xtivia-trusted-tech-partner-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1495</importID>
      <name>MinionWare, LLC</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://minionware.net/?utm_source=SQL%20Saturdayutm_campaign=SQLSat613utm_medium=imageutm_term=MinionWare</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14696.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2390</importID>
      <name>GroverDB, inc</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://groverdb.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://s3.amazonaws.com/grover-public-assets/groverdb+logo_blue+type+no+background.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2160</importID>
      <name>Sensible Data Integrations</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://sensibledataintegrations.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sensibledataintegrations.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/data_integrations_2.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1995</importID>
      <name>Mile Hi Power BI User Group</name>
      <label>Personal Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://milehipowerbi.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://ourlastbesthope.com/images/mhpbiug400.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2254</importID>
      <name>SQLCoop.com, LLC</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc1u_C8ukXd1Lkd9uF-Tj4w/videos?view=0sort=pview_as=subscriberflow=grid</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/877/EventSponsor_13514.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1431</importID>
      <name>Colorado Technical University</name>
      <label>Venue</label>
      <url>http://www.coloradotech.edu</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/Portals/444/SponsorImages/ColoradoTechnicalUniversity.PNG</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92923</importID>
      <name>Sean McCown</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sean McCown is a Certified Master with 23 years of experience in databases. He is also founder and co-owner of the MidnightDBA.com website, where he records free SQL Server training videos. He also writes the popular Minion Maintenance suite, the most configurable maintenance solution on the planet.</description>
      <twitter>@KenpoDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.midnightdba.com/dbarant</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KenpoDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89839</importID>
      <name>Todd Kleinhans</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Todd Kleinhans has been using SQL Server since the last millennium. He has served in different roles across many industries but he's mainly been a DBA. When not in virtual reality, he likes to speak at PASS sponsored events and volunteers in various groups like PASS, DSSUG, Colorado Virtual Reality and is the President of Denver/Boulder Unreal Engine group. He is on Twitter: @toddkleinhans and blogs at https://toddkleinhans.wordpress.com/</description>
      <twitter>@toddkleinhans</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/todd-kleinhans/0/920/981</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://toddkleinhans.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@toddkleinhans</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88561</importID>
      <name>Jeff Renz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeff Renz is a Senior Architect at RevGen Partners, currently working as the design architect and implementation lead on several projects for a Fortune Top 50 company. Jeff has worked with SQL Server and BI for 15+ years and has 10 years’ experience with data warehouse design and implementation. In addition to consulting, he is joining the University of Denver adjunct faculty and is expected to begin teaching in the ICT program starting in June.  He received his bachelor’s degree in Computer Science, his master’s degree in Operations Research from Colorado School of Mines, and will be graduating from the Harvard Business Analytics Program in December.</description>
      <twitter>jeff_renz</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-renz/29/82a/aa4</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.revgen.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jeff_renz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89807</importID>
      <name>Yuliya Quintela</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Yuliya is a consultant and developer for Business Intelligence Solutions. She has experience in various areas including Education, Finance, Telecommunications, and Software Technology into model data, visualize and deliver critical information to solve complex business decisions using Microsoft data platform and business analytics. She is an active member of the Business Intelligence and SQL Server community in Denver and a member of the Colorado SQL PASS chapter  user group. She specializes in SQL Server 2016 Reporting and Integration Services and holds professional certifications including MCSE for the Data Platform.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/yuliya-quintela-profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86687</importID>
      <name>Suresh Datla</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Worked on the Microsoft stack for 19 years now. Built successful Data Analytics Practices before. Currently focused on Data Platform, Data Analytics, Power BI and ML. I do Dashboard in a day sessions at Irvine MTC once every month. I also, conduct OC power BI user group to build a strong  Power BI Community. Worked with SQL Server product since it was version 7 and Power BI since its inception.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sureshdatla/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87800</importID>
      <name>Mike Byrd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Former rocket scientist and USAF Fighter Pilot -- now a SQL Server geek (24 years)! Past opportunities include free-lance technical writer for PC Magazine, Senior Software Manager for government sponsored munitions effectiveness committee, and insurance company CTO.  Currently senior database engineer consultant for several Austin companies.  

Presenter at many SQL Saturdays over last 6 years in United States, Europe, and Australia.

Specialize in SQL Server performance tuning; database (OLTP  OLAP) architecture; trouble-shooting; teaching TSQL (Basic through Advanced).

Video presentations (for local SQL Server user groups or SQL Saturdays) can be found at http://usergroup.tv/videos/category/speaker/mike-byrd</description>
      <twitter>ByrdNest_TX</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-byrd/1/aa0/bbb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://logicalread.solarwinds.com/?s=byrd, www.TSQLMentoring.com and SQLServerCentral.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ByrdNest_TX</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89801</importID>
      <name>TJay Belt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>TJay Belt is an outdoorsman at heart who enjoys riding dirtbikes, waterskiing, boating, playing racquetball and spending time with his family. 
When he can't be out playing, TJay loves to tinker with databases. TJay has been an IT professional for over a decade and a half. Currently serving as a Senior Database Administrator with Imagine Learning.  TJay has progressed through several roles in his database career including developer, data guy, database developer, database analyst and DBA.</description>
      <twitter>@tjaybelt</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/tjaybelt/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tjaybelt.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tjaybelt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87775</importID>
      <name>Mitchell Bottel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mitchell Bottel is a Senior Database Administrator and Operations Team Lead with Sutter Health, owner of Innovative IT Consulting and President of the Sacramento SQL Server User Group. He has 19 years of IT experience, focusing on SQL Server for the last 16 years with an emphasis on database administration and high availability solutions.</description>
      <twitter>SACSQLDude</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mjbottel/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SACSQLDude</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87091</importID>
      <name>Leslie Andrews</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leslie Andrews is an IT professional with almost 20 years of experience working with databases, designing databases, as well as designing and developing applications against those databases. 2018-2019 Idera ACE.</description>
      <twitter>landrews5807</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/leslie-andrews-csm/9/491/b89</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.lace.technology/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=landrews5807</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89326</importID>
      <name>Jason Horner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hi, my name is Jason. I spend most of my day helping clients solve business problems mostly in the Data and Advanced Analytics spaces. Sometimes this involves various and sundry cloud technologies including Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Data Lake Store, Azure Databricks, HDInsight and Azure SQL Database. I'm fluent in several languages including: SQL, C#, Python, and PowerShell.

I'm a Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server (MCM) and have been recognized for my technical excellence and evangelism efforts by Microsoft by being awarded the Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for the last 5+ years.

In my off hours I like to snowboard, karaoke, ride roller coasters, and play arcade games</description>
      <twitter>jasonhorner</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonhorner</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.jasonhorner.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jasonhorner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89809</importID>
      <name>Isak Sky</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Isak Sky works at Xledger USA. He is a full stack developer with a background in economics.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86690</importID>
      <name>Steve Wake</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Wake is currently the Principal BI Developer at Brown and Caldwell and has experience in consulting, advertising, media, manufacturing, retail, charities, telecommunications and financial services organizations using the full on-premises Microsoft BI stack. Recent experience with the Azure services: Analysis Services, Logic Apps,  Data Factory, Databricks, Snowflake and Power BI. Steve is also very involved in the SQL community, speaking at events around the world.</description>
      <twitter>stevewake</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/b5lurker</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.wakebi.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=stevewake</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87133</importID>
      <name>Meagan Longoria</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Meagan Longoria is a business intelligence consultant with Denny Cherry  Associates, and lives in Denver, Colorado. She is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Meagan spends a lot of time thinking about how to use data integration, DAX, and data visualization techniques to make data useful for people. She enjoys sharing her knowledge and experiences at conferences and user group meetings, as well as through her blog (DataSavvy.me).</description>
      <twitter>mmarie</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/meaganlongoria/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datasavvy.me</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mmarie</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89591</importID>
      <name>Elizabeth Noble</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Elizabeth Noble is a Director of Database Development in the metro Atlanta area. When she was introduced to her first database over 10 years ago, it was love at first sight. Her passion is to help others improve the quality and speed of deploying database changes through automation. When she is not trying to automate all of the things, she can be found spending time with her dogs, playing disc golf, or taking a walk at the gym.</description>
      <twitter>SQLZelda</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/elizabeth-a-noble</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLZelda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88037</importID>
      <name>Mark Moore</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Moore is a Cloud Solutions Architect working for Microsoft in North Texas.  Mark has been with Microsoft for 25 years serving in various roles in Services and Sales.  Prior to Microsoft Mark worked at Digital Equipment Corporation serving Federal and Government customers in San Antonio, Texas.  Mark currently resides with his Wife (Deanne) in the DFW area.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-moore-795876a?trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.msdn.com/b/markm</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89902</importID>
      <name>Paul Nielsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul is the founder of Tejon Technologies, inc, a software company offering a configurable, object/relational graph database solution built on the enterprise power of Microsoft SQL Server. Previously, Paul wrote the SQL Server Bible series, edited the MVP Deep Dives Vol 1 book, presented seminars in database design, and developed SQL Server courseware for Microsoft Learning. He was a Data Platform MVP from 2004 - 2016. IN the Startup Community he serves on the board of Peak Startup and is the chair of the annual Colorado Springs Startup Week.</description>
      <twitter>@PaulNielsen</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulnielsensql</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tejontech.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@PaulNielsen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88369</importID>
      <name>Manguirish Sardessai</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Manguirish is a Microsoft Certified Professional with 12 years’ experience in IT Industry specializing in Web Development, Database Development /Administration and Data Reporting. He provides efficient management and optimal performance for Datavail customers with health check analysis, installations and configuration of SQL Server plus automation of DBA tasks, disaster recovery solutions and providing customers with day-to-day comprehensive solutions to manage databases. He also undertakes business assessments and does project planning to deliver high-end pragmatic solutions for each client environment. When he’s not looking to play with databases, he enjoys traveling to new places and reading fiction literature.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/manguirishs</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/manguirish-sardessai/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/manguirishs</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88238</importID>
      <name>Jeff Moden</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With more than 51,000 posts and 39 mostly 5 star articles, Jeff Moden is a strong contributor on SQLServerCentral.com where he coined the term “RBAR” (Row By Agonizing Row) and helped make the "Tally Table" a household name.  Jeff has more than 2 decades of experience with SQL Server and is mostly self-trained in what he calls the “Black Arts” of T-SQL.  He’s known worldwide for his informative articles, high performance T-SQL coding methods, and methods of mentoring.  His dedication to helping others earned him the MS SQL Server MVP award for nine years and the RedGate Exceptional DBA Award in 2011.  His mantra is "Performance is in the code".</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89763</importID>
      <name>Scot Reagin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>TDWI Certified Business Intelligence Professional
Certified Data Vault Data Modeler

More than thirty years of technology experience serving in a wide variety of roles including: Software Designer, Solution Architect, and Operations and General Manager.  Experience designing and implementing complete analytic solutions for organizations of many sizes and in diverse industries.

Business intelligence specific experience encompasses all aspects of Enterprise Information solutions including: Information Quality, Enterprise Data Warehousing, Business Analysis Data Marts, and comprehensive visualization applications.</description>
      <twitter>@SDIScot</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sjreagin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sensibledataintegrations.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SDIScot</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89842</importID>
      <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Bossy (MCTS, MCP BI, CBIP) is a data and cloud analytics architect with 25 years of experience in software and database development. As a principal of Datalere, Carlos focuses on developing BI, Data Science, and Advanced Analytics solutions, including modeling data warehouses and delivering predictive models, integration, and visualization. He has developed warehouses and BI solutions for a variety of industries and state agencies, including health insurance, solar energy, foster care, telecom, and manufacturing.</description>
      <twitter>@carlosbossy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin/in/carlosbossy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.carlosbossy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@carlosbossy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92113</importID>
      <name>Carlos Robles</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Robles is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, a Friend of Redgate, and a technology lover. He has worked in the database management field on multiple platforms for over ten years in various industries.

He has diverse experience as a Primary Consultant and DBA Manager. He is currently working as a Solution Architect, helping customers to solve software/infrastructure problems in their on-premise or cloud environments.

Speaker, author, blogger, mentor, Guatemala SQL User group leader. If you don’t find him chatting with friends about geek stuff, he will be enjoying life with his family or exploring the beautiful outdoors of Colorado.</description>
      <twitter>dbamastery</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/croblesdba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.dbamastery.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=dbamastery</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87036</importID>
      <name>Michelle Haarhues</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michelle is a database administrator and has been working with SQL Server for over 15 years.  She started as a SQL Server developer and is currently a Database Administrator for Denver Health.  In many of her positions over the years, she was the lone SQL DBA\Developer so she loves talking about SQL Server to anyone who will listen.</description>
      <twitter>@mhaarhues</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://witsociety.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mhaarhues</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89846</importID>
      <name>Leslie Weed</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leslie Weed is currently a Data and BI Architect with RevGen Partners in Denver, CO. She has been a SQL Professional specializing in Business Intelligence, data analytics, systems implementation, integration, and solutions delivery for the last 20ish years, including a variety of Enterprise Data Warehouses in various industries.</description>
      <twitter>@weederbug</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@weederbug</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88299</importID>
      <name>Greg Moore</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Greg Moore is a graduate of RPI. There, he majored in CompSci, but probably spent as much time hiking, canoeing, caving and rock-climbing as he did studying.
He started working with SQL Server 4.21a in 1995 and has survived numerous upgrades.
He's been a Director and later VP of IT at several startups including PowerOne Media, TownNews and Traffiq and now consults. These days, when he's not busy with playing with SQL Server or spending time with his family, he can often be found underground caving or teaching cave rescue with the NCRC.
While his focus is on the operations side of DBA, his interests include DR, performance and general IT problem solving.
He is the author of: IT Disaster Response: Lessons Learned in the Field.</description>
      <twitter>@stridergdm</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gregdmoore</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blog.greenms.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@stridergdm</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87000</importID>
      <name>César Oviedo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>César Oviedo is a Data Platform MVP with more than 12 years of experience working in multidisciplinary projects running roles such as Scrum Master, Project Manager, BI Developer and DB Administrator. With experience leading teams and projects with more than 30 members. Currently focused on Data Science and Big Data platforms. Community Manager at “Business Intelligence LATAM” (BI PASS Chapter Leader for Costa Rica and PowerBI User Community), international speaker and trainer for Data and Cloud technologies.</description>
      <twitter>@bi_latam</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cesaroviedo</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.facebook.com/BusinessIntelligenceLatam</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@bi_latam</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89352</importID>
      <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kalen Delaney is a Data Platform MVP who has worked with SQL Server for more than 32 years. She has provided performance consulting services and taught advanced courses on SQL Server to thousands of people and organizations. In addition to her courseware development, Kalen has been writing about SQL Server for decades. She is the primary author of SQL Server Internals and the Inside SQL Server series. Kalen is also one of the primary editors for the Red Gate SQL Server Stairways tutorials.</description>
      <twitter>sqlqueen</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlqueen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89837</importID>
      <name>Marc Beacom</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marc Beacom, Managing Partner at Datalere, leverages over two decades of experience to better the data landscape for clients, along with nearly a decade of building and managing productive teams. Marc has led architecture and developed data integration strategies for dozens of Colorado based companies and organizations. Marc maintains an active presence in the Colorado community by volunteering and serving on nonprofit boards, speaking and running user groups.</description>
      <twitter>MarcBeacom</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/marcbeacom</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://datalere.com/author/marc-beacom/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MarcBeacom</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86691</importID>
      <name>Pini Krisher</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Manage DBA Teams and RD groups since 1996
lately work on:
SQL Server 2000-2017
SQL Azure
SSRS
SSIS
SNA
DATA Architect
noSQL
GraphDB
BIG DATA</description>
      <twitter>@krisherpi</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://il.linkedin.com/in/pinikrisher</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlazure.co.il</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@krisherpi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92652</importID>
      <name>Christopher Wolff</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Wolff has been a developer, report writer, and an admin in Microsoft and SQL Server Space since SQL Server 2000 in industries such as telecommunications, green energy, money transfers, and online accounting. He has been an active member of the Denver SQL User Group since 2011 and enjoys learning new things about computers. His interests includes video games, movies, and enjoying time with his wife and 2 kids.</description>
      <twitter>@tickytong</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/christopher-wolff/11/a07/458</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlred.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tickytong</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88239</importID>
      <name>Jeff Moden</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With more than 51,000 posts and 39 mostly 5 star articles, Jeff Moden is a strong contributor on SQLServerCentral.com where he coined the term “RBAR” (Row By Agonizing Row) and helped make the "Tally Table" a household name.  Jeff has more than 2 decades of experience with SQL Server and is mostly self-trained in what he calls the “Black Arts” of T-SQL.  He’s known worldwide for his informative articles, high performance T-SQL coding methods, and methods of mentoring.  His dedication to helping others earned him the MS SQL Server MVP award for nine years and the RedGate Exceptional DBA Award in 2011.  His mantra is "Performance is in the code".</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87289</importID>
      <name>Daniel Maenle</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Daniel is a Sr. Database Administrator at XTIVIA and the leader of Kansas City’s SQL Server Users group. Since diving into SQL 5 years ago, he worked on large-scale health care systems to small independent shops, all the way to Wall Street. He enjoys query tuning and has found Extended Events to be an aspect of SQL deserving widespread usage and should be leveraged on a daily basis.</description>
      <twitter>DanTheSQLMan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-maenle-1136295b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DanTheSQLMan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89735</importID>
      <name>Eric Peterson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eric Peterson is a consultant specializing in database architecture with experience in demanding Fortune 100 company environments. He has a Computer Science degree complemented with an MBA, which meshes well with his jobs integrating business information with the systems that process it. He has worked with SQL Server since its inception and was an instructor of SQL courses at a national technical training company. He also speaks are regional SQLSaturday events.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86811</importID>
      <name>Alex Grinberg</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have more than 20 years of IT experience. My primary focus is with the latest Microsoft technologies including .NET (VB and C#), SSRS and SSIS. I provide services in tuning, optimization, analysis and development for the creation of new applications, converting legacy technologies (SQL Server, VB.NET and C# ) and site training. I have worked for CSC, VerticalNet, IDP, LSAC , and TMNAS (to name a few) and I am currently employed with Cox Automotive. I am Apress author book "XML and JSON Recipes for SQL Server", also wrote number of articles for Simple-Talk and SQLServerCentral.com</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-grinberg-36773a6/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>87091</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87091</id>
          <name>Leslie Andrews</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 253</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Power of Data: The Complete Beginners Data Warehouse Kit</title>
      <description>For many of us data is scattered in many different systems.  We almost all have data that someone wants to compare or track but can't without a lot of manual manipulation.  So, how do you tie disparate systems together? With a Data Warehouse! In this presentation you will get the skills you need to start building your own. We will discuss the basics of what a Data Warehouse is, the tools needed to create, deploy and manage the Data Warehouse process, and the benefits of using the data you collect to manage operational processes and create data visualizations. After attending this session you will be able to return to your job and amaze people with your ability to show them the power of the data!</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87036</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87036</id>
          <name>Michelle Haarhues</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 260b</name>
      </location>
      <title>Keeping up with SSMS</title>
      <description>Starting with SQL Server 2016, SSMS became a stand-alone product.  Updates are sent out a lot more frequently than in the past and it can sometimes be difficult to keep up with all of the changes and new features.  There were 7 new version releases in 2017 and 8 new version releases in 2018.  With all of the new releases, are you using SQL Server Management Studio to its fullest?  We will discuss some of the features available in the SSMS v17 and v18.

On top of the new versions, there is a lot of cool stuff available in SSMS that you may not be aware is there.  We will discuss and demonstrate some features offered in SSMS that will help make Developers and Database Administrators more productive (and everyone wants to be more productive).  Whether a DBA or a Developer, you will take away knowledge about the new SSMS versions along with some useful SSMS tips/tricks to use in SSMS that you can apply in your day to day activities.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87000</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87000</id>
          <name>César Oviedo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 6</name>
      </location>
      <title>The next generation of Business Intelligence is done with DevOps</title>
      <description>The next generation of Business Intelligence practices is about improving effectiveness and accuracy. The simplest, most efficient way to do that is through DevOps.  DevOps for BI is no longer just getting your schemas into version control.  DevOps can bring the entire agile lifecycle to the BI world.  Agile development and continuous integration will improve the customer experience.  Advancements gained from using DevOps in BI are improved accuracy, consistency, and faster delivery.  DevOps for BI is a methodology of development, testing, QA, and Implementation that will increase the success of your projects and enhancements. This session explains with real-world examples the issues and solutions we have seen that will convince you to adopt this methodology.  We will walk through the steps to expand on what you do now and the efficiencies you will gain by starting or expanding your use of DevOps in your BI environment.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88561</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88561</id>
          <name>Jeff Renz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 253</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to the R Programming Language for BI Professionals</title>
      <description>The modern BI professional is taking on the challenge of operationalizing data science. Most BI developers are very strong in TSQL but their exposer to advanced statistics and visualizations were limited by what is available in the TSQL language. The R programming language allows us to clean, visualize, and apply advanced statistical methods to data. 

In this session I will demonstrate how to use R Studio to generate and test R scripts; generate R visuals in PowerBI; call R code in machine learning workflows; and execute R code in SQL Server. Additionally, I will cover these R programming fundamentals: creating and assigning variables; performing simple calculations; understanding R data types; vectors; matrices; factors; lists; data frames; and ggplot2 graphics.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88239</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88239</id>
          <name>Jeff Moden</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 256</name>
      </location>
      <title>“Black Arts” Index Maintenance #2: Better Methods that Can Actually Prevent Fragmentation for Weeks.</title>
      <description>Most people don’t realize it but the current “Best Practice” Methods are actually a leading cause of perpetual logical and physical fragmentation, totally unnecessary wasted memory, costly and continuous “Bad” page splits, unexplainable blocking, comparatively insane amounts of log file generation and, in an interesting “Catch 22”, a major part of why we have to do so much index maintenance.

This isn’t your typical presentation on Index Maintenance.

In this second of two back-to-back sessions, we’ll learn of several incredibly easy modifications to your Index Maintenance routines to actually prevent fragmentation for weeks rather than perpetuating it,  virtually eliminate “Bad” page splits, reduce wasted memory, make your log file  log file backups a whole lot more happy and increase the overall performance of even perfect code.

We’ll also learn that no simple method is a panacea, what to do about the horror of "expAnsive" updates, and how to make even GUID-keyed indexes work well.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87775</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87775</id>
          <name>Mitchell Bottel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 254</name>
      </location>
      <title>Effective Communication and Self Promotion for the IT Introvert (YOU!)</title>
      <description>Self-promotion is often confused with bragging, but most of the time it is the best tool to advance your career. In this session we talk about how self-promoting is the first step to creating your brand. Many IT Professionals struggle with how to stand out in a room, be noticed in a pile of resumes or maneuver for promotions. By learning to network and communicate effectively, these hurdles are converted into advancement ladders.  Self-Promotion and Networking are skills and therefore can be taught and learned. We will discuss ways to use social media, communities and other avenues to increase your brands visibility online. Equally important is your ability to interact with co-workers, clients and management face to face.  We will discuss ways to meet and network with other individuals and give you the tools to stand out from your peers.  Building and engaging with a large network will increase your worth to both your current and future employer.  Transform into a Networking Master.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88369</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88369</id>
          <name>Manguirish Sardessai</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 254</name>
      </location>
      <title>Accelerate SQL Server Migration to the AWS Cloud: Approach and Methodology</title>
      <description>In today’s marketplace, moving to the public Cloud(AWS) is a familiar and consistent trend within the SQL Server community. After all there are so many offering choices between AWS EC2 and RDS, each with their own distinctive features. Migrations to the cloud are only going to gain greater momentum as organizations grapple with their on-premises alternatives. 
In this presentation, we will discuss various methods and explain the advantages and disadvantages of using each method along with best practises. We’ll also showcase the surprises and pitfalls to avoid as we venture into the process.
Learn more on what trends you can expect to see, what the future holds for public clouds, and see how the DBA role and their responsibilities are undergoing changes to fit into the new profile necessary in managing the cloud framework.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86690</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86690</id>
          <name>Steve Wake</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 253</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Premium: Is it for your Company (and Worth it)?</title>
      <description>Power BI Premium is the top level of Power BI that your company can pay to get dedicated capacity for your Power BI reports and models. But at a starting price of $5000/month is it something your company needs and is it worth that price? In this session we will go over all of the current features offered with Power BI Premium and the features that we know are coming in the future so that you can help make that decision for your company. With multiple demos in this session you can see these features for yourself to help determine the worth. Come to this session if your company has been thinking about Power BI Premium but you have been unable to determine if it is right for your company or not. At the end of this session you will be armed with all of the knowledge you will need to make the right decision.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88238</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88238</id>
          <name>Jeff Moden</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 256</name>
      </location>
      <title>“Black Arts” Index Maintenance #1: How the “Best Practice” Methods are Silently Killing Performance</title>
      <description>Most people don’t realize it but the current “Best Practice” Methods are actually a leading cause of perpetual logical and physical fragmentation, totally unnecessary wasted memory, costly and continuous “Bad” page splits, unexplainable blocking, comparatively insane amounts of log file generation and, in an interesting “Catch 22”, a major part of why we have to do so much index maintenance.

This isn’t your typical presentation on Index Maintenance.

In this first of two back-to-back sessions on the subject, we’ll explore what happens to an index in the first year of its life for four different common Fill Factors along with how “Best Practice” methods executed once per week and once per day have their way with you, your indexes, your log files, wasted memory, and the performance of your code even if it’s perfect code.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87800</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87800</id>
          <name>Mike Byrd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 259</name>
      </location>
      <title>Indexing Like a Rocket Scientist</title>
      <description>Performance is what your users care about, and indexes can both improve and decrease
performance. As a SQL Developer, do you understand the difference between a clustered and
non-clustered index or what a covering index is? What is different between OLTP and data
warehouse databases when it comes to indexing?
This session is a deep dive into
 Clustered indexes
 Non-clustered indexes
 B-Tree traversal
 Primary Keys
 Covering indexes

This session will feature live query demos illustrating index utilization and performance using
statistics and query plans. Understand indexing like a rocket scientist by attending this session!

Some knowledge of T-SQL and Management Studio is recommended.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89352</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89352</id>
          <name>Kalen Delaney</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 256</name>
      </location>
      <title>Everlasting Issues with Temporary Tables and tempdb</title>
      <description>Tempdb has been a source of configuration confusion since the very first version of SQL Server. Each SQL Server instance only has one tempdb database used by all users in all databases. In this session, we’ll look at all the different uses of tempdb and how to configure your tempdb to support them. We’ll look at all the different kinds of temporary tables and see when you should use each type. We’ll talk about the difference between global and local temp tables, table variables and work tables. We’ll explore the various tools available that let you monitor the use (and abuse) of your tempdb database and we look at some best practice guidelines for how to keep your tempdb as healthy as possible.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87133</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87133</id>
          <name>Meagan Longoria</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 254</name>
      </location>
      <title>Creating Accessible Power BI Reports: Challenges  Opportunities</title>
      <description>Accessibility is catering for your whole audience, including those with disabilities. According to the US Census Bureau, 19 percent of the of the population had a disability in 2010. Do you know if your reports are designed in an inclusive way such that everyone can use them? This can be especially important if you are making reports for government entities, educational institutions, or the general public. In this session, we'll discuss accessibility standards and regulations of which you may want to be aware, how users with disabilities can consume Power BI reports, and guidance and pitfalls when designing inclusive reports.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89842</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89842</id>
          <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 256</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Science Tips and Tricks using Python and SQL</title>
      <description>The practice of Data Science has arrived and as data professionals we're on the forefront of this change. The data we collect can now be used in new and exciting ways, providing more value than ever before. 

To get started in this field, a number of tools and methodologies must be employed to help you achieve predictive analytics success with your data. In this session, we will start by providing an introduction to Python, quickly becoming the defacto programming language for data scientists who want to create enterprise-ready solutions.

Carlos will then cover predictive analytics using T-SQL and Python, providing a practical understanding of what it takes to develop your own predictive models making the most of the expertise you already have. The session includes an overview of definitions, concepts and terminology, successful applications of predictive analytics, and how predictive analytics fits into an analytics environment.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89735</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89735</id>
          <name>Eric Peterson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 259</name>
      </location>
      <title>So you want to be a consultant?</title>
      <description>Have you been looking for new opportunities and thought about consulting, but aren't sure if it's for you? We'll compare the different types of consulting options and the pros and cons of each. We'll look at the risks involved – from finance to lack of stability – and how to mitigate them.

Ever wondered what the advantages of being a Full Time Employee (FTE) vs a consultant are? We'll look at ways to get the most interesting projects as a consultant, the perception of consultants in the workplace, keeping your skills up and more.

We'll explore the expectations for consultants and how you can overcome the imposter complex. We'll also look at the logistics for payroll, retirement and taxes so you can stay on the right side of the IRS without driving yourself crazy.

Then we'll review the various ways you can find new projects because waiting for someone to call you out of the blue just isn't enough.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89326</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89326</id>
          <name>Jason Horner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 253</name>
      </location>
      <title>Real-World Data Movement and Orchestration Patterns using Azure Data Factory V2</title>
      <description>In this session, we will start with an overview of Azure Data Factory V2 concepts, then show you how you can use metadata to quickly build scalable serverless pipelines to move data from disparate data sources including On-Premises and Platform As A Service. Next, we will look at how to integrate the solution using continuous integration and deployment techniques. Finally, we will look at how to schedule, monitor and log our solution.
Whether you are just getting started with Azure Data Factory or looking to make your current data factory robust and enterprise-ready this session will take you to the next level.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89846</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89846</id>
          <name>Leslie Weed</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 253</name>
      </location>
      <title>Innovative Data Modeling: Make Data Warehousing Cool Again</title>
      <description>There is much more to life than 3rd normal form and dimensional modeling. Come explore how you can build a data warehouse solution or hybrid solution that is agile in nature with Data Vault. Discover this highly audit-able modeling technique used in international banking, manufacturing, insurance and many more industries.  Made a mistake? No worries, own your model. Design changes happen and it can be addressed quickly avoiding pain and project delays and ultimately keeping your business happy.  Let us bust the myth that data warehouses take too long to build and are too hard to modify by adding value to your environment and decreasing delivery time.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89801</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89801</id>
          <name>TJay Belt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 260b</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI, from a DBA's Perspective</title>
      <description>Microsoft’s Power BI is the new hotness. In this session, you will get your hands dirty and dive into PowerBI and create an actual report, with actual data. You will get to learn from examples from what a DBA has done to implement Power BI in his shop and make his data accessible.

As a DBA, we often need to collect and display data in a friendly and interactive fashion. We will play with some PowerShell to collect data from several systems, store this data in an Azure DB in the Cloud, then point Power BI at this data to display and interact with said data. You will learn a little about PowerShell, Azure SQL DB, Power BI, and how to make these work for you.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92923</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92923</id>
          <name>Sean McCown</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 260a</name>
      </location>
      <title>Loading SQL Server Data with Powershell</title>
      <description>Powershell has become the defacto standard for scripting Microsoft products. However, putting data in text files doesn’t scale. Here I’m going to show you the ins and outs of loading data into SQL Server using Powershell for the purpose of centralizing collections. We’re going to cover RBAR as well as bulk operations and the types of things you need to take into consideration in an enterprise setting. This is a no holds barred session taught by an enterprise SQL Server scripting expert. You can’t afford to miss this session if you do any level of scripting in your shop.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92652</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92652</id>
          <name>Christopher Wolff</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 260b</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server using Amazon Web Services EC2 Instances</title>
      <description>You have just been informed that you are moving to AWS. Now what? In this presentation, we’ll cover the ups and downs of using AWS Elastic Cloud Computing (EC2) instances for your SQL Server. We will show you how to make an EC2 instance and install SQL Server on it; go over networking, security and routing services; and demonstrate how to make a simple, highly available, two-node availability group. By the end of the session, you should be on the right track to start using AWS in your environment.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86811</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86811</id>
          <name>Alex Grinberg</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 259</name>
      </location>
      <title>CONVERT_IMPLICIT is a hidden danger</title>
      <description>Abstract: The CONVERT_IMPLICIT operator is part of an execution plan. When an execution plan has a CONVERT_IMPLICIT operator, this is a signal that “your statement has a problem”. This presentation will show you how to detect the Execution Plans with CONVERT_IMPLICIT operator; how to find the statement that causes conversion, and what DMVs can help to solve the problem. It will also show you the solution to collect the Execution Plans with CONVERT_IMPLICIT operator across the servers.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87289</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87289</id>
          <name>Daniel Maenle</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 259</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dump the Trace: Extending your Events</title>
      <description>This will be an introduction into using Extended Events and why to drop using SQL Trace. As well as some basic scripts with tools for parsing XQuery, and some good basic XE use cases.  This session will help become more comfortable with Extended Events.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89837</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89837</id>
          <name>Marc Beacom</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 254</name>
      </location>
      <title>Implementing a Cloud Analytics Solution: Options, Costs and More</title>
      <description>If you’ve looked at the cloud, you’ve realized the large number of options you have, to implement a complete cloud analytics solution. You can deploy dashboards, data ingestion and integration and advanced analytics to the cloud that will empower data-driven decisions for your organizations. This talk will discuss and review options you have, to run Cloud Analytic Solutions on Azure.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88299</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88299</id>
          <name>Greg Moore</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 260a</name>
      </location>
      <title>The very Model of a Modern Day Database</title>
      <description>Gilbert and Sullivan never had to create a database. But you do. This session will delve into details of the system databases.
These are created when the system is installed and then DBAs pretty much forget about them.  If you ask, they might have an idea of what their use is, but the truth is, they're sort of a black box to many.

This session will cover how and when to back them up, how to move them if necessary and how to take advantage of that "model" database that seems to just sort of sit there.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89809</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89809</id>
          <name>Isak Sky</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 260a</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building Composable Query Abstractions in TSQL</title>
      <description>A common critique of SQL is that it can be hard to write queries with reusable parts, something which is trivial in many programming languages. For example, even something simple, like running a query with different set of selections can be tricky to express. 

This presentation will show how this problem can be avoided by taking a data-first approach and using some advanced TSQL constructs. Along the way, we will also go over how to do GraphQL-like queries in TSQL.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89763</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89763</id>
          <name>Scot Reagin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 260b</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hyphenated Data Roles in Today's Information Environment</title>
      <description>A modern Information Environment requires a wide and growing variety of disciplines, each with discrete skills that should compliment but often overlap others.  By understanding disciplines like Data Management, Acquisition, Modeling, Engineering, Science and BI Developer, Analyst, and Architect you will better understand how to work with others and how you might grow or transition into other roles.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92113</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92113</id>
          <name>Carlos Robles</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 260a</name>
      </location>
      <title>Exploring SQL Server containers on Docker  Kubernetes</title>
      <description>In this session, we will explore the options we have when working with SQL Server running on Docker containers or Kubernetes. Also, will take a look at some real-world scenarios of backing up \ restoring databases in containers, high availability, version upgrades, and the most important portability. Join me to discuss further about this interesting topic that is called by some experts as “The Future of Database Infrastructure”.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89839</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89839</id>
          <name>Todd Kleinhans</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 260a</name>
      </location>
      <title>Storing Images in a Database - Tips and Techniques</title>
      <description>How many of you have digital pictures? We are drowning in them by their sheer numbers and storage space. We take so many we often don't even have time to look at them! Have you ever thought of storing them in a database? You will learn the pro's and con's about storing images in a database using varbinary(max), FileTable and by individual pixels. Technologies covered include Columnstore, In-Memory OLTP, Python, T-SQL, and of course Unreal Engine to display them in VR using the AdventureWorks database. Come and learn how to get a handle on storing and backing up your pictures!</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88037</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88037</id>
          <name>Mark Moore</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 256</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding Azure SQL Managed Instances</title>
      <description>Have you heard about Azure SQL Managed Instances and want to know more.  This session will discuss what SQL managed instances are and are not, we will cover the different families of Managed Instances and we will cover networking requirements for Managed Instances.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89807</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89807</id>
          <name>Yuliya Quintela</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 254</name>
      </location>
      <title>Say Anything: Using knowledge base, NLP and AI to enable customer</title>
      <description>Today companies have an abundance of unstructured data. It exists in emails, text files and documents. It is not easily searchable and usable without a lot of prep work. But this data contains valuable information! 
Companies can use this new information in many different ways, for example to enable customers for a self-service support. Customers might be looking for the same answer, but they will likely ask their questions in different ways. Customers really want to be able to ... say anything.
Come and learn how to use Azure technologies to build a Chat Bot to answer questions based on FAQ URLs, structured documents or product manuals.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86691</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86691</id>
          <name>Pini Krisher</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL DB and PowerBI the Best friends</title>
      <description>Since PowerBI is a great tool for telling us Data stories, and Azure SQL DB is the easiest place to hold DATA, Both are very good friends....</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89591</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89591</id>
          <name>Elizabeth Noble</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 260b</name>
      </location>
      <title>Migrate Your Database with Distributed AGs</title>
      <description>You find yourself needing to migrate to new hardware or new operating system. If you're running SQL Server 2016+, you're in luck! Distributed Availability Groups (AGs) may just be the solution you want.

In this session I will explain the purpose and usages of Distributed AGs, create a Distributed AG and the associated AGs, and perform a mock data center migration.

NOTE: This session expects that attendees are already familiar with Availability Groups.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86687</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86687</id>
          <name>Suresh Datla</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Security -  End to End</title>
      <description>Their many aspects to consider when securing Power BI applications. Starting with authentication all the way to Row Level Security and everything in between. We will discuss the different elements as well as best practices.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89902</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89902</id>
          <name>Paul Nielsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 259</name>
      </location>
      <title>Professional SQL Server Development</title>
      <description>You’ve seen numerous presentations with demos of code snippets and techniques but how do you wrap all those ideas into a comprehensive set of guidelines to ensure that your code is enterprise grade? In this session we’ll look at several examples of complex production grade code and offer guidelines to take your SQL Server code to the next level.</description>
      <startTime>4/6/2019 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/6/2019 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>