<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #208 - Riyadh 2013</name>
    <startDate>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+03:00) Kuwait, Riyadh</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatRiyadh</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Holiday Inn (AlQasr), Olaya.</name>
      <street>King Fahd Road</street>
      <city>Riyadh</city>
      <state>, Saudi Arabia</state>
      <zipcode>
      </zipcode>
      <longitude>46.687718</longitude>
      <latitude>24.684362</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1141</importID>
      <name>Starways Information Technology</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.starways.com.sa</url>
      <imageURL>https://devlifestyle.net/UploadedFiles/Sponsors/logo123.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>561</importID>
      <name>Development Space</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dev.sa</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.dev.sa/DevLogo/DevSpace%20LOGO_S.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>83</importID>
      <name>PluralSight</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pluralsight.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.srnimbus.com.br/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Pluralsight_logo_novo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15386</importID>
      <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niko Neugebauer is a Data Platform Consultant. A SQL Server MVP with over 20 years of experience in IT, he is passionate about the Microsoft Data Platform and community. Founder of the Portuguese SQL Server User Group and the main organizer of the first SQLSaturday event outside of North America (#78 Portugal), Niko speaks regularly at events such as PASS Summit, SQLRally, SQLBits, and SQLSaturday events around the world. Niko loves sharing information and knowledge and has authored over 130 blog posts on Columnstore Indexes, and regularly contributes to the open-sourced CISL library focused on Columnstore Indexes.</description>
      <twitter>NikoNeugebauer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pt.linkedin.com/in/webcaravela/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.nikoport.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=NikoNeugebauer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27174</importID>
      <name>Umit Tiric</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Umit Tiric has 16 years professional experience though he has started his career in 1989 by releasing his first commercially packaged. Since then, he has also designed, implemented computer network infrastructure projects on network layer but his main focus is designing and developing enterprise applications and integrations using various technologies, programming languages and products mostly focused on Microsoft products and technologies.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16089</importID>
      <name>Joe Chang</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>
      </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/joe_chang/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15385</importID>
      <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niko Neugebauer is a Data Platform Consultant. A SQL Server MVP with over 20 years of experience in IT, he is passionate about the Microsoft Data Platform and community. Founder of the Portuguese SQL Server User Group and the main organizer of the first SQLSaturday event outside of North America (#78 Portugal), Niko speaks regularly at events such as PASS Summit, SQLRally, SQLBits, and SQLSaturday events around the world. Niko loves sharing information and knowledge and has authored over 130 blog posts on Columnstore Indexes, and regularly contributes to the open-sourced CISL library focused on Columnstore Indexes.</description>
      <twitter>NikoNeugebauer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pt.linkedin.com/in/webcaravela/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.nikoport.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=NikoNeugebauer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21288</importID>
      <name>Nabeel Derhem</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nabeel is a data culture passionate who works at Microsoft as a Data Platform Architect. His +15 years of experience with data platform technologies moved him through OLTP, DW, BI, ML, and cloud.

As an ex SQL Server MVP (until joining Microsoft), Nabeel is still a regular speaker on international events.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/NabeelDerhem</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://sa.linkedin.com/in/nabeelderhem</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/NabeelDerhem</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23997</importID>
      <name>Hossam Alfraih</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hossam is a Senior Database Architect who is using SQL Server since version 7.0.
He is a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) who earned MCTS SQL Server 2005/2008 and MCITP SQL Server 2008 for Database Developer and Administrator certificates. He works as a freelancer Technical Consultant specialized in Database Systems and Performance Tuning. Moreover, he is writing and speaking about Cloud Computing since 2009.
He co-founded SQLServerPath.org | Blog: www.SaudiGeek.NET | Follow him @SaudiGeekNET</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.SaudiGeek.NET</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20998</importID>
      <name>Mohamad Halabi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>https://mvp.support.microsoft.com/profile/Mohamad.Halabi</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16090</importID>
      <name>Joe Chang</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>
      </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/joe_chang/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15200</importID>
      <name>Shehab El-Najjar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Shehab El-Najjar was the ONLY Microsoft SQL Server MVP in Gulf for the past 6 years and the 2nd one all over the Middle East  , he is the founder of SQL Gulf events series (SQL Gulf #1 , #2 and #3 ) where he spent so much time and efforts  to broadcast Microsoft SQL Server technologies all over the Gulf such as  KSA and Emirates and other Gulf cities ahead ..) 

	He is now Professional Services Manager at Saudi  Emircom 

	He was previously COO and business leader in KSA market through his startup WAJA IT for  3 years

	He is an influencing Database community leader all over the region  	
	A senior Database Consultant (SQL Server MVP for 6 years in row) -The 2nd MVP awardee SQL Server all over Middle East and Arabic region</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/MSQLPerformance</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=126446983amp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlserver-performance-tuning.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/MSQLPerformance</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24994</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>15200</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15200</id>
          <name>Shehab El-Najjar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL Performance Guidelines for better DB stress </title>
      <description>To reach your desired business functionalities, it  can be easy using some common T-SQL practices  like MTVF , scalar functions , Temp tables, Union…etc  and they might perform pretty well on development server coz neither adequate stress of users is exists there but actually they seem totally strange once going to live and they become performing badly ending up with standstill cases sometimes  , this is due to lack of stress powers of T-SQL codes which should be considered largely for critical mission DBs so I am going to talk to you about How to capture expensive queries using different techniques ..?and How to optimize them in the shortest time using scientific ways ..? (10 different T-SQL Practices will be analyzed within this session)</description>
      <startTime>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/23/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24994</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24994</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Data platform upgrade Techniques, best practices  notes from the field</title>
      <description>Why Upgrade?
This is the big question that every SQL Server user will be asking, from my experience I say not just for shiny new features but increase your productivity and do-more with-less practices.
Data Platform Upgrade topic has been a popular session that I've presented in major conferences like Microsoft Tech-Ed (North America, Europe  India) and SQLbits.
In this session, we will overview end-to-end upgrade process that covers the essential phases, steps and issues involved in upgrading SQL Server 2000, 2005,  SQL Server 2008 R2 (with a good overview on 2012 too) by using best practices and available resources. We will cover the complete upgrade cycle, including the preparation tasks, upgrade tasks, and post-upgrade tasks. Real-world examples from my Consulting experience expanding on why  how such a solution is offered.</description>
      <startTime>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/23/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27174</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27174</id>
          <name>Umit Tiric</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2012 Parallel Data Warehouse Appliance</title>
      <description>PDW is a massively parallel processing data warehousing appliance built for any volume of relational data (with up to 100x performance gains) and provides the simplest integration to Hadoop.

SQL Server 2012 Parallel Data Warehouse introduces PolyBase, a fundamental breakthrough in data processing used to enable seamless integration between traditional data warehouses and “Big Data” deployments.

-       Use standard SQL queries (instead of MapReduce) to access and join Hadoop data with relational data.

-       Query Hadoop data without IT having to pre-load data first into the warehouse.

-       Native Microsoft BI Integration allowing analysis of relational and non-relational data with familiar tools like Excel.

Scale and perform beyond your traditional SQL Server deployment with PDW’s massively parallel processing (MPP) appliance that can handle the extremes of your largest mission critical requirements of performance and scale.</description>
      <startTime>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/23/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20998</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20998</id>
          <name>Mohamad Halabi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>.NET and WCF Transactions for SQL Resource Manager</title>
      <description>The session first explains transactions architecture, tackling topics such as Resource Managers, Transaction Protocols, and Transaction Managers. Then it shows how DTC is used to aid in .NET and WCF distributed transactions.</description>
      <startTime>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/23/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15386</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15386</id>
          <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Inheriting a database for Developers, version 2</title>
      <description>There are very few applications which are being developed from zero, the most are apps are simply inherited from previous development teams. This session serves to show some easy implementable practices to follow after inheriting a database. Those practices allow to check some if the database design was done in regards to the actual data, or if while implementing some of the constraints and checks some tables were left behind. :) The practices shown in this session will allow to check the database design and identify some of the possible performance degradations.</description>
      <startTime>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/23/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23997</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23997</id>
          <name>Hossam Alfraih</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Tour in The Indexing World!</title>
      <description>Hossam will be your guided tour to the indexing world! We will visits index types, know where to use them, how they work, interesting facts, and best practices. We will see how to keep our indexes healthy for better performance as well.</description>
      <startTime>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/23/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16089</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16089</id>
          <name>Joe Chang</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Performance on Powerful Hardware</title>
      <description>Modern server systems are incredibly powerful, and yet it is clear that a brute force approach to SQL Server performance does not always work. Learn how to identify situations that require good SQL,indexes and statistics. Additional topics are automating performance analysis and parallel execution strategies.</description>
      <startTime>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/23/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16090</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16090</id>
          <name>Joe Chang</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Elements of Storage Performance</title>
      <description>Today it is possible to achieve exceptional storage performance for SQL Server without excessive costs. Unfortunately the solution proposed by storage system vendors generally ignores the special characteristics of database engines (not just SQL Server), resulting in marginal if not poor performance. Learn how to match the hardware elements of storage including IO channels, the role of cache, and the components hard drives, SSD - both enterprise class and lower cost options to the characteristics of SQL Server IO to achieve realizable query performance.</description>
      <startTime>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/23/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21288</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21288</id>
          <name>Nabeel Derhem</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>NoSQL, an Introduction</title>
      <description> Understanding when and how to use NoSQL is already becoming critical for all database professionals currently focusing only on the RDBMS world. This session is about explaining NoSQL for the SQL Server professional  where we will discuss the history and needs that led to the NoSQL solutions, and the strengths and weaknesses in comparison with the RDBMS. We'll also explore the several NoSQL Data Models available in the market today (Key-Value, Column-Family, Document, and Graph) along with explaining the current solutions implementing them (Cassandra, MongoDB, Redis, Neo4j, etc..).</description>
      <startTime>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/23/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15385</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15385</id>
          <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Analyzing Twitter Data</title>
      <description>This session will concentrate on explanation of how to start using and analysing the data from one of the most popular social networks - Twitter. We shall take a look at the different dashboards and we shall try to understand some of the meanings. This presentation shall try to explore the best of the existing Microsoft technologies for an accessible Twitter data analysis. </description>
      <startTime>5/23/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/23/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>