<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #599 - Plovdiv 2017</name>
    <startDate>5/27/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Cairo</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatPlovdiv</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Culture Centre "Boris Hristov"</name>
      <street>15 Gladston Str., 4000 Plovdiv, Bulgaria</street>
      <city>Plovdiv</city>
      <state>Plovdiv, Bulgaria</state>
      <zipcode>4000</zipcode>
      <longitude>24.7428</longitude>
      <latitude>42.14192</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1155</importID>
      <name>SuperHosting.BG</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.superhosting.bg/</url>
      <imageURL>https://media.infragistics.com/community/SQLSaturday/SuperHostingBG-logo-small.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1773</importID>
      <name>SQL Master Academy</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlmasteracademy.com/</url>
      <imageURL>http://www.mateev.net/logos/SQLMA-hor-small.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>697</importID>
      <name>ICB-InterConsult Bulgaria Ltd.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.icb.bg</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/878/EventSponsor_14268.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1683</importID>
      <name>TechTalks.bg</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://techtalks.bg/</url>
      <imageURL>http://azure-camp.eu/sofia-bootcamp/images/sofia/sponsors/techtalks-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1407</importID>
      <name>SBTECH</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sbtech.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/878/EventSponsor_14270.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1829</importID>
      <name>Adatis</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.adatis.co.uk</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/878/EventSponsor_14266.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1699</importID>
      <name>Bulpros</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.bulpros.com/</url>
      <imageURL>http://azure-camp.eu/sofia-bootcamp/images/sofia/sponsors/bulpros-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56694</importID>
      <name>Alexander Arvidsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alexander is a principal solutions architect at Solution Xperts in Linköping, Sweden. Nobody really knows what it means to be a principal solutions architect, but he spends his days helping clients of all shapes and sizes to take better care of their data. 

He has spent the last 23 years toying with databases and related infrastructure services such as storage, networking and virtualization, occasionally emerging from the technical darkness to attend a Star Wars convention somewhere in the world.  

He is a frequent international speaker, a Data Platform MVP, podcaster, blogger and a Microsoft Certified Trainer, focusing on SQL Server, the Azure data stack and Power BI.</description>
      <twitter>arcticdba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexanderarvidsson</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.arcticdba.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arcticdba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57183</importID>
      <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mihail Mateev is a technical consultant, community enthusiast, PASS Regional Mentor for CEE, chapter lead, Microsoft Azure MVP, Microsoft Regional Director. He works as a Senior Solutions Architect at EPAM Systems, focused on Data Platform, IoT and cloud related solutions. He also worked many years like a Technical evangelist in the Infragistics. Last years Mihail was focused on various areas related to technology Microsoft: Data Platform, Visual Studio, ASP.Net, Windows client apps, Data Platform, and Microsoft Azure. Michael also has a PhD in cloud computing area. He is a university lecturer on Smart Homes and Smart Energy IoT Solutions.</description>
      <twitter>mihailmateev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mihail-mateev/1/6b3/4b1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mmateev.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mihailmateev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>58093</importID>
      <name>Sergiy Lunyakin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sergiy Lunyakin (MCSA, MCSE, MCTS) is a Big Data Architect at SoftServe, Inc.
He has extensive experience in designing and developing Big Data Analytics, Data Warehouse, and BI solutions, using both on-premises and cloud products. In 2016, Sergiy became Microsoft Data Platform MVP and has since maintained his MVP status. Sharing knowledge is another one of his passions. He regularly speaks at international conferences such as SQLSaturday, SQLDay, SQLNexus, and SQLBits. He also runs the Lviv SQL Server User Group in Ukraine and organizes SQLSaturday Lviv.</description>
      <twitter>slunyakin</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/slunyakin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://slunyakin.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=slunyakin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>62927</importID>
      <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Martorana Tusa is a Business Intelligence Team Manager at Würth Phoenix,  the IT and consulting company of the Würth-Group. 
He is awarded as MVP in the Data Platform category

Former BI Specialist at Widex, a Danish manufacturing company, and BI Developer in the IT department of an Italian banking group. 20+ years of experience working with data. 
He is focused on the entire BI stack: database development, data warehousing, data analysis, reporting, etc. 
Andrea is a usual speaker at many events: SQLSaturdays, conferences in Europe and PASS Summit, and for PASS Virtual Groups. 

Andrea is an author for sqlshack.com, sqlservercentral.com, and UGISS (User Group Italiano SQL Server).</description>
      <twitter>bruco441</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bruco441</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>62399</importID>
      <name>Miroslav Lessev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a PhD candidate at Faculty of Economics and Business Administration, University of Sofia quot;St. Kliment Ohridskiquot; in Implementation of modern computer engineering in economic studies at. I have study on cloud computing and its effect on economics and people. I have more than 20 years of experience in designing, developing, implementing and supporting databases. At the moment I#39;m a Big Data Developer in DataCore Software.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://bg.linkedin.com/pub/miroslav-lessev/62/238/34</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63838</importID>
      <name>Margarita Naumova</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Magi Naumova is SQL Server Architect and Consultant, speaker and trainer, Microsoft Certified Master, MVP Data Platform, MCT, Founder of SQL Master Academy, founder and leader of the Bulgarian SQL User group. She has more than 15 years SQL Server training and consulting experience. Magi is a former member of Microsoft Services Worldwide Technical Leadership Team, а Microsoft Women worth watching http://zd.net/1lwNYKH Currently she speaks, writes, trains and consults people on SQL Server technology. She runs a Data Platform consulting company part of which is SQL Master Academy training program. It helps hundreds of specialists to feel knowledgeable in their daily work or to find an inspirational career path in the world of SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://bg.linkedin.com/pub/margarita-naumova/9/965/206</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>www.maginaumova.com; http://blogs.technet.com/b/magi/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63731</importID>
      <name>Iva Velkova</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Iva Velkova is a SQL Server trainer in SQL Master Academy. She has nearly 4 years’ experience with SQL Server. 
Focusing on querying SQL Server, SQL Server development, performance tuning and optimization, and SQL Server patterns and practices. 
Iva Velkova has successfully completed the requirements to be recognized as a Microsoft Certified Professional.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56960</importID>
      <name>John Tunnicliffe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr John Tunnicliffe is a well-respected designer and architect of business intelligence solutions who likes nothing more than getting his hands dirty with real life coding problems.  John is a recognised expert in applying continuous integration techniques to data warehouse projects, thereby ensuring code is automatically built, deployed and tested as changes are made by the development team.  As a regular speaker at the SQLBits conference and PASS SQL Saturday events, John has covered topics such as building an infrastructure to support real-time OLAP and continuous integration and the data warehouse.</description>
      <twitter>Dr_John_T</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/drjohntunnicliffe</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://devops-your-dwh.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Dr_John_T</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61625</importID>
      <name>Jonathon Eve-O'Connor</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jon is a director of Adatis Bulgaria, located in Sofia.  He has over 8 years experience developing and managing BI projects across a wide range of industries and the full Microsoft BI Stack, he is passionate about Business Intelligence and the wider SQL community.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.adatis.co.uk/jonathoneveoconnor/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56774</importID>
      <name>Gilberto Zampatti</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Time ago (a lot of time ago…) an excellent IT pro brought me with him and became my Mentor in the IT wonderland…it was a world full of mainframes…
I met the Relational theory when there were no commercial RDBMS, and I was spellbound by that “magic”. When Microsoft appeared in the IT market, I felt finally which trek I had to follow. I’m still walking on such road, and in my rucksack I’ve ben putting some other stuff (like SharePoint, for example). My sole regret:  I’ve left the College to consecrate all my time to my job; curiously, since then, I’ve never stop learning…</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61511</importID>
      <name>Simon Whiteley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Simon Whiteley is the Director of Engineering for Advancing Analytics Ltd and a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Simon is a seasoned solution architect and technical lead with well over a decade of Microsoft Analytics experience. A deep techie with a focus on emerging cloud technologies and applying "big data" thinking to traditional analytics problems, Simon also has a passion for bringing it back to the high level and making sense of the bigger picture. When not tinkering with tech, Simon is a death-dodging London cyclist, a sampler of craft beers, an avid chef, and a generally nerdy person.</description>
      <twitter>MrSiWhiteley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/pub/simon-whiteley/32/994/aa8</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.adatis.co.uk/blogs/simonwhiteley/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MrSiWhiteley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59430</importID>
      <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen, as the founder of Savory Data, has a long history of providing customer solutions in the areas of data engineering, data science, and Business Intelligence. He is a certified software engineer, a graduated business educator, and professor of Databases  Project Management at HTL Leonding, and is certified as an MCSE  MCT. He is a published author and writes articles for well-known journals. He co-founded PASS Austria and organizes SQLSaturdays in Austria. Markus is a founding member of Power BI Usergroup Austria. Since 2017 Markus was awarded as an Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>MEhrenmueller</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markus-ehrenmueller/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.savorydata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MEhrenmueller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56772</importID>
      <name>Miroslav Dimitrov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Miroslav Dimitrov is a Senior Big Data and Analytics Engineer at DXC Technology, regular speaker at various events and Microsoft Certified Trainer. He is MCSE: Data Platform for SQL Server and MCITP on SQL 2008. In the last years he had worked on great variety of customers' environments and involved in complex transitions and transformation projects as well as developing private and public cloud solutions. Miroslav is also leading database courses at Sofia University.</description>
      <twitter>@miro_dd</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://bg.linkedin.com/in/dimitrovmiroslav</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlshack.com/author/miroslav-dimitrov/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@miro_dd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>62734</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56776</importID>
      <name>Gilberto Zampatti</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Time ago (a lot of time ago…) an excellent IT pro brought me with him and became my Mentor in the IT wonderland…it was a world full of mainframes…
I met the Relational theory when there were no commercial RDBMS, and I was spellbound by that “magic”. When Microsoft appeared in the IT market, I felt finally which trek I had to follow. I’m still walking on such road, and in my rucksack I’ve ben putting some other stuff (like SharePoint, for example). My sole regret:  I’ve left the College to consecrate all my time to my job; curiously, since then, I’ve never stop learning…</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63800</importID>
      <name>Rozalina Zaharieva</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL expert in Microsoft’s Data Platform Solution. Enthusiast with more than 10 years of experience in support, implementation, design and architecture of small and large projects for SQL Core – Consolidations and Migrations. Passionate speaker in SQL Master Academy and events like SQL Saturday and community events. Experience in Financial Sector Data platform Operations.</description>
      <twitter>RozenceZ</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rozalina-zaharieva-35402761/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=RozenceZ</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57029</importID>
      <name>Andrey Nikolov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrey is MCSA for SQL Server 2012/2014 with almost 20 years of experience in designing and implementing applications for Windows. He is working with various database platforms, but SQL Server is his favorite. He is also a leader of Plovdiv Power BI User Group and active member of local .NET, Power BI and SQL Server communities.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64551</importID>
      <name>Ezra Levi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A senior DBA, working in the data field for the last 12 years. An experienced and professional DBA in SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB, Hadoop and other big data technologies.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ezra-levi-688b1257/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57058</importID>
      <name>Ivan Donev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a Data platform MVP with more than 10 years of real-life experience with SQL Server and its stack of services. Besides the support and project work, I am also a trainer, conference speaker and user group organizer (and volunteer).</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ikdonev</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivandonev/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ikdonev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61506</importID>
      <name>Terry McCann</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Microsoft MVP. Principal Consultant and Owner of Advancing Analytics Limited, an Advanced Analytics consultancy in the UK. Advancing Analytics helps businesses advance their analytical capabilities. Our focus is on Data Science, Data Engineering, DataOps and applied AI. Terry holds a Master's degree in Data Science - with a focus on DataOps for Machine Learning. Speaker at conferences across the world and the host of the Data Science in Production Podcast.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLShark</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tpmccann</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.advancinganalytics.co.uk/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLShark</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56951</importID>
      <name>Christopher Adkin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris is a freelance SQL consultant who has been working with SQL Server since 2000, his passion is for squeezing every last drop of performance out of SQL Server and understanding the database engine at a level which conventional tools cannot provide any insights on.</description>
      <twitter>ChrisAdkin8</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/wollatondba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.chrisadkin.io</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ChrisAdkin8</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61514</importID>
      <name>Oliver Frost</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am currently working as a Data Engineer, improving the company data platform and providing the necessary resources for our data consultants. I am extremely fortunate to dabble with a number of tools including those from the Microsoft BI stack and NoSQL tech like Neo4j, R and Python. My strengths lie in integrating multiple technologies for a specific business problem.

I aim to present material that BI consultants and developers can all take away something new to apply to their own work processes. I try to apply knowledge and skills from my previous life as a neuroscientist and as a blindfolded Rubik's Cube world record holder. I am of the belief that, one day, neuroscience and big data will come together in a big way.</description>
      <twitter>@ConsolidataLtd</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/olliefrost</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ConsolidataLtd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63788</importID>
      <name>Eugene Polonichko</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leader of PASS Local Chapter in Donetsk (Ukraine). I work  as DWH/BI architect.  Responsible for designing and developing Data Warehouse and BI solutions with using Microsoft  BI Stack products.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/EvgenPolonichko</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/eugenepolonichko/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://msolapblog.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/EvgenPolonichko</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56997</importID>
      <name>Kaloyan Kosev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kaloyan Kosev is a SQL Server expert working with enterprise companies for the last 12* years. His daily work routine is a mixture of troubleshooting bugs and issues, consulting and advising clients and presenting to students. Within his free time he is trying to balance between SQL and x-sports.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/nosqltillcoffee</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://bg.linkedin.com/in/kosev</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/nosqltillcoffee</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66201</importID>
      <name>Valio Bonev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>IT enthusiast keen to explore new avenues for solving real business challenges. Не has a vast experience in bringing solutions to some of the most interesting e-commerce and financial organizations. He is a Solution Architect at BULPROS.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59496</importID>
      <name>Jan Mulkens</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jan Mulkens is a Microsoft MVP in AI, a Solution Expert at Ordina Belgium, and a Microsoft Data Platform  BI Consultant.
In his spare time, he is a speaker at conferences and user groups in Europe and he organizes two user groups and a conference in Belgium.
Power BI Days conference (www.powerbidays.com), Belgium Microsoft Advanced Analytics User Group (bit.ly/msaaug), and Flemish Power BI User Group (meetup.powerbibelgium.com).</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/JanMulkens</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/janmulkens</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.janmulkens.be</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/JanMulkens</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>56960</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56960</id>
          <name>John Tunnicliffe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Continuous Integration and the Data Warehouse [EN]</title>
      <description>Continuous Integration is not normally associate with data warehouse projects due to the perceived complexity of implementation.  John will be showing how modern tools make it simple to apply continuous integration techniques to data warehouse projects.  In particular, the session will cover: 

* Setting up SQL Server Data Tools for automated deployments: DAC Publish profiles  SQLPackage.exe

* Automating your build and deployments with PowerShell and psake

* Guide to configuring TeamCity as your build server

* Automated Integration and Regression testing of your Data Warehouse using various test frameworks

* Overcoming issues with cube and tabular model deployment</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59430</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59430</id>
          <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Game of Hierarchies: Mastering Recursive Queries</title>
      <description>Hierarchies are the bread and butter of most business applications and you find them almost everywhere:
* Product Categories
* Sales Territories
* Calendar and Time
Even when there is a big need from a business perspective, the solutions in relational databases are still sort of awkward. The most flexible hierarchies are modeled as self-referenced tables. If you want to successfully query such self-referenced hierarchies, you will need either loops or recursive Common Table Expressions. You will learn how to master both and will learn how make them fast.
Join this session for a journey through best practices to transform your hierarchies into useful information. We will have fun playing around with a sample database based on G. R. R. Martin’s famous “Game of Thrones”.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59496</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59496</id>
          <name>Jan Mulkens</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Enabling Citizen Data Science with Microsoft</title>
      <description>In times past, Data Science was only for those elite few with a rare combination of skills including advanced knowledge of statistics.

Microsoft has been making sure that everyone can participate in the data revolution by giving people access to predictive API’s, in-database advanced analytics and drag-and-drop predictive experiments. All thanks to SQL Server 2016 and the Cortana Intelligence Suite in Azure.

These advances have given people with less knowledge of statistics and programming the ability to become what Gartner calls citizen data scientists.
Should we be worried about fools-with-tools or should we embrace the democratization of data science as the golden age of data?

Using a combination of theory and demo’s, we explore Microsoft’s solutions to ensure democratization of data science and the possible dangers that lurk below the surface.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61511</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61511</id>
          <name>Simon Whiteley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Datawarehouse: 0-100 DWUs</title>
      <description>So, with much fanfare and cheering, Azure DataWarehouse is now live, but what does that mean to you? Reflecting on a large-scale Azure DW project, this session gathers together learnings, successes, failures and general opinions into a crash course in using Azure DataWarehouse “properly”.

We'll start by quickly putting the technology in context, so you know WHEN to use it, WHERE it’s appropriate and WHY it works the way it does.

 - Introducing the ADW technology
 - Explaining distributions  performance
 - Explaining polybase

We will then dive into HOW to use it, looking at some real-life design patterns, best practice and some “tales from the trenches” from a recent large Azure DW project.

 - Performance tips  tricks (designing for minimal data movement, managing distribution skew, CTAS, Resource classes and more)
 - ETL Patterns (Surrogate keys  Orchestration)
 - Common Mistakes  Pitfalls
 - Conclusions  Recommendations</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56951</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56951</id>
          <name>Christopher Adkin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Problem Solving With The In-Memory Engine</title>
      <description>There is a vast array of material in the SQL Server community that covers the in-memory engine in great detail, this session will cover some of the internals of the in-memory engine, however what it will also do is fill in the void as to common performance issues and how they can be solved with the in-memory engine, specifically:

- Staging data as fast as possible
- Turbo charging scalar aggregate functions
- Implementing a scalable sequence
- Overcoming the performance limitations of temporary tables
- Making the critical path in your code base run faster</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61514</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61514</id>
          <name>Oliver Frost</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Exploring Dark Data with SQL Server 2016 and R</title>
      <description>With the addition of R into SQL Server 2016, Microsoft have provided a few extra degrees of freedom for the standard SQL developer. You can now use the R language to wrangle, clean and collect external data, using libraries and functionality that simply wasn’t available to you before with regular T-SQL. Performing data enrichment at scale with SQL Server or even Microsoft R Server can provide extremely valuable new insights for your clients and start reaping the benefits of big data.

In this session, Consolidata’s Oliver Frost shows you how to develop your own application for tapping into ‘dark data’. Ollie will demonstrate how to stream live tweets, perform aggregations in R and pipe the output to a Power BI dashboard, giving you a full end-to-end experience of the importance of learning some basic R code in 2016. 

This session is for anyone who is new to R and is interested in expanding their skill set beyond their comfort zone in SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61625</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61625</id>
          <name>Jonathon Eve-O'Connor</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS Common Design Patterns, Tips  Tricks</title>
      <description>SSIS is a fantastic tool and now well established as the go-to tool for performing on premise ETL and data movement within the Data Warehouse environment. Whether you're an experienced developer or starting your career as a data professional the fundamentals of a good ETL design are an essential building block of the data warehouse environment which cannot be overlooked. 

In this talk Jon provides an introduction to common design patterns used in SSIS to tackle typical ETL scenarios as well as providing insight and tips on how you can use SSIS to realise it's full potential.  

The talk will focus on the following patterns:

- How to orchestrate a successful ETL loading routine using SSIS
- Applying effective logging during loads
- Flat file loading
- Incremental loading patterns
- Dimension loading
- Fact table loading</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>62734</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>62734</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hacking SQL Server</title>
      <description>How easy is it to hack a SQL Server? 
In this session we'll see examples on how to exploit SQL Server, modify data and take control, while at the same time not leaving a trace.
We'll start by gaining access to a SQL Server (using some "creative" ways of making man-in-the-middle attacks), escalating privileges and tampering with data at the TDS protocol level (e.g. changing your income level and reverting without a trace after payment), hacking DDM, and more. 
Most importantly, we'll also cover recommendations on how to avoid these attacks, and take a look at the pros and cons of new security features in SQL Server 2016.
This is a demo-driven session, suited for DBAs, developers and security consultants.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63800</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63800</id>
          <name>Rozalina Zaharieva</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>I am a DBA! "What is the next"?</title>
      <description>In this session, we will discuss where to start when you get your job as a DBA. What are the first steps you need to do to discover and arrange the environment for which you are responsible. How to answer questions like: How many databases do you have on each server? How big are they? What they are used for and how many of them are critical? Do you need backups and do you have such, Etc. There are many questions you got from the day 1, but where to start is always the key to not get panicked. The goal of this session is to help you perform your first steps in a DBA job, especially when you get into a situation with only one Excel spreadsheet containing your servers’ list.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56694</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56694</id>
          <name>Alexander Arvidsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Database - the cloud awakens</title>
      <description>There has been an awakening. SQL Database in Azure is no longer merely useful tool, but essential for your continued innovation. This session outlines the  offerings available in SQL Database in Azure and how to move your database loads away from virtual machines and towards SQL Database, as well as gives a glimpse of the astounding force multipliers inherent in the Azure cloud. May the cloud be with you – always.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56776</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56776</id>
          <name>Gilberto Zampatti</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016: New and improved features in SQL Server Integration Services</title>
      <description>At last SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) introduces new capabilities so that you can add SSISDB to an AlwaysOn Availability Group; The Incremental Package Deployment feature allows you to deploy one or more packages to an existing or new project without deploying the whole project; Upgrading SSIS projects from previous to the current version, the project-level connection managers will continue to work as usual and the package layout/annotations are retained. In this session we will explore these new/improved features of SSIS to evaluate new benefits.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56997</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56997</id>
          <name>Kaloyan Kosev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Embrace the future: Running SQL Server in containers</title>
      <description>Well, the future is now. Join me in demo heavy session covering SQL server running in containers. Starting from scratch we will go through a complete container implementation.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64551</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64551</id>
          <name>Ezra Levi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Integrating schema-free data into the relational world</title>
      <description>Here, at SB-Tech we were able to combine both of the schema-free data into our main relation business production database. 
We do so by collaborating the technologies of all worlds together, using SQL Server, MongoDB and even MySQL all together. In this presentation I will share our topology and details on what we are doing in SB-Tech.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61506</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61506</id>
          <name>Terry McCann</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why TSQL was the language of the year!</title>
      <description>TSQL was voted best programming language in 2013, let’s explore why! In this session we will explore what make SQL such a fascinating language. We will do this by looking at a few real life problems and common design challenges.  What in particular will we look at? Well… Tally tables, CURSORS, hidden CURSORS, CTEs, Recursive CTE, Manual Pivot, TSQL Pivot, CROSS JOIN, CROSS APPLY, CORRELATED QUERIES, STUFF(), RANK(),GO, DENSE_RANK(),LAG(), LEAD(), ROW_NUMBER(), XML PATH, MOD %,  STRING_AGG(), DBCC DROPCLEANBUFFERS, DBCC FREEPROCCACHE, STATISTICS IO  TIME.  (A bit of TSQL)</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56772</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56772</id>
          <name>Miroslav Dimitrov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Myths and Misconceptions</title>
      <description>SQL Server is full of misunderstood features and misnomers that could affect how it is operating and respectively our applications. If you do not want to be surprised in a bad way by some intended, but not widely known SQL functionalities, join me in this session where we will, in an entertaining way, examine some of the most common behaviors that you probably have not expected.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63838</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63838</id>
          <name>Margarita Naumova</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>From the start to the end of a Performance battle (a story from real life)</title>
      <description>Performance problems are most often than not happen in SQL Server. Come to this session to hear real stories from the field and to see where to start when a problem occurs and how to achieve a great win in the SQL Server performance battle.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57183</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57183</id>
          <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Creating Custom BI Solutions with Power BI Embedded</title>
      <description>Microsoft Power BI Embedded is a Microsoft Azure that enables developers to integrate Power BI reports into their web or mobile applications so they don’t need to build custom solutions to visualize data for the users. 
Microsoft Power BI Embedded helps Independent Software Vendors to use Power BI data experiences within their applications. Customers, who use applications with Power BI Embedded don’t need to have a Power BI account or to know anything about this Azure service. 
This talk is a practical session on Microsoft Power BI Embedded concept with many examples how to create custom BI solutions using this technology.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63731</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63731</id>
          <name>Iva Velkova</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Collation: A small leak will sink a great ship</title>
      <description>The collation is one of the most misunderstood settings in SQL Server. But if you underestimate it, you could get into a lot of troubles.
Attend this session to understand what the collation is. How could the collation impact the performance of your queries, linked servers or cross database queries. 
What are the good practices and how to cope with different collations? What kind of issues can be caused by unequal collations, what to be taken into account?</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63788</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63788</id>
          <name>Eugene Polonichko</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Factory. Ingest,prepare, transform and publish your data</title>
      <description>Data Factory is a cloud-based data integration service that orchestrates and automates the movement and transformation of data. You can create data integration solutions using the Data Factory service that can ingest data from various data stores, transform/process the data, and publish result data to the data stores.   Cool.  What is it? It is cloudy ETL? Really? Why can't I used SSIS? What  is the difference between SSIS and Azure DataFactory?  So  come to my session and I can answer all question about Azure Data Factory.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66201</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66201</id>
          <name>Valio Bonev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL 2 Go</title>
      <description>Take your SQL server in a nicely packed container and scale at will. “Cloud” it up and enjoy the taste of freedom</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57029</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57029</id>
          <name>Andrey Nikolov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>CSI: Database</title>
      <description>An elite team of forensic experts investigates a series of crimes against a set of databases. Join the team to help them to uncover the mysteries. Follow the clues to find these ruthless criminals and save innocent databases from being murdered.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56774</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56774</id>
          <name>Gilberto Zampatti</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016: Improvements to In-Memory OLTP</title>
      <description>In-Memory OLTP has been significantly improved, so that this technology enable scaling to larger databases and higher throughput in order to support bigger workloads. Moreover, a number of limitations concerning tables and stored procedures have been removed to make it easier to migrate your applications to and leverage their benefits. In this session we will explore the new and enhanced features (like altering Memory-optimized Tables and Natively Compiled Stored Procedures, using Scalar UDF, supporting subqueries in Natively Complied Stored Procedures and more).</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 5:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 6:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>62399</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>62399</id>
          <name>Miroslav Lessev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Running MSSQL on Mac OS - Mission Possible</title>
      <description>Recently Microsoft has released SQL Server 2016 for Linux. It features another option option to run MSSQL on Mac OS using Docker.
Probably, you would never choose this option for your production environment but it is a good opportunity for all Mac fans to have a working database running on their MacBooks. 
In this session we will go through all options to run SQL Server on Mac OS and what development tools are available to connect and use your database.
The session will include a live demo, so you will be able to see step by step the installation process and how you can connect and use the database.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>62927</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>62927</id>
          <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Geocoding with SQL Server, Bing and Google Maps API</title>
      <description>Geocoding is the process of converting addresses into geographic coordinates (latitude and longitude). 
Geographic coordinates can then be converted into SQL Server spatial data type and stored in a database. 
In this session we will learn: 
- how to retrieve coordinates from an address, using Google Maps API and Bing API;
- how to get a free license from API services; 
- how to automate the process and convert coordinates into a geography data type using SQL Server Integration Services;
- how to store the data into a database;
- how to perform calculation on spatial data;
- how to represent data on a map using Reporting Services and Power BI.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57058</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57058</id>
          <name>Ivan Donev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Are your SQL Server indexes effective?</title>
      <description>Indexes are important! They can make your life easy, but they can be a huge performance killer. No matter your role - DBA or DEV, you need to design effective indexing strategy and most importantly - know if those indexes are really effective. SQL Server gives you number of possibilities to track the use of your indexes and suggest you new ones. But what else we need to be careful for? How to keep our SQL Server in proper index shape? Join me for this one-hour session where we will have real fun on indexes and I promise you, you will leave with plenty of ideas for improving your index environment!</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 11:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>58093</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>58093</id>
          <name>Sergiy Lunyakin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>Meta-Data Driven Tabular Modeling with TOM in SSAS</title>
      <description>Analysis Services 2016 uses JSON as a format to store the metadata of a model and you can change it with C# using TOM (Tabular Object Model). The new object model has a one-to-one mapping between physical entities in the database and objects in the model. This is very usefull if you need to add or change measures without redeploying the whole project to server.
For example, you need to generate set of new measures every year or end users want to add measures themselves and so on.  Using TOM and meta-data table you can automate this process and save tons of time. Join this session for learning how to implement this.</description>
      <startTime>5/27/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/27/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>