<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #664 - Katowice 2017</name>
    <startDate>9/16/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>350</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Belgrade, Bratislava, Budapest, Ljubljana, Prague</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatpoland</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Wyższa Szkoła Bankowa (WSB University)</name>
      <street>ul. Sportowa 29</street>
      <city>Chorzow</city>
      <state>Silesian Voivodeship, Poland</state>
      <zipcode>41-506 Chorzow</zipcode>
      <longitude>18.95639</longitude>
      <latitude>50.2795</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2017</importID>
      <name>Wyższa Szkoła Zarządzania i Bankowości w Krakowie</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.wszib.edu.pl</url>
      <imageURL>https://wszib.edu.pl/logo/logo-poziome.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1928</importID>
      <name>dbWatch</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://cilbuper.se/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14439.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2019</importID>
      <name>Wyższa Szkoła Bankowa w Chorzowie</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.wsb.pl/chorzow/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.wsb.pl/chorzow/sites/chorzow.nowestrony.sandbox.dti.teb-akademia.pl/files/wsb_chorzow_katowice_0.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68028</importID>
      <name>LEONEL ABREU</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>An IT Pro who likes to play chess and baseball. 

System Engineer degree since 2007, formerly Data Warehousing teacher at university levels from 2008 to 2009. Microsoft Student Partner during the years 2006 - 2007, Second Place in Microsoft Andean Imagine Cup (2006), MCTS, MCITP and MCP with over a decade of experience with SQL Server, working in BI, DBA, Database Development, .net Development, SharePoint and other several areas. 

Since 2014 based in Barcelona, Spain. Learning enthusiast and always with passion for new technologies and new challenges.</description>
      <twitter>leonel_abreu</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/abreulj/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=leonel_abreu</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65003</importID>
      <name>Sergiy Lunyakin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sergiy Lunyakin (MCSA, MCSE, MCTS) is a Big Data Architect at SoftServe, Inc.
He has extensive experience in designing and developing Big Data Analytics, Data Warehouse, and BI solutions, using both on-premises and cloud products. In 2016, Sergiy became Microsoft Data Platform MVP and has since maintained his MVP status. Sharing knowledge is another one of his passions. He regularly speaks at international conferences such as SQLSaturday, SQLDay, SQLNexus, and SQLBits. He also runs the Lviv SQL Server User Group in Ukraine and organizes SQLSaturday Lviv.</description>
      <twitter>slunyakin</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/slunyakin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://slunyakin.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=slunyakin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67377</importID>
      <name>Hubert Kobierzewski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hubert works at Codec-dss as BI Practice Lead. He helps customers to gather their data and convert it into valuable information using Microsoft Data Platform technologies. Hubert is also a board member of Data Community Poland and a leader of Warsaw Power BI User Group.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kobierzewski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68037</importID>
      <name>Grzegorz Stolecki</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Business Intelligence expert with 20+ years of experience. Grzegorz worked as architect, developer and trainer. Currently he focuses on developing specialized analytical and reporting solutions using machine learning models for large and mid-size enterprises. He also works on financial planning, consolidation and budgeting applications. Grzegorz is one of the leaders of Polish Data Community (former Polish SQL Server User Group PLSSUG). You can meet him very often at community meetings, conferences and other events. He is an active speaker and ATE member. Microsoft MVP in Data Platform Area since 2010.</description>
      <twitter>gstolecki</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/grzegorzstolecki</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=gstolecki</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66949</importID>
      <name>Stephanie Locke</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steph Locke leads a life of data, coffee, books and board games. During the day, Steph runs her own consultancy helping people start doing data science. Steph enjoys being her own gal as it means she gets to spend plenty of time building communities to provide platforms for people to help each other be better with data.</description>
      <twitter>@stefflocke</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/stephanielocke</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://itsalocke.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@stefflocke</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67384</importID>
      <name>Tomasz Libera</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>MVP Data Platform, MCT, leader of Krakow Data Community Poland user group. Organizer of SQLDay  and SQL Saturday conferences. SQL Server Developer and academic trainer. Speaker at group meetings and conferences.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/tomasz_libera</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/tomaszlibera</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/tomasz_libera</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68073</importID>
      <name>Marek Maśko</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marek works as a Principal Database Analyst at Sabre Polska where he is developing a database solution for flight planning system. He supports teams of developers, testers, delivery, and technical support staff in this large international project. Fan of query optimization and exploration of knowledge about SQL Server Internals. He professionally works on databases and in particular with SQL Server since 2010. Earlier, a Java and C# coder. An active member of the Krakow chapter of the Polish Data Community. Marek is MCSE: Data Platform and MCSE: Data Management and Analytics.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/marekmasko</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marekmasko/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.sqlterritory.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/marekmasko</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66351</importID>
      <name>Pawel Potasinski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>CTO at Elitmind. Focused on determining the company's technological directions and transforming Clients into successful data driven organizations. Former Microsoft employee (Data Insights Product Manager for Poland). In 2007 Pawel started Polish SQL Server User Group (PLSSUG), currently known as Data Community Poland, an official PASS Chapter in Poland. Pawel has been a speaker at many conferences in Poland and worldwide (e.g. SQLDay, SQLSaturday, European PASS Conference). He has been awarded with Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) sixtimes in his career. Father of three. Avid runner.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/PawelPotasinski</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pawelpotasinski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.sqlgeek.pl</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/PawelPotasinski</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69464</importID>
      <name>Andrzej Kukula</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Consultant and trainer in SQLExpert.pl with more than 20 years of IT experience. Architect of HA/DR solutions, BI solutions, Data Platform solutions, cloud solutions. Solves SQL Server related problems, including performance tuning. Passionate about SQL Server and programming. Speaker at various conferences including SQLSaturday, SQLDay, SQLNexus, AzureDay, Global Azure Bootcamp and local user groups.</description>
      <twitter>@andrzejkukula</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrzejkukula</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@andrzejkukula</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65508</importID>
      <name>Grzegorz Łyp</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server Database Engine tuning enthusiast. Product Manager and Team Leader at Asseco Business Solutions. Developing SQL Database Engine enterprise scale solutions for 10 years.</description>
      <twitter>@GrzegorzLyp</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/grzegorzlyp/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.lyp.pl/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@GrzegorzLyp</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67998</importID>
      <name>Agnieszka Cieplak</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Database administrator, Data Community Poland - Lublin chapter leader.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/AgCieplak</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/agnieszka-cieplak-27a9043</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/AgCieplak</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67249</importID>
      <name>Mikael Wedham</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mikael Wedham is the first SQL Server MCM in Sweden and the only one who also is a Microsoft Certified Trainer. He has been paid to do things in SQL Server since 1993. His long experience makes him an appreciated speaker at events and conferences all over Europe. To be prepared for deep dives, he is also certified as an Open Water Scuba Instructor.</description>
      <twitter>@wedham</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.wedham.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@wedham</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67953</importID>
      <name>Damian Widera</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server MVP amp; MCT
Software engineer with 18+ years of professional experience in all aspects of software development.
Damian participated in a number of projects in international environments and possesses practical knowledge of procedures and tools which are necessary for successful implementation of such projects.
Now he focuses on building solutions based on Microsoft SQL Server environment (including complex database driven systems, database tuning and optimization).</description>
      <twitter>@DamianWidera</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/damian-widera-0b56284</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://codingfamily.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DamianWidera</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66624</importID>
      <name>David Postlethwaite</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Postlethwaite has been a DBA for Liverpool Victoria in Bournemouth, England since 2008
He supports both Oracle and SQL Server from 2000 to 2017, DBMS, SSIS, SSAS and Reporting Services.
In 2015 David built and deployed the company's first cloud solution using Microsoft Azure SQL Database and web services 

Before becoming a DBA David was a .NET developer and way back in history a Windows and Netware administrator. 

He is an occasional blogger on www.gethynellis.com

David is a regular speaker for SQL Saturday.
Most of his presentations can be found on his YouTube channel www.youtube.com/c/DavidPostlethwaiteSQL</description>
      <twitter>@postledm</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidpostlethwaite</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gethynellis.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@postledm</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65599</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66614</importID>
      <name>Denis Reznik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denis Reznik is a Data Architect at Intapp, Inc. He has more than ten years experience in software development, database design, and performance tuning for cloud and on-premises solutions. In 2010 Denis became Microsoft Data Platform MVP and maintains MVP status today. Apart from his professional career, Denis actively participates in the development of the Ukrainian Data Community.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DenisReznik</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/denis-reznik/3/502/234</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://reznik.uneta.com.ua</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DenisReznik</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>65599</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65599</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Aula A</name>
      </location>
      <title>2,4,8  16 - Upgrade your journey with SQL Server</title>
      <description>2,4,8  16 - these aren't just numbers to count or calculate. These are years that how SQL Server evolved as number of years!

Why Upgrade? 
Data Platform Upgrade topic has been a popular session that I've presented in major conferences like Microsoft Tech-Ed (North America, Europe  India) and SQLbits since 2008. 

In this session, we will overview in depth end-to-end upgrade process that covers the essential phases, steps and issues involved in upgrading  SQL Server (2000 to  2012),  SQL Server 2014 (with a good overview on 2016 too) by using best practices and available resources. 

What to-do and what not-to-do?

A popular session that I have been presenting since the year 2008, in MS Tech-Ed, SQL Saturday  SQLbits UK.
We will cover the complete upgrade cycle, including the preparation tasks, upgrade tasks, and post-upgrade tasks. Real-world examples from my Consulting experience expanding on why  how such a solution.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66614</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66614</id>
          <name>Denis Reznik</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Aula A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Performance Tuning Nowadays</title>
      <description>Nothing is perfect, which means that your database may be not perfect as well. And one day you may decide that your database is slow and it's time to optimize it. But.. Where to start? When to end? What to look at? Which queries are slow? How to identify the real bottleneck? And so on, and so on. There are a lot of questions that should be answered in a process of performance tuning. 

In this session, we will find answers to all these questions going from collecting data for analysis, through identifying bottlenecks to optimization of the particular queries. On this way, we will learn performance tuning practical techniques and solve a bunch of issues in real-time. And despite I'm a big fan of Profiler and old-fashioned tools and technics, new, more interesting and useful instruments are available nowadays, so will use them to find the bottleneck and tune performance. Minimum of theory and a lot of practice.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67249</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67249</id>
          <name>Mikael Wedham</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Aula A</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Masters view on Locking and blocking</title>
      <description>How do the wait stats show you that you have a locking issue?
This session will show you how to detect and view blocking and lock waits, and understand the cause of it.
An extensive walkthrough of the different isolation levels and their respective benefits and drawbacks.
And finally a real-world quick list of suggestions on what you can do to solve some of the common issues I come across in my daily work.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66351</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66351</id>
          <name>Pawel Potasinski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Aula B</name>
      </location>
      <title>R'em All. Use R in Power BI to Deal with Data</title>
      <description>R becomes a commodity in Microsoft Data Platform, including Power BI as one of this platform's elements. By learning R data analysts and BI developers can significantly expand capabilities of Power BI, and perform much more sophisticated analysis. R can be used for getting data, for data transformations, for analysis with additional power of statistics and predictive algorithms, and finally for nontrivial visualizations. The purpose of this session is to showcase some step by step examples of how R code can be an integrated part of Power BI reports, as well as provide several scenarios in which R brings more power into Power BI.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66949</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66949</id>
          <name>Stephanie Locke</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Aula A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Build your first bot – no code required!</title>
      <description>Learn how to build a bot that will answer questions asked by users. Learn how to customise it and embed it on your website. Learn how to do all of this without having to write a single line of code.

I’ll be using Microsoft’s qnamaker.io site to build an FAQ bot and the putting it live with an Azure Bot Service and the Skype Web Control. The end result is a little snippet you can add to any web page, making implementation a breeze.

You can follow along as I build the bot live, or just soak it all in. Either way, you’ll see how easy it is to build a bot and you’ll know the next steps to follow to start building more complex bots.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67384</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67384</id>
          <name>Tomasz Libera</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Aula B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Reporting Services  Power BI Server</title>
      <description>Microsoft finally released Power BI Server - on-premise platform for Power BI solutions. 
During the session I’m going to explain licensing model and show how to use it. Finally, I’ll compare Power BI cloud service and on-premise capabilities.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65508</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65508</id>
          <name>Grzegorz Łyp</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Sala 6</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tuning large queries</title>
      <description>Tuning large queries is going to show techniques and tools that allow to find optimizing solution when query plan is large. Multiple joins, function calls, many views and inline functions is what I call complex plan. In this short session I will try to tune large queries with multiple techniques.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67377</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67377</id>
          <name>Hubert Kobierzewski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Aula B</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS – Transform Your Data in Parallel</title>
      <description>There are few DWH environments out there which struggle with their data loading window and whole night is not enough for them to push all fresh data to those hungry star schemas. Since SQL Server 2016 we may speed up things by enabling new way of dealing with data processing – SSIS Scale Out. This full-of-demos session will show you how to set up workers, establish communication, split your workload among them in attempt to shorten execution times and where to find additional log files. This session will show you if parallel processing is the future of ETL in Microsoft world of data.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>