<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #875 - Sydney 2019</name>
    <startDate>8/3/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>180</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+10:00) Brisbane</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatSydney</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Sydney Reactor</name>
      <street>Level 10, Sydney Startup Hub  11-31 York St</street>
      <city>Sydney</city>
      <state>New South Wales, Australia</state>
      <zipcode>2159</zipcode>
      <longitude>151.205526874274</longitude>
      <latitude>-33.8653642656913</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/875/EventSponsor_13969.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2532</importID>
      <name>FTS Data  AI</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://data.ftsg.com.au</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/875/EventSponsor_13951.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>98</importID>
      <name>Angry Koala</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://angrykoala.com.au</url>
      <imageURL>http://angrykoala.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/ak_logo_250.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1272</importID>
      <name>WARDY IT Solutions</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.wardyit.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/986/EventSponsor_14725.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2002</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.red-gate.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/875/EventSponsor_14011.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/875/EventSponsor_13590.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94383</importID>
      <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Koesmarno, MCSE Data Platform, and MCSE Business Intelligence, MCT, is a Senior Program Manager at Microsoft, with a Bachelor’s degree in IT. She has over 10 years of experience working with SQL Server for large-scale and multi-million-dollar OLTP and ETL projects as a SQL Server developer and system analyst/designer. Her past projects include delivering a SQL Server 2012 data warehouse and BI solutions in the US and Australia. She now works with hybrid, cloud and on-prem SQL projects.</description>
      <twitter>@mssqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliekoesmarno</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mssqlgirl.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mssqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91474</importID>
      <name>Shehab El-Najjar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Shehab El-Najjar was the ONLY Microsoft SQL Server MVP in Gulf for the past 6 years and the 2nd one all over the Middle East  , he is the founder of SQL Gulf events series (SQL Gulf #1 , #2 and #3 ) where he spent so much time and efforts  to broadcast Microsoft SQL Server technologies all over the Gulf such as  KSA and Emirates and other Gulf cities ahead ..) 

	He is now Professional Services Manager at Saudi  Emircom 

	He was previously COO and business leader in KSA market through his startup WAJA IT for  3 years

	He is an influencing Database community leader all over the region  	
	A senior Database Consultant (SQL Server MVP for 6 years in row) -The 2nd MVP awardee SQL Server all over Middle East and Arabic region</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/MSQLPerformance</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=126446983amp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlserver-performance-tuning.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/MSQLPerformance</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93346</importID>
      <name>Manohar Punna</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Manohar Punna is an Data Platform Geek and Vice President of DataPlatformGeeks by passion and a Data Platform Consultant by profession. He is a speaker at various conferences like PASS Summit, SQLBits, DPS. He has authored over 150 blogs and has written a One DMV a Day series which is a longest one day series on any topic on SQL Server till date.
Manohar is a product of this community and strongly believes in giving back to the community. So, ask him anything you would like to know and he is happy to learn it with you.</description>
      <twitter>ManuSQLGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/manohar-punna/15/153/508</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservergeeks.com/author/manoharpunna/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ManuSQLGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93866</importID>
      <name>Rolf Tesmer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rolf has 20+ years IT experience and has been working with the SQL platform since v6.0 (that’s 1994!) and has done just about everything you can around SQL related data and data platforms / architectures ever since then.  I have a personal interest in All Things Cloud and Data (Azure, Streaming Data / IoT, Data Warehousing, Machine Learning, Visualisation and SQL Spatial).  I have had the opportunity to present at PASS, TechEd, PASS SQL Saturday, PASS Virtual Chapter, SQL User Groups, Big Data Seminars, Microsoft Technology Roadshows, Breakfast Seminars, ++ and enjoy sharing and learning new ideas.</description>
      <twitter>@TesmerR</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rolftesmer</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mrfoxsql.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TesmerR</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91796</importID>
      <name>Mohamed Kabiruddin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mohamed is a Cloud Solutions Architect with extensive experience in designing BI / Data Analytics solutions with expertise in analysis, design, modelling and implementation. He is a keen data enthusiast with a flair for managing and consolidating data.</description>
      <twitter>mdkabir</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/pub/mohamed-kabiruddin/32/639/8b8/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.nobrainerlab.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mdkabir</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92001</importID>
      <name>Anupama Natarajan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Anu Natarajan is a Data and AI Consultant with 15+ years of experience working in design and development of Data Warehouse, Business Intelligence, AI enabled applications, and SaaS integrated solutions. Anu is a Microsoft MVP Data Platform, Microsoft Certified Trainer and passionate in sharing knowledge. She loves solving complex business problems with innovative solutions using technologies. 
Anu also speaks at conferences including PASS Summit, SQL Saturdays, Data Platform Summit, Difinity, and she organizes local user group meetups.</description>
      <twitter>@shantha05</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/in/anupama-natarajan-516a107</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.anupamanatarajan.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@shantha05</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92560</importID>
      <name>Craig Bryden</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Craig has been working with SQL Server for over 20 years and currently holds several SQL Server based certifications. He has also previously held an MCT certification. Craig's contribution to the SQL Server community was recognised in 2018 with a Microsoft MVP award. He was involved with Microsoft Learning to set some of the current SQL server Exams. Craig is the Chief Data Strategist at BiTQ. Craig is an organiser of the QLD Power BI User Group</description>
      <twitter>@cbryden</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/craigbryden/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cbryden</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94909</importID>
      <name>Grant Paisley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Grant Paisley is an Microsoft  MVP and founder of Angry Koala, http://angrykoala.com.au a Microsoft Business Intelligence consultancy based in Sydney, Australia. Grant runs the Microsoft Data Wranglers usergroup https://www.meetup.com/microsoft-data-wranglers/ and is an internationally recognized speaker haven spoken at Teched USA, Australia and  China on Machine Learning, Reporting Services and Power BI.  Data visualization is his specialty. He also co-authored "SQL Server 2008 Analysis Services with MDX", "Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services Recipes", and "Professional Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services".  Hobbies include snow kiting and mountain biking.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90222</importID>
      <name>Rob Douglas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robs SQL history started as a remote DBA, branched into consultancy and now includes providing SQL Solutions to a variety of businesses, government departments and banks throughout Australia and New Zealand using a variety of native SQL solutions to meet their performance, higher availability and Disaster Recovery needs.</description>
      <twitter>Rob_DouglasNZ</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=AAMAAAoSId0BNgwoSf_o5y24oIW3PjEHbAmdY-camp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gumption.co.nz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rob_DouglasNZ</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92435</importID>
      <name>Victor Isakov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Victor Isakov (MCA, MCM, MCSM, MCT, MVP) is a Database Architect and trainer who provides consulting and training services to various organizations in the public, private, and NGO sectors globally. He regularly speaks at international conferences such as Microsoft TechEd/Ignite, PASS Summit, IT/Dev Connections, and SQLSaturdays.
Victor has written a number of books on SQL Server and has worked with Microsoft to develop the SQL Server exams and certification. In 2017 he authored "Exam Ref 70-764 Administering a SQL Database Infrastructure (1st Edition)".
He is one of only three non-Microsoft, Microsoft Certified Architects in the world.</description>
      <twitter>@victorisakov</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/victorisakov</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.victorisakov.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@victorisakov</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94658</importID>
      <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Flynn is a Senior Database Administrator with 10 years experience in large 24 x 7 enterprise environments. He is a certified master for SQL Server and a regular attendee of the PASS Summit.

Has presented at SQLSaturday events in Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane and Auckland, Edmonton and Calgary, Oslo and Cambridge</description>
      <twitter>sqllensman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqllensman.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllensman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94879</importID>
      <name>Stefano Tempesta</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stefano Tempesta is CTO at Connecting Software, Microsoft Regional Director and MVP, and advisor to the Department of Industry, Australia, on the National Blockchain Roadmap. His current focus is on helping people around the world gain and own their digital identity, with specific attention to the Education sector.
Stefano is also technology advisor at Carbon Asset Solutions, a climate action and sustainability network with a mission to slow carbon dioxide emissions and remove excess atmospheric CO2 by using regenerative agriculture technologies.</description>
      <twitter>stefanotempesta</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://linkedin.com/in/stefanotempesta</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.tempesta.space</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=stefanotempesta</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90868</importID>
      <name>Gilbert Quevauvilliers</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Power BI  Data Analytics Consultant with over 12 years experience.

From small to enterprise implementations on Azure (Azure Analysis Services, Function Apps, Runbooks, Automation Accounts, SQL Serverless DB) and On-Premise Microsoft Platform (SQL Server, Integration Services, Analysis Services Multidimensional and Tabular, Reporting Services)

Recently I have focused on Power BI, with its rapidly changing features and incredible uptake it has allowed me to consult in a variety of different and challenging solutions.

I was awarded the Microsoft MVP award for Power BI since 2017.

I have spoken at the Microsoft Business Applications Summit (Seattle  Atlanta), Power BI World Tour,SQL Saturdays  other events.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/gilbertque</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/fourmoo/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.fourmoo.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/gilbertque</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92874</importID>
      <name>Pio Balistoy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pio Balistoy is a Microsoft MVP  Certified Trainer for Data Platform. A SQL Server professional with more than 17 years of experience with SQL Server operations, architecture and administration. He brings his passion for SQL Server as the community leader for Singapore SQL PASS and Philippine SQL Server User Group. He is currently one of the Lead Microsoft Data Platform Consultant for The Pythian Services - a global IT product and services company with headquarters in Ottawa, New York, Sydney, UK and India.  He also co-founded Excent One Inc, a technology solutions company based in the Philippines and Singapore that helps SMEs integrate and develop Microsoft based business Applications.</description>
      <twitter>Pioisms</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/piobalistoy/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://lazysqlwriter.wordpress.com/; https://blog.pythian.com/author/balistoy/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Pioisms</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93151</importID>
      <name>Bernard Spence</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a Senior Business Intelligence Consultant with 21 years experience with SQL Server. I work at Readify where I help clients improve the performance of their SQL Server instances, SSAS solutions, and SSIS packages</description>
      <twitter>TweetItReal</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TweetItReal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95834</importID>
      <name>Ajit Ananthram</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a senior strategy advisor specialising in digital transformation through data engineering and advanced analytics. I have over 14 years of experience assisting organisations in becoming data-led and data-driven. I specialise in leveraging Microsoft Azure and its capabilities in data platform engineering, machine learning, AI and data visualisation to solve business problems. I am also active in the Microsoft community through presentations at events and technical publications.</description>
      <twitter>ajitananthram</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ajit-ananthram/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://ajitananthram.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ajitananthram</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93242</importID>
      <name>Martin Cairney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin has 20 years’ experience in SQL Server technologies. His experience spans both the Database Engine and infrastructure requirements, and Data Warehousing and BI implementations. 
He has worked across many industry sectors including London’s global financial institutions and both State and Federal Government Departments. 
He is a SQL Server MVP, MCT and an experienced conference presenter, having presented at PASS Summit, SQLBits, and SQL Saturday events and User Groups round the world</description>
      <twitter>martin_cairney</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/in/martincairney</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=martin_cairney</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93760</importID>
      <name>Geoff Black</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Geoff is the Training Team Leader at WARDYIT Solutions. With more than 30 years experience in the world of IT, Geoff has been witness to some major changes in technology throughout out his various roles as a Microsoft Certified Trainer, Database Developer, Consultant and Business Intelligence Specialist. High performance and power has always been the driving force behind both his professional and personal interests as an avid fan of the MotoGP and a keen motorcyclist.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://wardyit.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92724</importID>
      <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warwick Rudd is a Data Platform MVP, Microsoft Certified Master, Founder and Principal Consultant at SQL Master Consulting. With 20+ years of experience beginning with the release of SQL Server 6.5, he has worked in both Australia and England from small start-ups to Multi-National Corporations. He hosts the PASS DBA Fundamentals Downunder Virtual Chapter, Organises the PASS SQL Saturday Brisbane event and has spoken at many SQL Server User Groups  SQL Saturday events globally. When not playing with the SQL stack, Warwick likes to get away to the cold and spend time snowboarding.</description>
      <twitter>warwick_Rudd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/pub/warwick-rudd/0/956/718</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmastersconsulting.com.au/Blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=warwick_Rudd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92402</importID>
      <name>Martin Catherall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin is a data consultant in Melbourne, Australia, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, and PASS Regional Mentor for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region.
Martin founded the Christchurch, New Zealand PASS Local Group and lead the group for a number of years before relocating to Melbourne.
He has been using SQL Server in various roles since 2000. In addition to anything data related, he enjoys playing the guitar and having fun with his family.</description>
      <twitter>MartyCatherall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/martincatherall</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://martincatherall.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MartyCatherall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90683</importID>
      <name>Greg Low</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Greg Low is well-known in the SQL Server community as a mentor, trainer, author, and community leader. He is a certified master for SQL Server, was an instructor in that program, and holds a PhD in Computer Science. Microsoft often calls on Greg to develop data-related content, and to train their staff. He regularly speaks at tier-one conferences internationally. Greg is best known for his SQL Down Under podcast, SDU Tools, and his eBooks and whitepapers. He heads up a boutique consultancy called SQL Down Under in Melbourne Australia. Greg has been awarded as an MVP since 2001.</description>
      <twitter>greglow</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/greglow</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.greglow.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=greglow</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>91474</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91474</id>
          <name>Shehab El-Najjar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>FTS Data  AI</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL Performance Guidelines for the optimal DB stress powers</title>
      <description>To reach your desired business functionalities, it can be easy using some common T-SQL practices like MTVF , scalar functions , Temp tables, Union…etc and they might perform pretty well on development server coz neither adequate stress of users nor adequate volume of data exist there but actually they seem totally strange once going to live where they become performing badly ending up eventually with and sharp skew of performance and standstill cases sometimes , this is due to the lack of stress powers of T-SQL codes which should be considered largely for critical mission DBs in particular more therefore I am going to talk to you about How to capture expensive queries using different techniques ..?and How to optimize them in the shortest time using scientific ways ..? (10 different T-SQL Practices will be explained within this session)</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 9:05:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 10:05:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92001</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92001</id>
          <name>Anupama Natarajan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wardy</name>
      </location>
      <title>Build your first notebook using Azure Notebooks</title>
      <description>Sharing and documenting Machine Learning solutions is now easier with Azure Notebooks. Azure Notebooks will allow Data Scientists to share the whole machine learning process from data acquisition, to data cleaning, and finally creating a machine learning model.
With Azure Notebooks the information can also be presented to non-technical stakeholders in an easier way. In this session you will learn 
•	What are Azure Notebooks?
•	How to create your first notebook in Azure Notebooks?
•	How to use code snippets and visualisations in a notebook?
•	Create a slideshow of your notebook
•	How to share your notebook with your team?
By the end of the session you will get a good understanding about Azure Notebooks and how to use them for real world problems.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90868</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90868</id>
          <name>Gilbert Quevauvilliers</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Infographic related on the Power BI Eco System</title>
      <description>What actually makes up the Power BI Eco System?
		
		Have you ever wondered what are all the parts that make up the Power BI Eco System and their features?
		
		In this session I will cover the area's which make up the Power BI Eco system. This will include Power BI Desktop, Power BI Service (Free, Pro  Premium), Power BI Gateway, Power BI Report Server  Power BI Mobile App.
		
		The goal of this session will be to give you a better understanding of all the working parts. And once you have a better understanding it will allow you to have the knowledge to know what to do where.
		
		It will be an insightful journey into how much is actually going on within the world of Power BI in an easy to understand and digest manner.
		
The most popular blog posts are ones where it is easier concepts and details on how Power BI works.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 10:25:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 11:25:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93760</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93760</id>
          <name>Geoff Black</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>FTS Data  AI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Analysis Services</title>
      <description>They say every cloud has a silver lining, well this one is gold! This demo heavy session will introduce you to Azure Analysis Services. We begin by looking at a traditional analytics platform, and how this fits into the "modern data warehouse". This session will guide you through the processes (and pitfalls) of modernizing your data analytics solution. Still using PowerPivot models or for that matter still using SQL Server Analysis Services on-premise? Let's see how to leverage these assets into the modern would of cloud computing using Azure Analysis Services, with minimal downtime. Prepare to be amazed at what is possible with all the wonders of cloud computing in the Azure world.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 10:25:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 11:25:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94658</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94658</id>
          <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>FTS Data  AI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Get Comfortable with Query tuning and Execution Plans</title>
      <description>Even as many of the traditional DBA activities become automated or managed by Cloud providers, the ability to tune and optimize database query performance remains a desirable and marketable skill.

Central to ability to tune queries is an ability to use information provided from Execution plans, DMVs, Query Store and Extended Events.

In this demo based session we will look into:
- What information is available 
- How it can be used.
- Techniques to improve performance. 

Attendees will leave with an understanding of possibilities of turning queries and a roadmap for further learning.

This session will assume a basic knowledge of T-SQL and execution plans.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95834</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95834</id>
          <name>Ajit Ananthram</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>FTS Data  AI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automate your Machine Learning</title>
      <description>A typical machine learning experiment involves the following phases - data preparation, algorithm selection, model training, model testing and hyperparameter tuning. The process is usually repeated for a range of machine learning algorithms and then the most optimum model is selected for scoring. This model needs to be exposed to client applications – in SQL Server the model can stored in a table and then wrapped in a stored procedure, while models built using machine learning libraries such as scikit-learn can be exposed through REST APIs.

The machine learning lifecycle is iterative and often time-consuming. What if there was a way to automate some of the processes involved so that the outcome could be generated sooner? In this session, you will see Automated Machine Learning in Microsoft Azure in action. You’ll get to learn key concepts and takeaway enough knowledge to be able to run simple machine learning experiments.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 11:35:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 12:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91796</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91796</id>
          <name>Mohamed Kabiruddin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>FTS Data  AI</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Wrangling for ETL enthusiasts</title>
      <description>Data wrangling is a significant problem when working with big data, especially if you haven’t been exposed to the challenges it brings, or you don’t have the right tools to clean and validate data in an effective and efficient way. In this session, we'll explore data wrangling concepts and Azure data services to achieve the desired data transformations. If you are an ETL enthusiast or love SSIS, this session will take you through data ingestion-transformation techniques and tools available to build your modern data platform on Azure. We'll dive deep into using Azure Data Factory (dataflows) and Azure Databricks to transform data to meet your enterprise business needs.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 1:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 2:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94879</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94879</id>
          <name>Stefano Tempesta</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wardy</name>
      </location>
      <title>Secure multiparty Machine Learning with SQL Server Always Encrypted with Secure Enclaves</title>
      <description>Preserving privacy when processing data from multiple sources with machine learning is always a 
challenge. Organizations want to perform collaborative data analytics while guaranteeing the privacy of their individual datasets. Combining multiple data sources to support a better outcome improves accuracy of prediction, but it may come at cost of confidentiality, if sensitive information is not accurately protected.
SQL Server 2019 adds new data security capabilities with Always Encrypted with Secure Enclaves. By using trusted execution environments (TEEs) to protect your data while in use, you can use machine learning algorithms across different organizations to better train models, without revealing the processed data.
In this session, Stefano Tempesta, Microsoft Regional Director and MVP on AI and Business Application, will present the benefits of Confidential Computing in an ML scenario, where separate health institutes collaborate on data analysis and prediction using Azure ML.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 10:25:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 11:25:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92435</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92435</id>
          <name>Victor Isakov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Roadmap for SQL Server</title>
      <description>With support for Linux and Containers SQL Server 2017 opened up a new world of possibilities for Microsoft. SQL Server 2019 will bring to market a new modern data platform including support for Linux, Docker Containers and rich features in intelligent performance, HADR, machine learning, and graph database. Come learn about the roadmap and new functionality planned for SQL Server including intelligent query processing, data virtualization, new features for mission critical security and HADR, and new scenarios for Linux and Docker Containers. Understand where Microsoft is taking its Data Platform and align your organization's SQL Server with Microsoft's roadmap.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93151</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93151</id>
          <name>Bernard Spence</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wardy</name>
      </location>
      <title>Never get lost again with SQL Server spatial technology</title>
      <description>If you find yourself getting lost then SQL Server’s spatial technology is here to help. At first glance, the spatial functions and data types can be quite confusing and weird. This presentation will demystify SQL Server’s spatial features so that you can use them confidently in your job. I will step through the theory and show a number of examples and best practices.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 1:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 2:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94909</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94909</id>
          <name>Grant Paisley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>Top 10 Tech Tips for Power BI</title>
      <description>Here are a super secret set of must have tips for making the best of Power BI. 
(it includes crazy twisting)</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92724</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92724</id>
          <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Studio – The New Frontier</title>
      <description>Azure Data Studio is no longer the new kid on the block. How many of you have used Azure Data Studio? 
              In this session we will take you on a journey introducing you to Azure Data Studio so that you can understand the ins and outs and when you should consider using Azure Data Studio in place of SQL Server Management Studio. In this idemo heavy session we will look at how productive you can be with Azure Data studio and some of the features that are not available in SQL Server Management Studio.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 1:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 2:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93346</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93346</id>
          <name>Manohar Punna</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>Gems of Power BI</title>
      <description>Power BI is with no doubt the market leader in building BI systems in the recent years with highest growth trends in adoption. It suits both small  medium businesses and enterprise organisations. With a vast spectrum of choices of using Power BI some of the rare gems which makes every BI professional and end user life easier being unknown. In this session you get to choose which important features/tips you want to uncover from a wide list of choices. They range from new features to most useful features you may not have known before. I will demonstrate those features of your choice in the available time during this session.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 11:35:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 12:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92874</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92874</id>
          <name>Pio Balistoy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>FTS Data  AI</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Deployment Options and When to Use Them (Full Instance vs Managed Instance vs PAAS)</title>
      <description>With the advent of cloud we now have multiple deployment options for SQL Server. Be it a Full instance on premise or in the cloud, to a managed instance or a Platform as a service in the form of Azure SQL Database - each deployment options have their own use case. In this session, we will explore SQL Server's deployment options to help you decide which path is applicable to which scenarios.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 9:05:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 10:05:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93242</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93242</id>
          <name>Martin Cairney</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Upgrades and Migrations - The Right Way</title>
      <description>There has been lots of focus recently on upgrades and migrations with the end-of-life of SQL Server 2008 and 2008R2.

With so many critical databases running on these older versions, how do you ensure that you achieve a successful and safe transition to your new platform? Fortunately there are some fantastic tools and defined processes that can lead you through each stage. 

There are tools to test different versions and infrastructures, processes to track query regressions and provide a way to remediate them.

This session will walk through the upgrade process from end-to-end and show what tools can help you at each step.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 10:25:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 11:25:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92402</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92402</id>
          <name>Martin Catherall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wardy</name>
      </location>
      <title>Looking at the Cosmos(DB)</title>
      <description>Azure Cosmos DB is Microsoft’s Globally Distributed, Multi-Model database service.  Transparently scaling across multiple Azure regions, Cosmos DB provides for many API’s including MongoDB, Cassandra, Gremlin and SQL. It offers multiple consistency models and guarantees uptime or 5 9’s.

In this session we’ll take a look at this technology and learn how it might be useful – either now or in the future.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 9:05:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 10:05:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94383</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94383</id>
          <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wardy</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Database Edge - Tiny but mighty</title>
      <description>Have you ever thought what would it be like to run SQL Server engine in a small footprint? Well, wait no more. 
Running on Arm and x64 architecture with a reduced footprint, the proven performant and most secure Microsoft SQL engine is coming to the Edge in interactive devices and edge gateways. Combining new capabilities on data streaming and time-series, with in-database machine learning (ML) and graph, Azure SQL Database Edge is optimized for low-latency analytics right on the Edge. This session will showcase the scenarios Azure SQL Database Edge can enable.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 11:35:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 12:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90222</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90222</id>
          <name>Rob Douglas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>PASS</name>
      </location>
      <title>Demystifying Encryption</title>
      <description>With the release of the GDPR regulations and similar global standards security is finally becoming the focus it always should have been.  Businesses are now able to put a number on how much a data breach will cost them...and that number is big enough to put many firms out of business.  
  In this session we'll talk about the various ways you can implement Encryptian natively within SQL Server - with Backup Encryption, Transparent Data Encryption(TDE), AlwaysEncrypted, and connection encryption</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 9:05:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 10:05:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93866</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93866</id>
          <name>Rolf Tesmer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>Liberate Your Data with Visualisation  Conversation!</title>
      <description>Modern enterprises today collect more data than cumulatively any other time in history.  This creates both complex challenges yet offers unique opportunities.  How can you aggregate and make sense of this data?  How can you engage with and present relevant data to business without being overwhelming?  In this session we’ll explore data storytelling, and demonstrate some fun and interesting ways to work with data in the Azure Cloud using Power BI, Bots and Cognitive Services that helps expose relevant data in consumable ways.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 1:35:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 2:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90683</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90683</id>
          <name>Greg Low</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>Technologies to Watch: A Gaze into Greg's Crystal Ball</title>
      <description>Last year, Greg delivered a session on technologies that fascinate a technologist as the keynote for SQL Saturday Auckland. People were raving about it afterwards and wanted to see a longer version of it. This is a longer and updated version of that keynote. Greg dives into technologies that fascinate him, that he thinks will fascinate you, and that he thinks will fundamentally alter the world. He looks into how they are likely to change work as we know it today. Come and be intrigued and inspired.</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 11:35:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 12:35:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92560</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92560</id>
          <name>Craig Bryden</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Angry Koala</name>
      </location>
      <title>Modern Enterprise BI in Azure</title>
      <description>With  lot of BI and Analytics solutions moving to the cloud, you might be asking yourself what a modern, end-to-end BI solution looks like now. There are several different options for how you can implement such a solution. In this session, Craig will discuss and demonstrate how you can implement enterprise BI in Azure. Craig will do so by taking "on-premises" data into Azure SQL Data Warehouse and then surface this in Power BI. Some of the technologies used will include:
- SQL Server
- Azure Data Factory
- Azure SQL Data Warehouse
- Azure Analysis Services
- Power BI</description>
      <startTime>8/3/2019 9:05:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/3/2019 10:05:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>