<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #310 - Dublin 2014</name>
    <startDate>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>350</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT) Greenwich Mean Time : Dublin, Edinburgh, Lisbon, London</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatDublin</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Hilton Hotel</name>
      <street>Charlemount Place</street>
      <city>Dublin</city>
      <state>, Ireland</state>
      <zipcode>2</zipcode>
      <longitude>-6.260027</longitude>
      <latitude>53.331096</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>85</importID>
      <name>Pyramid Analytics</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.PyramidAnalytics.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://pages.pyramidanalytics.com/rs/pyramidanalytics/images/logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1073</importID>
      <name>Spanish Point Technologies Ltd</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.spanishpoint.ie</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/862/EventSponsor_13576.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1146</importID>
      <name>Storm Technology</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.storm.ie</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.prodata.ie/events/SqlSat310/images/StormLogo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>13</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/sqlsaturday/eventsponsors/Quest_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>487</importID>
      <name>Codec-dss</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.codecdss.ie/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/b95833b2-eaa5-4950-bb7a-003c1a24491a.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>255</importID>
      <name>Safefood 360</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://safefood360.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://safefood360.com/images/logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>966</importID>
      <name>Prodata</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.prodata.ie</url>
      <imageURL>http://www.prodata.ie/images/Prodata_Logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>8</importID>
      <name>FusionIO</name>
      <label>Platinum</label>
      <url>http://www.fusionio.com/solutions/microsoft-sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/files/18b704b1-226d-48fe-b0b8-f7b4d3443b3d.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>853</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Iireland</name>
      <label>Platinum - MS</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.ie</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/301/images/sponsors/MSFT_Logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1115</importID>
      <name>SQL Sentry</name>
      <label>Silver - SqlSentry</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlsentry.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sentryone.com/Images/logos/sentryone-black.svg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>83</importID>
      <name>PluralSight</name>
      <label>SWAG Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pluralsight.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.srnimbus.com.br/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Pluralsight_logo_novo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>20</importID>
      <name>O'Reilly Books</name>
      <label>SWAG Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://oreilly.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://oreilly.com/images/oreilly/oreilly.gif</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1281</importID>
      <name>Wiley</name>
      <label>SWAG Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.wiley.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/023c5608-6225-48e4-8401-2c545a63ded2.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14015</importID>
      <name>Ewan Fairweather</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ewan Fairweather is a Senior Program Manager on the Azure Customer Advisory (CAT) team at Microsoft.  He has extensive background on building complex, high-end OLTP applications on SQL Server as well as significant experience with the largest Windows/SQL Azure applications deployed today.  
He has worked for Microsoft for seven years in a number of field and Redmond based roles. Lead author on "Applied Architecture Patterns on the Microsoft Platform," and has written many whitepapers. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9286</importID>
      <name>Allan Mitchell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Allan Mitchell is a SQL Server MVP and runs elastio, a small consultancy helping customers to make informed decisions about their data storage and integration.  His focus is on enterprise search as well as real-time data integration.</description>
      <twitter>@allanSQLIS</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://onlysearch.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@allanSQLIS</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24647</importID>
      <name>Stacia Varga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stacia Varga is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and SSAS Maestro with a Bachelor’s Degree in Social Sciences. A consultant, educator, author, and principal of Data Inspirations, her career spans more than 30 years, with a focus on improving business practices through technology.

Since 2000, Stacia has provided consulting and education services for Microsoft's Business Intelligence technologies. As Stacia Misner, she also authored several books covering the Microsoft BI stack.</description>
      <twitter>@_StaciaV_</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/staciavarga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.datainspirations.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_StaciaV_</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11476</importID>
      <name>Chris Webb</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Webb is a member of the Power BI CAT team. He is the author of "Power Query for Power BI and Excel" and a co-author of "SQL Server Analysis Services 2012: The BISM Tabular Model", "Expert Cube Development with SQL Server 2008 Analysis Services", and "MDX Solutions with Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services 2005 and Hyperion Essbase".</description>
      <twitter>@cwebb_bi</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/chriswebb6/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blog.crossjoin.co.uk/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cwebb_bi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21017</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry </name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denny Cherry is the owner and principal consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates Consulting and has over a decade of experience working with platforms such as SQL Server, Hyper-V, vSphere and Enterprise Storage solutions. Technical expertise include system architecture, performance tuning, security, replication and troubleshooting. Holds several SQL Server Certifications (versions 2000 through 2008) including the MCM and MVP.  Denny has written several books and dozens of technical articles.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.dcac.co</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16410</importID>
      <name>Jen Stirrup</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jen Stirrup, Microsoft Regional Director and MVP is a well-known Business Intelligence and Data Visualization expert, author, data strategist, and Master of Business Administration (MBA) student in London. Jen leads a boutique analytics consultancy, delivering strategic advice to companies large and small.

Jen has presented in Africa, India, Europe and North America. Jen has presented at Ignite, Techorama, TechEd, PASS Summit, SQLBits, and SQLSaturday events in Europe and the US. She also delivers the MAPA Azure Architects course worldwide with Microsoft team members. Jen was also featured on the Best of PASS Summit 2015 DVD as one of the top 10 speakers. Jen also was awarded PASS prestigious PASSion Award in 2012</description>
      <twitter>@jenstirrup</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/jenstirrup/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.jenstirrup.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@jenstirrup</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17601</importID>
      <name>James Rowland Jones</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>James Rowland-Jones is a Principal Consultant for The Big Bang Data Company. His focus and passion is to architect and deliver highly scalable analytical platforms that are creative, simple, and elegant in their design. James specializes in big data warehouse solutions that leverage both SQL Server Parallel Data Warehouse and Hadoop ecosystems. James is a keen advocate for the SQL Server community; both internationally and in the UK. He currently serves on the Board of Directors for PASS.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.bigbangdata.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18121</importID>
      <name>Kennie Pontoppidan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kennie Nybo Pontoppidan is a senior program manager in Microsoft working in the Dynamics NAV server backend team. He has worked in the dangerous field between developers, dbas, customers and project managers for many years and done his part of mistakes as a developer before that in his 15+ years in the it industry. He enjoys working with databases and really, really enjoys his daily dose of sql. Kennie has no humor.</description>
      <twitter>@KennieNP</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kennie</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.pontop.dk/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KennieNP</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24789</importID>
      <name>Mladen Prajdić</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mladen Prajdić is a Data Platform MVP from Slovenia. He's been programming for 20 years, developing diﬀerent types of applications in .Net (C#) and SQL Server, ranging from standard line-of-business, image-processing applications to high performace and IoT applications. He's a regular speaker at various conferences and usergroup meetings, really likes to optimize slow SQL statements, analyze performance, and find unconventional solutions to difficult SQL Server problems. In his free time, he also develops a very popular add-in for SSMS, called the SSMS Tools Pack (www.ssmstoolspack.com).</description>
      <twitter>@MladenPrajdic</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mladenprajdic</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/mladenp</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MladenPrajdic</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20125</importID>
      <name>Mark Stacey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Stacey founded the Aphelion Software Group, and works tirelessly to cross the business/technical boundaries in Business Intelligence, working in both SharePoint and SQL. He has published two books on BI - Sharepoint 2010 BI and Visual Intelligence and frequently speaks at both SQL Saturday and SharePoint Saturday events. Mark is one of the few Microsoft PDW trainers, and has trained in Africa, India and Europe on the PDW, as well as all over the world on other technologies </description>
      <twitter>@MarkGStacey</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://MarkGStacey.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MarkGStacey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19083</importID>
      <name>Leonard Lobel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leonard Lobel (Microsoft MVP, Data Platform) is CTO and co-founder of Sleek Technologies, Inc., a New York-based development shop with an early adopter philosophy toward new technologies. He is also a principal consultant at Tallan, Inc., a Microsoft National Systems Integrator and Gold Competency Partner.

Programming since 1979, Lenni specializes in Microsoft-based solutions, with experience that spans a variety of business domains, including publishing, financial, wholesale/retail, health care, and e-commerce. Lenni has served as chief architect and lead developer for various organizations, ranging from small shops to high-profile clients. He is also a consultant, trainer, and frequent speaker at local usergroup meetings, VSLive, SQL PASS, and other industry conferences.

Lenni has also authored several MS Press books and Pluralsight courses on SQL Server programming.</description>
      <twitter>@lennilobel</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/lennilobel</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://lennilobel.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@lennilobel</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11097</importID>
      <name>Buck Woody</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Born helpless, naked, and unable to provide for himself, Buck Woody overcame these amazing handicaps to become a software developer, data professional, teacher, and a productive invertebrate member of society.</description>
      <twitter>BuckWoodyMSFT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/buckwoody</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://buckwoody.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=BuckWoodyMSFT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9217</importID>
      <name>Alex Whittles</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alex is a Data Platform MVP, and is the owner and lead consultant at Purple Frog, a SQL Server Business Intelligence consultancy in the UK. He specializes in Data Warehouse modelling, ETL, Cubes, MDX amp; DAX. He#39;s a chartered engineer amp; has an MSc in Business Intelligence.

He runs the Birmingham (UK) SQL Pass chapter amp; Azure user groups, and is on the SQLBits and SQL Relay committees in the UK. 

Alex is a regular speaker at global events including SQLBits, PASS Summit, SQL Relay, SQL Saturdays as well as numerous SQL Pass chapters around Europe</description>
      <twitter>@PurpleFrogSys</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/alexwhittles</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.PurpleFrogSystems.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@PurpleFrogSys</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18494</importID>
      <name>Klaus Aschenbrenner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Klaus Aschenbrenner provides independent SQL Server consulting services across the United States and Europe, focusing on the .NET Framework and SQL Server 2005 and 2008. In 2004 and 2005, he received the Microsoft MVP award for his support of the .NET community. Klaus has also written a book, “Pro SQL Server 2008 Service Broker,” published by Apress (2008).</description>
      <twitter>@Aschenbrenner</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.SQLpassion.at/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Aschenbrenner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21475</importID>
      <name>Justin Wheeler</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niall joined Fusion-io in October 2010 and is now responsible for the direction of technical marketing across the EMEA region. Having worked through the storage revolution from DAS to SAN, and now solid state, Niall has extensive knowledge and experience in utilising infrastructure resources to deliver application performance. Niall began his career in IT in the late 1990s at Data General then moved on to EMC working in number of roles starting in consultancy.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.fusionio.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15123</importID>
      <name>Henk van der Valk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Since 2000 Henk has specialized in optimizing large-scale Microsoft application and database solutions.
He’s been authoring and contributing numerous whitepapers around SQL Server performance tuning and also produced the famous ETL Data loading World Record with SSIS.  
About a year ago, Henk left Microsoft and co-founded a new company: SQLMasters BV and dedicates his time since in developing cool SQL Estate data management solutions and full stack performance tuning.  
During his presentations he usually dives into the real-world performance challenges @customer sites  and shares tips that will make you job easier!</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/henkvandervalk</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.henkvandervalk.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10925</importID>
      <name>Boris Hristov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Boris is a SQL Server Consultant, but also an Author for Pluralsight and a SQL Server MVP. He is frequently speaking at conferences all accross Europe and is heavily involved in training students and organizations in what he calls quot;The Art of SQL Serverquot;. Boris is frequently blogging and is the host of SQLHangouts.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BorisHristov</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://bg.linkedin.com/in/borishristov</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://borishristov.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BorisHristov</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34564</importID>
      <name>André Kamman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>André is a freelance SQL Server specialist. In previous roles he’s done a lot of DBA work on 100’s of servers where he discovered his love for Powershell and automating processes in general. Today the better part of his day he’s building and tuning ETL processes.
André is a SQL Server MPV, Dutch PASS Chapter Leader and organiser of SQL Rally Amsterdam and SQL Saturday Holland</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://andrekamman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18460</importID>
      <name>Kevin Kline</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Kline, a longtime Microsoft SQL Server MVP living in Nashville, is a founder and former president of SQLPASS.org and the author of popular books such as 'SQL in a Nutshell'. Kline tweets at @kekline and blogs at http://KevinEKline.com.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://KevinEKline.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10566</importID>
      <name>Bob Duffy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Duffy is a SQL Server MVP from Dublin, Ireland who is MCA, MCM. and Analysis Services Maestro certified. 

Bob works as a Database Architect at the Prodata SQL Centre of Excellence where he specializes in business intelligence and performance tuning.</description>
      <twitter>@bob_duffy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=8301243amp;authType=NAME_SEARCHamp;authToken=MWkaamp;locale=en_USamp;srchid=83012431382480825815amp;srchindex=1amp;srchtotal=767amp;trk=vsrp_people_res_nameamp;trkInfo=VSRPsearchId%3A83012431382480825815%2CVSRPtargetId%3A8301243%2CVSRPcmpt%3Aprimary</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.prodata.ie/author/bob.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@bob_duffy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11705</importID>
      <name>Carmel Gunn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carmel is the Managing Director of the Prodata SQL Centre of Excellence in Dublin, Ireland, where she is a data management specialist, working in the areas of analytics and visualisations.

As a committee member for the SQL Server Ireland User Group, she has played an active roll in bringing 2 SQL Saturdays to Dublin, and is heavily involved in the SQL community.





</description>
      <twitter>@carmelgunn</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ie.linkedin.com/in/carmelgunn/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.prodata.ie</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@carmelgunn</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24440</importID>
      <name>Simon Sabin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Simon has worked with data for all his career enabling companies to make the most of the data they have .
 
He works with companies to help them
1. Optimise their data platform, including performance, scalability, security and certification
2. Understand and define a cloud strategy.
3. Improve their data development practices including implementation of agile methodologies and continuous integration. 

Simon is also a SQL Microsoft Certified Master and has been Microsoft MVP since 2005</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblogcasts.com/blogs/simons/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22835</importID>
      <name>Regis Baccaro</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Regis has more than 15 years of experience with SQL Server, SharePoint and .Net as an architect and developer. R#233;gis is a SQL Server MVP since 2014 and a frequent speaker at SQL conferences, a PASS Regional Mentor and the founder of SQL Saturday Denmark community event. He is also a certified industry trainer on the APS/PDW platform. In his freetime he is an avid runner, cook and farmer.</description>
      <twitter>@regbac</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/regisbaccaro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://theblobfarm.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@regbac</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>28208</importID>
      <name>William Durkin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>William Durkin is a DBA, Data Platform MVP, and Data Platform Architect for Data Masterminds (http://datamasterminds.io). He uses his decade of experience with SQL Server to help multinational corporations achieve their data management goals. Born in the UK and now based in Germany, William has worked as a Database Developer and DBA on projects ranging from single server installations, up to environments spanning 5 continents, using a range of high availability solutions. William is a regular speaker at conferences around the globe, organizes the popular event SQLGrillen (http://sqlgrillen.com).</description>
      <twitter>@sql_williamd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/wdurkin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://williamdurkin.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sql_williamd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10565</importID>
      <name>Bob Duffy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Duffy is a SQL Server MVP from Dublin, Ireland who is MCA, MCM. and Analysis Services Maestro certified. 

Bob works as a Database Architect at the Prodata SQL Centre of Excellence where he specializes in business intelligence and performance tuning.</description>
      <twitter>@bob_duffy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=8301243amp;authType=NAME_SEARCHamp;authToken=MWkaamp;locale=en_USamp;srchid=83012431382480825815amp;srchindex=1amp;srchtotal=767amp;trk=vsrp_people_res_nameamp;trkInfo=VSRPsearchId%3A83012431382480825815%2CVSRPtargetId%3A8301243%2CVSRPcmpt%3Aprimary</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.prodata.ie/author/bob.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@bob_duffy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17879</importID>
      <name>Karen Lopez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Karen Lopez is a Sr. Project Manager and Architect for InfoAdvisors. A frequent speaker at conferences and local user groups, she has 20+ years of experience in project and data management on large, multi-project programs. Karen is a chronic volunteer, a Data Platform MVP, and an active advocate for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education and data quality.

Karen’s presentations are known for their lively and interactive approach to learning. Her motto: “Love Your Data!”</description>
      <twitter>datachick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/karenlopez</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datamodel.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=datachick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9669</importID>
      <name>Daire Cunningham</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11787</importID>
      <name>Conor Cunningham</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Conor Cunningham is a principal software architect at Microsoft on the SQL Server Query Processor Team. He's worked on database technologies for Microsoft for over 10 years and holds numerous patents related to query optimization and query processing. Conor is the author of a number of peer-reviewed articles on query optimization techniques. Recently, he wrote a chapter for the book "Microsoft SQL Server 2008 Internals" on how the query optimizer works. He publishes a blog called "Conor vs. SQL" (http://blogs.msdn.com/conor_cunningham_msft/default.aspx), where he answers questions about databases.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>9286</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9286</id>
          <name>Allan Mitchell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>4. Ideal Husband</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQOOP - Taking relational data to Hadoop and back again</title>
      <description>SQOOP or SQL to Hadoop is a tool in the Hadoop ecosystem that lets you take your "SQL" data and put it into Hadoop or vice versa.  The use cases are numerous.  You can have Hadoop perform the heavy lifting using Map Reduce and then use SQOOP to take the results and put them in "SQL".  You can have Hadoop act as your Data Warehouse and use SQOOP to do your daily loads from your relational DB into Hadoop.
SQOOP is a command line tool but don't let that put you off.  
This session will look at SQOOP and the plethora of options available to you on the command line.  If you want to learn about SQOOP then this is the session for you.
</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10565</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10565</id>
          <name>Bob Duffy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1. Lady Windermere</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Irish Economic Crisis Visualised with Power BI</title>
      <description>In this session we will explore the Irish Economic Crisis from multiple perspectives, using Microsoft’s latest Visualisation tools including Power BI, Power Query, Power Map, Power View and SharePoint”.   It starts from a very common business angle, where people need to make sense of data, fast, but don't know what questions to ask, nor how to combine available sources in a way that makes sense.   This session converts the Irish Economic crisis into a story that can be explored in an interactive way, using familiar tools, in a way that people may feel should have been noticed in the run-up to the crisis. Come by to find out what led to a small country owing over 200 billion euro and if Power BI could have helped.   Come and find out where all the money came from and what Ireland spent it on!</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11705</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11705</id>
          <name>Carmel Gunn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2. Dorian Gray</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>First steps in continuous integration for databases with Red Gate’s SQL Automation Pack.</title>
      <description>At previous SQL Saturday Dublin events, you’ve seen how easy it is to get your SQL Server databases in source control.
In this session, we’ll build on this foundation and look at the resources you can use to set up an automated build process for your databases.
Starting with a database that’s source controlled using Red Gate’s SQL Source Control, we’ll use the SQL Automation Pack and Team City to set up a simple build process that runs every time you commit a change.
You’ll see how this process helps you spot and fix errors quicker, and how you can use it to produce an artefact you can use for reliable, repeatable deployments in the future.
One lucky session attendee will also win a license of the SQL Automation Pack during this session, so don’t miss out!
</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14015</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14015</id>
          <name>Ewan Fairweather</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>4. Ideal Husband</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Shared technical learnings for building highly scalable and available cloud application</title>
      <description>The Azure CAT team has successfully architected, designed and built over 200 cloud projects. In this session we will share the learnings on how to design a cloud application to scale to handle large, complex workloads. We will have a special focus on the telemetry management and monitoring requirements such large systems require.  Building cloud applications are different than building on premise SQL Server applications. Agenda I) Share some of the existing successful cloud deployment feeds and speeds. II) The challenges we faced III) It is all about the architecture up front IV) Lessons Learned V) Summary QA.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16410</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16410</id>
          <name>Jen Stirrup</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>3. Intentions</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>A One Hour Data Analysts Toolkit: using R and PowerBI</title>
      <description>If you want to conduct advanced Business Intelligence development and Business Analysis, then it is useful to understand data visualisation and have R as a tool in your toolset. In this intensive one hour session, we will look at the latest suite of Microsoft Business Intelligence tools - Microsoft Power BI in conjunction with R. The demos will be implemented in both tools in an end-to-end hour long session so that delegates can see when to use each technology in order to determine 'what to use' and 'when to use it', as well as seeing where the technologies complement each other. We will visualise the data according to data visualisation principles set out by Stephen Few amongst others.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19083</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19083</id>
          <name>Leonard Lobel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2. Dorian Gray</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Learning Entity Framework 6</title>
      <description>Microsoft has clearly positioned the Entity Framework 6 (EF) as the primary data access platform for .NET applications. But many developers have yet to embrace the powerful Object Relational Mapping (ORM) capabilities that EF offers. Whether you’re new to ORM, or you’ve dabbled in other ORM technologies, Lenni will show how quickly you can start working with EF6 and boost your productivity when building data-centric .NET applications.

We’ll begin with a quick introduction to ORM and EF, and then explain many of the special ORM features in EF6, such as the Entity Data Model, and table splitting, inheritance, entity splitting, and many-to-many relationships. With the basics covered, Lenni will then dive right into live demos that show what EF can do for you as a data access layer, using database-first, model-first, and code-first approaches with both direct SQL and stored procedures. We’ll also discuss new features introduced in EF6, and show how to use EF in N-Tier scenarios.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24440</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24440</id>
          <name>Simon Sabin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>3. Intentions</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Storing of sensitive data in SQL Server - Meeting the PCI Data Security Standards </title>
      <description>Your business needs to process credit card data and you need to store it somewhere.

The Payment Card Industry (PCI) requires that you store the data in an encrypted form and make sure your processes are robust to protect the data. These requirements are the PCI Data Security Standards currently at version 3.0 https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/security_standards/pcidss_agreement.php?association=pcidss 
 
If you want to use SQL Server as your data store what do you need to do?
 This session covers the following for SQL Server 
* Encrypting data in SQL Server
* Meeting Key management requirements of 
* Detect and audit access to the data
* Retro fitting encryption of data into an existing application

 We will do an overview of all the areas and drill down into the storage of data and how that can be achieved seamlessly from the application.
At the end of the session you will know what you need to do, to be able store card details in SQL Server and achieve PCI certificatio</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18460</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18460</id>
          <name>Kevin Kline</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1. Lady Windermere</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Convince Me – Persuasion Techniques That Get Things Done</title>
      <description>Ever wanted to convince the boss to try something new but didn't know where to start? Ever tried to lead your peers only to fail to achieve your goals? This session will teach you the eight techniques of influencing IT professionals so that you can innovate and achieve change in your organization.

You’ll learn:
• The fundamental difference between influence and authority and how you can achieve a high degree of influence without explicit authority
• The eight techniques of influencing IT professionals, when to apply them, and how to best use them
• The communication and procedural techniques that ensure your ideas get a hearing by managers and peers and how to win support for them</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21017</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21017</id>
          <name>Denny Cherry </name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2. Dorian Gray</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Storage for the DBA</title>
      <description>Storage can be one of the biggest bottlenecks when it comes to database performance.  It's also one of the hardest places to troubleshoot performance issues because storage engineers and database administrators often do not speak the same language.  In this session, we'll be looking at storage from both the database and storage perspectives.   We'll be digging into LUNs, HBAs, the fabric, as well as the storage configuration.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17601</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17601</id>
          <name>James Rowland Jones</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>4. Ideal Husband</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Migrating to APS</title>
      <description>Analytics Platform System (APS) isn't SQL Server - it's different. It's bigger than that. It's a massively parallel-processing, distributed-database platform that leverages SQL Server as part of its architecture. But it has so much more to offer...

In this 1-hour session, you will learn how to "embrace the change" and accelerate your migration to the data warehouse storage engine for the Microsoft Data Platform. This session will be packed with advice and recommendations from actual customer deployments and real-world experiences. Get on board the APS train, and transform your data warehouse with the Microsoft Analytics Appliance!
</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20125</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20125</id>
          <name>Mark Stacey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>5. Lord Arthur Saville</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS Patterns-Performance testing, parallel packag</title>
      <description>There are several patterns in SSIS that are easy and super useful - once you know them! In this session, you will learn how to create a performance testing framework to run multiple versions of your package, how to run packages in parallel, and a hashing algorithm based on FNV1a to vastly improve your load times 

 </description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11476</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11476</id>
          <name>Chris Webb</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>3. Intentions</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power Query: Beyond The Basics</title>
      <description>You already know that you can accomplish a lot within the Power Query user interface. If you are a data steward, however, you may be asked to deliver complex data sets in Power Query that require some knowledge of advanced functionality, including the M language. This session will examine what these requirements might be, how to implement them, and how best to deploy them to end users. </description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9669</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9669</id>
          <name>Daire Cunningham</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>3. Intentions</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Power BI and SharePoint as a rapid development BI Strategy</title>
      <description>See how you can use Excel and SharePoint to quickly implement a BI solution with Power BI. The Power BI tools allow you to extract, transform and load your data (Power Query), model that data (Power Pivot) and visualise the resulting analyses (Power View and Power Map) all within Excel. The results can be shared simply in the cloud with Office365 SharePoint Online. If you’re ready for the next level you can migrate your model to SQL Server Analysis Services on-premise or stick with the cloud using Azure Virtual Machines.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24789</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24789</id>
          <name>Mladen Prajdić</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2. Dorian Gray</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Digging Into the .Net SqlClient</title>
      <description>The prevailing opinion is that the optimizations for SQL Server are usually only done on the server itself. But is there anything we can do on the client to gain more speed? In this session aimed at .Net and SQL developers, we'll dive into the workings of the .Net SqlClient and give you insight into way more than just SqlCommand.ExecuteReader() and SqlCommand.ExecuteNonQuery().</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21475</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21475</id>
          <name>Justin Wheeler</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>5. Lord Arthur Saville</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using ioMemory to leverage Buffer Pool Extension and In-memory OLTP capability with Microsoft</title>
      <description>Leveraging Buffer Pool Extension and In-Memory OLTP in SQL Server 2014 with Fusion’s ioDrive2 product line increases database performance by allowing solid state storage to exist alongside DRAM. Fusion’s memory-like performance helps reduce costs by enabling organizations to scale with NAND flash versus DRAM. </description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17879</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17879</id>
          <name>Karen Lopez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>4. Ideal Husband</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Windows Azure SQL Database Design: Concepts and Trade-offs</title>
      <description>Data modelers and designers need to understand the logical, physical, and technical differences in designing for Windows Azure SQL Databases (WASDs) and traditional on-premise SQL Server databases. In this session, we'll review the concepts that still work in both and the features that need to be tailored to each target environment.

You’ll see demonstrations of the database creation and initial design processes and gain best practices for model-driven development for each environment, including tool support. We’ll finish up with 5 tips for designing databases for both WASD and SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24647</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24647</id>
          <name>Stacia Varga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>3. Intentions</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Multidimensional vs Tabular - May the Best Model Win</title>
      <description>Are multidimensional models dead on arrival? Are tabular models the future of analysis? Come to this session to learn the similarities and differences between these two approaches to analytical modeling first introduced in SQL Server 2012 Analysis Services. We'll explore the pros and cons of each type of model and review how to select the appropriate model to your analytical requirements.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11787</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11787</id>
          <name>Conor Cunningham</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1. Lady Windermere</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Inside the SQL Server Query Processor</title>
      <description>Conor will go through how the query processor works, with focus on query optimization and how new technologies like the in-memory OLTP (Hekaton) and Columnstore Indexes/Batch Execution modes work.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22835</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22835</id>
          <name>Regis Baccaro</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>5. Lord Arthur Saville</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>DBAs are from Mars,  SharePoint admins are from Ve</title>
      <description>SharePoint databases are considered a black box - touch them and you lose support. Furthermore, SharePoint leaves an unintelligible track of database names and GUIDs on your server. They are supposed to scale, but how and how much? Here are some techniques DBAs should be aware of to optimize SharePoint performance and scalability. This demo-packed session, based on real-life experiences, will show you how to tune your SQL Server for SharePoint and how to customize your SharePoint installation so that it fits your IT conventions, not the other way around.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18121</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18121</id>
          <name>Kennie Pontoppidan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2. Dorian Gray</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL anti patterns</title>
      <description>You can learn SQL in three days but it'll take you 10 years to become good at it. In this session we will have a look at some basic design errors and get a notion of the things that absolutely doesn't work. Antipatterns is a way of naming common design errors in order to make them easier to remember - even if you haven't done them yet.

We will become acquainted with antipatterns on a physical level, a logical level and an sql-queries and application level, and spice it up with some seriously foolish errors made by me and my colleagues. The session is relevant for developers and DBAs.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34564</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34564</id>
          <name>André Kamman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>5. Lord Arthur Saville</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to write professional Powershell scripts</title>
      <description>You probably have a few Powershell scripts sitting around, perhaps written from scratch but most likely you borrowed the idea from a blog somewhere, and then used those as templates to achieve your goal. It's time to take those ad-hoc scripts turn them into your very own module. And while we're at it we might as well add proper error handling, parameterization and pipeline support. I will also demonstrate how to build help, force and whatif support.
This is a demo rich session and all demos will be covering practical SQL Server related solutions.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9217</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9217</id>
          <name>Alex Whittles</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>3. Intentions</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>MDX 101</title>
      <description>Give your queries a multidimensional makeover. In this session we'll look at the structure and basics of MDX, the Multi Dimensional query eXpression language for querying Analysis Services OLAP cubes.

We'll start at the beginning, so you need no previous MDX experience, but it does help to understand what a cube is.
Learn the difference between a member, measure, tuple, set and dimension. Well describe how to decypher a [] from a {} or (). We'll look at examples of each, and show how you can easily access the imense power of cubes with relative ease.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11097</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11097</id>
          <name>Buck Woody</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>4. Ideal Husband</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data, Big Project</title>
      <description>By now, we're past the "hype cycle" of what Big data is - but how many people have really implemented a Big Data project yet? And what do those projects contain? Come here Microsoft's Buck Woody describe a big Data project engagement, and learn what to expect, how to prepare, and how to run your own project successfully.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>28208</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>28208</id>
          <name>William Durkin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>5. Lord Arthur Saville</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Replication Troubleshooting  Monitoring</title>
      <description>Replication is a powerful feature that has long been available in SQL Server.  However, with great power come great headaches! Replication normally runs happily once set up, but if things go wrong it can turn into a seemingly never ending list of errors.  In this session I will dig into how replication can go wrong (and has gone wrong for me) and what steps you can take to fix these issues.  Along the way I will go into what monitoring options you have when working with replication and also a couple of gotchas that have caught me out in the past.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18494</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18494</id>
          <name>Klaus Aschenbrenner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2. Dorian Gray</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Plan Caching in SQL Server</title>
      <description>Plan Caching is the most powerful concept in SQL Server. But on the other hand it's also the most dangerous thing that can lead to queries that are executed with a completely wrong Execution Plan. In this session we will have a more detailed look into the Plan Cache of SQL Server, in which different ways SQL Server can cache Execution Plans in the Plan Cache, and how you can troubleshooting wrong performing queries directly from the Plan Cache.</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15123</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15123</id>
          <name>Henk van der Valk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>4. Ideal Husband</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server PDW (APS)  vs SQL Server, let's see the big differences </title>
      <description>In this session we will present a live comparison between the SMP and MPP versions of SQL Server, with a special attention to architecture , hadoop integration and Performance! The spirit of the session will be “Forget the slides… let’s just do live Demos!”
</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10566</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10566</id>
          <name>Bob Duffy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>4. Ideal Husband</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Blending SQL Azure with SQL Server to drive Performance Insights</title>
      <description>Peter O'Connell will show how DELL Software deployed a SQL Azure solution that takes feeds of performance data from on-premise diagnostics and monitoring software to provide unique insights on SQL Server performance across thousands of instances</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10925</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10925</id>
          <name>Boris Hristov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2. Dorian Gray</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>The nightmare of locking, blocking and isolation levels!</title>
      <description>I am sure you all know that troubleshooting problems related to locking and blocking (hey, sometimes there are deadlocks too) can be a real nightmare! In this session, you will be able to see and understand why and how locking actually works, what problems it causes and how can we use isolation levels and various other techniques to resolve them!</description>
      <startTime>9/20/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/20/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>