<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #673 - Denver 2017</name>
    <startDate>9/16/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-07:00) Mountain Time (US and Canada)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatDenver</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>University of Denver - Sturm Hall</name>
      <street>2040 S Race St</street>
      <city>Denver</city>
      <state>Colorado</state>
      <zipcode>80210</zipcode>
      <longitude>-104.963994294036</longitude>
      <latitude>39.6796368251049</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>607</importID>
      <name>DELL EMC</name>
      <label>Premier Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.dellemc.com/en-us/index.htm</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/913/EventSponsor_14262.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1988</importID>
      <name>Rubrik</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.rubrik.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/945/EventSponsor_14614.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1549</importID>
      <name>BlueGranite, Inc.</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.blue-granite.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.blue-granite.com/hubfs/logo-2.png?t=1507557297195</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2007</importID>
      <name>Datalere</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://datalere.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://datalere.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/datalere-default-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>5</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/947/EventSponsor_14722.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>360</importID>
      <name>Actifio</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.actifio.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://d38mhi8jtu7akf.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/actifio-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>558</importID>
      <name>Delphix</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.delphix.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://s1g.s3.amazonaws.com/8d76d3158dc5762281edd77ad20e50d4.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1005</importID>
      <name>RevGen Partners</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.revgenpartners.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.revgenpartners.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/logo-300x70.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2008</importID>
      <name>Data Savvy</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://datasavvy.me/</url>
      <imageURL>https://datasavvy.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/cropped-color_logo_transparent2x.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1995</importID>
      <name>Mile Hi Power BI User Group</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://milehipowerbi.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://ourlastbesthope.com/images/mhpbiug400.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66237</importID>
      <name>Rushabh Mehta</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rushabh Mehta is a Business Intelligence Mentor with SolidQ and the Managing Director for Solid Quality India Pvt. Ltd. He served as PASS President for 2010/2011 term.

Rushabh has worked with MS Data Platform since 1998 and has designed and developed BI systems since 2001. He has been the lead architect for many large-scale and complex BI solutions for clients such as Publix, Raymond James, Jackson Hewitt, US Dept. of Defense, and Microsoft. He is an MVP with Microsoft, Damp;B amp; Melissa Data

</description>
      <twitter>@rushabhmehta</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rushabhbmehta</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/RushabhMehta</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@rushabhmehta</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68052</importID>
      <name>Reeves Smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reeves Smith, owner and principal architect of Macer Consulting, is passionate about applying data technologies that empower organizations. Reeves wields his knowledge and experience to lead, design, architect, and teach, working with both data center and business project teams. He approaches every project by first understanding the organization’s business challenges, and then developing a unique approach that targets those business needs accurately and effectively.

Reeves Smith has more than 20 years of experience working on the SQL Server stack. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and Microsoft Certified Master, and regularly delivers technical presentations at international, regional, and local conferences and user groups.</description>
      <twitter>SQLReeves</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/reevessmithiii/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://reevessmith.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLReeves</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67989</importID>
      <name>Lynn Winterboer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lynn Winterboer coaches and educates Analytics, Business Intelligence and Data Warehousing teams on how to apply agile principles and practices to their work.  Through a career focused on Agile and BI, Lynn understands the unique challenges faced by data teams who want to benefit from the incremental, value-focused approaches of Agile and Lean delivery.  

Ms. Winterboer is Co-Chair of Mile High Agile 2017  2018, organizes the monthly Agile Denver Data  Analytics Meetup, and is a frequent speaker at events such as Agile 20xx, Mile High Agile, Agile Denver, SQLSaturday, PASS, TDWI and DAMA. She teaches throughout North America and Europe for The Data Warehousing Institute (TDWI) and The Cutter Consortium.</description>
      <twitter>@AgileLynn</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lynnwinterboer</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://winterboeragileanalytics.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@AgileLynn</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68061</importID>
      <name>Yuliya Quintela</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Yuliya is a consultant and developer for Business Intelligence Solutions. She has experience in various areas including Education, Finance, Telecommunications, and Software Technology into model data, visualize and deliver critical information to solve complex business decisions using Microsoft data platform and business analytics. She is an active member of the Business Intelligence and SQL Server community in Denver and a member of the Colorado SQL PASS chapter  user group. She specializes in SQL Server 2016 Reporting and Integration Services and holds professional certifications including MCSE for the Data Platform.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/yuliya-quintela-profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66371</importID>
      <name>Eric Peterson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eric Peterson is a consultant specializing in database architecture with experience in demanding Fortune 100 company environments. He has a Computer Science degree complemented with an MBA, which meshes well with his jobs integrating business information with the systems that process it. He has worked with SQL Server since its inception and was an instructor of SQL courses at a national technical training company. He also speaks are regional SQLSaturday events.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67991</importID>
      <name>Glenn Berry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Glenn works as a Principal Consultant for Dr. DMV, LLC in Elizabeth, CO. He was a Data Platform MVP from 2007-2017, and he has a whole collection of Microsoft certifications, including MCITP, MCDBA, MCSE, MCSD, MCAD, and MCTS, which proves that he likes to take tests. His expertise includes DMVs, high availability, hardware selection, performance tuning, and Azure SQL Database.  He is also an Adjunct Faculty member at University College - University of Denver, where has been teaching since 2000. He has completed the Master Teacher Program at Denver University - University College. He is heavily involved in the SQL Server community, and is a frequent speaker at user groups, SQL Saturdays, and the PASS Community Summit.</description>
      <twitter>GlennAlanBerry</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/public-profile-settings?trk=prof-edit-edit-public_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://glennsqlperformance.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=GlennAlanBerry</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68127</importID>
      <name>Gabriel Villa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gabriel is a skilled leader, architect, and technical expert focusing primarily on Microsoft technologies and is passionate about open-source technologies for integration, automation, and development. Gabriel’s versatility extends from systems, data and development and leverages hybrid/SaaS/Cloud integration, proven software engineering platforms, and best-of-breed data management and business intelligence solutions.

Originally from El Paso, Texas, Gabriel lives in Colorado Springs with his wife and kids, where he is an Architect for RevGen Partners, volunteers in the tech community and enjoys the Colorado outdoors.</description>
      <twitter>@extofer</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabevilla</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://extofer.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@extofer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65727</importID>
      <name>Patrick LeBlanc</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick LeBlanc is a currently a Principal Program Manager at Microsoft and a contributing partner to Guy in a Cube. Along with his 15+ years’ experience in IT he holds a Masters of Science degree from Louisiana State University. He is the author and co-author of five SQL Server books. Prior to joining Microsoft he was awarded Microsoft MVP award for his contributions to the community.  Patrick is a regular speaker at many SQL Server Conferences and Community events.</description>
      <twitter>patrickdba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrickdleblanc</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://patrickdleblanc.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=patrickdba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68149</importID>
      <name>Julia Renz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julia is a student of technology with a passion for learning new things.  She loves math, computers and science.  Julia has a passion for dance and softball in her spare time.</description>
      <twitter>@jmr0323</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@jmr0323</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69430</importID>
      <name>Denver SQL Server User Group</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denver SQL Server User Group</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66303</importID>
      <name>Chase Aucoin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chase Aucoin has nearly a decade working several large scale data driven application including FedEx Freight, with over half a billion transactions per day.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://vinsolutions.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68059</importID>
      <name>Keith Tate</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Keith Tate is a Senior Database Administrator with over 17 years of experience as a data professional. During Keith#39;s professional career he has been a developer, DBA and data architect. Keith is also active in the SQL Server community and is currently the chapter leader of the Albuquerque SQL Server User Group.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/keith_tate</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/keith-tate/34/a40/a46</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://thesqlchef.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/keith_tate</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68142</importID>
      <name>Eddie Wuerch</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eddie Wuerch has 20 years of experience as a SQL Server specialist in a much-longer IT career. A Microsoft Certified Master, Eddie spends his days in the Salesforce Marketing Cloud, focusing on performance, scale, and uptime for the massive SQL Server backend. These SQL Servers churn billions of transactions daily against trillions of rows of data in a 24x7 continuously-available online system accessed by millions worldwide every day.</description>
      <twitter>@EddieW</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/eddiewuerch</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.indydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@EddieW</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67661</importID>
      <name>TJay Belt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>TJay Belt is an outdoorsman at heart who enjoys riding dirtbikes, waterskiing, boating, playing racquetball and spending time with his family. 
When he can't be out playing, TJay loves to tinker with databases. TJay has been an IT professional for over a decade and a half. Currently serving as a Senior Database Administrator with Imagine Learning.  TJay has progressed through several roles in his database career including developer, data guy, database developer, database analyst and DBA.</description>
      <twitter>@tjaybelt</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/tjaybelt/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tjaybelt.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tjaybelt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68092</importID>
      <name>Cathrine Wilhelmsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cathrine loves teaching and sharing knowledge :) She is based in Norway and works as a Senior Business Intelligence Consultant in Inmeta, focusing on Data Warehousing, Data Integration, Analytics, and Reporting projects. Her core skills are Azure Data Factory, SSIS, Biml and T-SQL development, but she enjoys everything from programming to data visualization. Outside of work she's active in the SQL Server community as a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, BimlHero Certified Expert, author, speaker, blogger, organizer and chronic volunteer.</description>
      <twitter>@cathrinew</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cathrinewilhelmsen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.cathrinewilhelmsen.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cathrinew</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65474</importID>
      <name>Angela Henry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Angela is a Solution Architect, living in High Point, NC and loves what she does. She's worked with all versions of SQL Server  worn all the hats that come with dealing with SQL Server throughout the years: developer, administrator, data architect and BI developer. She has her MSCE in Data and Analytics (f.k.a., Business Intelligence), is a Data Platform MVP, and a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT).  She is the former chapter leader for the PASS Triad SQL User Group in Greensboro, NC. In her spare time you can probably find her in or at the pool, she's an avid US Masters Swimmer, Coach and Instructor.</description>
      <twitter>SQLSwimmer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/angelahenrydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SQLSwimmer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLSwimmer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67056</importID>
      <name>Michael Fal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mike is a specialist in data management technologies. As a community advocate, public speaker, and blogger, Mike is a practicing thought leader for data and automation. He is passionate about DevOps and data, building platforms to optimize, protect, and use data efficiently.

Since 1999, Mike has been working in the database field, focusing primarily on SQL Server and specializes in automating data solutions to improve the reliability and efficiency of his environments. He has been caught playing trombone in public on more than one occasion.</description>
      <twitter>@Mike_Fal</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelfal/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mikefal.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Mike_Fal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66438</importID>
      <name>Steve Wake</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Wake is currently the Principal BI Developer at Brown and Caldwell and has experience in consulting, advertising, media, manufacturing, retail, charities, telecommunications and financial services organizations using the full on-premises Microsoft BI stack. Recent experience with the Azure services: Analysis Services, Logic Apps,  Data Factory, Databricks, Snowflake and Power BI. Steve is also very involved in the SQL community, speaking at events around the world.</description>
      <twitter>stevewake</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/b5lurker</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.wakebi.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=stevewake</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68035</importID>
      <name>Bill Fellows</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bill Fellows is a SQL Server MVP and has been a database developer for most of his career, with the past 15 years focused on ETL. He is the organizer of Kansas City's eight SQL Saturdays and a speaker at many other SQL Saturdays, User Groups and the PASS Summit. Bill is the owner of Sterling Data Consulting where he gets to solve interesting data problems.</description>
      <twitter>@billinkc</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/billinkc</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.billfellows.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@billinkc</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68121</importID>
      <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Bossy (MCTS, MCP BI, CBIP) is a data and cloud analytics architect with 25 years of experience in software and database development. As a principal of Datalere, Carlos focuses on developing BI, Data Science, and Advanced Analytics solutions, including modeling data warehouses and delivering predictive models, integration, and visualization. He has developed warehouses and BI solutions for a variety of industries and state agencies, including health insurance, solar energy, foster care, telecom, and manufacturing.</description>
      <twitter>@carlosbossy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin/in/carlosbossy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.carlosbossy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@carlosbossy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66575</importID>
      <name>Mindy Curnutt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mindy Curnutt is a 5X Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Business Owner and Entrepreneur. Her specialties include SQL Server hardware, configuration, migrations, scalability, performance tuning.  She has been actively involved in the SQL Server Community for over two decades and has become a well known speaker within the SQL and Transportation Management communities. She is a two-time PASS Volunteer of the Month, has presented at 6 SQLPASS Summits, Live360, DevConnections, MVPMix and too many SQL Saturdays to count. She is currently the President of the North Texas SQL Server User Group out of Dallas/Fort Worth, TX.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mindycurnutt</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mindycurnutt.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68051</importID>
      <name>Levi Syck</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Levi Syck is a senior consultant with BlueGranite who lives just outside Detroit, MI. His work focuses on enabling analytics by building dependable and extensible data back-ends. He enjoys automating the many manual tasks introduced by BI and analytics tools, and loves learning about new techniques.</description>
      <twitter>@levisyck</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lsyck/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@levisyck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68126</importID>
      <name>Todd Kleinhans</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Todd Kleinhans has been using SQL Server since the last millennium. He has served in different roles across many industries but he's mainly been a DBA. When not in virtual reality, he likes to speak at PASS sponsored events and volunteers in various groups like PASS, DSSUG, Colorado Virtual Reality and is the President of Denver/Boulder Unreal Engine group. He is on Twitter: @toddkleinhans and blogs at https://toddkleinhans.wordpress.com/</description>
      <twitter>@toddkleinhans</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/todd-kleinhans/0/920/981</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://toddkleinhans.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@toddkleinhans</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65497</importID>
      <name>Tim Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tim Gorman is a senior technical consultant for Delphix who securely enables masked data virtualization to increase the agility of IT development and testing while ending decades of security risk in SDLC.

Tim has co-authored six books on data warehousing and database administration, has performed technical review on eight more books, and has an author#39;s page on Amazon.com (http://www.amazon.com/Tim-Gorman/e/B00BKCTO5E).</description>
      <twitter>@TimGormanTech</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timgorman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://evdbt.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TimGormanTech</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66061</importID>
      <name>Scot Reagin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>TDWI Certified Business Intelligence Professional
Certified Data Vault Data Modeler

More than thirty years of technology experience serving in a wide variety of roles including: Software Designer, Solution Architect, and Operations and General Manager.  Experience designing and implementing complete analytic solutions for organizations of many sizes and in diverse industries.

Business intelligence specific experience encompasses all aspects of Enterprise Information solutions including: Information Quality, Enterprise Data Warehousing, Business Analysis Data Marts, and comprehensive visualization applications.</description>
      <twitter>@SDIScot</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sjreagin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sensibledataintegrations.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SDIScot</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66413</importID>
      <name>Kathi Kellenberger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kathi Kellenberger is the editor of Simple Talk at Redgate and a Data Platform MVP. She has worked with SQL Server for over 20 years and has authored, co-authored, or tech edited over a dozen technical books. Kathi is the co-leader of the PASS Women in Technology Virtual Group and a volunteer at LaunchCode. When Kathi isn’t working, she enjoys spending time with family and friends, cycling, singing, and climbing the stairs of tall buildings. Be sure to check out her courses on Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>auntkathi</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kathikellenberger</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://auntkathisql.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=auntkathi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67994</importID>
      <name>Rob Volk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob Volk is a SQL Server DBA in the Metro Atlanta area since 2001. He also moderates and answers the forums on SQLTeam.com. While an old-time cranky DBA, he no longer considers quot;business intelligencequot; an oxymoron or quot;the cloudquot; as merely atmospheric moisture, and is delightedly dipping his toes into both of these new oceans, and loves to do things in new and and unusual ways.</description>
      <twitter>sql_r</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rob-volk-134ba81</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/robv/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sql_r</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68095</importID>
      <name>Michael Wall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Wall has been an IT professional going back to when he had his own software store and worked with his customers with their “dose” problems.  Originally hired by a small consulting firm to write web pages, he was thrust into the SysAdmin world when their lead consultant changed the passwords of all of the servers at a major pulp and paper company’s systems to 100%s$%t and walked out the door.  He was sent down with a copy of UNIX for Dummies and 50 cents for the bus ride back.  Fast forward a few years, he was asked if he wanted to be a DBA after successfully managing a fifty server Y2K upgrade.  Since then, he’s never looked back and has survived a number of data and system challenges.
When not wrangling cats at home, he currently</description>
      <twitter>michaelDwall1</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-wall/b/110/9a</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.becomingamaster.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=michaelDwall1</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67990</importID>
      <name>Glenn Berry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Glenn works as a Principal Consultant for Dr. DMV, LLC in Elizabeth, CO. He was a Data Platform MVP from 2007-2017, and he has a whole collection of Microsoft certifications, including MCITP, MCDBA, MCSE, MCSD, MCAD, and MCTS, which proves that he likes to take tests. His expertise includes DMVs, high availability, hardware selection, performance tuning, and Azure SQL Database.  He is also an Adjunct Faculty member at University College - University of Denver, where has been teaching since 2000. He has completed the Master Teacher Program at Denver University - University College. He is heavily involved in the SQL Server community, and is a frequent speaker at user groups, SQL Saturdays, and the PASS Community Summit.</description>
      <twitter>GlennAlanBerry</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/public-profile-settings?trk=prof-edit-edit-public_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://glennsqlperformance.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=GlennAlanBerry</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68075</importID>
      <name>Leslie Weed</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leslie Weed is currently a Data and BI Architect with RevGen Partners in Denver, CO. She has been a SQL Professional specializing in Business Intelligence, data analytics, systems implementation, integration, and solutions delivery for the last 20ish years, including a variety of Enterprise Data Warehouses in various industries.</description>
      <twitter>@weederbug</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@weederbug</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69510</importID>
      <name>Rick Lowe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick is a Microsoft Certified Master with more than 20 years of SQL Server experience in a variety of roles. He currently lives in Washington state and works as an independent consultant providing remote performance DBA and performance tuning services for clients in the USA and Canada. His first exposure to SQL Server was as a database developer, but over time he became more and more interested in how the database engine operated... eventually specializing more on performance issues than code.

Rick will work with all things relational, but most enjoys helping smaller companies get better performance from MSSQL, as well as smoothing over relationships between DBA and development teams.</description>
      <twitter>DataFLowe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rick-lowe/a/228/441/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataflowe.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataFLowe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65643</importID>
      <name>Vern Rabe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vern Rabe is an independent SQL Server consultant and contract trainer in Portland, OR, and leader of the Oregon Data Community user group, formerly OregonSQL. He has attained MCSE, MCITP (both Administration and Development), and MCT certifications, among others. Vern has been passionate about databases since 1992 and has worked with SQL Server since version 4.21a. He provides broad technical SQL Server knowledge gained from the mixture of academic and practical experiences acquired from his classroom instructing and varied consulting contracts. Vern regularly presents technical sessions at SQL Server user group meetings, SQLSaturdays, and PASS Summit.</description>
      <twitter>@VernRabe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/vern-rabe/a/ba3/980</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.rabedata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@VernRabe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65502</importID>
      <name>Christopher Wolff</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Wolff has been a developer, report writer, and an admin in Microsoft and SQL Server Space since SQL Server 2000 in industries such as telecommunications, green energy, money transfers, and online accounting. He has been an active member of the Denver SQL User Group since 2011 and enjoys learning new things about computers. His interests includes video games, movies, and enjoying time with his wife and 2 kids.</description>
      <twitter>@tickytong</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/christopher-wolff/11/a07/458</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlred.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tickytong</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68204</importID>
      <name>Jimmy May</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jimmy May is a Microsoft Certified Master (MCM).  He's formerly a Principal Architect at Microsoft as well as Senior Program Manager for the SQL Server Customer Advisory Team (SQL CAT) where he managed the Customer Lab which hosts the biggest, fastest,  most interesting SQL Server apps from all over the world.  More recently he was a SQL Server Technologist for what was Fusion-io's Data Propulsion Lab (DPL), since acquired by Western Digital.  He is a founder of the IndyPASS  IWUG user groups.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/aspiringgeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aspiringgeek</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.flippingthefasterbit.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/aspiringgeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65468</importID>
      <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kellyn Pot’Vin-Gorman is a member of the Oak Table Network and an Idera ACE and Oracle ACE Director alumnus. She is a Data Platform Architect in Power BI with AI in the EdTech group at Microsoft. Kellyn is known for her extensive work with multi-database platforms, DevOps, cloud migrations, virtualization, visualizations, scripting, environment optimization tuning, automation, and architecture design. 

Kellyn has spoken at numerous technical conferences for Oracle, Big Data, DevOps, testing, and SQL Server. Her blog (http://dbakevlar.com) and social media activity under her handle, DBAKevlar, is well respected for her insight and content.</description>
      <twitter>DBAKevlar</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellynpotvin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dbakevlar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAKevlar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69124</importID>
      <name>Patrick LeBlanc</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick LeBlanc is a currently a Principal Program Manager at Microsoft and a contributing partner to Guy in a Cube. Along with his 15+ years’ experience in IT he holds a Masters of Science degree from Louisiana State University. He is the author and co-author of five SQL Server books. Prior to joining Microsoft he was awarded Microsoft MVP award for his contributions to the community.  Patrick is a regular speaker at many SQL Server Conferences and Community events.</description>
      <twitter>patrickdba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrickdleblanc</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://patrickdleblanc.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=patrickdba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65478</importID>
      <name>Wendy Pastrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wendy Pastrick is from Chicago, IL, and for the past 15 years has served as a Database Administrator supporting both development and production environments. Her many years of involvement with PASS include WIT Virtual Chapter and the Chicago Suburban User Group, serving as Regional Mentor, and as a PASS Board member since 2013. Wendy has organized several highly successful SQLSaturday events in Chicago.</description>
      <twitter>@wendy_dance</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://wendyverse.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@wendy_dance</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>65643</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65643</id>
          <name>Vern Rabe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>253</name>
      </location>
      <title>Proper DataType Usage=Guaranteed Better Performance and Accuracy</title>
      <description>It’s an all too common occurrence to have table columns or variables that have been assigned less than ideal data types. 

In this demo-heavy presentation I will show you the importance of choosing the proper data type; show you some guidelines in determining what an appropriate data type would be; and once chosen, give you some tools for its usage and management. I will demonstrate several performance and accuracy issues, along with their possible solutions, caused by either the assignment of inappropriate data types or improper usage of them. In addition I will cover several data type related functions, and point out caveats in their usage. I expect even advanced T-SQL developers and DBAs to walk away with a useful nugget or two.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65468</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65468</id>
          <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>287</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Next Frontier-  Opportunities When Migrating to the Cloud with Virtualization</title>
      <description>Cloud is everywhere and the database administrator is caught in the middle. How do you know where to start and what to migrate first? How do you perform consolidation planning and ensure data security? This session builds on a full demonstration, along with tips and tricks to show how the DBA can secure their environment to allow a self-service option so they no longer are the constraints to projects! The attendee will leave with a clear understanding of:
* Principles of virtualization and why it’s the answer to so many challenges we face today.
* How easy it is to secure data in the cloud using data masking features.
* The ease of connecting to the cloud and migrating environments.
* How to troubleshoot when issues arise and the tools available to diagnose issues.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65497</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65497</id>
          <name>Tim Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>287</name>
      </location>
      <title>Accelerating DevOps and TDM Using Data Virtualization</title>
      <description>DevOps is the merger of app development, testing, and IT ops.  All tasks from coding to testing to operations should be automated so new features and fixes can be continuously quickly.

Test Data Management (TDM) is the optimization of the process of software quality, ensuring that applications properly work according to their specifications.

Constraining both DevOps and TDM is database size. "Storage is cheap" is not merely a lie, but more to the point it takes a lot of time to push terabytes around from place to place, and time itself is expensive and dear.

Providing full databases for each developer or tester on each task of each project seems unrealistic, when each copy might require terabytes of storage, so for decades everyone has limited themselves to working in shared dev/test environments that are refreshed only every few months, where conflicts occur,  quality suffers, and things move slowly.

Come learn why data virtualization is the solution to a problem everyone knows.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66438</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66438</id>
          <name>Steve Wake</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>234</name>
      </location>
      <title>Make Power BI Your Own with the Power BI APIs</title>
      <description>Power BI makes accessing data from various sources and building advanced visualizations for analytics easy to do. Behind the scenes Power BI is built on standard technologies and APIs that allow it to be customized in multiple ways to fit in with your environment the way you need it to. In this session we will walk though samples and demos that show how you can extend Power BI with custom visualizations, access custom data sources, embed various Power BI elements in your applications, and be able to push your data into a Power BI report/dashboard. Each of these items take advantage of the Power BI APIs in different ways and we will discuss each and provide the code samples for you to take back and get a head start. This session will be showing code to access the Power BI REST API using C# and NodeJS along with some M for accessing and manipulating custom data sources.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66413</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66413</id>
          <name>Kathi Kellenberger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>234</name>
      </location>
      <title>Kerberos Delegation Made Simple</title>
      <description>Kerberos delegation is often needed for SQL Server Reporting Services security. Many DBAs avoid Kerberos because of the complexity and come up with workarounds that may violate security policies in their shops. They also may not understand why Kerberos delegation is even required. 
Configuring Kerberos for SSRS can be broken down into three simple steps: SPN registration, setting delegation properties, and application configuration. It’s really not so difficult, and there are a number of tools that can help you troubleshoot when things don’t go as planned.
Attend this session to learn why Kerberos is necessary and how to configure and troubleshoot it.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67661</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67661</id>
          <name>TJay Belt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>233</name>
      </location>
      <title>PowerBI, from a DBA</title>
      <description>Microsoft’s PowerBI is the new hotness. In this session, you will get your hands dirty and dive into PowerBI and create an actual report, with actual data. You will get to learn from examples from what a DBA has done to implement PowerBI in his shop and make his data accessible.

As a DBA, we often need to collect and display data in a friendly and interactive fashion. We will play with some PowerShell to collect data from several systems, store this data in an Azure DB in the Cloud, then point PowerBI at this data to display and interact with said data. You will learn a little about PowerShell, Azure SQL DB, PowerBI, and how to make these work for you.

You will be given permissions to an Azure DB, and get connected to this source. You will also need to have PowerBI desktop downloaded and installed. We will be using this to create the report during the session. So please come prepared to interact with the internet, with a cloud-based database you will be provided, and PowerBI Desk</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66575</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66575</id>
          <name>Mindy Curnutt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>275</name>
      </location>
      <title>Impostor Syndrome: Are You Faking It  Will they Find Out?</title>
      <description>Have you ever thought to yourself  “All these people think I’m smarter than I really am" or "I really don’t know what I’m doing, they're going to figure out I'm a fraud!”  If yes, then you suffer from the Impostor Syndrome. And despite all the accomplishments, awards and accolades, you still doubt yourself. It’s rampant in the modern day tech workplace, and the fear will make you shrink back from opportunities. You dismiss praise. You overcompensate by working harder, being charming and demanding perfection from yourself. What would happen if you were released from this bondage, and kicked your impostor to the curb? In this session, learn 3 powerful techniques that can help to improve your confidence and silent that annoying voice in your head!</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65727</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65727</id>
          <name>Patrick LeBlanc</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>233</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Analysis Services</title>
      <description>You have been wanting to using SQL Server Analysis Services, but just don't have the physical resources on-premises to set one up.  Analysis Services has typically shipped with SQL Server on premises, but now it has been implemented as a fully managed service in Azure. Join this session to learn how to create a and deploy a model, load and refresh data using Azure functions, secure the model, view the model and a little about pricing.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68059</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68059</id>
          <name>Keith Tate</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>275</name>
      </location>
      <title>Profiler is Dead! Long Live Extended Events!</title>
      <description>Did you know that Profiler and SQL Trace are deprecated? I know it still works, but it will never be updated with the latest features. In fact it will never be updated at all! That means if you want to capture information about any new feature, from version SQL Server 2012 and beyond, you need to use another tool.
That new tool is Extended Events (XE). Not only has it replaced Profiler, and can be used to capture information on all new features, but it is a substantially better tool!
In this session we will discuss the architecture of Extended Events, how to setup a new trace from scratch or convert an existing Profiler trace, and the new abilities that never existed in Profiler. We will also cover the difference in overhead cost of Profiler and Extended Events. 
Profiler was a friend of mine, but it is time to embrace the new king!</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67989</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67989</id>
          <name>Lynn Winterboer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>210</name>
      </location>
      <title>Behavior-Driven Design and Test Automation: Agile Enablement for DW and BI Teams</title>
      <description>Behavior-Driven Design (BDD) and test automation are key practices that allow data warehouse and business intelligence teams to be more successful in their agile journeys. While there are lots of test practices and automation tools out there for software development teams to leverage, very few are targeted to data-related development and testing. Agile analytics practitioner Lynn Winterboer and DW/BI architect Cher Fox will share essential agile test foundations, describe BDD, and identify data-focused test automation technologies to help data warehousing and business intelligence teams get a leg up on these important agile practices, including a BDD exercise and a test automation demo!</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68204</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68204</id>
          <name>Jimmy May</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>253</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 Always On AGs Perf, Internals,  Lessons Learned</title>
      <description>Always On Availability Groups (AGs) were introduced in SQL Server 2012. AGs significantly expanded our HA/DR options. However, in both SQL 2012 and SQL 2014 two limitations were extant in the code—both Network Transport and Log Redo significantly compromised performance. In SQL Server 2016, these limitations have been significantly improved.
 
Our work shows enhancements of 7x – 10x, allowing over 1/2GB/s (4Gb/s) across the wire. These improvements expand solutions options for Tier 1 OLTP and Data Warehouse workloads, Tier 1 and Tier 2 consolidation, and more. This presentation explains the improvements, characterizes the new solutions, and shows commodity servers and modern non-shared in-server flash storage showing the profound contrast between SQL Server 2014 vs. 2016. Doing so moves the performance bottleneck from the SQL Server codebase to the CPU where it belongs.
 
1.       Revealing the fantastic perf enhancements in SQL Server 2016 AGs
2.       Sharing SQL Server 2016 AGs</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67990</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67990</id>
          <name>Glenn Berry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>253</name>
      </location>
      <title>Analyzing I/O Subsystem Performance</title>
      <description>SQL Server is often I/O bound - but why? Do you feel lost when talking to your storage administrator?  Are your storage subsystems like a mysterious black box where your databases live but you can’t go visit? This session will get you up to speed with the fundamentals of storage subsystems for SQL Server. You will learn about the different types of storage that are available, and how to decide what type of storage to use for different workload types. You will also learn useful tips and techniques for configuring your storage for the best performance and reliability. We’ll cover methods to effectively measure and monitor your storage performance so that you will have valuable information and evidence available the next time you have to discuss IO performance with your storage administrator. Come to this session to learn how to analyze I/Os as well as options to reduce the bottlenecks.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67991</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67991</id>
          <name>Glenn Berry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>253</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dr. DMV's Troubleshooting Toolkit</title>
      <description>Dynamic Management Views and functions allow you to easily see exactly what is happening inside your SQL Server instances and databases with a high level of detail. You can discover your top wait types, most CPU intensive stored procedures, find missing indexes, and identify unused indexes, to name just a few examples. This session presents, demonstrates and explains a complete set of diagnostic DMV queries that you can easily use to detect and diagnose configuration and performance issues in your SQL Server instances and databases. 

This session goes into exhaustive detail on how to interpret the results of each of the diagnostic queries, including relevant background information on how to properly configure your hardware, storage subsystem, operating system, SQL Server instance and databases in order to avoid performance and scalability issues.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68092</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68092</id>
          <name>Cathrine Wilhelmsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>235</name>
      </location>
      <title>Level Up Your Biml: Best Practices and Coding Techniques</title>
      <description>Is your Biml solution starting to remind you of a bowl of tangled spaghetti code? Good! That means you are solving real problems while saving a lot of time. The next step is to make sure that your solution does not grow too complex and confusing - you do not want to waste all that saved time on future maintenance!

Attend this session for an overview of Biml best practices and coding techniques. Learn how to centralize and reuse code with include files and the CallBimlScript methods. Make your code easier to read and write by utilizing LINQ (Language-Integrated Queries). Share code between files by using Annotations and ObjectTags. And finally, if standard Biml is not enough to solve your problems, you can create your own C# helper classes and extension methods to implement custom logic.

Start improving your code today and level up your Biml in no time!</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68035</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68035</id>
          <name>Bill Fellows</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>235</name>
      </location>
      <title>Metadata driven development</title>
      <description>The longer I've been coding, the less time I want to spend coding - at least, the boring, repetitious bits. In this talk, I'll share the approaches I've used to systematically generate SQL artifacts based on metadata and templates. 

The approach is basic: Get data. Process through some templating engine. Collect output.

The specifics scenarios we'll cover
* Biml/C#: we'll build SSIS packages, tables and stored procedures
* Python: we'll use pyratemp to build tables and CLR stored functions
* Versioning: Version your templates and your data</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68121</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68121</id>
          <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>234</name>
      </location>
      <title>Operationalizing Data Science</title>
      <description>The challenge of developing a predictive model is the secret sauce that data science practitioners strive to achieve. While sophisticated predictive models can be game changers that give you a competitive edge, they must be nurtured and closely watched to ensure they perform as expected. This session shows attendees how to build a framework and develop a data model that handles prediction logging, prediction performance management, and analysis. A case study will show predictions can degrade and ultimately fail, further emphasizing the importance of tracking their performance.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66061</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66061</id>
          <name>Scot Reagin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>254</name>
      </location>
      <title>Agile Data Modeling with Data Vault</title>
      <description>Agility and Business Intelligence are two good things that often struggle to be good together. A primary cause of this struggle is the inability of traditional Data Warehouse models to respond to change in a (business) timely manner. Data Vault is an evolution of Enterprise Data Warehouse modeling that removes the barriers to Data Warehouse agility. A Data Vault warehouse eliminates re-engineering both of the data schema and ETL as the model evolves in response to changing business needs and definitions.
In this session we’ll compare modeling techniques in real world scenarios to understand how Data Vault can make your EDW more capable and agile.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67994</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67994</id>
          <name>Rob Volk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>254</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tame Your Unruly Data With Constraints</title>
      <description>Bad data comes in many forms: duplicate rows, wrong data type, invalid values, and orphaned or missing foreign keys. Time is wasted cleansing, reviewing and correcting data, not to mention the potential hazards bad data can cause. This introductory presentation will explain the data types and constraints available in SQL Server, and how they can replace or augment business rules that would otherwise be written in application or procedure code. Performance benefits provided by constraints will be demonstrated. We will examine the various system views and procedures that describe constraints and how to use them to document your databases. You will be able to apply this knowledge to your database environments and see significant improvements in data quality, performance, and reliability.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68095</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68095</id>
          <name>Michael Wall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>275</name>
      </location>
      <title>Becoming a Master by Giving it All Away</title>
      <description>It has been said that novices absorb knowledge like a sponge, intermediates hoard it for themselves, and masters just simply give it away.  
The community spirit of PASS is for like-minded professionals to interact and share knowledge.  But how do you do this in your own workplace?  What happens when Bob takes off with one day of notice?  How do you manage when Jane unfortunately has to spend a month in the hospital?
All joking aside, the only way to truly become a master at your craft is to share your precious knowledge with your peers and workmates.  We will discuss past and current trends in knowledge transfer, the reasons why you should (and shouldn’t) pass on knowledge, and methods for making this happen in your workplace and in your life.
Be prepared for an interactive and lively discussion and to walk away with some new concepts that are going to make you think about how you too can become a Master!</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68061</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68061</id>
          <name>Yuliya Quintela</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>235</name>
      </location>
      <title>Biml 101: Automation and Patterns</title>
      <description>Biml (Business Intelligence Markup Language) is a programming language for creating business intelligence objects. It is a simple XML that can be extended with small nuggets of C# or VB code to automatically generate SQL scripts, SSIS packages and SSAS cubes. It will allow you to turn tedious repetitive tasks into reusable scripts - no more drag-and-dropping! Using Biml will significantly cut down development time, reduce errors and improve quality of your code. In this session, you'll find out everything you need to know to start with Biml development. Our focus will be on SSIS solutions.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68149</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68149</id>
          <name>Julia Renz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>233</name>
      </location>
      <title>Even I Can Power BI!</title>
      <description>Power BI Desktop is so intuitive when it comes to creating reports that even a 13 year old can do it.  In fact I'm 13 and I can do it! Don't believe me?  Come to my session as I demonstrate how to import data, create dashboards, and publish them to the Power BI service.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68052</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68052</id>
          <name>Reeves Smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>234</name>
      </location>
      <title>The New Revolution in Data Science, R integrated into SQL Server</title>
      <description>Data Science is an ever increasing topic in the Data Analytics space and the R language is at the center of most conversations. R is an open source statistical language that is rapidly gaining popularity due to a robust set of machine learning functionality and a never-ending set of R packages.  

The R language is run as a desktop application and was not built with performance and scale required to accommodate Big Data. Revolution Analytics, a wholly owned subsidiary of Microsoft, has solved the performance and scaling issues of a desktop application by creating a more robust enterprise architecture. SQL Server 2016 brings the power of R and Revolution Analytics into the industry leading relational database. 

This session will introduce R and demonstrate the functionality and power of using R within SQL Server. 

This presentation is ideally suited for Business Intelligence professionals that are interested in understanding the new R Service that is being added to SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68051</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68051</id>
          <name>Levi Syck</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>235</name>
      </location>
      <title>Stop Repeating Yourself – Automating Azure Data Movement With BimlScript</title>
      <description>Have you begun using Azure Data Factory (ADF) to copy data to and from Azure? Have you realized how fast ADF development becomes tedious and error-prone?  Azure Data Factory can make it simple to process your data, but the minimal web UI and JSON configuration files make it easy to make a mistake. Your solution might have hundreds, or thousands, of files after you create datasets and activities for each source query or file. Finished development and need to make a design change? You could be looking at hours of manual updates. But you don’t have to settle for manual ADF development.

In this session I’ll introduce you to BimlScript and the BimlExpress add-in for Visual Studio and I'll demonstrate how to use these tools to automate the creation of ADF datasets and pipelines. I’ll use real-world examples to show you how automation can decrease your development time and encourage iterative development.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68126</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68126</id>
          <name>Todd Kleinhans</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>253</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Life Cycle of a Query in Virtual Reality</title>
      <description>How would you like to learn about using Virtual Reality (VR) to present information? The ability to become immersed and walk around inside of a VR environment is a new and unique way to present and look at information. As data professionals we need to be open to novel displays of data and explore what VR can do that for us that we have not been able to do in the past. VR can provide a way for people to see relationships and interact among data sets which can be difficult for computers to display visually on a flat screen.

The Life Cycle of a Query in Virtual Reality is built using Epic Games video game engine called Unreal Engine 4 (UE4). With native support for VR, UE4 has been used for applications beyond just video games. With the commercial availability of affordable VR headsets, data professionals can now create visually compelling environments that were almost impossible or extremely expensive just a few years ago on both PC and mobile devices.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67056</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67056</id>
          <name>Michael Fal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>287</name>
      </location>
      <title>Exploring the new SqlServer PowerShell module</title>
      <description>If you’ve dabbled in PowerShell, you probably know that there are many ways to use it in conjunction with SQL Server. While using the provided tool set has been a challenge for many data professionals, recent upgrades and improvements to the PowerShell module for SQL server provide a solid tool set for new and experienced users. This session will cover the SqlServer module in detail, exploring the various commands and demonstrating various use cases for the tool set. Attendees will get a solid overview of the module and real world examples of how users can get the most out of their code.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68075</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68075</id>
          <name>Leslie Weed</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>235</name>
      </location>
      <title>Source Control and Database Projects - Just Do It</title>
      <description>If you aren't using database projects you should be and if you aren't using any source control well..... NOW IS THE TIME.  We'll review basic functionality and purpose of both and walk through how they work together.   Let's talk about the type of foundation pieces you need to pay attention to and how to organize this into team and agile work.  Lots of tips and tricks to remove the often experienced headaches that developers have experienced with implementing both of these items.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69430</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69430</id>
          <name>Denver SQL Server User Group</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>210</name>
      </location>
      <title>Sponsor Spotlight: Dell EMC - The Path to #GetModern</title>
      <description>To succeed in this new digital world, companies will require an IT Transformation. Dell EMC has announced a wave of innovations to help customers on their path towards a modern infrastructure and business agility.
Join us to learn how to innovate faster, create competitive advantage, improve IT operations, reduce costs and ultimately #GetModern.

Session presented by Bryan Walsh, Product Marketing Manager, Dell EMC</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65478</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65478</id>
          <name>Wendy Pastrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>254</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why NULL is not a value (and other SQL gotchas)</title>
      <description>Allowing NULL "values" in your database is simple, but managing them is a whole different story. Learn what NULL really means and why you may want to avoid it in your systems. I will share techniques for overcoming NULL and other SQL idiosyncrasies leading to bad data or incorrect query results.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69510</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69510</id>
          <name>Rick Lowe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>233</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why Should I Care About ... Partitioned Views?</title>
      <description>Partitioned tables are awesome and partitioned views are dead, right? Well, sure partitioned views are not sexy but there are still plenty of applications where they are critical. And not necessarily just for standard edition who aren't on the new service pack yet. If your data is time stamped, do you see different queries run against older data than new data? Do you wish you could segment your data across multiple columns? Do you have data you need to partition horizontally? It's possible partitioned views may still be for you. Come hear why this is still an important topic long after cargo pants and trucker hats went away ... and possibly even after 2016 SP1.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68142</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68142</id>
          <name>Eddie Wuerch</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>275</name>
      </location>
      <title>Never Lose Data! Digging Out From Corruption</title>
      <description>A "Disaster" doesn't need to be on a massive scale to cause widespread destruction in your enterprise. Simple things like failing hardware, strange storage bugs, a forgotten WHERE clause, or an angry employee can either cause devastation or be just a nuisance to the properly-prepared DBA. This session is a survey of recovery techniques that should be in every DBA's toolbox.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65474</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65474</id>
          <name>Angela Henry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>254</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to Integration Services (SSIS)</title>
      <description>This session is a very basic introduction to Integration Services (SSIS).  We’ll cover the basics; what it’s used for and the various parts and pieces to get you started creating your own projects in no time.  We’ll talk about packages, connections and project parameters and their respective tasks/properties.  We’ll also cover some basic performance tuning to make your packages run faster.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65502</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65502</id>
          <name>Christopher Wolff</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>287</name>
      </location>
      <title>Amazon Web Services RDS with SQL Server</title>
      <description>Are you wanting to make more SQL Servers but don't want to invest in more hardware? Then Relational Database Service (RDS) in Amazon Web Services (AWS) maybe the right choice for you. We will begin with creating a server using the Amazon Web Console, explore how to automate installation through Cloud Formation, show how to administrate the service, and walk through advanced features. Whether you are familiar with AWS or are brand new to it, this presentation should at least give you a good overview to decide if RDS is the right service for you.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 12:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66371</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66371</id>
          <name>Eric Peterson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>234</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL vs noSQL</title>
      <description>A SQL perspective on noSql document databases.
What’s the difference between a SQL database and a document db?
Why would you choose one over the other?
What does the implementation look like?
Are noSql databases taking over the world?</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68127</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68127</id>
          <name>Gabriel Villa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>254</name>
      </location>
      <title>Two Guys and a Transformation: ETL Best Practices and Techniques</title>
      <description>ETL (Extract, Transform and Load) is the backbone of any data project and can be upwards of 70% or more of the effort. The tools you have access to allow you to make progress in a hurry. However, are you implementing best practices and techniques that will scale to the demands you need? Or will you be refactoring far too quickly than you should to meet performance requirements?
Gian helpful insights from decades of lessons learned and walk away with best practices you can implement in your own ETL solution.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66303</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66303</id>
          <name>Chase Aucoin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>287</name>
      </location>
      <title>MySql using Containers and Windows Server 2016 for Active-Active deployments</title>
      <description>Standing up a highly scalable data infrastructure can be a very time-consuming task especially in larger enterprises with multiple teams and data needs across multiple teams. In this session, we will see how to leverage containers and storage spaces in Windows Server 2016 to create highly reliable, highly scalable database deployments in just a few minutes.

You will be able to leave this session with some great thoughts on how to leverage containers for infrastructure and state management within your organization and have the knowledge to hit the ground running.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69124</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69124</id>
          <name>Patrick LeBlanc</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>275</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Build your Brand and Become a Thought Leader</title>
      <description>Your personal brand is how you distinguish yourself from other people but how you develop and nurture your brand can be the difference between stagnation and opportunity in your career. We'll discuss your branding, the importance of taking control of your brand, and how to begin developing your personal brand. By the end of this session, you'll have a better idea of how to begin building your personal brand into something that can take your career to the next level.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66237</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66237</id>
          <name>Rushabh Mehta</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>233</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power Query Tips and Tricks for Power BI</title>
      <description>In this session, we will first learn how to expose organizational data using the data management gateway to Power BI. We will then look at how to use Power Query to acquire and cleanse data from organizational and external sources. As part of the session, we will also look at some tips and tricks to facilitate data acquisition and cleansing.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>