<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #658 - Toulouse 2017</name>
    <startDate>9/16/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>100</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Brussels, Copenhagen, Madrid, Paris</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatToulouse</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>La Cantine</name>
      <street>27 rue d'aubuisson</street>
      <city>Toulouse</city>
      <state>Midi-Pyrénées, France</state>
      <zipcode>31000</zipcode>
      <longitude>1.45412</longitude>
      <latitude>43.60275</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>57</importID>
      <name>Data by Design</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dataxdesign.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://034f89a.netsolhost.com/Images/DataByDesign_logoSmall.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1993</importID>
      <name>Groupe SRA</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.groupe-sra.fr</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.groupe-sra.fr/wp-content/themes/SRA/images/logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1994</importID>
      <name>Conseil IT</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.conseil-it.fr/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.conseil-it.fr/images/logo_conseil_it.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2024</importID>
      <name>Neotech Solutions</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.neotech-solutions.fr/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.neotech-solutions.fr/media/1050/logoneotechsolutions.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>415</importID>
      <name>Azeo</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.azeo.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://guss.pro/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/AZEO-Copier.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67653</importID>
      <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wolfgang Strasser creates solutions based on the Microsoft Data Platform tools in his day-to-day job as Business Intelligence consultant. Either using SQL Server Database Engine, SSIS, reporting with SSAS and SSRS, implementing Power BI solutions or cloud tools for data analysis - the data-tools-landscape is broadening every day! Based on his professional careers as a software developer he likes to work on structured development processes.
Wolfgang shares his knowledge with the community at many national and international events. For his community work, Wolfgang has been awarded with the Microsoft MVP Award for Data Platform in October 2015</description>
      <twitter>wstrasser</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/wolfgang-strasser/7b/912/22b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://workingondata.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=wstrasser</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64742</importID>
      <name>Isabelle Van Campenhoudt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Isabelle Van Campenhoudt is a system engineer (MCSE; MVP SQL Server) who has been working for more than 15 years in the world of databases; she lives in Belgium; Isabelle has strong experience in Business Intelligence. Trainer (Microsoft Certified Trainer), speaker and consultant, she used to collaborate with developers; infra (design and performance). She is also a teacher at EPHEC (Brussels) for the Bachelor of Computer Science curriculum. Isabelle is co-founder of CLUG; V-chapter Francophone</description>
      <twitter>@thesqlgrrrl</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://be.linkedin.com/pub/isabelle-van-campenhoudt/2/558/52b/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://thesqlgrrrl.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@thesqlgrrrl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67357</importID>
      <name>Gregory Boge</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior SQL Server DBA
Kankuru creator
GUSS member (French SQL Server User Group)</description>
      <twitter>@kankurusql</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.kankuru.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@kankurusql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64703</importID>
      <name>Christian Cote</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Christian Coté is an IT professional with more than 15 years of experience working in data warehouse and business intelligence projects.  Christian developed an expertise in data warehousing over the years and designed many ETL/BI processes using a range of tools on multiple platforms. He's been presenting at several conferences and code camps. He currently co-leads the SQL Server PASS chapter in Montreal as well as Global French SQL PASS Chapter.  He is also a Microsoft Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP).</description>
      <twitter>Christian_SQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://ca.linkedin.com/in/ccote</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://bi-blogger.typepad.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Christian_SQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67352</importID>
      <name>Charles-Henri Sauget</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Consultant décisionnel depuis 2009, j'ai eu l'occasion d'explorer certaines des fonctionnalités offertes par SQL Server, et cela est loin d'être terminé avec la croissance des volumes de données, et les nouveaux outils à disposition (Data Insights), de nouveaux défis vont très certainement s'offrir à nous. Même si la B.I. reste mon coeur de métier, je ne cache pas mon intérêt pour le Moteur SQL Server, surtout si l'on rajoute à ceci l'impact d'un hébergement en IaaS dans Azure !</description>
      <twitter>SaugetCh</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/charleshenrisauget</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sauget-ch.fr</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SaugetCh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69118</importID>
      <name>Sébastien Pertus</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Evangéliste technique chez Microsoft France, Sébastien est en charge d'accompagner les communautés de développeurs autour des technologies innovantes de Microsoft.  
En charge de tout ce qui touche au développement web front end avec TypeScript, d’Azure côté Backend, et enfin la donnée autour de SQL Server.  
Grand passionné de techno, Sébastien s’intéresse à la partie Microsoft Open Source, allant du monde Java chez Microsoft, .Net Core sur Mac ou encore Visual studio Code</description>
      <twitter>@sebastienpertus</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sebastienpertus/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/seb</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sebastienpertus</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67524</importID>
      <name>Patrice Lamarche</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Après avoir passé plus de 5 ans en tant que Consultant/Formateur au sein des sociétés de conseil Wygwam, et Bewise, j’ai rejoint le monde de l’édition de logiciels en tant que leader technique pendant plus de 5 ans, puis le développement en interne chez Chausson Materiaux.

Curieux et intéressé par tout ce qui a trait au développement avec les technologies Microsoft, j’essaie de partager mes connaissances avec la communauté Microsoft depuis 2001 notamment grâce à plus d’une trentaine de sessions présentées depuis 2004 à des évènements tels que les Microsoft DevDays, aux Microsoft Techdays, etc.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/PatriceVB</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/patricelamarche</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://patricelamarche.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/PatriceVB</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64736</importID>
      <name>Paul Bertucci</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul Bertucci is the founder of Data by Design, LLC (www.dataxdesign.com – formerly Database Architechs), a global database consulting firm with offices in the United States and Paris, France. Former Chief Architect/Shared Services Director for Autodesk (BI/DW/ODS, Big Data, Identity Management, SOA, Integration (EAI amp; ETL), MDM, Collaboration/Social, SaaS platforms, and Enterprise Architecture). Former Chief Data Architect at Symantec. Author SQL Server Unleashed book series, SQL Server High Availability, and SQL Performance and Tuning.  Frequent speaker at Database and MDM conferences around the globe. Formal education: UC. Berkeley, Electrical Engineering and Computer Science.</description>
      <twitter>@ptbertucci</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/paul-bertucci-59738b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ptbertucci</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67712</importID>
      <name>Cédric Charlier</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cédric is a talented architect and Data Platform MVP active in the domain of Business Intelligence and Data warehousing. He has more than 10 years of successful experiences with SQL Server in European industrial groups and services companies. Driven by quality and reliability, he is the main developer of an open-source solution for testing BI solutions (cubes, etl, reports) named NBi (www.nbi.io). Cedric also advocates for the introduction and general usage of agile practices in BI’s world.</description>
      <twitter>@Seddryck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://be.linkedin.com/in/cedriccharlier</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://seddryck.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Seddryck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66750</importID>
      <name>Christophe Laporte</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Christophe Laporte is based in Toulouse, France and has worked with SQL Server since 1997, starting with SQL Server 6.5. Focusing on high availability, VLDBs, and virtualization, Christophe also delivers performance audits on SQL Server and helps companies in choosing the appropriate architectures (Cloud, OnPremise, or Hybrid). 
In addition to his MCM certification, Christophe is also a SQL MVP, speaker, and Microsoft Certified Trainer since 2000.</description>
      <twitter>conseilit</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://fr.linkedin.com/in/christophelaporte</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://conseilit.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=conseilit</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67600</importID>
      <name>Jean-Pierre Riehl</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Architect, Consultant, Trainer and also Manager, Jean-Pierre leads the Data  BI Practice at AZEO, a French Microsoft "pure-player" partner. 
Jean-Pierre is MVP Data Platform since 2008 and speaks at many events in France and in Europe. JP leads the local community (GUSS) and organize events in France since 2011 : MS Cloud Summit, Les Journées SQL Server, SQLSaturday, etc. 
JP is passionate by data concerns in business like Data Governance, Data Quality or Data Vizualisation and since 2010, he’s specialized in Self-Service BI. His favorite topic is Power BI and business usages and technical architectures that go with.</description>
      <twitter>djeepy1</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://fr.linkedin.com/in/djeepy1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.djeepy1.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=djeepy1</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64737</importID>
      <name>Paul Bertucci</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul Bertucci is the founder of Data by Design, LLC (www.dataxdesign.com – formerly Database Architechs), a global database consulting firm with offices in the United States and Paris, France. Former Chief Architect/Shared Services Director for Autodesk (BI/DW/ODS, Big Data, Identity Management, SOA, Integration (EAI amp; ETL), MDM, Collaboration/Social, SaaS platforms, and Enterprise Architecture). Former Chief Data Architect at Symantec. Author SQL Server Unleashed book series, SQL Server High Availability, and SQL Performance and Tuning.  Frequent speaker at Database and MDM conferences around the globe. Formal education: UC. Berkeley, Electrical Engineering and Computer Science.</description>
      <twitter>@ptbertucci</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/paul-bertucci-59738b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ptbertucci</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67354</importID>
      <name>Joël Crest</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Docteur en Intelligence Artificielle
Consultant Business Intelligence
Microsoft Certified Solution Expert Data Management and Analytics</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/JoelCrest</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/joelcrest</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://bonjourjoel.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/JoelCrest</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64560</importID>
      <name>Stijn Wynants</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stijn is a Microsoft Premier Field Engineer on Data  AI and a DataMinds core member. He is also one of the organizers of the local user group sessions  the yearly event called DataMinds Connect (SQL Server Days). He is a speaker at various international events (SQL Saturday,PASS Summit,Difinity,...).  He spends his days tuning SQL Servers  solving problems with the full data platform. His focus is primarily on sql server core, but has also done various BI  ETL projects. He gets his kicks out of Columnstore indexes  tuning queries but shivers at the sight of an SSAS cube.

When Stijn is not working with SQL Server, you can probably find him enjoying the local cuisine  local beers or enjoying time with his wife and his dog.</description>
      <twitter>SQLStijn</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/stijn-wynants-ba528660?trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://swyssql.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLStijn</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66886</importID>
      <name>David Barbarin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Barbarin is Consultant at dbi services. He has more than ten years of experience in Microsoft solutions. He is specialized in SQL Server technologies and associated topics such as installation, migration, security audits, troubleshooting of performance issues, or high availability architectures etc. David Barbarin is SQL Server MVP (since 2010), Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) for SQL Server, and Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT).</description>
      <twitter>mikedavem</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://fr.linkedin.com/in/mikedavem/en</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.dbi-services.com/index.php/blog/dbi-bloggers/blogger/listings/dab</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mikedavem</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>64737</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64737</id>
          <name>Paul Bertucci</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1 - DBA  Cloud-DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA  Cloud-DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>High Availability and Disaster Recovery on SQL Server, Azure and beyond</title>
      <description>Do you need five 9's or greater of up time? High Availability of applications and databases are rapidly becoming the "norm" around the globe. Clearly one of the hottest topics in the world to fully understand and to plan for.  Mr. Bertucci will reveal a complete methodology around High Availability and present several  architecture and technology solutions to HA that he showcases in his new Book (MS SQL Server 2016 High Availability Unleashed!).  He will also cover Disaster Recovery options and Business Continuity considerations along the way. In particular, this presentation covers assessing, planning, choosing, implementing and administering a high availability solution along with the business justifications of different approaches to achieve high availability (Coverage includes MS SQL Server options such as AlwaysOn and Availability Groups, Azure/AWS options, and Big Data HA architectures and hybrid solutions).</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64742</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64742</id>
          <name>Isabelle Van Campenhoudt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2 - BI  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI  Analytics</name>
      </location>
      <title>Turn insight into action using Microsoft Flow and Power BI</title>
      <description>By combining the power of Power BI data alerts with the hundreds of actions available for Flow, we’re making it easier than ever to go from insight to deep, meaningful action.

Microsoft Flow is a SaaS offering for automating workflows across the growing number of applications and services that business users rely on. You can set up Flows to take care of the important, repeating tasks that take place daily in your organization. For example, you can create a Flow to text you via SMS when your manager sends you an e-mail marked as  “high importance.” Or, automatically create a to-do item in Wunderlist when a customer e-mails your support line.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66750</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66750</id>
          <name>Christophe Laporte</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1 - DBA  Cloud-DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA  Cloud-DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Les bases du dépannage SQL Server</title>
      <description>SQL Server, base de données la plus vendue en nombre de licences, reste relativement facile à administrer, tout en offrant un niveau de performance de premier ordre et une fiabilité excellente. Combien de "pannes" avec vous eu lors des 5 ou 10 dernière années ? Attention, ne me faites pas dire que l'on peut se passer des systèmes de haute disponibilité, FCI ou groupes de disponibilité. Il suffit de déterminer le RPO et le RTO et de monnayer l'indisponibilité du serveur pour déterminer si une stratégie de disaster recovery suffit, ou bien s'il faut prévoir la mise en haute disponibilité des ressources SQL.
Au final, le logiciel est fiable et ne provoque que très rarement des erreurs, des "plantages". 
Par contre, au quotidien, cela ne veut pas dire qu'il ne va pas y avoir de problèmes sur l'instance, principalement de connexion, d'autorisation ou de performance.
Au cours de cette session, nous allons aborder les bases du diagnostic et du dépannage SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67653</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67653</id>
          <name>Wolfgang Strasser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>3 - Dev  Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Dev  Data</name>
      </location>
      <title>Scale-Out your SSIS Package Executions</title>
      <description>With a rising number of parallel SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) package executions the resource requirements on the SSIS server can be a limiting factor. In older SQL Server versions, scale-out architectures needed to be implemented by hand and required a lot of manual implementation effort. Beginning with SQL Server 2017, SSIS provides a built-in scale-out functionality for package executions. 
After the definition of scalability-types, the SSIS scale-out architecture and the involved system-parts are introduced. The attendees will learn the basics, get checklists and best practices when building up their own SSIS scale-out cluster. In addition to the configuration using SSMS other configuration options (command line, T-SQL,..) are presented. Behind the scenes information like logging, the programmability interfaces and configuration options will be shared.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69118</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69118</id>
          <name>Sébastien Pertus</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>3 - Dev  Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Dev  Data</name>
      </location>
      <title>Les nouveautés SAAS de la plateforme AZURE : Cosmos DB, MySQL et PostgreSQL as a service !</title>
      <description>Cette session sera divisée en 2 parties : Une première partie pour découvrir les deux nouvelles offres SAAS d’Azure, concernant les bases de données relationnelles MySQL et PostgreSQL.
Nous verrons ensemble quelles sont les possibilités qu’offrent ce nouveau mode de fonctionnement pour ces deux bases de données extrêmement répandues.
Dans une seconde partie nous aborderons une grosse nouveauté dans le mode No SQL, apportée par Cosmos DB, l’évolution majeure de Document DB, avec l’adjonction de nouvelles fonctionnalités de scaling et un nombreux choix de modèles de données.
Chacune de ses deux parties vous permettra d’avoir une vision globale des possibilités que peut apporter une solution basée sur une infrastructure cloud comme AZURE, tout particulièrement les garanties de PRA, qui sont souvent un point très important dans le management de nos structures de données.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67600</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67600</id>
          <name>Jean-Pierre Riehl</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2 - BI  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI  Analytics</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Lake : SELECT People FROM DataLake WHERE Happy = TRUE</title>
      <description>Discover Azure Date Lake through a complete demo : how to get insights from tons of text, photos and videos ? From different media files and raw data, we will analyze sentiment of characters and get valuable information in a Power BI dashboard, using Cognitive Services, CNTK, .NET and U-SQL.
This session will mainly showcase Azure Data Lake and U-SQL language. But demos will involve different tools like Azure Data Factory for data supply chain and orchestration, Azure SQL Datawarehouse for corporate data and also Azure Machine Learning and Power BI.
Even if this session is demo-driven, we won't omit to present you concepts and features of Azure Data Lake.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67354</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67354</id>
          <name>Joël Crest</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2 - BI  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI  Analytics</name>
      </location>
      <title>POWER BI PREMIUM : POUR QUELS USAGES ?</title>
      <description>Quelques mois après son annonce en General Availability, il est temps de revenir en détail sur l'offre Power BI Premium.

Présentée comme complémentaire des deux modes de licences actuels (Free et Pro), cette nouvelle offre adresse de nouveaux usages : quels sont-ils ? Pour quel public et quel type de clients ? Peut-on disposer de certains avantages de Power BI Premium sans avoir souscrit à l'offre ?

Autant de questions auxquelles je répondrai au cours de cette session.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67357</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67357</id>
          <name>Gregory Boge</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1 - DBA  Cloud-DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA  Cloud-DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Scale out dans la vraie vie</title>
      <description>Avec un nombre de batch requests par seconde qui augmente énormément et des connexions depuis le monde entier, on est obligé de distribuer les données sur plusieurs serveurs.
Ceci nécessite de faire des choix d'architecture, nous utilisons la réplication transactionnelle pour répondre à nos besoins mais ce n'est pas sans galère.
Dans cette session, j'essayerai de vous expliquer quelle est notre architecture et pourquoi nous sommes toujours on-premise, pourquoi nous utilisons de la double réplication transactionnelle, quelles sont nos problématiques et nos solutions (Intégration continue, déploiement, monitoring, migration de publisher, etc...).</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67712</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67712</id>
          <name>Cédric Charlier</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>3 - Dev  Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Dev  Data</name>
      </location>
      <title>Des graphs partout! Microsoft se prendrait-il pour Banksy?</title>
      <description>Jusqu'il y a peu, les graphs étaient les grands absents de l'écosystème data de Microsoft. Depuis peu ceux-ci envahissent l'espace de SQL Server mais aussi CosmosDB! Cette session traversera les différentes possibilités de graphs proposées par Microsoft depuis la clause MATCH de SQL Server en passant par le language Gremlin et la plateforme TinkerPop de CosmosDB. Des démos illustreront les différentes API et languages proposes par ces outils.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67352</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67352</id>
          <name>Charles-Henri Sauget</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2 - BI  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI  Analytics</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSAS Tabulaire - Optimisation</title>
      <description>Quel est la démarche à adopter lorsque nos requêtes sont lentes ? Nous verrons ensemble les outils à disposition du développeur, et comment les utiliser afin de trouver la source du problème (Modélisation, requête ...) afin d'améliorer les performances de nos requêtes.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67524</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67524</id>
          <name>Patrice Lamarche</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>3 - Dev  Data</track>
      <location>
        <name>Dev  Data</name>
      </location>
      <title>L'ALM pour les bases de données SQL Server grâce à Visual Studio, ReadyRoll et VSTS</title>
      <description>L'ALM n'est pas uniquement valable pour le code applicatif de vos applications .net (Windows, Web ou mobile) ! Encore souvent "oublié" et l'objet d'interventions manuelles, venez découvrir comment versionner vos bases de données SQL Server et déployer les mises à jour de schémas de vos BDD ainsi que de vos données via des processus d'intégration continue, et de déploiement continu. Tout ceci grâce à Visual Studio, ReadyRoll, et Visual Studio Team Services.

Vous en avez marre d'effectuer vos mises à jour de BDD manuellement avec des SQL Compare :), venez apprendre comment automatiser le tout de manière simple !</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64703</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64703</id>
          <name>Christian Cote</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>2 - BI  Analytics</track>
      <location>
        <name>BI  Analytics</name>
      </location>
      <title>Reporting Services 2016 and beyond</title>
      <description>SQL Server Reporting Services has been completely revamped in 2016. This session will talk about the novelties of this version and how it can be used In conjunction with Power BI. We'll also have some glimpse of how vNext will go further with Power BI to facilitate it's use in corporate environments.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64560</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64560</id>
          <name>Stijn Wynants</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1 - DBA  Cloud-DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA  Cloud-DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Real-Time Analytics: OLAP  OLTP in the mix!</title>
      <description>In this session we will talk about the Operational analytics possibilities using ColumnStore indexes with SQL Server 2016. This will be a deep-dive on how this works, and will give you an explanation on the new Columnstore features. We will also talk about the difference between hot  warm data, and how to make this fit for your environment.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66886</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66886</id>
          <name>David Barbarin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1 - DBA  Cloud-DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBA  Cloud-DBA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introducing SQL Server on Linux for DBAs</title>
      <description>Open source is definitely part of the Microsoft strategy. Indeed, you may run SQL Server either on a physical or a virtual machine, and recently on the top of Windows or Linux operation system as well. In this session, let’s see how Microsoft managed to move SQL Server on Linux and then let’s explore which features will be available in this new world.</description>
      <startTime>9/16/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/16/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>