<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #810 - Linz 2019</name>
    <startDate>1/18/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>175</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Sarajevo, Skopje, Warsaw, Zagreb</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatLinz</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Tabakfabrik Linz</name>
      <street>Peter-Behrens-Platz 10</street>
      <city>Linz</city>
      <state>Upper Austria, Austria</state>
      <zipcode>4020 Linz</zipcode>
      <longitude>14.298801</longitude>
      <latitude>48.3114449</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/972/EventSponsor_14605.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>838</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Austria</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.at</url>
      <imageURL>https://austria.pass.org/Portals/325/microsoft%20logo-lg-1x.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1909</importID>
      <name>webtelligence IT consulting GmbH</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.webtelligence-itc.net</url>
      <imageURL>https://static1.1.sqspcdn.com/static/f/1061143/27584209/1496646835533/logo_big_dbplus.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1792</importID>
      <name>ETC - Enterprise Training Center</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.etc.at</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1015/EventSponsor_14910.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1900</importID>
      <name>Quest Software Deutschland</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/de-de/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/917/EventSponsor_14232.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1448</importID>
      <name>oh22</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.oh22.net</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/950/EventSponsor_14467.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1726</importID>
      <name>Solisyon GmbH</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.solisyon.de/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/917/EventSponsor_13876.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1746</importID>
      <name>Trivadis AG</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.trivadis.com/de</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.trivadis.com/sites/all/themes/custom/img/header_logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2311</importID>
      <name>GRZ IT Center GmbH</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.grz.at/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.grz.at/eBusiness/services/resources/media/1077528498541834366-NA-1097265370012041770-1-42-NA.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1831</importID>
      <name>pmOne Analytics</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.pmone.com/unternehmen/pmone-analytics-gmbh/</url>
      <imageURL>https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/830749492483915780/oHkrtiy5_400x400.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>926</importID>
      <name>O'Reilly Verlag GmbH  Co. KG</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.oreilly.de</url>
      <imageURL>http://ssis-components.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/oreilly_logo_neu_rot_web_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85356</importID>
      <name>Alexander Arvidsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alexander is a principal solutions architect at Solution Xperts in Linköping, Sweden. Nobody really knows what it means to be a principal solutions architect, but he spends his days helping clients of all shapes and sizes to take better care of their data. 

He has spent the last 23 years toying with databases and related infrastructure services such as storage, networking and virtualization, occasionally emerging from the technical darkness to attend a Star Wars convention somewhere in the world.  

He is a frequent international speaker, a Data Platform MVP, podcaster, blogger and a Microsoft Certified Trainer, focusing on SQL Server, the Azure data stack and Power BI.</description>
      <twitter>arcticdba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexanderarvidsson</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.arcticdba.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arcticdba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86208</importID>
      <name>Thomas Martens</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thomas "Tom" Martens has been awarded as a MSFT Data Platform MVP and works as Lead Expert at b.telligent (www.btelligent.com). For 20+ years Tom delivers Business Intelligence, Data Warehousing and Analytics solutions. Tom helps organizations to become data driven by implementing self service Business Intelligence tools at enterprise scale. His current interest is about the visualization of data and applying analytical methods to small and large amounts of data. Tom is a regular speaker at the PASS User Groups, Power BI User Group, SQL Saturdays, the PASS Camp and also the SQL Server Konferenz.</description>
      <twitter>tommartens68</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tommartens68</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://minceddata.info</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=tommartens68</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85587</importID>
      <name>Mario Schnalzenberger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mario Schnalzenberger ist seit 20 Jahren in der IT-Industrie t#228;tig und hat sich in den letzten acht Jahren im Bereich Statistik und Big Data an der Universit#228;t und im Predictive Bereich besch#228;ftigt. Seit zwei Jahren ist er im cubido-Team und unterst#252;tzt die Kunden in diesem spannenden Umfeld. Mario hat Abschl#252;sse in Statistik, Volkswirtschaftslehre und Sozial- und Wirtschaftswissenschaften. Er unterrichtet seit 7 Jahren an der Universit#228;t Linz und anderen Hochschulen in #214;sterreich sowie der HTL Leonding. Er tr#228;gt regelm#228;#223;ig bei verschiedensten Konferenzen in den vielf#228;ltigen Themen der angewandten Statistik, Informatik und Big Data vor.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85975</importID>
      <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Broadbent is a Data Platform MVP and SQL Server MCM with more than 20 years of experience working with SQL Server and principal of SQLCloud, a consultancy specializing in concurrency control and highly available solutions. He is the founder of the UK's SQLSaturday Cambridge (its first and largest), SharePoint Saturday Cambridge, the Hybrid Virtual Chapter and the East Anglia SQL User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@retracement</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/retracement</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tenbulls.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@retracement</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86133</importID>
      <name>Oliver Engels</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Oliver Engels is CEO of oh22data AG, a Microsoft Gold Partner in Germany specializing in CRM and BI. His special interests are Azure, Data Governance and Integration, Visualisation Tools like SSRS, Power BI, Tableau, R, and SharePoint. He has worked with SQL Server since version 6.5 and is a founder and Board member of PASS Germany, a PASS Regional Mentor, and runs the Frankfurt PASS Local Group. For more than seven years he is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a Microsoft pTSP.</description>
      <twitter>@oengels</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ssis-components.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@oengels</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>87322</importID>
      <name>Ben Weissman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben Weissman has been working with SQL Server since SQL Server 6.5, mainly in the BI/Datawarehousing field. He is a Data Platform MVP, MCSE Data Management and Analytics, and a Certified Data Vault Data Modeler. He is also the first BimlHero Certified Expert in Germany and a co-author of  'SQL Server Big Data Clusters' and 'The Biml Book'.
Ben has been involved in more than 150 BI Projects and is always looking for ways to become more productive and make SQL Server even more fun!
Together with his team at Solisyon, Ben provides training, implementation and consultancy for SQL/BI developers and data analysts in upper-mid-market companies around the globe.</description>
      <twitter>bweissman</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://de.linkedin.com/in/weissmanben</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bweissman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86037</importID>
      <name>Björn Peters</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I've started with SQL Server 6.5 but only as a sys-admin and not as DBA. Later I'd worked as a full DBA with SQL Server 2000 and my love to SQL Server started. In 2015  I'd got more interested in SQL PASS and tried to speak for the first time... the main part of my job is to work as DB-Admin and solution architect but I'm trying to widen my horizons. In 2016 I've visited and volunteered at the German SQL Saturdays und SQLGrillen and since October 2016 I'm the organizer of Azure Meetup Hamburg.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sql_aus_hh</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bj%C3%B6rn-peters-b26b5813b/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sql-aus-hamburg.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sql_aus_hh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86768</importID>
      <name>Michael Roedeske</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael graduated from the State Academy for Data Processing in Boeblingen, Germany, as  State-Certified IT Specialist with a business information systems specialisation in 1998. In the first years of his career he was involved in IT infrastructure projects. Soon afterwards he moved into a commercial software environment. In the following years he assumed functions in this field as Technical Architect for Oracle,  Microsoft SQL Servers and Microsoft Dynamics AX further organisational and project management roles in business intelligence and software development projects. He founded webtelligence IT consulting GmbH as its Managing Partner in summer 2011 to provided professional Microsoft SQL server database platform services and products.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-roedeske</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85246</importID>
      <name>Damian Widera</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server MVP amp; MCT
Software engineer with 18+ years of professional experience in all aspects of software development.
Damian participated in a number of projects in international environments and possesses practical knowledge of procedures and tools which are necessary for successful implementation of such projects.
Now he focuses on building solutions based on Microsoft SQL Server environment (including complex database driven systems, database tuning and optimization).</description>
      <twitter>@DamianWidera</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/damian-widera-0b56284</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://codingfamily.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DamianWidera</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85307</importID>
      <name>William Durkin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>William Durkin is a DBA, Data Platform MVP, and Data Platform Architect for Data Masterminds (http://datamasterminds.io). He uses his decade of experience with SQL Server to help multinational corporations achieve their data management goals. Born in the UK and now based in Germany, William has worked as a Database Developer and DBA on projects ranging from single server installations, up to environments spanning 5 continents, using a range of high availability solutions. William is a regular speaker at conferences around the globe, organizes the popular event SQLGrillen (http://sqlgrillen.com).</description>
      <twitter>@sql_williamd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/wdurkin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://williamdurkin.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sql_williamd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86189</importID>
      <name>Mikael Wedham</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mikael Wedham is the first SQL Server MCM in Sweden and the only one who also is a Microsoft Certified Trainer. He has been paid to do things in SQL Server since 1993. His long experience makes him an appreciated speaker at events and conferences all over Europe. To be prepared for deep dives, he is also certified as an Open Water Scuba Instructor.</description>
      <twitter>@wedham</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.wedham.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@wedham</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85190</importID>
      <name>Bartosz Ratajczyk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Database developer and (sometimes) administrator working with SQL Server Data Platform. Currently focusing on ETL development, delivery automation using TFS, query tuning, SQL Server training. Data Community Poland (DC) member, local group and conference speaker.</description>
      <twitter>@b_ratajczyk</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pl.linkedin.com/in/bartoszratajczyk</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.bartekr.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@b_ratajczyk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86052</importID>
      <name>Asgeir Gunnarsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ásgeir Gunnarsson is a Data Platform MVP and Chief Consultant at Datheos in Denmark. He works on Business Intelligence solutions using the whole of the Microsoft BI stack. Ásgeir has been working in BI since 2007 both as a consultant and internal employee. Before turning to BI, Ásgeir worked as a technical trainer and currently teaches BI courses at the Continuing Education Department of the University of Iceland. 

Ásgeir speaks regularly at events both domestically and internationally, and is the group leader of the Icelandic PASS Group, as well as the Icelandic Power BI User Group. 

Ásgeir is passionate about data and loves solving problems with BI.</description>
      <twitter>bidgeir</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://is.linkedin.com/in/asgeirgun</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bidgeir</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86218</importID>
      <name>Johan Ludvig Brattås</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Johan Ludvig Brattås is a managing consultant at Capgemini, and a dedicated community guy. He has worked with MS SQL server since late 1999, mostly with BI in one form or another. The last 6 years, most of his work has been in Azure working on data platforms, Power BI and the last three years expanding to Azure IoT and Stream Analytics.

Combining his passion for Microsoft SQL Server with his passion for sharing knowledge, he has spoken at various events in the SQL Community. This is also a way to give back to the community for all the things he has learned over the years. When not working, Johan Ludvig either spends his time with his kids, playing with new technology, or teaching coeliacs how to bake glutenfree food.</description>
      <twitter>intoleranse</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/johanludvig/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://brattas.org/sqlmusings</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=intoleranse</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86211</importID>
      <name>Marcos Freccia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Currently working as a Microsoft SQL Server DBA at Zalando SE, Marcos has over 9 years of SQL Server experience, working from small to enterprise environments with High Availability, Disaster Recovery, Database Optimization, etc.. Holding several Microsoft certifications such as: MCITP DBA  DEV, MCSE Data Plataform and his last certification on Microsoft Azure Design and Implement Cloud Data Platform Solutions. In 2013 Marcos was awarded as a Microsoft MVP by his contributions in the Brazilian SQL Server community. Marcos is a frequent speaker in the SQL Server Community and he was the organizer of the first SQL Saturday in South Brazil.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlfreccia</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://br.linkedin.com/in/marcosfreccia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://marcosfreccia.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlfreccia</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86646</importID>
      <name>Suha Güngören</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mag. Suha Güngören studierte Betriebswirtschaft mit Schwerpunkt Rechnungswesen, Unternehmensfinanzierung und Kapitalmärkte und ist seit 1995 als Trainer tätig. 
Seit 1998 ist er Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT). Seine Spezialgebiete sind Datenbanken, Business Intelligence und SharePoint als Präsentationsmedium. 
Weitreichende Erfahrungen konnte er aus einer Vielzahl an Projekten innerhalb der unterschiedlichsten Branchen sammeln. Die Mehrheit dieser Projekte hatten den Bereich Datenbanken im Projektfokus.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85892</importID>
      <name>Frank Geisler</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Frank Geisler is owner and CEO of GDS Business Intelligence GmbH. He is SQL Server MVP, MCT,  MCSE – Business Intelligence, MCSE – Data Plattform and MCSE - Azure Solutions Architect. In his Job he is building Business Intelligence Systems based on Microsoft Technology, mainly on SQL Server and SharePoint.</description>
      <twitter>@Frank Geisler</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=4839367</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gdsbi.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Frank Geisler</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86127</importID>
      <name>Gabi Münster</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gabi Münster is working as a Business Intelligence consultant and team lead and brings in her experience with SQL Server, data warehousing, relational and multidimensional database design and implementation, report and dashboard design, and Master Data Services, as well as project management into the community as a regional PASS Local Group lead. She is also passionate about motivating other women to start a technical career and therefore initiates and supports "Women in Technology" events. Apart from SQLSaturdays, she also spoke at SQLBits, SQL Nexus, Tuga IT, and 2015's and 2017's PASS Summit. In October 2017 Gabi received her first Data Platform MVP award.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLMissSunshine</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabimuenster/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLMissSunshine</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85165</importID>
      <name>David Postlethwaite</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Postlethwaite has been a DBA for Liverpool Victoria in Bournemouth, England since 2008
He supports both Oracle and SQL Server from 2000 to 2017, DBMS, SSIS, SSAS and Reporting Services.
In 2015 David built and deployed the company's first cloud solution using Microsoft Azure SQL Database and web services 

Before becoming a DBA David was a .NET developer and way back in history a Windows and Netware administrator. 

He is an occasional blogger on www.gethynellis.com

David is a regular speaker for SQL Saturday.
Most of his presentations can be found on his YouTube channel www.youtube.com/c/DavidPostlethwaiteSQL</description>
      <twitter>@postledm</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidpostlethwaite</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gethynellis.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@postledm</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85181</importID>
      <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server DBA with over 10 year's experience. Originally from Wales but now living in Ireland</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewpruski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbafromthecold.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86099</importID>
      <name>Markus Schröder</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Schröder works as a principal systems consultant at Quest Software in Cologne in the information management business unit. He works since 1994 with relational databases and focused since 2001 on performance and availability management.
Before he joined Quest in 2001 he worked as a consulltant at Oracle, Sysbae and BMC Software.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85151</importID>
      <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dejan Sarka, MCT and Data Platform MVP, is an independent trainer and consultant that focuses on development of database and business intelligence applications. Besides projects, he spends about half of his time on training and mentoring. He is the founder of the Slovenian SQL Server and .NET Users Group. Dejan Sarka is the main author or co-author of eighteen books about databases and SQL Server. Dejan Sarka has also developed many courses and seminars for Microsoft, Radacad, SolidQ, and Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>DejanSarka</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/dsarka/Home.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DejanSarka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>86161</importID>
      <name>Martin Pöckl</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin Pöckl has been a technology advisor for the Microsoft data platform in the enterprise customer and partner segment at Microsoft Austria since 2008. His technological focus is mainly on Microsoft SQL Server, Power BI as well as Azure Data and Analytics Services covering business-critical applications, business intelligence, data warehousing, big data and IoT projects.
Prior to joining Microsoft, he gained 10 years of experience in the IT sector including technical project and product management at a financial services software vendor and as a software design manager at Ericsson Austria.
As a founding member of PASS Austria he actively engages in the SQL Server community with regular lectures and discussion groups.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/mpoeckl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mpoeckl/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/mpoeckl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>85185</importID>
      <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen, as the founder of Savory Data, has a long history of providing customer solutions in the areas of data engineering, data science, and Business Intelligence. He is a certified software engineer, a graduated business educator, and professor of Databases  Project Management at HTL Leonding, and is certified as an MCSE  MCT. He is a published author and writes articles for well-known journals. He co-founded PASS Austria and organizes SQLSaturdays in Austria. Markus is a founding member of Power BI Usergroup Austria. Since 2017 Markus was awarded as an Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>MEhrenmueller</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markus-ehrenmueller/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.savorydata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MEhrenmueller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>85165</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85165</id>
          <name>David Postlethwaite</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud (Application Development  Deployment)</track>
      <location>
        <name>ETC</name>
      </location>
      <title>Shard Attack - Horizontal Scaling in Azure SQL Database</title>
      <description>Traditionally, when a server starts to reach its limit we have simply thrown more resources at it, either more CPU, memory or disk. 
However there comes a point, especially in the cloud, where it is no longer possible to add more resources to a single database.  Here we need a different solution.
Instead of scaling up we must scale out, sometimes called horizontal scaling or sharding.
 
In this talk we will look at how to scale out in Microsoft Azure SQL database using the Azure Elastic Database tools
We will look at the requirements and options for horizontal scaling in Azure and then we will have a go at sharding an Azure SQL database and then querying and updating the different shards
We will be using t-sql, PowerShell and c# so come prepared for some serious coding</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85151</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85151</id>
          <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI (Architecture, Advanced Analytics, Visualization, Information Delivery)</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBPro</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2017: Data Science with Python or R?</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 brought support or the R language. SQL Server 2017 added a new language to the list, the Python language. Both languages target advanced analytics scenarios, popularly known as data science. For a SQL Server professional who wants to move in the data science area, the first question is which language to choose. In this presentation, you will learn basics about both languages. We will try to solve the same problem with both languages. This way, through demos with a lot of explanation, you will realize the most important differences between the two competing languages. You will understand which one is more appropriate for you to start with.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86127</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86127</id>
          <name>Gabi Münster</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud (Application Development  Deployment)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Quest</name>
      </location>
      <title>FROM DATA LAKE TO DAX QUERY</title>
      <description>Collecting data from and combining data out of different data sources is the essential requirement for BI. In times of cloud services this is getting a lot easier.
Azure offers a variety of services that work hand in hand and can be fully automated using PowerShell or.NET.

In this session we will show an example of how data from various sources such as FTP, databases or streaming data can be loaded via ADF and processed in Azure Data Lake.

But getting the information out of Azure Data Lake still requires a special skill set and doesn‘t allow for usage by the broader audience or standard visualization tools. This is a typical requirement of Azure Analysis Services.

But how to implement the model? Can this even be automated in a way?
We will present you one approach to accomplish this.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85307</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85307</id>
          <name>William Durkin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (Platform, Architecture)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Store without SQL 2016 = Open Query Store</title>
      <description>When SQL Server 2016 was released, it offered a fantastic new feature with the Query Store. Long term, statistics based, query tuning became a reality. But what about the thousands of servers that aren't upgrading to SQL 2016 or newer? The open source project Open Query Store is designed to fulfill that need.

This session will give a short introduction to the Query Store feature in SQL 2016 and then dive into the Open Query Store (OQS) solution. William (co-creator of the OQS project) will explain the design of OQS and demonstrate the features. You will leave this session with an understanding of the features of Query Store and Open Query Store, and a desire to implement OQS in your systems when you return to the office.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86099</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86099</id>
          <name>Markus Schröder</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (Platform, Architecture)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Quest</name>
      </location>
      <title>Der moderne DBA in einer heterogenen Datenbankwelt: Performance- und Verfügbarkeitsüberwachung</title>
      <description>Die Überwachung der Datenbankperformance und der Verfügbarkeit war schon immer ein essentieller Bestandteil der täglichen Administration.  Neben den klassischen Systemen wie dem SQL Server etablieren sich auch Open Source-Lösungen und NoSQL Datenbanken am Markt und gewinnen an Bedeutung in der Unternehmensinfrastruktur. Die steigende Zahl von Datenbanken, für die ein DBA verantwortlich ist und die verschiedenen Architekturen, machen eine zentrale und einheitliche Überwachung von Performance- und Verfügbarkeitsmetriken unumgänglich. Wir diskutieren die Probleme und Lösungsansätze, um einen Teil der Arbeit für DBAs zu erleichtern.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85190</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85190</id>
          <name>Bartosz Ratajczyk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Quest</name>
      </location>
      <title>Start testing your SSIS packages with ssisUnit</title>
      <description>How do you test your SSIS packages? Do you prepare them, set the parameters and variables, maybe get some sample or production data and run few times by hand in SSDT? It’s not a bad practice when you start your ETL journey, but after some time you probably think about automation. If not – you should. Perhaps you have some SQL scripts that verify data in the tables after package execution, but if you are like me, somewhere inside you feel that it’s not enough. It’s time you start automated SSIS unit and integration testing.

On this session, I will show you how to start with automated testing of the packages and the whole projects using ssisUnit – the free SSIS testing library. I will start with some basics and move forward to the real-life examples of the unit and integration testing of the SSIS packages/ projects/solutions. You will see the benefits of automated testing and that testing is hard only at the beginning.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85356</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85356</id>
          <name>Alexander Arvidsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (Platform, Architecture)</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBPro</name>
      </location>
      <title>Headless chicken - calming the sysadmin that turned DBA</title>
      <description>Last night you went to bed as a sysadmin, but today you are realizing with a rising dread that you have woken up as a DBA. It sounds like a bad dream, but it doesn't seem to go away. Maybe the previous DBA won a million bucks and quit on the spot or was hit by a bus and will spend the next couple of months in the hospital; the fact remains that you're now THE DBA. It really doesn't matter if you have a single database on-prem or thirty in the cloud - you've pulled the short straw and you quickly need to get up to speed. This session is a fast-paced, exciting and fun database primer for sysadmins. You will learn how to best feed and care for your new toy, where to scratch, where to kick and most importantly - what never to do. Bring me your fear and despair and I will give you the confidence needed to continue your new DBA journey.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86037</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86037</id>
          <name>Björn Peters</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud (Application Development  Deployment)</track>
      <location>
        <name>ETC</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Get Started with Azure Managed Instance</title>
      <description>This session will be about how to start with Azure Managed Instances and what you'll need to know before.

Showing and explaining how you to steer around all the cliffs and make sure everything works smoothly.

It is about the features and why it might save you costs and make the life of your admin much easier by using Azure Managed Instances. Showing how to deploy, connect and migrate your application data. 
After this session, you'll understand this great database a bit better and know how to deploy it via portal and Powershell and why it a step ahead.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86211</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86211</id>
          <name>Marcos Freccia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (Platform, Architecture)</track>
      <location>
        <name>ETC</name>
      </location>
      <title>My 10 favorite PowerShell commands</title>
      <description>As a DBA I am always trying to automate the tasks that I have to do. In this session, I want to show you 10 Powershell commands that will make your life easier and increase your productivity. 
I promise that at least one new thing you will learn it</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86133</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86133</id>
          <name>Oliver Engels</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI (Architecture, Advanced Analytics, Visualization, Information Delivery)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Quality matters! Go for a quality roundtrip in the MS data platform</title>
      <description>In the times of data explosion, a dazzling array of information streams and unbelievable possibilities of different techniques to manage data via the Microsoft Data Platform, this session asks the question: what about data curation? 
We dive into the requirements of modern curation and show in examples, what the Microsoft Data Platform has to offer: Can SQL Server Master Data Service (MDS), Data Quality Services (DQS) and Integration Service (SSIS) especially with the integration in ADF help? Which options offers the Azure Data Catalog and how does the Microsoft Common Data Service come into play? We also look at the potential of the new integrated languages in the Data Platform like R or U-SQL. At the end of this session you will have an overview and understanding of the possibilities, that Microsoft Data Platform offers you to address your data curation requirements.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86052</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86052</id>
          <name>Asgeir Gunnarsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI (Architecture, Advanced Analytics, Visualization, Information Delivery)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Quest</name>
      </location>
      <title>Enterprise Power BI – Development Lifecycle</title>
      <description>When your development team is up to a certain size, and often no matter what size it is, you want to start following best development practices. 
These include things like source control, multiple environments, deployment processes, and governance. 

As Power BI content is developed using Power BI Desktop and not Visual Studio as most Microsoft BI solutions are, these things can get tricky. In this session we will look at what Power BI has to offer when it comes to development lifecycle. 
We will look at the different options available to the developer when it comes to source control, multiple environments, deployment and distribution of Power BI content. Lastly, we will look at governance and see how it is possible to secure the content and audit the usage of Power BI. 

For all these topics we will look at the capabilities Power BI offers and how we, in the company where I work, decided to implement it.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86218</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86218</id>
          <name>Johan Ludvig Brattås</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud (Application Development  Deployment)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Quest</name>
      </location>
      <title>Don't Cross the Streams! A Closer Look at Azure Stream Analytics</title>
      <description>Azure is ready to receive all your event and device data for storage and analysis. But which options in the Azure message handling portfolio should you use to receive and manage your data? In this session I will explain the different options, take a closer look at how they work and what this means for you. Furthermore, I will take a closer look at the Azure Stream Analytics (ASA) language. You will learn how to develop both simple and complex ASA queries, and how to debug. We will look at the possibilities, limitations and pitfalls in the Azure Stream Analytics language. And finally, look at the different input and output choices and when to use which one. This includes a look at how to build a live stream dashboard with Stream Analytics data in PowerBI. The session is based on real world project experiences and will use real world data in the demos.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86208</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86208</id>
          <name>Thomas Martens</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI (Architecture, Advanced Analytics, Visualization, Information Delivery)</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBPro</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Data Modeling</title>
      <description>This session explains why data modeling is so important even if Power BI utilizes the in-memory columnar xVelocity engine or simply SSAS Tabular. Different data modeling approaches are compared from a performance point of view, but also the complexity of DAX measures is compared that are incorporated in different data models. 
New data modeling features like many-to-many relationships and aggregations have been released during the last months. This session demonstrates how these features can be used to solve complex problems and how these techniques can be used on top of large amounts of data.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85892</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85892</id>
          <name>Frank Geisler</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Quest</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Studio - The new kid in town</title>
      <description>On PASS Summit 2017 Microsoft revealed a new tool for managing and developing SQL Server: Azure Data Studio. In his demo packed session German Data Platform MVP Frank Geisler will show how to use SQL Operations Studio, what is new compared with SQL Server Management Studio and he will show what capabilites this tool has not only to develop SQL Server Solutions but also how to monitor a SQL Server with Azure Data Studio. By the way: One of the biggest advantages is that Azure Data Studio is not only available for Windows but also for Mac and for Linux.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85587</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85587</id>
          <name>Mario Schnalzenberger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI (Architecture, Advanced Analytics, Visualization, Information Delivery)</track>
      <location>
        <name>ETC</name>
      </location>
      <title>Woodworks on Azure ML Workbench</title>
      <description>As an integrated, end-to-end data science and advanced analytics solution Azure ML services helps data scientists prepare data, develop experiments, and deploy models at cloud scale. Azure ML Workbench is, as a part of it, a desktop application plus command-line tools offering access to the services. As such you can use it to develop ML-solutions for the cloud on premises. It integrates with many IDEs, Jupyter Notebooks, aso. 

We will go through two experiments to classify raw data and image data using PYTHON and the Azure ML stack.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86161</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86161</id>
          <name>Martin Pöckl</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>Let's build an end-to-end IoT solution - from Edge to Cloud</title>
      <description>Building an IoT solution from scratch can be difficult and might require a lot of development effort. Using the building blocks of Microsoft's Azure IoT and Data services things get much easier. The Azure IoT Solution Accelerators let you build your IoT solution in a few hours instead of days and weeks.

This demo-heavy session is for the cast and crew of developers that make any IoT solution work for its intended audience. It's a guide not just to the “Things”, but to their secure connection to the “Internet” that powers every IoT solution and the analytics that allows you to gain insight from your data.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85246</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85246</id>
          <name>Damian Widera</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud (Application Development  Deployment)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>U-SQL in great depth</title>
      <description>I would like to invite to the session about Microsoft Azure Data Lake and the USQL. I would like to show how quickly you can do data analysis using traditional C# and a new language that is a bit similar to the TSQL. I will also show more complicated things  -how to run Python and R scripts to perform even more robust analysis</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 3:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 4:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85181</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85181</id>
          <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud (Application Development  Deployment)</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBPro</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Containers</title>
      <description>As containers are becoming more and more prevalent, this session provides an introduction to the different options of running containers in Azure. 

I'll cover the following different options for running Docker containers in Azure: 
Azure Container Registry
Azure Container Instances 
Azure Container Services (AKS) 

This session is aimed at SQL Server DBAs and Developers who have some experience with Docker (Docker for Windows) and want to know the different options that are available in Azure. 

Each topic will be backed up with demos which will show how simple it is to get up and running with these technologies.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85975</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85975</id>
          <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>Persistence is Futile - Implementing Delayed Durability in SQL Server</title>
      <description>The concurrency model of most Relational Database Systems are defined by the ACID properties but as they aim for ever increasing transactional throughput, those rules are bent, ignored, or even broken.

In this session, we will investigate how SQL Server implements transactional durability in order to understand how Delayed Durability bends the rules to remove transactional bottlenecks and achieve improved throughput. We will take a look at how this can be used to compliment In-Memory OLTP performance, and how it might impact or compromise other things.

Attend this session and you will be assimilated!</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86768</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86768</id>
          <name>Michael Roedeske</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (Platform, Architecture)</track>
      <location>
        <name>ETC</name>
      </location>
      <title>Anomalien Monitoring und SQL Abfragen-Analyse</title>
      <description>Algorithmen analysieren das SQL Server Datenbankverhalten nach Auffälligkeiten und Ausreißern. Sie visualisieren diese und geben Empfehlungen zur Optimierung. Langzeithistorie der Ausführungsstatistik und Planverwendung einzelner Abfragen sowie Plan Guide-Erstellung auf Knopfdruck. Tolle Innovationen für mehr Effizienz und mehr Erfolg beim SQL Server Query-Tuning mit dem intuitiven vollgrafischen DBPLUS Performance Monitor™.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>87322</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>87322</id>
          <name>Ben Weissman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI (Architecture, Advanced Analytics, Visualization, Information Delivery)</track>
      <location>
        <name>ETC</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2019 Big Data Clusters – a game changer?</title>
      <description>Big Data Clusters are probably the biggest feature in SQL Server 2019. They provide additional AI, ML, Scale Out and Data virtualization capabilities. But what does that mean? We will take a deeper look at the extended Polybase options (Data Virtualization) as well as the option to integrate and query Big Data in SQL Server with the use of Kubernetes Clusters, Notebooks and more!</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86189</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86189</id>
          <name>Mikael Wedham</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBPro</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Masters view on Query plans and indexing</title>
      <description>Do you find query optimization a mystery? This session will straighten out your question marks.
You will se how queries are run, how indexes are used and get an insight into what query plans tell you.
Further on you'll be introduced to In-Memory and Column Store indexing to get a fair chance of 
selecting appropriate indexing for your query load.</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>86646</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>86646</id>
          <name>Suha Güngören</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (Platform, Architecture)</track>
      <location>
        <name>DBPro</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data und Data Science</title>
      <description>Vorstellung Suha Güngören
Bedeutung von Big Data und Data Science 
Was kann man sich unter Data Science und Big Data vorstellen?
Prozesse Big Data und Data Science
Warum betrifft Big Data und Data Science auch Sie?
Der Microsoft Data Science  und Big Data Track
Big Data und Data Science Ausbildungsweg
Angebot: Hybride Ausbildung bei ETC – MPP DS und MPP BD
Q  A</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>85185</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>85185</id>
          <name>Markus Ehrenmueller-Jensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Administration (Platform, Architecture)</track>
      <location>
        <name>Microsoft</name>
      </location>
      <title>Lightning Talk</title>
      <description>Ana María Bisbé York - "Power BI + R, two scenarios in 10 minutes"
Matija Lah - “You dread talking to lawyers? Try designing their apps.”
Gianluca Sartori - "Benchmarking with WorkloadTools"
Oliver Engels - "10min Flash on Common Data Model"
Roman Lansky - "How much memory you need for your SSAS Tabular solution?"</description>
      <startTime>1/18/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>1/18/2019 9:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>