<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #1019 – Singapore – Virtual 2020</name>
    <startDate>11/28/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>150</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+08:00) Irkutsk, Ulaan Bataar</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatSingapore</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Singapore Office</name>
      <street>182 Cecil Street, Frasers Tower, Level 11 · Singapore</street>
      <city>Singapore</city>
      <state>, Singapore</state>
      <zipcode>069547</zipcode>
      <longitude>103.8474008</longitude>
      <latitude>1.2786632</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1781</importID>
      <name>Microsoft</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1019/EventSponsor_14912.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2678</importID>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://cloud.google.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1019/EventSponsor_14914.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2689</importID>
      <name>Red Hat</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://www.redhat.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1019/EventSponsor_14913.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2696</importID>
      <name>Melissa</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>http://www.melissa.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1019/EventSponsor_14915.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1951</importID>
      <name>dbWatch AS</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dbwatch.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1019/EventSponsor_14921.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108936</importID>
      <name>Gilbert Quevauvilliers</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Power BI  Data Analytics Consultant with over 12 years experience.

From small to enterprise implementations on Azure (Azure Analysis Services, Function Apps, Runbooks, Automation Accounts, SQL Serverless DB) and On-Premise Microsoft Platform (SQL Server, Integration Services, Analysis Services Multidimensional and Tabular, Reporting Services)

Recently I have focused on Power BI, with its rapidly changing features and incredible uptake it has allowed me to consult in a variety of different and challenging solutions.

I was awarded the Microsoft MVP award for Power BI since 2017.

I have spoken at the Microsoft Business Applications Summit (Seattle  Atlanta), Power BI World Tour,SQL Saturdays  other events.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/gilbertque</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/fourmoo/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.fourmoo.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/gilbertque</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108627</importID>
      <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Uwe Ricken is working with IT systems since the 90’s. The primary passion for developments with Microsoft SQL Server expanded in 2007 with his engagement as a DBA for Deutsche Bank AG in Frankfurt am Main. After 6 years of operational experiences as a DBA and over 14 years as a developer of complex database models he achieved the “Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008” certification which “was” the highest technical certification. In the same year he earned his first award as a Data Platform MVP for his support to the Microsoft SQL Server community in Germany and Europe. Uwe Ricken is a speaker on many international conferences and events and preferred topics are “Database Internals”, “Indexing” and “Development”.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dbBerater</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=270775013amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmaster.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dbBerater</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108595</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denny Cherry is the owner and principal consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates Consulting and has over a decade of experience working with platforms such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Microsoft SQL Server, Hyper-V, vSphere, and Enterprise Storage solutions. Denny’s areas of technical expertise include system architecture, performance tuning, security, replication, and troubleshooting. Denny currently holds several Microsoft Certifications related to SQL Server 2000 through 2019, including being a Microsoft Certified Master, Microsoft MVP and VMware vExpert Award.</description>
      <twitter>mrdenny</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrdenny</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.dcac.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mrdenny</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108632</importID>
      <name>Mohammad Asif Waquar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Asif is Microsoft MVP ,Microsoft Azure Platform .He specialises in Microsoft development, Blockchain, Mobile App and Cloud technologies. He works as Solution Architect at ABN AMRO Bank .He is certified in Corda and Hyperledger Development Framework for block chain. He has successfully implemented solutions for Trade finance on the Quorum Block chain.

He has completed his Masters in Software Engineering from NUS Singapore.Actively blogs at http://asifwaquar.com. Active in the developer community as public speaker, mentor etc. As an active member of SQL Server community and Azure Community, Asif leads Singapore SQL Server Pass Chapter (User group).</description>
      <twitter>asifwaquar</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-asif-6a6153111/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://asifwaquar.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=asifwaquar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108885</importID>
      <name>Eduardo Pivaral</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am an MCSE, MCSA SQL Server Database Administrator/Developer with experience in large environments.  
I have worked in IT for nearly 15 years in different areas. 

Currently dedicated to Administer Production, QA, Development SQL Server Databases, and components for all Microsoft supported versions.

Regular technical writer for different sources and developer/reviewer of Open Source tools for SQL Server database administration, development, and productivity.

Board member of PASS Guatemala SQL Server users group.
MSSQLTips.com Rookie of the year 2018</description>
      <twitter>EduardoDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/eduardo-pivaral/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlguatemala.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=EduardoDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108614</importID>
      <name>Dinesh Priyankara</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dinesh is an experienced professional and database enthusiast with skills in database management systems and business intelligence. Possessing over 18 years of experience on data related technologies, he does training, consulting, and is a top contributor to the local SQL Server community. In recognition of his contributions and expertise he has demonstrated, he was awarded the Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) award for SQL Server for 13 consecutive years since 2006.
He is a Subject Matter Expert on SQL Server exams and has contributed for SQL Server 2012, 2016, 2017 and Azure Data Engineering exam development and Job Task Analysis (JTA).
Dinesh is the Founder/Principal Architect of dinesQL (Pvt) Ltd (http://dinesql.com). In his</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/dinesh_priya</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://lk.linkedin.com/in/dineshpriyankara/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dinesql.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/dinesh_priya</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108799</importID>
      <name>Murilo Miranda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Murilo Miranda is a blogger, speaker and SQL Server MVP from Portugal. Nowadays he#39;s a Cloud Operations Engineer at DataStax. Murilo’s passion for working with people coupled with his honesty have helped him establish effective, meaningful relationships with his clients. When he isn’t working, he can be found enjoying life with his family, watching football and playing Playstation.</description>
      <twitter>murilocmiranda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pt.linkedin.com/in/murilomiranda/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=murilocmiranda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108601</importID>
      <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Koesmarno, MCSE Data Platform, and MCSE Business Intelligence, MCT, is a Senior Program Manager at Microsoft, with a Bachelor’s degree in IT. She has over 10 years of experience working with SQL Server for large-scale and multi-million-dollar OLTP and ETL projects as a SQL Server developer and system analyst/designer. Her past projects include delivering a SQL Server 2012 data warehouse and BI solutions in the US and Australia. She now works with hybrid, cloud and on-prem SQL projects.</description>
      <twitter>@mssqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliekoesmarno</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mssqlgirl.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mssqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108647</importID>
      <name>Alexander Arvidsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alexander is a principal solutions architect at Solution Xperts in Linköping, Sweden. Nobody really knows what it means to be a principal solutions architect, but he spends his days helping clients of all shapes and sizes to take better care of their data. 

He has spent the last 23 years toying with databases and related infrastructure services such as storage, networking and virtualization, occasionally emerging from the technical darkness to attend a Star Wars convention somewhere in the world.  

He is a frequent international speaker, a Data Platform MVP, podcaster, blogger and a Microsoft Certified Trainer, focusing on SQL Server, the Azure data stack and Power BI.</description>
      <twitter>arcticdba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexanderarvidsson</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.arcticdba.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arcticdba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108886</importID>
      <name>Martin Catherall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin is a data consultant in Melbourne, Australia, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, and PASS Regional Mentor for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region.
Martin founded the Christchurch, New Zealand PASS Local Group and lead the group for a number of years before relocating to Melbourne.
He has been using SQL Server in various roles since 2000. In addition to anything data related, he enjoys playing the guitar and having fun with his family.</description>
      <twitter>MartyCatherall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/martincatherall</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://martincatherall.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MartyCatherall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108618</importID>
      <name>Aroh Shukla</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Aroh works as a Microsoft partner, MVP in Data platform and a MCT. He is primarily focusing on SharePoint Online and Power BI. He helps the customers with their digital transformation journey through cutting edge Microsoft solutions.</description>
      <twitter>aaroh_bits</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/arohshukla/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aarohblah.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=aaroh_bits</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108790</importID>
      <name>Manohar Punna</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Manohar Punna is an Data Platform Geek and Vice President of DataPlatformGeeks by passion and a Data Platform Consultant by profession. He is a speaker at various conferences like PASS Summit, SQLBits, DPS. He has authored over 150 blogs and has written a One DMV a Day series which is a longest one day series on any topic on SQL Server till date.
Manohar is a product of this community and strongly believes in giving back to the community. So, ask him anything you would like to know and he is happy to learn it with you.</description>
      <twitter>ManuSQLGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/manohar-punna/15/153/508</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservergeeks.com/author/manoharpunna/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ManuSQLGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108756</importID>
      <name>Marco Russo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marco is a Business Intelligence consultant and mentor. He wrote several books about Power BI, Analysis Service, and Power Pivot. He also regularly writes articles and white papers that are available on sqlbi.com. Marco is a Microsoft MVP and an SSAS Maestro, the highest level of certification on Microsoft Analysis Services.
Today, Marco focuses his time with SQLBI customers, traveling extensively to train and consult on DAX and data modeling for Power BI and Analysis Services. Marco also teaches public classes worldwide.
Marco is a regular speaker at international conferences like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and SQLBits. He also enjoys delivering evening sessions at local user groups during his trips.</description>
      <twitter>marcorus</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlbi</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlbi.com/blog/marco</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=marcorus</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>109003</importID>
      <name>Dharmendra Keshari</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dharmendra Keshari has strong and in-depth experience in Database Management. Currently, working as Technical Specialist for Data Platform at Microsoft in Singapore and handling one of the most critical databases support for clients.

Dharmendra is an avid, regular mentor on social media, helping several enthusiast in solving their problems related to Database management. he is co-leader and regular speaker at Singapore SQL Server Pass Chapter (User Group). He has done certification for “Microsoft SQL Server#174; 2008, Implementation” and “Maintenance amp; Administering Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Database”.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://sg.linkedin.com/in/dharmendra-keshari-a7043398</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dharmendrakeshari.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108593</importID>
      <name>Stefano Tempesta</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stefano Tempesta is CTO at Connecting Software, Microsoft Regional Director and MVP, and advisor to the Department of Industry, Australia, on the National Blockchain Roadmap. His current focus is on helping people around the world gain and own their digital identity, with specific attention to the Education sector.
Stefano is also technology advisor at Carbon Asset Solutions, a climate action and sustainability network with a mission to slow carbon dioxide emissions and remove excess atmospheric CO2 by using regenerative agriculture technologies.</description>
      <twitter>stefanotempesta</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://linkedin.com/in/stefanotempesta</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.tempesta.space</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=stefanotempesta</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108612</importID>
      <name>Naginder Singh Virdi</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Naginder is currently working as Technical Architect. With years of proven IT enterprise architecture experience, Naginder has successfully led many innovative projects and technology initiatives which have resulted in efficient ecosystems. 

Naginder specializes in providing data driven solutions with Advanced Analytics, HA/DR solutions, performance optimization, consolidations. Has hands on experience in AI/BI, Azure Data Services. Past experience involves Database Administration and management, RD, Release cycles across multiple sectors like financial services and IT services.

Naginder’s acknowledged hands on experience in the IT industry has seen him speak at international conferences and level 400 trainings for microsoft clients</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/naginder-singh-virdi/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108745</importID>
      <name>Greg Low</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Greg Low is well-known in the SQL Server community as a mentor, trainer, author, and community leader. He is a certified master for SQL Server, was an instructor in that program, and holds a PhD in Computer Science. Microsoft often calls on Greg to develop data-related content, and to train their staff. He regularly speaks at tier-one conferences internationally. Greg is best known for his SQL Down Under podcast, SDU Tools, and his eBooks and whitepapers. He heads up a boutique consultancy called SQL Down Under in Melbourne Australia. Greg has been awarded as an MVP since 2001.</description>
      <twitter>greglow</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/greglow</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.greglow.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=greglow</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108629</importID>
      <name>Nisal Mihiranga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nisal Mihiranga is a Data enthusiastic and a BI Professional who has more than 8 years of exposure on Microsoft Business Intelligence stack and other data-driven technologies. He is very passionate about technologies like Microsoft SQL Server, SSIS, SSAS, Power BI and some other areas like advanced Analytics, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning etc. In his professional life he is working as a Business Intelligence Consultant at Fortude.  He shares his knowledge with the community by writing technical articles, blog posts and frequently speaking at tech conferences and community events. He also a Microsoft Certified Trainer.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/nisalm</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nisalm/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://nisalbi.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/nisalm</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108840</importID>
      <name>Edwin M Sarmiento</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Edwin M Sarmiento is the Managing Director of 15C, a consulting and training company that specializes in designing, implementing and supporting SQL Server infrastructures. He is a 12-year former Microsoft Data Platform MVP and Microsoft Certified Master from Ottawa, Canada (but he’s originally from the Philippines) specializing in high availability, disaster recovery and system infrastructures running on the Microsoft server technology stack. His background in Unix has taken him to the world of DevOps and Docker to containerize SQL Server. He is very passionate about technology but has interests in music, professional and organizational development, leadership and management matters when not working with databases.</description>
      <twitter>EdwinMSarmiento</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/edwinmsarmiento</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.EdwinMSarmiento.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=EdwinMSarmiento</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108611</importID>
      <name>Javier Villegas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Javier Villegas is a Database Administrator Manager for Mediterranean Shipping Company. Javier has more than 20 years working with SQL Server on every version from 6.5 to SQL Server 2019, Including SQL Azure Database and SQL Azure Managed Instance. His specialization is Administration, Performance Tuning and High Availability.
He is a Microsoft MVP in Data Platform.
Javier is a frequent speaker in conferences and events such as SQL Saturday , PASS Virtual Groups, 24 Hours SQL PASS , vOpen(NetConf), GroupBy and DataPlatformGeeks.
@sqlargentina</description>
      <twitter>https://www.twitter.com/javier_vill</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://ar.linkedin.com/in/javiervillegas</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sql-javier-villegas.blogspot.com.ar/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://www.twitter.com/javier_vill</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108704</importID>
      <name>M A A Mehedi Hasan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>This is M A A Mehedi Hasan working in EBS Group since 2005. Starting career as a Software Developer, I am now Chief Technology Officer (CTO) of EBS Group. In this long journey, I have got opportunity to work with various technologies like Microsoft Data Platform, Telecom Value Added Service, and Audio/Video streaming.

I have hands-on experience in managing Telecom Value Added projects, Web/App/Audio/Video streaming projects. Apart from these, I also manage large database, testing and deployment, performance tuning, long term capacity planning, and streamlining operational workflow.

Being a member of techforumbd,  I regularly speak and organize sessions at local and virtual PASS chapters, SQL Saturdays, and Azure conferences.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/m-a-a-mehedi-hasan-0956298a</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.techearth.xyz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>109220</importID>
      <name>Pio Balistoy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pio Balistoy is a Microsoft MVP  Certified Trainer for Data Platform. A SQL Server professional with more than 17 years of experience with SQL Server operations, architecture and administration. He brings his passion for SQL Server as the community leader for Singapore SQL PASS and Philippine SQL Server User Group. He is currently one of the Lead Microsoft Data Platform Consultant for The Pythian Services - a global IT product and services company with headquarters in Ottawa, New York, Sydney, UK and India.  He also co-founded Excent One Inc, a technology solutions company based in the Philippines and Singapore that helps SMEs integrate and develop Microsoft based business Applications.</description>
      <twitter>Pioisms</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/piobalistoy/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://lazysqlwriter.wordpress.com/; https://blog.pythian.com/author/balistoy/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Pioisms</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>108627</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108627</id>
          <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Red Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Daily indexing problems and its - possible - solution</title>
      <description>Have you ever been in the situation that an application performed well the last day and - suddenly - you run into problems? Although you have Index Maintenance jobs and statistics up to date you will monitor a big degrade of performance! This session will demonstrate in a over 80 percent demo based presentation the following scenarios which happend this way in real life!
- Why performance degradation in spite of maintenance jobs?
- just one more database in the result set and the query runs really bad - why?
- usage of literals is completely different from the usage of variables - why?
- identical data types but the query runs in part perfect and in part bad...
- your execution plan shows an INDEX SEEK - but the table will be scanned!
- you get a query from the business which performs really bad but when you test it it runs pretty cool - why?</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108936</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108936</id>
          <name>Gilbert Quevauvilliers</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Green Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>What is Tabular Editor and how can it help me with Power BI?</title>
      <description>Have you heard of Tabular Editor?
Tabular Editor provides an intuitive hierarchical view of every object in your Tabular Model metadata in an offline mode. This includes displaying everything in your data model (Columns, Measures, Hierarchies)
Tabular Editor is another tool you should have in your Power BI Toolkit. 

In this session I will cover the following items

	• The basics of Tabular Editor and its features.
	• Creation of Measures
	• Deployment to AAS
	• Special preview of Tabular Editor being used with Power BI Desktop
	• Automation options (Formatting All DAX Measures, Putting DAX Measures into Description fields)
	• Calc Groups
		○ Multiple measures 
		○ Currency format strings
	• Other tips and tricks
		○ Copy and paste also between pbix
		○ Move to new folders
		○ Best Practice Analyzer
	• Questions</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108595</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108595</id>
          <name>Denny Cherry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Purple Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Maintain the Same Level of Utilities in Cloud Deployments - Securability, Reliability and Sca</title>
      <description>In this session we will review the differences between deploying Microsoft SQL Server 2016 in Microsoft Azure and on-premises from a Security, Reliability and Scalability perspective. We'll review the common mistakes which people make when deploying SQL Server Virtual Machines to Azure which can lead to security problems including data breaches.  We'll review the common performance problems which people encounter, and how to resolve them. Finally, we'll review the common scalability misunderstandings of Azure and SQL Server Virtual Machines. Join us for this fun session and learn how to improve the security, reliability and scalability of your Azure deployments of SQL Server 2016.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108601</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108601</id>
          <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Red Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Kusto Query Language (KQL) in Azure Data Studio</title>
      <description>Join this session to learn more about the Kusto Query Language (KQL) experiences in Azure Data Studio. This is a quick overview session on how to get started with KQL in Azure Data Studio. You'll learn how to connect to Azure Data Explorer and Azure Log Analytics in notebooks. In this demo-filled session, you will also learn a practical example of analyzing Azure SQL database log stored in an Azure Log Analytics workspace.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108647</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108647</id>
          <name>Alexander Arvidsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Purple Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Untruthful Art - Five Ways of Misrepresenting Data</title>
      <description>In this age of information it is imperative to be able to be able to clearly, simply and accurately explain and communicate sometimes complex data. 
Right at the intersection of journalism and statistics lies visual communication - the art of using data, charts and maps to convey information. This has been called "the truthful art" as it is an extremely powerful tool that must be wielded with the utmost care. 
Just like any other tools, however, it can be used for sinister purposes. This session is all about exploring ways that data can be misrepresented to further a goal - while still seem perfectly reasonable. It is intended as an eye opener for anyone interested in the how and why of data deception. We will walk through five stories and explore where the trickery is hidden, discuss a more honest way to communicate the information as well as look at ways to spot potential foul play with data.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108614</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108614</id>
          <name>Dinesh Priyankara</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Purple Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Machine Learning Like Never Before - Azure Machine Learning Service</title>
      <description>Azure Machine Learning environment is enhanced, it has more features now, and it allows us to create our models with no-code, less-code or with code as well. Let's have a look on its components and features, and let's see how we can easily create a predictive analytics model.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108756</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108756</id>
          <name>Marco Russo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Green Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>My Power BI Report is Slow: What Should I Do?</title>
      <description>You created a wonderful Power BI report, but when you open it you wait too much time. Changing a slicer selection is also slow. Where should you start analyzing the problem? What can you do to optimize performance?

This session will guide you in analyzing the possible reasons for a slow Power BI report. By using Task Manager and DAX Studio, you will be able to determine whether you should change the report layout, or if there is something in DAX formulas or in the data model that is responsible for the slow response.

At the end of this session, you will understand how to locate a performance bottleneck in a Power BI report, so you will focus your attention on the biggest issue.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108799</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108799</id>
          <name>Murilo Miranda</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Green Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automating the deployment of Linux VMs with SQL Server through Ansible</title>
      <description>With the recent technological evolution caused by the growth of the cloud, as well as by the open-source revolution at Microsoft, new challenges and tasks have emerged. Functions such as Data Engineer and Cloud Engineer become more and more common and requested.
In an environment with high-scale needs and agility in the processes, it became imperative to use some kind of automation, in order to meet the demand in an intelligent and standardized way.
In this session, I will show you how Ansible can help us create VMs on Azure, adjust their settings and install a SQL Server instance. All of this in a scalable and consistent way. With the automation, you will be moved from lead actor to a mere spectator, but you will still be the protagonist :)</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108593</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108593</id>
          <name>Stefano Tempesta</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Red Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Secure multiparty Machine Learning with SQL Server Always Encrypted with Secure Enclaves</title>
      <description>Preserving privacy when processing data from multiple sources with machine learning is always a 
challenge. Organizations want to perform collaborative data analytics while guaranteeing the privacy of their individual datasets. Combining multiple data sources to support a better outcome improves accuracy of prediction, but it may come at cost of confidentiality, if sensitive information is not accurately protected.
SQL Server 2019 adds new data security capabilities with Always Encrypted with Secure Enclaves. By using trusted execution environments (TEEs) to protect your data while in use, you can use machine learning algorithms across different organizations to better train models, without revealing the processed data.
This session presents the benefits of Confidential Computing in an ML scenario, where separate health institutes collaborate on data analysis and prediction using Azure ML.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108618</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108618</id>
          <name>Aroh Shukla</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Green Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>SharePoint Data and Power Apps – Better Together</title>
      <description>Just imagine the day when you as a business user are managing tasks that is making you crazy. Today with SharePoint Online and Power Apps could make life easier for business users. In this session will see how SharePoint Online and Power Apps can provide assist you creating beautiful apps that can work on web, tablet and mobile without lining a single line of code.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108790</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108790</id>
          <name>Manohar Punna</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Purple Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deploy Azure SQL with Cloud IaC using Terraform</title>
      <description>In recent years, the cloud has been adopted by most companies. It offers greater flexibility in terms of infrastructure and resource management at a greater scale. Although, if not noticed the prices of maintaining this infrastructure and resources will blow through the roof.
DevOps and deployability of resources as needed have become even more critical with the cloud. Infrastructure as code is a necessity than a luxury. Terraform offer great IaC solution across multiple cloud vendors. In this session, I will explain the importance of infrastructure as code for cloud resources and introduce how Terraform can be used for building your multi-cloud IaC solutions for you SQL environments.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108629</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108629</id>
          <name>Nisal Mihiranga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Green Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Let's Make Semantic Models Simpler using Calculation Groups in SSAS Tabular</title>
      <description>Calculation Groups is a new feature introduced in DAX which can significantly reduce the calculation redundancy in a Semantic model. This great feature also useful when handling complex calculation requirements. Let's join with me to see how this feature can make the data models simpler yet powerful.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108840</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108840</id>
          <name>Edwin M Sarmiento</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Red Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Transaction Log and How It Affects HA/DR</title>
      <description>When choosing the appropriate SQL Server HA/DR solutions, it is important to understand the SQL Server Transaction Log as it affects any solution you choose. In this session, we will look at transaction log basics, how logging and recovery works and how it affects all of the HA/DR solutions available in SQL Server. You’ll be surprised to know that the transaction log is the most important part of your database.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108885</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108885</id>
          <name>Eduardo Pivaral</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Green Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL Basics: Coding for performance</title>
      <description>It is very common in the IT field for a developer to switch to a database developer/administrator role. Even when the programming concepts are the same, the skillsets required to properly code T-SQL are different.
 
In this session, we will learn some basic tips to improve our code and improve database performance from early application planning stages to existing production applications that require performance tuning.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108612</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108612</id>
          <name>Naginder Singh Virdi</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Purple Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Whats new with OSS Databases on Azure</title>
      <description>In this session, we will look at all the new announcements on the Open Source Databases platform on azure during the ignite this year.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108745</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108745</id>
          <name>Greg Low</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Red Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tips and Tricks for Using SQL Server Management Studio Effectively</title>
      <description>Most SQL Server developers and DBAs work with SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS) all the time. But SSMS is a very capable tool and most users only know how to use a fraction of its features. Greg has recently published an eBook that has been years in the making. Join Greg to see his favourite tips and tricks for working with SSMS.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>109003</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>109003</id>
          <name>Dharmendra Keshari</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Red Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Sneak Peek at SQL Server 2019</title>
      <description>Let's Play with SQL Server 2019 in 100% demo to explore many new capabilities
- Data Virtualisation with Polybase to reduce the need for data movement
- Secure Enclaves Security enhancements such as Always Encrypted | Data Classification
- Intelligent Performance to boost query performance with no application changes
- Accelerated Database Recovery
- Tempdb Contention Optimisation
- UserDB Contention Optimisation
- Others</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108632</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108632</id>
          <name>Mohammad Asif Waquar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Purple Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Blockchain It's all about Data !!</title>
      <description>In this session ,We are going to see how data plays a very important role in the Blockchain network . How we can manage data confidentiality without sacrificing the speed, throughput and integration to existing applications or services using Azure Blockchain Services. We will also explore how we can maintain off chain storage using SQL Server or CosmosDB and display Power BI reports.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108886</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108886</id>
          <name>Martin Catherall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Red Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Exploring Window Functions</title>
      <description>Window Functions first emerged with the 2005 release – and were enhanced in 2012.
They provide a window over the result set and the ability to access data other than the current row.
This means that somethings that may  - at first - seem like they need row-by-row processing can be done in one single set-based query.
The set of window functions available also includes server analytical functions that give the ability to perform statistical analysis.
Come along to this session and see a deep dive into window functions and learn how their use will add to your ability to process data and write more efficient – and cleaner – queries.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108611</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108611</id>
          <name>Javier Villegas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Green Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Monitoring SQL Server using Community solutions (Free)</title>
      <description>In this session we will cover how to monitor and support any SQL Server Environment using free tools created by community members</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108704</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108704</id>
          <name>M A A Mehedi Hasan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Purple Line</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to SQL SERVER 2019 ML Services</title>
      <description>Introduction to ML Services, brief history, installation, installation verification, running the Hello World Python script. Internal Architecture, running a predictive model and its deployment.</description>
      <startTime>11/28/2020 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/28/2020 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>