<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #852 - Finland 2019</name>
    <startDate>5/11/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Cairo</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatFinland</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Finland HQ</name>
      <street>Keilalahdentie 2-4</street>
      <city>Helsinki</city>
      <state>, Finland</state>
      <zipcode>02150 Espoo</zipcode>
      <longitude>24.8279642</longitude>
      <latitude>60.171334</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/852/EventSponsor_13719.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2367</importID>
      <name>Nordcloud</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://nordcloud.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/852/EventSponsor_13338.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2362</importID>
      <name>Invenco Oy</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.invenco.fi/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.invenco.fi/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Invenco-tiedolla-johtaminen-raportointi-analytiikka-suunnittelu-logo-uusi-092018.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1824</importID>
      <name>DB Pro Oy</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sqlgovernor.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlgovernor.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Sql_Governor_June2018/Image/Governor-logo-sivuteksti-valkoinen.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2413</importID>
      <name>Sovelto Oyj</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sovelto.fi/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/852/EventSponsor_13528.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/908/EventSponsor_14257.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2084</importID>
      <name>Enfo Oyj</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.enfogroup.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/852/EventSponsor_13625.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2359</importID>
      <name>Profit Software Ltd</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://profitsoftware.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/852/EventSponsor_13317.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92860</importID>
      <name>Ola Hallengren</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ola Hallengren is a database architect from Sweden. Currently he's working in an investment bank in Copenhagen.

Ola is the author of the popular maintenance solution at https://ola.hallengren.com and a Microsoft MVP.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/olahallengren</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://ola.hallengren.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93191</importID>
      <name>Mika Sutinen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mika Sutinen is a DBA Team Lead at Nordcloud with over two decades of experience from working in IT industry. For most of that time, SQL Server has had some role to play in his daily work. While Mika has done most of his career in the operations side of the business, he did spend couple years working in a product development organization in a role of a Product Owner. That experience was really and eye-opener for him and led him to become a believer in DevOps that succesfully includes databases.

Besides Microsoft data platform, Mika is a fan of the public cloud platforms. When not working he enjoys blogging, reading about data related technologies and science fiction in any form and shape.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLFinn</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mika-sutinen-6170821/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlstarters.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLFinn</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90175</importID>
      <name>Vedran Kesegic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vedran Kesegic is a Microsoft Certified Master for SQL Server, with Oracle background. With 14+ years enjoyed in exploration of SQL Server depths, developing smart algorithms, optimizing SQL Servers and SANs. He is the author of XDetails, Addin for SQL Management Studio that shows detailed info about indexes and other objects. He likes to hang out, share knowledge, and talk about more or less important things in life.</description>
      <twitter>@VedranKesegic</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://hr.linkedin.com/in/vedrankesegic</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.sqlxdetails.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@VedranKesegic</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89455</importID>
      <name>Dave Ruijter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave is Technology Consultant Data  Analytics and Microsoft MVP, bringing a decade’s worth of Microsoft Azure Data Platform and Power Platform experience to the table. He is a very passionate Power BI evangelist, eager to share his knowledge and experiences from the field.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/daveruijter</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/daveruijter</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://moderndata.ai</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/daveruijter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91762</importID>
      <name>Zhenbo Zhang</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Zhenbo is the cloud solution architect in Microsoft focusing on data platform and advanced analytics. He has extensive experience in software engineering and data analytics across different industries. Currently he is helping Microsoft's strategic global accounts in their digital transformation journey, unleashing the hidden value of data assets and modernizing the data platform.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90077</importID>
      <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>José Manuel Jurado currently works as SQL Escalation Engineer and Subject Matter Expert in Azure SQL Database at Microsoft Spain. With over 20+ years of experience in SQL Server environments (administration and database development), he is a speaker for internal events at Microsoft and for public events such as SQLSaturday, SQL Nexus, SQLBits, Pass Summit, SQL Server Konferenze, TechReady, DotNetConference, and Azure BootCamp. In the past, he worked as Project Manager for large global retail company for more than 10 years developing projects using different Microsoft Technologies.</description>
      <twitter>jmjuradodiaz</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-manuel-jurado-diaz-5a586014/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jmjuradodiaz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89206</importID>
      <name>Alexander Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alexander Klein is a senior Business Intelligence consultant with more than 15 years of experience. He focuses on Business Intelligence and Data Warehouse projects with Microsoft technologies like SQL Server, Power BI, Azure ML or Cortana Intelligence. 

Since 2008, he has been a self-employed consultant in large and medium-sized projects in all sectors across Europe. He has been visiting SQL Saturdays and other Data Conference all over Europe since 2013. Speaker at national and international events since 2017.</description>
      <twitter>@SQL_Alex</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-klein-13a04b3a</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQL_Alex</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89341</importID>
      <name>Oskari Heikkinen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have several years of experience in using Azure for data analytics at large scale. I have been implementing numerous projects for some of the largest companies in the Nordics.

I am a Microsoft MVP, and I currently hold the MCSE: Data Management and Analytics certification. As a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT), I hold classes for subject-matter experts and consultants internally as well as give external customer training sessions. I am also an active speaker on community events.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/oskariheikkinen/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88801</importID>
      <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server DBA with over 10 year's experience. Originally from Wales but now living in Ireland</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewpruski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbafromthecold.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DBAFromTheCold</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89138</importID>
      <name>John Martin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Martin is a Data Platform Engineer working in the financial sector, as well as Vice President Marketing for the PASS organization and currently a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Previously John has worked as a product manager for SentryOne and a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft UK.

John has over a decade of experience working with SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. Working as a DBA, developer and consultant for Microsoft, he has been lucky enough to see how best, and how not, to use SQL Server and the Data Platform effectively.</description>
      <twitter>SQLDiplomat</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/johnqmartin/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mssqltips.com/sqlserverauthor/291/john-martin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLDiplomat</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92061</importID>
      <name>Arun Justus</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have recently moved into a Global Account Executive role in the Telco Industry. My previous role was as Cloud Architect in Data Platform area working for Microsoft Finland. Prior roles at Microsoft include Big Data Advisor, Data Platform Solution Architect, Dynamics CRM Technical Lead and Business Intelligence Lead at Microsoft Western Europe Area level.

Past work experience is from SAP and Land Transport Authority, Government of Singapore.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88703</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89447</importID>
      <name>Daniel Hutmacher</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior database developer with a long-running passion for performance tuning on SQL Server. I run my own consultancy business where I help companies with database development, ETL work, performance tuning and technical training on SQL Server.
Board member of the Swedish SQL Server usergroup 2017-2019, organizer of SQL Saturday Stockholm, and co-organizer of GroupBy.org.</description>
      <twitter>@dhmacher</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://se.linkedin.com/in/danielhutmacher</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlsunday.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dhmacher</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92091</importID>
      <name>Jouko Nyholm</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Passion driven business-minded technology enthusiast building enterprise solutions using Microsoft Cloud with 10+ years of experience working as a consultant, project manager, architect and/or developer.

100+ implementations using Microsoft Power Platform, Data Platform, Dynamics 365, Office 365, Azure and related technologies for a large customer base consisting mainly of large enterprises.

Speciality Data Driven process implementations, governance consultation and trainings. Lots of domain specific expertise in e.g. sales  marketing processes.

Background as full stack lead developer/architect in multiple SaaS platforms. Productization expert, fan of lean  data driven product development processes.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/JoukoNyholm</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/joukonyholm/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/JoukoNyholm</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92058</importID>
      <name>Vesa Tikkanen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vesa is agile oriented architect from Finland. He is Microsoft Certified Master and MVP. He has passion towards Microsoft Data Platform including both relational and non-relational worlds! Vesa has been working with SQL Server since SQL Server 2000 and counts himself as DBA because he has seen corruption. :) Nowadays he spends his time with advanced analytics related workloads on cloud and on-premise. Vesa Blogs at http://www.qumio.com</description>
      <twitter>vesat</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://fi.linkedin.com/in/vesatikkanen/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.qumio.com/Blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=vesat</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88696</importID>
      <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Martorana Tusa is a Business Intelligence Team Manager at Würth Phoenix,  the IT and consulting company of the Würth-Group. 
He is awarded as MVP in the Data Platform category

Former BI Specialist at Widex, a Danish manufacturing company, and BI Developer in the IT department of an Italian banking group. 20+ years of experience working with data. 
He is focused on the entire BI stack: database development, data warehousing, data analysis, reporting, etc. 
Andrea is a usual speaker at many events: SQLSaturdays, conferences in Europe and PASS Summit, and for PASS Virtual Groups. 

Andrea is an author for sqlshack.com, sqlservercentral.com, and UGISS (User Group Italiano SQL Server).</description>
      <twitter>bruco441</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bruco441</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90863</importID>
      <name>Kevin Kline</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Kline is a database and industry expert serving as Principal Program Manager at SentryOne, the industry leading SQL Server database tools vendor. A Microsoft SQL Server MVP since 2003, he is a founder and former president of PASS. Kevin is an author of many books, blogger, columnist, and popular international speaker. Kevin’s best known book is the best-selling SQL in a Nutshell and contributes monthly to Database Trends  Applications magazine. He tweets at @kekline and blogs at http://Blogs.SQLSentry.com/Author/KevinKline.</description>
      <twitter>kekline</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kekline/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.sentryone.com/author/kevinkline</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kekline</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89453</importID>
      <name>Dave Ruijter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave is Technology Consultant Data  Analytics and Microsoft MVP, bringing a decade’s worth of Microsoft Azure Data Platform and Power Platform experience to the table. He is a very passionate Power BI evangelist, eager to share his knowledge and experiences from the field.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/daveruijter</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/daveruijter</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://moderndata.ai</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/daveruijter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89819</importID>
      <name>Marc Lelijveld</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Power BI enthusiastic, public speaker and passionated for everything which transforms data into action! Working at Macaw in the Netherlands as a Data  Analytics consultant.

What I like the most? Sharing my thoughts, experience, best-practices and enthusiasm about Power BI and related Microsoft Products with others. I mostly do this in public speaking for the user group, conferences, customer presentations and end-user training. But wouldn't it be great to cross borders and expand the community!</description>
      <twitter>@Marclelijveld</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://linkedin.com/in/marclelijveld</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://data-marc.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Marclelijveld</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90944</importID>
      <name>Jani K. Savolainen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have worked with databases and Microsoft SQL Server technology for the last 18 years. I have got extensive experience on e.g. software development, DW/BI, data science, SQL data platform, diagnostics  code optimization, and writing crypto graphical algorithms. I am also a chairman of the Finland PASS chapter "PASS Helsinki".</description>
      <twitter>@savolaisenjani</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://fi.linkedin.com/in/jani-k-savolainen-90446a13</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlgovernor.com/en/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@savolaisenjani</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90895</importID>
      <name>Rami Laine</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>About 7 years ago i decided to change my path. That decision led me to become SQL Server DBA.  Now after these years just sucking knowledge from the leaders, i think its my time to give something back to the community. Your feedback is highly appreciated to make my presentations better.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90997</importID>
      <name>Pinal Dave</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pinal Dave is a SQL Server Performance Tuning Expert and an independent consultant. He has authored 12 SQL Server database books, 30 Pluralsight courses and has written over 5000 articles on the database technology on his blog at a https://blog.sqlauthority.com. Along with 16+ years of hands-on experience, he holds a Masters of Science degree and a number of database certifications.</description>
      <twitter>pinaldave</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pinaldave</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blog.sqlauthority.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pinaldave</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89049</importID>
      <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erland Sommarskog is an independent consultant based in Stockholm, working with SQL Server since 1991. He was first awarded SQL Server MVP in 2001, and has been re-awarded every year since. His focus is on systems development with the SQL Server Database Engine and his passion is to help people to write better SQL Server applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sommarskog.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88876</importID>
      <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mihail Mateev is a technical consultant, community enthusiast, PASS Regional Mentor for CEE, chapter lead, Microsoft Azure MVP, Microsoft Regional Director. He works as a Senior Solutions Architect at EPAM Systems, focused on Data Platform, IoT and cloud related solutions. He also worked many years like a Technical evangelist in the Infragistics. Last years Mihail was focused on various areas related to technology Microsoft: Data Platform, Visual Studio, ASP.Net, Windows client apps, Data Platform, and Microsoft Azure. Michael also has a PhD in cloud computing area. He is a university lecturer on Smart Homes and Smart Energy IoT Solutions.</description>
      <twitter>mihailmateev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mihail-mateev/1/6b3/4b1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mmateev.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mihailmateev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91906</importID>
      <name>Pekka Korhonen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pekka is a SQL Server Database Specialist.

His current position is Consultant  Partner at Sovelto and Lead Architect at DB Pro. He is also co-founder of Sovelto which is a Microsoft Gold Learning Partner at Helsinki, Finland. He has been working with SQL Server since the version 1.1.

He has worked with many SQL Server Projects (OLTP and DW/BI) during the last 20 years. He has also conducted over a thousand SQL Server Courses in Finland (Admin, Programing, SSRS, SSAS, SSIS, MDX, DQS, MDS, Replication, HA, perf. tuning, Power BI, DAX, Machine Learning, Big Data etc.).</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>88695</importID>
      <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Martorana Tusa is a Business Intelligence Team Manager at Würth Phoenix,  the IT and consulting company of the Würth-Group. 
He is awarded as MVP in the Data Platform category

Former BI Specialist at Widex, a Danish manufacturing company, and BI Developer in the IT department of an Italian banking group. 20+ years of experience working with data. 
He is focused on the entire BI stack: database development, data warehousing, data analysis, reporting, etc. 
Andrea is a usual speaker at many events: SQLSaturdays, conferences in Europe and PASS Summit, and for PASS Virtual Groups. 

Andrea is an author for sqlshack.com, sqlservercentral.com, and UGISS (User Group Italiano SQL Server).</description>
      <twitter>bruco441</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bruco441</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>88696</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88696</id>
          <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Failure prediction for manufacturing industry with SQL Server  R</title>
      <description>Working in manufacturing industry means that you must deal with product failures. As a BI and/or Data Scientist developer, your task is not only monitor and report product’s health state during its lifecycle, but also predict the likelihood of a fail in the production phase or when product has been delivered to the customer. 
Machine Learning techniques can help us to accomplish this task.  Starting from past failure data, we can build up a predictive model to forecast the likelihood for a product to fail or giving an estimate on its duration. And now it is possible to develop an end-to-end solution in SQL Server, because of the introduction of advanced analytics tools like R since release 2016. 
In this session, we start from the real case of a manufacturing company to create some predictive models: a) Regression model ; b) binary and multivariate models. 
Binary or multi-class classification problem. Some reports are also created to deliver the outcome to the stakeholders.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88695</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88695</id>
          <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL advanced: Grouping and Windowing</title>
      <description>This session aims to explore all the features offered by the language T-SQL for aggregating and calculating data. There's much more of the clause GROUP BY.
With grouping and ranking functions you can calculate in your query grandtotal, running totals, find islands in intervals, select the last-not-null value, etc.
Windows functions apply directly on a set of rows defined by the OVER clause ("a window"). Windows function do not perform aggregation on group level and do not hide row details.
So they allow mixing detail and total elements in the same query.
The session is mainly based on a copious array of demos, to make explicit every concept introduced taking into account the impact on performances for every solution.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88876</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88876</id>
          <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Premium vs Power BI Embedded for Modern BI Solutions</title>
      <description>Power BI Premium introduces a new developer layer for embedding Power BI in custom applications, and a new on-premises deployment option as well. Microsoft Power BI Embedded applications enables developers to integrate Power BI reports into their web or mobile applications so they don’t need to build custom solutions to visualize data for the users. It helps Independent Software Vendors to use Power BI data experiences within their applications.
This talk is abou the best practices designing and implementing in business solutions Power BI Embeded and Power Bi Premium: which version to use and how to take the best advantage from different version and tier of Power BI, offered from Microsoft.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89453</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89453</id>
          <name>Dave Ruijter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques  Machine Learning</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence for the business analyst, leveraging new AI features in Power BI</title>
      <description>AI is everywhere, and of course also in Power BI. AI can aid you in your data exploration by automatically finding patterns, help you to understand what the data means, and in predicting future outcomes to drive better business results. The recently added AI features in the Power BI Service allow you to enrich your dataflow solutions with Artificial Intelligence. Whether you are a business user, analyst or data scientist, there is something to use and learn for all of you. Let's take a journey along all these powerful features! 
In this session you will learn:
• How to use R or Python in Power BI
• How to do Key Driver Analysis
• How to invoke Azure Cognitive Services
• How to integrate existing Azure Machine Learning models
• How to create a Machine Learning model directly in Power BI using the new AutoML capability</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89447</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89447</id>
          <name>Daniel Hutmacher</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Not just polish – How good code also runs faster</title>
      <description>I want to show you how just a little neater and tighter code can also run a lot faster. These are some of the instant performance improvements that won’t change a lot of code, won’t generate weeks of testing and validation for your colleagues, and can be relatively quick to implement.

But most of all, they’ll make the code prettier and easier to understand for the next person.

We’ll look at common ways that null values, implicit datatype conversions and foreign key constraints can radically affect the performance of your queries. Inspired by an actual client case, where I tuned a 20 hour query down to a few minutes, with only a minor code change.

This presentation is all-code, some execution plans, and no-powerpoint.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89819</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89819</id>
          <name>Marc Lelijveld</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Storytelling  interactive reports with Power BI Bookmarks  Drillthrough</title>
      <description>How to make sure that the end-user of your Power BI report understands the information well? There is way more involved in presenting your data then only a chart. Think about interaction, presenting the right information at the right time and much more! 

By using Story telling it is possible to tell the story behind the data. Where does the information need come from and how did we get to an answer? The complete storyline covered in your reports and dashboards to make sure the data is interpreted in the right way by the users. 

During this session I well tell more about the principles of story telling. Beside of that this session will be covered with lots of Power BI demos. During these demos I will give examples of functionality within Power BI which can be used to create your own story in Power BI. I will not only show the end result, but also how to create a report or dashboard like that to tell your own story!</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 2:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 3:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89049</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89049</id>
          <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>When Things go Wrong - Error Handling in SQL Server</title>
      <description>In an ideal world, we would not need any error handling, because there would be no errors. But in the real world we need to have error handling in our stored procedures. Error handling in SQL Server is a most confusing topic, because there are such great inconsistencies. But that does not mean that we as database developers can hide our head in the sand.

This presentation starts with a horror show of the many different actions SQL Server can take in case of an error. We will then learn how should deal with this - what we should do and what we should not and that with SET XACT_ABORT we get better consistency. We will learn how TRY-CATCH works in SQL Server, and we will get a recipe for how to write CATCH blocks. More generally, we will learn why it pays off to be simple-minded to survive in this maze. The session mainly looks at traditional T-SQL code, but the session ends with a quick look at natively compiled stored procedures, where everything is different.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 2:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 3:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88801</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88801</id>
          <name>Andrew Pruski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Architecture, Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server  Kubernetes</title>
      <description>Running SQL Server in containers has huge benefits for Data Platform professionals but there are challenges to running SQL Server in stand alone containers. Orchestrators provide a platform and the tools to overcome these challenges.

This session will provide an overview of running SQL Server in Kubernetes, which is the leading orchestrator.

Topics covered will be: -
An overview of Kubernetes.
Definition of deployments, pods, and services.
Deploying SQL Server containers to Kubernetes.
Persisting data for SQL Server in Kubernetes.

This session is aimed at SQL Server DBAs and Developers who want to learn the what, the why, and the how to run SQL Server in Kubernetes.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90863</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90863</id>
          <name>Kevin Kline</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Ten Query Tuning Techniques Every SQL Programmer Should Know</title>
      <description>SELECT statements have a reputation for being very easy to write, but hard to write very well. This session will take you through ten of the most problematic patterns and anti-patterns when writing queries and how to deal with them all.  Loaded with live demonstrations and useful techniques, this session will teach you how to take your SQL Server queries mundane to masterful.

Goal 1: Implement a reusable Transact-SQL test harness for reliable query results.
Goal 2: Learn ten patterns that kill the performance of SELECT statements and how to avoid them.
Goal 3: Discover the high-impact metadata that shows how a SELECT statement behaves … or misbehaves.

Attend this session to take your query writing and query tuning skills to the next level!</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90944</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90944</id>
          <name>Jani K. Savolainen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Architecture, Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Monitoring Mission-critical SQL Servers: How to utilize alerting to predict system bottlenecks</title>
      <description>In this session, we will deep-dive into the ocean of SQL Server monitoring alerts in large-scale and mission critical systems, from basic alerting and baselines into alerts assisted by machine learning. SQL Servers have dozens of important performance counters that DBA’s should follow on server, instance, and database level. It is practically impossible to monitor all of these performance counters over time without a proper alerting strategy, methodology, and implementation. How to maximize your uptime? How to avoid unplanned unavailability situations?

This session goes through 10 different pain points in SQL Server monitoring and covers the ideology and mechanisms on why, how and when to utilize alerts.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90997</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90997</id>
          <name>Pinal Dave</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Kick Start! SQL Server 2017 Performance Tips and Tricks</title>
      <description>Every new release of SQL Server brings a whole load of new features that an administrator can add to their arsenal of efficiency. SQL Server 2017 has introduced many new features. This session is carefully crafted to help overcome the beginner’s inertia for DBAs who have been using SQL Server for a while but aren't sure how to get started with the new features introduced in SQL Server 2017. 

Here is a glimpse of the features we will cover in this session:
• Adaptive query plans
• Batch mode adaptive join
• New cardinality estimates for optimal performance
• Indexing Improvements
• Automatic Tuning
• Memory optimizations

At the end of the session, DBAs will learn 3 essential processes which can be game changers for their career. After implementing the suggestions discussed in this session, DBAs will have extra time to handle more pressing issues which they were not able to focus on earlier.
 
This 75 minutes will be the most productive time for any DBA or Developer.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91762</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91762</id>
          <name>Zhenbo Zhang</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mondern Data Lake - Foundation for Advanced Analytics and Busines</title>
      <description>Data lake concept has evolved a lot recent years. Traditionally, data lake is used interchangeably with Hadoop. In Hadoop data and compute are co-located to reduce data transfer latency, thus improving the  performance. However, in Cloud era, data lake concept is dramatically evolved. Nowadays in cloud, compute nodes and data storage are normally decoupled, which brings significant benefit for scalability, cost optimization, upgradability etc. Modern cloud data ecosystem is all built upon this concept. The data lake storage is the foundation for most of the Azure data services, e.g. data factory, databricks, Azure datawarehouse, PowerBI. The concept of common data model enables business application and Azure services to work with same data in Azure data lake storage and makes different roles in organization e.g. data engineer, data scientists, business analysts to work in a much more seamless way.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93191</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93191</id>
          <name>Mika Sutinen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>DBA as the Cloud era Data Professional</title>
      <description>Database Administrators have been safeguarding the business critical data assets of the organizations for decades, managing not just the data but often also the infrastructure in the on-premise environments. However the times are rapidly changing and so are the expectations towards the DBA profession. These new expectations revolve around the ongoing digital transformation across different industries and the DBAs ability to answer to challenges presented by the modern, disruptive technologies.

When it comes to disruptiveness, very few technologies can match the public cloud and as a company working with all the major hyperscalers, Nordcloud has a unique perspective on the requirements on the skillsets needed to manage data in the cloud. Join our session to learn what core DBA skills will still be relevant in the cloud era, and what are the technologies and skills to learn!

*Norcloud - Gold Sponsor Session (30 minutes)*</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92860</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92860</id>
          <name>Ola Hallengren</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Architecture, Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Analyzing Performance Problems Using XEvents, DMVs  Query Store</title>
      <description>Extended Events, Dynamic Management Views, and Query Store are highly useful tools that give you a lot of data when analyzing performance problems. The challenge is which tool to use for which problems and how to correlate the data.

You are troubleshooting a performance problem in a business-critical database, a query is not completing, the users are complaining, and you are trying to understand what is happening. You have data from Extended Events, you are looking in the execution related DMVs, and now you are trying to find the query in Query Store. How do you put it all together?

In this session, we will look at how the tools work in different scenarios, how to correlate the data, and how you can use them in your performance troubleshooting.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90077</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90077</id>
          <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Architecture, Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Attention Contention!!!</title>
      <description>In this session we will discuss about tempdb contention in SQL Server on-premises, Azure SQL Managed Instance and Azure SQL Database. We will analyze both, Allocation Contention and Metadata contention, describing in detail WHEN and HOW it occurs, How to diagnose it, Best Practices and how to prevent it. The session will have both approaches in on-premisses and in Azure Managed Instance: - Theoretical, to understand what and why it occurs. - Practical, with examples causing it, offering alternatives to solve it and to prevent it.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92091</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92091</id>
          <name>Jouko Nyholm</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dataflow - The Power BI Version - Role in Data Platform strategy,</title>
      <description>Power BI Dataflow might just the missing link for many companies regarding their Data Platform strategy and goal to enable more effective self-service analytics. In this session, we'll review typical Data Platform architectures, use cases, related stakeholders and governance practices and talk about scenarios where Dataflow can fill the gaps and how it should be governed in order to be adopted successfully. CDM aspects? Yes, in the scope.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90895</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90895</id>
          <name>Rami Laine</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Architecture, Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2019 Architecture - High Availability and Disaster rec</title>
      <description>New and old things from sql server 2019 HA and disaster recovery point of view. Also tips what to consider if you bundle more than just database engine component into HA plan.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 2:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 3:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89455</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89455</id>
          <name>Dave Ruijter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Cheat Sheet explained!</title>
      <description>In this demo-rich session, Dave  Marc discuss the Power BI Cheat Sheet that went viral on social media. The sheet is crammed with Power BI tips and best practices based on years of experience, but with little to no room for comments. No worries! We will describe, demonstrate and discuss all the items! And of course, there will be a Cheat Sheet for everyone attending!</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89206</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89206</id>
          <name>Alexander Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques  Machine Learning</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>101 BI and AI</title>
      <description>How does the AI make my BI applications smarter?

How can the AI make my BI application smarter? Everybody is talking about AI but what can you do with it today? Currently there are tools like the Cognitive Services, Azure ML or Azure Bot Framework, which can help in the classic ETL process to prepare or enrich data. Examples are the analysis of large data streams from the IoT area, how can I improve my demand planning of a call center or the analysis of social media regarding trends.
If you already have your BI application in the cloud, Azure Data Factory, Logic App or Azure Stream Analytics would be the right components for an AI extension.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>88703</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>88703</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB - What you need to know to build globally distributed apps?</title>
      <description>In this session let us find about (technical overview)what are the foundations and design goals of Azure CosmosDB.  There are many benefits which will fit for web, mobile and globally distributed applications that need elastic scaling, high availability with a predictable performance which can elevate ease of development with NoSQL capabilities that every developer/architect/DBA should know about.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90175</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90175</id>
          <name>Vedran Kesegic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Magic Show</title>
      <description>The most beautiful and fun way to get know the depths of SQL Server is through magic. You will see a series of SQL Server experiments that look like a trick or illusion. But they are not. It is just exploiting the deep knowledge of how SQL works. This will deepen your knowledge and increase ability to solve real-world challenges.
The tricks:
Select count(*) from table - returns wrong count (any # you like)
Deadlock - single statement, without transactions
Database - without files
Online index changes - on Standard edition
Reading plaintext data of TDE-encrypted database - without SQL access</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92061</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92061</id>
          <name>Arun Justus</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques  Machine Learning</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Arun's and Vesa's Azure SQL DW deep-dive version 2 for Gen2</title>
      <description>Last year we had the version 1 of this session. Now Azure SQL DW has evolved one year more, and we are seeing it evolving at faster and faster pace. If last year it was great it is even better this year. Same hopefully goes for the session also! Full of demos, examples, some bad jokes and deep internal explanations why you should pick Azure SQL DW for your Cloud-born data warehouse solution.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89138</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89138</id>
          <name>John Martin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Architecture, Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Making Managed Instance Perform, a dive into storage.</title>
      <description>Moving to the cloud means that we need to take a different approach when it comes to how we design and tune databases. Managed Instance is a case in point, get the storage configuration wrong and it will not perform. Together we will look at the storage options and architecture for Managed Instance before demonstrating how to get tune the storage layer to get the performance we need. Of course none of this is any use without knowing what level of performance you need so we will look at how you can get this information before you start testing.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92058</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92058</id>
          <name>Vesa Tikkanen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Flow - The Azure version deepdive</title>
      <description>ETL OR ELT? What actually is the T and if I just want to do something else than CTAS? Just bring me my SSIS Data Flow in modern flavour and I would be happy. Here you have it: Azure Data Factory Data Flow. How it works? What's in it? And is it for any good?</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 2:50:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 3:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89341</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89341</id>
          <name>Oskari Heikkinen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Data Lake</title>
      <description>Aure Data Lake is an umbrella term consisting of multiple Azure services, most notably Azure Data Lake Store and Azure Data Lake Analytics. As the name implies, these services are built for big data processing purposes. During this session, you will gain the understanding of the use cases you should consider using these in particular. I will introduce both Data Lake Store and Data Lake Analytics, and how they have been built under the hood. In addition, I will do a couple of demos to show you how you actually can get started with them.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91906</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91906</id>
          <name>Pekka Korhonen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques  Machine Learning</track>
      <location>
        <name>ROOM 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Machine Learning Services with R and Python</title>
      <description>Install and Use In-Database Machine Learning Services for high-performance advanced predictive analytics. What's the difference between ML Server and In-Database ML Services? Examples of using R and Phyton libraries from SQL Server to create Machine Learning solutions.</description>
      <startTime>5/11/2019 1:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/11/2019 2:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>