<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #536 - Gothenburg 2016</name>
    <startDate>8/27/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Sarajevo, Skopje, Warsaw, Zagreb</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat536</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Scandic Opalen</name>
      <street>Engelbrektsgatan 73</street>
      <city>Gothenburg</city>
      <state>Västra Götalands Län, Sweden</state>
      <zipcode>412 52 Göteborg</zipcode>
      <longitude>11.98492</longitude>
      <latitude>57.70155</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1403</importID>
      <name>Informator</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.informator.se</url>
      <imageURL>https://informator.se/media/bilder/logo/informator_logo_sc-webb.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>85</importID>
      <name>Pyramid Analytics</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.PyramidAnalytics.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://pages.pyramidanalytics.com/rs/pyramidanalytics/images/logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>84</importID>
      <name>Pure Storage</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.purestorage.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/945/EventSponsor_14396.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1473</importID>
      <name>SQL Service Nordic AB</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlservice.se</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14826.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1069</importID>
      <name>SolidQ Nordic</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.solidq.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14821.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>299</importID>
      <name>SQLvariant</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://sqlvariant.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlvariant.com/BlogSupport/Images/SQLvariant_Logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS USE ONLY</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48603</importID>
      <name>Mike Boswell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mike works for Microsoft as a Data Platform Solution Architect. He likes to get involved in SQL Saturdays and the larger Data Platform conferences within Europe. You will also often see him talking at Microsoft events and how data is changing the way we work.
 
During his time, in Microsoft, he has worked with customers across the EMEA region in Finance, Utilities, Healthcare Public Sector and Retail. He was one EMEA Data Platform leads, where he has worked with others to with engineer’s knowledge, product launches, IP and career development.

He has extensive knowledge on our APS Systems along with core, and BI skills on SQL Server 2014/2016 and hybrid solutions on Azure. </description>
      <twitter>MikeBozBoswell</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/boswellmike</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MikeBozBoswell</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52580</importID>
      <name>Håkan Winther</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>H#229;kan Winther is a senior SQL server specialist at SQL Service Nordic, with SQL server experience since 1995 and passion for T-SQL development, performance tuning, large databases and BI Solutions.  
He contributes to the SQL server community by sharing his experience as an active member of ask.sqlservercentral.com, mentor at LabCenter and as a speaker at TechDays, Microsoft Sommarkollo and the Swedish PASS Chapter.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLWinther</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://se.linkedin.com/in/hakanwinther</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservice.se/blogg/?person=145</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLWinther</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50924</importID>
      <name>Stijn Wynants</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stijn is a Microsoft Premier Field Engineer on Data  AI and a DataMinds core member. He is also one of the organizers of the local user group sessions  the yearly event called DataMinds Connect (SQL Server Days). He is a speaker at various international events (SQL Saturday,PASS Summit,Difinity,...).  He spends his days tuning SQL Servers  solving problems with the full data platform. His focus is primarily on sql server core, but has also done various BI  ETL projects. He gets his kicks out of Columnstore indexes  tuning queries but shivers at the sight of an SSAS cube.

When Stijn is not working with SQL Server, you can probably find him enjoying the local cuisine  local beers or enjoying time with his wife and his dog.</description>
      <twitter>SQLStijn</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/stijn-wynants-ba528660?trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://swyssql.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLStijn</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49090</importID>
      <name>Alexander Arvidsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alexander is a principal solutions architect at Solution Xperts in Linköping, Sweden. Nobody really knows what it means to be a principal solutions architect, but he spends his days helping clients of all shapes and sizes to take better care of their data. 

He has spent the last 23 years toying with databases and related infrastructure services such as storage, networking and virtualization, occasionally emerging from the technical darkness to attend a Star Wars convention somewhere in the world.  

He is a frequent international speaker, a Data Platform MVP, podcaster, blogger and a Microsoft Certified Trainer, focusing on SQL Server, the Azure data stack and Power BI.</description>
      <twitter>arcticdba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexanderarvidsson</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.arcticdba.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arcticdba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50252</importID>
      <name>Jens Vestergaard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jens performs the traditional BI disciplines from imports in Integration Services through data consolidation in Analysis Services, to report in Power BI or Reporting Services. Jens has worked with The Stack since SQL 2000 and has a core competence in Integration Services and Analysis Services. Along with the certified skills in Microsoft SQL Server, Jens has also worked with Microsoft .Net platform for more than 15 years and currently manages a BI Platform in Azure for the CatMan Solution application(s).</description>
      <twitter>@vestergaardj</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/jvestergaard</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.t-sql.dk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@vestergaardj</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48605</importID>
      <name>Bjorn D. Jensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bjørn Dörr Jensen, Decision Intelligence Specialist, who is developing a system that turns raw sensor data into recommended actions 
to improve turbine availability and decreasing cost of energy. 
Working for Vestas Wind Systems A/S with Microsoft SQL Server 2016. 
Worked as a (PL/)SQL Developer from 2000 - 2006 at TDC, Stibo and IBM. 
Broad experience with structured query languages.
Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert (Data Management and Analytics).
M. Sc. in Physics and a Six Sigma Green Belt certification.</description>
      <twitter>@BjornDJensen</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/bdjensen/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BjornDJensen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48916</importID>
      <name>Asgeir Gunnarsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ásgeir Gunnarsson is a Data Platform MVP and Chief Consultant at Datheos in Denmark. He works on Business Intelligence solutions using the whole of the Microsoft BI stack. Ásgeir has been working in BI since 2007 both as a consultant and internal employee. Before turning to BI, Ásgeir worked as a technical trainer and currently teaches BI courses at the Continuing Education Department of the University of Iceland. 

Ásgeir speaks regularly at events both domestically and internationally, and is the group leader of the Icelandic PASS Group, as well as the Icelandic Power BI User Group. 

Ásgeir is passionate about data and loves solving problems with BI.</description>
      <twitter>bidgeir</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://is.linkedin.com/in/asgeirgun</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bidgeir</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48371</importID>
      <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Broadbent is a Data Platform MVP and SQL Server MCM with more than 20 years of experience working with SQL Server and principal of SQLCloud, a consultancy specializing in concurrency control and highly available solutions. He is the founder of the UK's SQLSaturday Cambridge (its first and largest), SharePoint Saturday Cambridge, the Hybrid Virtual Chapter and the East Anglia SQL User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@retracement</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/retracement</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tenbulls.co.uk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@retracement</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50460</importID>
      <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erland Sommarskog is an independent consultant based in Stockholm, working with SQL Server since 1991. He was first awarded SQL Server MVP in 2001, and has been re-awarded every year since. His focus is on systems development with the SQL Server Database Engine and his passion is to help people to write better SQL Server applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sommarskog.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>51030</importID>
      <name>David Söderlund</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David has been a SQL Server Developer and Consultant since 2008. He has been building and integrated ERP systems for small to medium sized companies as well as holding a key role in building a major financial systems for a large company in Scandinavia. He joined SolidQ in 2013 and his main focus areas are data modeling, ETL and T-SQL.</description>
      <twitter>@QuadmanSWE</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/soderlunddavid</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@QuadmanSWE</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52530</importID>
      <name>David Postlethwaite</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Postlethwaite has been a DBA for Liverpool Victoria in Bournemouth, England since 2008
He supports both Oracle and SQL Server from 2000 to 2017, DBMS, SSIS, SSAS and Reporting Services.
In 2015 David built and deployed the company's first cloud solution using Microsoft Azure SQL Database and web services 

Before becoming a DBA David was a .NET developer and way back in history a Windows and Netware administrator. 

He is an occasional blogger on www.gethynellis.com

David is a regular speaker for SQL Saturday.
Most of his presentations can be found on his YouTube channel www.youtube.com/c/DavidPostlethwaiteSQL</description>
      <twitter>@postledm</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidpostlethwaite</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gethynellis.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@postledm</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50285</importID>
      <name>Arne Bartels</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Master of physic in Germany 2000, worked as MS Flightsimulator Expert on the side. Employed at OLTEC Windamp;Solar as C++/Web/PHP/MySQL -Programmer. Company bought by Vestas 2004 shifting to MS-SQL,SSIS until now.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=207669359amp;trk=nav_responsive_tab_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50748</importID>
      <name>Emanuele Zanchettin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Emanuele Zanchettin, after studying in Computer Engineering, began his career with DB2 in the banking sector in 1998. After a few years and a change of scope of application, he encountered Access and Oracle with which he subsequently worked for several years in data access tuning and database design for new application features. Since 2007 he has also launched into the SQLServer world 2K, 2005, 2008* and 201* and more importantly, since 2011, into Azure SQL Database (SQL Azure). In order to have a greater capacity for assessment and familiarity with the various technologies that the market offers, he has deepened his knowledge to include MySQL and DocumentDB. Today Emanuele is mainly involved in IT projects and database management.</description>
      <twitter>@_thinkIT_</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://it.linkedin.com/pub/emanuele-zanchettin/18/921/34/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_thinkIT_</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52546</importID>
      <name>Daniel Hutmacher</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior database developer with a long-running passion for performance tuning on SQL Server. I run my own consultancy business where I help companies with database development, ETL work, performance tuning and technical training on SQL Server.
Board member of the Swedish SQL Server usergroup 2017-2019, organizer of SQL Saturday Stockholm, and co-organizer of GroupBy.org.</description>
      <twitter>@dhmacher</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://se.linkedin.com/in/danielhutmacher</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlsunday.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dhmacher</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48289</importID>
      <name>John Martin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Martin is a Data Platform Engineer working in the financial sector, as well as Vice President Marketing for the PASS organization and currently a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Previously John has worked as a product manager for SentryOne and a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft UK.

John has over a decade of experience working with SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. Working as a DBA, developer and consultant for Microsoft, he has been lucky enough to see how best, and how not, to use SQL Server and the Data Platform effectively.</description>
      <twitter>SQLDiplomat</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/johnqmartin/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mssqltips.com/sqlserverauthor/291/john-martin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLDiplomat</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50446</importID>
      <name>Mike Byrd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Former rocket scientist and USAF Fighter Pilot -- now a SQL Server geek (24 years)! Past opportunities include free-lance technical writer for PC Magazine, Senior Software Manager for government sponsored munitions effectiveness committee, and insurance company CTO.  Currently senior database engineer consultant for several Austin companies.  

Presenter at many SQL Saturdays over last 6 years in United States, Europe, and Australia.

Specialize in SQL Server performance tuning; database (OLTP  OLAP) architecture; trouble-shooting; teaching TSQL (Basic through Advanced).

Video presentations (for local SQL Server user groups or SQL Saturdays) can be found at http://usergroup.tv/videos/category/speaker/mike-byrd</description>
      <twitter>ByrdNest_TX</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-byrd/1/aa0/bbb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://logicalread.solarwinds.com/?s=byrd, www.TSQLMentoring.com and SQLServerCentral.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ByrdNest_TX</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50905</importID>
      <name>Tillmann Eitelberg</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tillmann Eitelberg is CEO and co-founder of oh22information services GmbH, which specializes in data integration and data management. Tillmann is an active blogger at www.ssis-components.net, writing regularly about data quality topics and his passion: spatial data. In addition, he has published several SSIS components on Codeplex and GitHub. Tillmann is a Data Platform MVP, a board member of PASS Germany e.V., a PASS CL for the Cologne/Bonn region, and a PASS RM.</description>
      <twitter>@_Tillmann</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tillmanneitelberg</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ssis-components.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_Tillmann</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49732</importID>
      <name>Jason Horner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hi, my name is Jason. I spend most of my day helping clients solve business problems mostly in the Data and Advanced Analytics spaces. Sometimes this involves various and sundry cloud technologies including Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Data Lake Store, Azure Databricks, HDInsight and Azure SQL Database. I'm fluent in several languages including: SQL, C#, Python, and PowerShell.

I'm a Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server (MCM) and have been recognized for my technical excellence and evangelism efforts by Microsoft by being awarded the Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for the last 5+ years.

In my off hours I like to snowboard, karaoke, ride roller coasters, and play arcade games</description>
      <twitter>jasonhorner</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonhorner</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.jasonhorner.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jasonhorner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48654</importID>
      <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Uwe Ricken is working with IT systems since the 90’s. The primary passion for developments with Microsoft SQL Server expanded in 2007 with his engagement as a DBA for Deutsche Bank AG in Frankfurt am Main. After 6 years of operational experiences as a DBA and over 14 years as a developer of complex database models he achieved the “Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008” certification which “was” the highest technical certification. In the same year he earned his first award as a Data Platform MVP for his support to the Microsoft SQL Server community in Germany and Europe. Uwe Ricken is a speaker on many international conferences and events and preferred topics are “Database Internals”, “Indexing” and “Development”.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dbBerater</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=270775013amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmaster.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dbBerater</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48124</importID>
      <name>Bent Pedersen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bent is a Data Platform MVP and working as Senior Business Analytics Architect at Kapacity A/S, where he have been working with enterprise customers on solutions with SSAS Tabular, SQL Server and in general Azure Data Platform services for the last years. During the past years, he concentrated on working with architecturing, devOps, Automation, testing and simplifying development processes for the Azure Data Platform.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLBent</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://dk.linkedin.com/in/bentnissenpedersen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.biblog.eu</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLBent</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69649</importID>
      <name>Peter Larsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Larsson is a key player for performance written code. He can turn a 10 hour query into a 3 minute piece of code. Peter is also a SQL Server MVP since 2009. He often hangs out at SQLTeam.com (27k+ posts) and other various sites where he helps all people understand SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>SwePeso</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqltopia.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SwePeso</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>52539</importID>
      <name>Markus Winand</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Markus Winand tunes developers for high SQL performance. He also published the book quot;SQL Performance Explainedquot; and offers in-house training as well as remote coaching at http://winand.at/</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/MarkusWinand</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/markuswinand/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://use-the-index-luke.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/MarkusWinand</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48144</importID>
      <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr.SubraMANI Paramasivam is a Microsoft MVP, PhD, Microsoft Certified Trainer and Head of Data  AI at DAGEOP Ltd having 21 years of DB, BI, Analytics and AI experience. Mani has also spoken in various events like MS IGNITE, PASS Summit, MS Inspire, SQLBITS, Power Platform Summit, Global AI Bootcamp, Data  BI Summit, SQLRelay,  Power BI World Tour, Data Platform Summit, INSIDESQL UK, Global AI Nights, SQLServerGeeks Summit, MCT Global Summits, Data Day Events and various user group events. Mani also believes in Empowering Every Person in the planet and spreads the awareness on Global challenges via www.EmpoweringEveryPerson.com. He is also a co-owner of 1 Global AI Meetup and 3 Power BI PUG  PASS local / user groups.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dageop</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/dageop</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.yoursqlman.com/index.php/blogs</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dageop</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48141</importID>
      <name>Magnus Ahlkvist</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Independent database consultant and certified trainer with a passion for chasing that extra millisecond.
20 years of database development and administration but trying to be humble enough to understand that I'm still learning.</description>
      <twitter>Transmokopter</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://se.linkedin.com/in/magnusahlkvist</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tsql.nu</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Transmokopter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50416</importID>
      <name>Cathrine Wilhelmsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cathrine loves teaching and sharing knowledge :) She is based in Norway and works as a Senior Business Intelligence Consultant in Inmeta, focusing on Data Warehousing, Data Integration, Analytics, and Reporting projects. Her core skills are Azure Data Factory, SSIS, Biml and T-SQL development, but she enjoys everything from programming to data visualization. Outside of work she's active in the SQL Server community as a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, BimlHero Certified Expert, author, speaker, blogger, organizer and chronic volunteer.</description>
      <twitter>@cathrinew</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cathrinewilhelmsen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.cathrinewilhelmsen.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cathrinew</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>48124</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48124</id>
          <name>Bent Pedersen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Knippla</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hybrid BI</title>
      <description>With the introduction of SQL 2016 and all its new features, Hybrid BI is more in focus then ever. Doing BI is no longer bound to be on-premise or in the cloud. With all the new features and the Azure platform Microsoft has made it easier then ever to implement a hybrid platform.

When working with a hybrid platform your organisation will be able to select strategy and features based on the highest ROI. During this session I will go through three different aspects of Hybrid BI which is infrastructure, data-storage and reporting. 

As part of this i will go through the advantages and disadvantages of each area to supply you with the information you need to choose the right direction for your platform.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48916</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48916</id>
          <name>Asgeir Gunnarsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Knippla</name>
      </location>
      <title>Who, What, When. Monitoring usage of your MS BI stack</title>
      <description>You have created great cubes and Reporting Services reports but how do you know if it is being used? Learn how to set up the collection of the usage data and how you can use this data in your decision making. 

We will talk about how to collect the data, how to build something meaningful from the data and how you can report on top of the data. We will do this for OLAP cubes and for Reporting Services Reports and we will explore ways you can further develop this for your own organization.

At the end of the session all participants will leave with all the code as well as the know how to get started with the collection of usage statistics for their Microsoft BI Solutions</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49090</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49090</id>
          <name>Alexander Arvidsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Knippla</name>
      </location>
      <title>Unicorn safari - alleviating consolidation pains with SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>Database consolidation was once described to me as a bit of a mix between the holy grail and a unicorn. Not that difficult in theory, but have a way of getting very messy in practice. SQL Server 2016 brings several new features to simplify the whole process, and hopefully provide the DBA and the people footing the license bill some sorely needed respite.
This presentation will outline the classic issues with consolidation of small and medium-sized databases and explore what new pain relief SQL Server 2016 brings to the table.
At the end of this session you will have a good understanding of the challenges and solutions available in SQL Server for solving consolidation workloads.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48289</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48289</id>
          <name>John Martin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Vrångö 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Making Row Level Security and Dynamic Data Masking work for you!</title>
      <description>Azure SQL DB has had Row Level Security and Dynamic Data Masking for a while now, SQL Server 2016 brings that on-premises. But just how can you use it, what changes do you need to make to your model to get the most from it?

These new features have the potential to really improve application security, especially in compliance scenarios. Pushing the security restrictions down into the database layer has many benefits, notably only the data needed leaves the database. But there are a number of gotchas that you need to be aware of that can really mess up performance if you get them wrong.

In this session we will look at how you can get the most out of these features and retain the performance of your system.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50460</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50460</id>
          <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Knippla</name>
      </location>
      <title>GIving Permissions through Stored Procedures</title>
      <description>You probably know that with a stored procedure you can permit users to access or update data even if they have no direct permissions on the table. But you may have noticed that this does not work when the SP uses dynamic SQL. 

In this session you will learn why it is so and techniques how you can use to overcome this. You will also learn that the same techniques can be to permit users to perform specific actions they need to do without granting them general high-level permissions on database or server level by packaging these actions into a stored procedure. You will also learn why should should be careful with setting a database TRUSTWORTHY.

The session should be of interest both to DBAs and application developers that need to consider advanced permissions in their stored procedures.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50446</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50446</id>
          <name>Mike Byrd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Asperö</name>
      </location>
      <title>SS2014/2016 In-Memory Tables --Formula One Performance Unleashed???</title>
      <description>Query performance is what it is all about.  SQL Server 2014 now has the new in-memory functionality that takes a completely different approach to data access and manipulation.  This session will consolidate the relevant information from all these sources so the production DBA/Developer will be able to understand, create, use, maintain, and trouble-shoot in-memory table functionality.  This session will also examine several demo scripts showing performance gains using the in-memory tables with and without columnstore indexes over equivalent disk based tables.  
This session is all about when and how to apply in-memory tables in a production environment.
After this session you will
1.	 Understand what in-memory tables are and how to create and maintain them including their limitations
2.	Be able to identify performance gains over equivalent disk back tables
3.	Comprehend the new data monitoring needed for in-memory table
</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48605</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48605</id>
          <name>Bjorn D. Jensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Donsö</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why (data) quality matters</title>
      <description>Poor data quality has a cost. 
Examples of data quality challenges and their impact.
Having correct data is very important to make correct decisions. 
Data quality goes hand in hand with proper data modelling.
Knowledge about use cases and workload is important input to your data modelling. 
Different kinds of compression can be relevant depending on your usage scenario.
Storing data economically also means that data should be easy to use. 
Having focus on deadlines whithout having (data) quality in mind will hit you hard at an later point in time.

Delivering good query performance and reports in time is important to business users,
but how to measure it from their perspective?

And obviously the features you provide should work. 
This is where you benefit from unit testing. (Demo of unit testing with SSDT.)
</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49732</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49732</id>
          <name>Jason Horner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Vrångö 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dimensional Modeling Design Patterns: Beyond the Basics</title>
      <description>Dimensional modeling is one of cornerstones of successful Business Intelligence initiatives. Even with new technologies like PowerPivot and Analysis Services Tabular models, you need to represent your organization’s data in a way that is accessible for end users and IT staff alike. An effective dimensional model will also ensure that your data warehouse or data mart will be responsive and capable of accommodating emerging requirements.
In this session, we will dive deeper into the art of dimensional modeling. We will look at how and when to create the different types of fact and dimension tables, Including patterns for enriching dimensional data, creating usable hierarchies for efficient navigation, and tracking historical changes. After attending this session you will be able to confidently assess the quality of your organization’s dimensional model and recommend and implement changes. Bring your toughest quandaries to help make this an interactive and engaging session.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50285</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50285</id>
          <name>Arne Bartels</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Vrångö 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Shadow prediction: SQL spatial data types and astronomy well mixed</title>
      <description>In the Wind turbine industry it is often desirable to know where a wind turbine casts its shadow as it can case annoyance to neighbours.
This session is supposed to be a more entertaining then practical exercise to combine scarsely used data types in unusual fashion, combined with a bit of astronomy and math, to calculate and visualize the relationship between sun and wind turbine purely by using SQL2016 Management Studio. 

The calculation of the daily path of a shadow can be seen as a rather complex three-dimensional problem. By turning around the perspective and 'painting' the picture of turbines in the sky this can be decribed as a much simpler two-dimensional problem on a sphere. For this the geography data type will be used and in turn the richness of its functionality demonstrated. Even a sufficient visualisaton is included in SSMS 2016.  Apart from 2-3 formulas everything will be handeled in SQL and no complex math is needed. </description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48654</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48654</id>
          <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Donsö</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mastering DML Operations like a master</title>
      <description>DML operations mean lot of work for the database engine of Microsoft SQL Server. Understanding the details of a DML transaction may give you great benefits when planning workloads for INSERT, UPDATE and DELETE operations.

Come and learn the differences of space allocation/deallocation between Clustered Indexes and Heaps in this demo oriented session. It will answer these questions:

What is the difference of data page allocation for heaps and clustered indexes?
What is the amount of transaction log when you update data in a heap and/or in a clustered index?
What are the differences when data are delete from a heap and clustered index?
Can ETL processes be improved by usage of the right strategy for INSERTS and DELETES?
What performance drawbacks have Page Splits and Forwarded Records for my application design?</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50416</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50416</id>
          <name>Cathrine Wilhelmsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Vrångö 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tools and Tips: From Accidental to Efficient Data Warehouse Developer</title>
      <description>You have probably heard about the Accidental DBA, but what about the Accidental Data Warehouse developer? We stumbled into the world of data warehousing, learned dimensional modeling and work with T-SQL and SSIS daily. We are masters of googling solutions to our problems and make sure our ETL processes run without errors. We deliver data to business users... but we rarely deliver data as fast as we want.

You might not be able to rewrite your entire Data Warehouse or change your team's processes over night, but there are many things you can do to increase your own productivity and become a more efficient Data Warehouse developer.

In this session I will show you some of what I have learned and discovered that has made me exclaim "Oh wow! Why did I not know this yesterday!?" - including SSMS features, tools for query analysis and tuning, free tools and scripts, Biml for SSIS and even a couple of things I used to think were only useful for those scary DBAs.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52530</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52530</id>
          <name>David Postlethwaite</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Knippla</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL 2016 New features</title>
      <description>SQL 2016 is now here packed with new features such Always Encrypted, Dynamic Data Masking, temporal tables, stretched tables, Query Store, Live Query stats and more. This talk gives an overview of what's  new and improved in SQL Server 2016 and demonstrates some of these features</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>51030</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>51030</id>
          <name>David Söderlund</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure and Cloud related</track>
      <location>
        <name>Asperö</name>
      </location>
      <title>Streaming data: from signal to query</title>
      <description>In this session we will look at techniques for transforming and refining data in a stream with Reactive Linq.
We will use example data coming from a mock-up parking garage and send it to SQL Server leveraging in-memory objects.  We will also let our data streams leverage Azure Stream Analytics and Azure Machine Learning.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50748</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50748</id>
          <name>Emanuele Zanchettin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure and Cloud related</track>
      <location>
        <name>Asperö</name>
      </location>
      <title>Implementing and Maintaining an Azure SQL Database project</title>
      <description>This is an evergreen session, it follows Azure SQL Database evolution and each time is different: it looks at how to implement, maintain and evolve/update solutions developed on Azure SQL Database, through the use of the tools like SQL Sever Management Studio and Visual Studio. Through examples and case studies, will be presented the versatility, power and reliability of the database as a service in the cloud.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52539</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52539</id>
          <name>Markus Winand</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Donsö</name>
      </location>
      <title>Indexes: The neglected performance all-rounder</title>
      <description>Proper indexing is a very time and cost-effective way to improve SQL performance. Yet it is hardly known how to get it right and how different ways to phrase a query affects indexing and performance. In this session I’ll explain why this knowledge is sparse and what developers can do about it. Finally we will go through the most important indexing mistakes by example and discuss them during a short live quiz with the audience.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50905</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50905</id>
          <name>Tillmann Eitelberg</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure and Cloud related</track>
      <location>
        <name>Asperö</name>
      </location>
      <title>Bioinformatics on Azure</title>
      <description>If people think about big data, they always think about Twitter or Facebook. But there are other areas where much more data amounts incurred and the analyzes are more complex. In this talk, we talk about a real example from bioinformatics. We will explain the actual scenario and how the various Microsoft platforms from SQL Server to Azure Data Lake and Power BI could help us – or not.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50924</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50924</id>
          <name>Stijn Wynants</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Donsö</name>
      </location>
      <title>Real-Time Analytics: OLAP  OLTP in the mix!</title>
      <description>In this session we will talk about the Real-Time analytics possibilities with SQL Server 2016. This will be a deep-dive on how this works, and will give you an explanation on the new Columnstore features. We will also talk about the difference between hot  warm data.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48371</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48371</id>
          <name>Mark Broadbent</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Donsö</name>
      </location>
      <title>Schizophrenic High Availability with SQL and Windows 2016</title>
      <description>As SQL Server, Windows and Cloud availability solutions have reached maturity, their capabilities and interoperability has grown to such an extent that it is no longer clear what technologies to use, when to use them, what they deliver and when things can go wrong.

In this session we will take a look at some of the new features provided by SQL Server and Windows 2016, how existing high availability solutions can benefit from their adoption and when schizophrenic HADR can be bad idea!</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48144</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48144</id>
          <name>Dr. Subramani Paramasivam</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Vrångö 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Think  work like a Data Scientist with SQL 2016 R</title>
      <description>What are these DATA Scientists up to? How can we see their statistical model in our day to day familiar tool like Microsoft SQL Server?

You now have answers to these questions and thanks to Microsoft for integrating R Revolution within new SQL Server 2016. We all now have the opportunity to use R packages and see the results within SQL 2016.

In this session, you will definitely take away a breakthrough concept of Advanced R Analytics within SQL 2016 and get ready to kick your creative horse, and go beyond your imagination on how you can build advanced analytics and impress your employers/customers.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48141</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48141</id>
          <name>Magnus Ahlkvist</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Knippla</name>
      </location>
      <title>Statistics, an unreliable friend.</title>
      <description>You learned that your statistics should be regularly updated. You even implemented Ola Hallengren's maintenance scripts. That should be enough, right? What if it's not?
Join me on some head-ache, a dive into statistics histograms, trace flags and some proof to why the terrible sentence "It depends" always applies.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52546</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52546</id>
          <name>Daniel Hutmacher</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Vrångö 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>We need to go deeper: Exploring CTEs</title>
      <description>Join me for a twisting and turning session where we look at some interesting uses of common table expressions and recursive CTEs. We'll look at nested CTEs, managing duplicate rows, string and XML parsing as well as dependency trees and other hierarchies. These are not just cool tricks - they're powerful T-SQL patterns that can improve the stability and performance of your data cleansing and ETL code.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50252</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50252</id>
          <name>Jens Vestergaard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure and Cloud related</track>
      <location>
        <name>Asperö</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure IoT, Windows 10 Core  Raspberry PI</title>
      <description>This session will begin, with a high level introduction to Azure Internet of Things, Windows 10 Core and Raspberry PI. Once we have established the basics about the technology, we will be connecting the dots, with a live demo on some of the parts. The focus during the demo, will mainly be on Azure IoT Hub, Windows 10 Core and the Raspberry PI. As visualization we will be using Power BI.</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>52580</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>52580</id>
          <name>Håkan Winther</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Donsö</name>
      </location>
      <title>SELECT TOP 5 Feaures FROM SQL 2016 ORDER BY Coolfactor DESC</title>
      <description>This session will cover some of the most interesting features of SQL Server 2016. In 60 minutes you will get enough arguments why you should upgrade to this new version of SQL Server. There will lots of demo of and a few slides about:
QueryStore,
Temporal,
Stretch,
Row level security,
Dynamic data masking


</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48603</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48603</id>
          <name>Mike Boswell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure and Cloud related</track>
      <location>
        <name>Asperö</name>
      </location>
      <title>Configuring SQL Server Analysis Services for use with Azure SQL DW</title>
      <description>Configuring SQL Server Analysis Services for use with Azure SQL Data Warehouse (Preferred session)
Session objectives:
#183;         Enable OLAP and tabular analytics against SQL DW
#183;         Provide technical configuration to get the best from SSAS when connecting to SQL DW
#183;         Recommendations for process and approach
#183;         Optimize OLAP and SQL DW for performance</description>
      <startTime>8/27/2016 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>8/27/2016 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>