<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #120 - Orange County 2012</name>
    <startDate>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-08:00) Pacific Time (US and Canada); Tijuana</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat120</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Goldenwest College</name>
      <street>15744 Goldenwest Street</street>
      <city>Huntington Beach</city>
      <state>California</state>
      <zipcode>92647</zipcode>
      <longitude>-118.0066274</longitude>
      <latitude>33.7333707</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1277</importID>
      <name>WhereScape USA Limited</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.wherescape.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/3feab36d-22a5-4511-94e1-afd5d16b7ef7.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1</importID>
      <name>Confio</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.confio.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/resized-confio_logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>8</importID>
      <name>FusionIO</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.fusionio.com/solutions/microsoft-sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/files/18b704b1-226d-48fe-b0b8-f7b4d3443b3d.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>812</importID>
      <name>MarkTab Consulting</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.marktab.net</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.marktab.net/images/MarkTabNet_100x40.gif</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>299</importID>
      <name>SQLvariant</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://sqlvariant.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlvariant.com/BlogSupport/Images/SQLvariant_Logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>760</importID>
      <name>StrateSQL</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.jasonstrate.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.jasonstrate.com/images/StrateSQLBanner.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>264</importID>
      <name>Shannon Lowder</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://shannonlowder.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://shannonlowder.com/wp-content/themes/vigilance_pro/images/lowder-wp-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>664</importID>
      <name>Golden West College</name>
      <label>Facilities Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.goldenwestcollege.edu/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/3433e738-8d66-4225-9de2-08ffa7e17077.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10310</importID>
      <name>Ben Aminnia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben Aminnia is a database architect / .NET developer / consultant at Pointer Corporation with over 25 years of experience in developing database systems and managing a team of SQL Server developers and DBAs. He's also the architect of Virtual Information Portal (VIP) System and the past-president of Los Angeles SQL Server Professionals Group.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.pointercorp.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13091</importID>
      <name>Denise McInerney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denise McInerney is a data professional with over 20 years of experience. She began her career as a database administrator and has worked as a data analyst and data engineer. She now works as a data architect at Intuit, where she designs and implements analytics solutions with a focus on enabling the work of analysts, data scientists, and business users. Denise is active in technical community organizations and has spoken at user groups and conferences over two dozen times. She served on the PASS Board of Directors for six years.</description>
      <twitter>@denisemc06</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/denisemcinerney/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/denisem/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@denisemc06</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>31531</importID>
      <name>Lynn Langit</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lynn Langit is a Cloud and Big Data Architect.  She's been working with a team on an AWS IoT project this year.  Lynn speaks, blogs and creates courses on technical topics for LinkedIn/Lynda.com.
 
She holds a number of partner awards - Microsoft MVP for Data Platform, AWS Community Hero, Google Developer Expert (Cloud). Her blog is at www.LynnLangit.com. She is also director of the non-profit Teaching Kids Programming (www.TeachingKidsProgramming.org).</description>
      <twitter>@lynnlangit</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/lynn-langit/1/621/b40</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.lynnlangit.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@lynnlangit</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30483</importID>
      <name>Janis Griffin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Janis Griffin has over 30 years of DBA/database experience including design, development and implementation of many critical database applications. Before coming to Quest Software, Janis primarily worked in the Telecom/Network Industry, working with both real-time network routing databases and OLTP business to business applications.  Janis also held positions as a Principal Architect and Senior Manager, mentoring other DBAs on best practices in database performance tuning.</description>
      <twitter>DoBoutAnything</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/janis-griffin/0/914/aba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DoBoutAnything</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9958</importID>
      <name>Audrey Hammonds</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Audrey Hammonds is a Data Platform Specialist for Microsoft in South Florida. Twenty-one years ago, she volunteered for database training to escape the clutches of COBOL and has never looked back. A firm believer in good fundamentals and solid design, she gets her kicks from making data do nifty things.  These days, she gets her kicks from helping customers adopt data services in Azure.</description>
      <twitter>@DataAudrey</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/audreyhammonds/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datachix.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DataAudrey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11323</importID>
      <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Bossy (MCTS, MCP BI, CBIP) is a data and cloud analytics architect with 25 years of experience in software and database development. As a principal of Datalere, Carlos focuses on developing BI, Data Science, and Advanced Analytics solutions, including modeling data warehouses and delivering predictive models, integration, and visualization. He has developed warehouses and BI solutions for a variety of industries and state agencies, including health insurance, solar energy, foster care, telecom, and manufacturing.</description>
      <twitter>@carlosbossy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin/in/carlosbossy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.carlosbossy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@carlosbossy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21463</importID>
      <name>Nitin Salgar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Nitin C Salgar has over 7 years of DBA experience including planning,design, development and implementation of line of business database applications. Nitin has worked primarily as a  consultant holding  positions primarily in the Benefit Management, Transportation and Government. He has worked on OLTP and OLAP applications housed on Premise (Co-Lo/Datacenter) as well as Cloud. He also possesses several Microsoft certifications on 2008, gearing toward 2012

I'll be co-presenting with @andythir</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22112</importID>
      <name>Phil Helmer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Phil has been designing and building relational databases in a variety of industries ever since he first realized how many people don't understand the limitations of Excel and sticky notes as databases. When he was a poor college student, that meant teaching himself MS Access. After moving to SQL Server 13 years ago, he found out about the PASS community and never looked back. He now spends his days developing databases using T-SQL, exploring data management tools  techniques and trying to make sense of Microsoft's marketing.</description>
      <twitter>@philhelmer</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/philhelmer</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.philhelmer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@philhelmer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>31921</importID>
      <name>Mitchell Bottel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mitchell Bottel is a senior database administrator with Sutter Physician Services, owner of Innovative IT Consulting and President of the Sacramento SQL Sevrer User Group. He has 14 years of IT experience, focusing on SQL Server for the last ten years with an emphasis on database administration and high availability solutions. He has authored blog posts on the SQLServerPerformance website and written White Papers on using Dynamic Management Views.</description>
      <twitter>@SacSQLDude</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mitchespitch.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SacSQLDude</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>33855</importID>
      <name>Warren Sifre</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warren Sifre has been in the IT community since 1998 and has worked in a variety of industries deploying solutions utilizing MS SQL Server in one capacity or another. In 2003, he decided to make SQL Server his mastery and has since developed skills in most defined disciplines of MS SQL.  Currently he is a Principal Consultant and Technology Leader with Moser Consulting.  He is responsible for BI Solution Architecture and the mentorship of team members.  He has been a SQL Saturday Speaker since 2012, Azure Global Bootcamp, and many user groups in 2015 alone.  He has a passion for knowledge transfer and solutions architecture, with a keen interested in Info Security.</description>
      <twitter>WAS_SQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/wsifre</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.broadstrokeconsulting.com/blog/, http://www.allegient.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=WAS_SQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9959</importID>
      <name>Audrey Hammonds</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Audrey Hammonds is a Data Platform Specialist for Microsoft in South Florida. Twenty-one years ago, she volunteered for database training to escape the clutches of COBOL and has never looked back. A firm believer in good fundamentals and solid design, she gets her kicks from making data do nifty things.  These days, she gets her kicks from helping customers adopt data services in Azure.</description>
      <twitter>@DataAudrey</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/audreyhammonds/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datachix.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DataAudrey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11468</importID>
      <name>Chris Dickey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Dickey has been an independent consultant specializing in SQL Server performance tuning for the last 14 years. I first started using SQL Server back in 1989. I also have a strong background in applications built using C++, C# and .NET. Recently I have been working with parallel and async features in C# 5 and .NET.Chris is a graduate of UC SanDiego.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.FastSqlServer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30360</importID>
      <name>Ike Ellis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ike Ellis is a Senior Data Architect and partner for Crafting Bytes. He has designed and implemented data solutions for many well-known organizations.  He has been a Microsoft Data Platform MVP since 2011. He co-authored the book "Developing Azure Solutions," now in its second edition. He is a popular speaker at SQLBits, PASS Summit, and SQL in the City. He speaks at user groups, code camps, and SQLSaturdays. He has written courses on SQL Server for developers, Power BI, SSRS, SSIS, and SSAS for Wintellect. He has an upcoming course on CosmosDB. He founded the San Diego Tech Immersion Group, a technical book club based in San Diego and is the co-chair of the San Diego Software Architecture Group.</description>
      <twitter>@ike_ellis</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ellisteam.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ike_ellis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18091</importID>
      <name>Kendra Little</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kendra Little is a Microsoft Certified Master and a Microsoft MVP. Kendra fell in love with the challenge of deploying software to a complex database environment when she worked in a build operations team at a software startup. She went on to become a database administrator for performance critical databases at Microsoft Corporation. Since then, Kendra has worked internationally as a teacher and consultant, and founded the training site SQL Workbooks. She joined Redgate as a Product Evangelist in 2018.</description>
      <twitter>Kendra_Little</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendralittle</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://littlekendra.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Kendra_Little</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13395</importID>
      <name>Douglas Barrett</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Douglas has worked in the field of Business Intelligence for 20 years - concentrating primarily on data.  Data Warehouse design, data processing, tuning, data quality - leading projects for Banks, Airlines, Retailers, Brewers (dim_beer anyone?), Universities etc.  When not building data warehouses Douglas loves hiking in the Northwest.  

It becomes abundantly clear after project 1 that agility - prototyping, iterations and collaboration with SMEs / BAs is the only way to de-risk a data project.  Douglas works for WhereScape - a software company that builds agile tools for developing / managing data warehouses / vaults / hubs.  The design will change - when it meets the data, when it meets the users - it is expected, lets make it easier.</description>
      <twitter>@dougy_jb</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dougyb/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.wherescape.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dougy_jb</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27564</importID>
      <name>Warren Sifre</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warren Sifre has been in the IT community since 1998 and has worked in a variety of industries deploying solutions utilizing MS SQL Server in one capacity or another. In 2003, he decided to make SQL Server his mastery and has since developed skills in most defined disciplines of MS SQL.  Currently he is a Principal Consultant and Technology Leader with Moser Consulting.  He is responsible for BI Solution Architecture and the mentorship of team members.  He has been a SQL Saturday Speaker since 2012, Azure Global Bootcamp, and many user groups in 2015 alone.  He has a passion for knowledge transfer and solutions architecture, with a keen interested in Info Security.</description>
      <twitter>WAS_SQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/wsifre</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.broadstrokeconsulting.com/blog/, http://www.allegient.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=WAS_SQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30481</importID>
      <name>Janis Griffin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Janis Griffin has over 30 years of DBA/database experience including design, development and implementation of many critical database applications. Before coming to Quest Software, Janis primarily worked in the Telecom/Network Industry, working with both real-time network routing databases and OLTP business to business applications.  Janis also held positions as a Principal Architect and Senior Manager, mentoring other DBAs on best practices in database performance tuning.</description>
      <twitter>DoBoutAnything</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/janis-griffin/0/914/aba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DoBoutAnything</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11322</importID>
      <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Bossy (MCTS, MCP BI, CBIP) is a data and cloud analytics architect with 25 years of experience in software and database development. As a principal of Datalere, Carlos focuses on developing BI, Data Science, and Advanced Analytics solutions, including modeling data warehouses and delivering predictive models, integration, and visualization. He has developed warehouses and BI solutions for a variety of industries and state agencies, including health insurance, solar energy, foster care, telecom, and manufacturing.</description>
      <twitter>@carlosbossy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin/in/carlosbossy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.carlosbossy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@carlosbossy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29980</importID>
      <name>Diana Dee</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Diana Dee has been a Microsoft Certified Trainer since 1996.  Since 2005, she has specialized in training and consulting on SQL Server administration, Transact-SQL querying, and database design.  
    Diana lives in Huntington Beach with her husband and two Labrador retrievers.  Diana is one of the authors of TribalSQL (tribalsql.com).
</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30269</importID>
      <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Grant Fritchey is a Data Platform MVP with over 20 years’ experience in IT, including time spent in support and development. He has worked with SQL Server since 6.0 back in 1995. He has also developed in VB, VB.NET, C#, and Java. Grant has written books for Apress and Simple-Talk. Grant presents at conferences and user groups, large and small, all over the world. He joined Redgate Software as a product evangelist in January 2011.</description>
      <twitter>@gfritchey</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/scarydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://scarydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@gfritchey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32030</importID>
      <name>Michael Steineke</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Steineke is a Windows Server Platform expert with an industry-wide reputation as an innovator in the areas of Windows Server, storage and network architecture, disaster recovery, datacenter configuration, and SQL Server. He is a Cloud and Datacenter Management MVP specializing in High Availability and has spoken on subjects like Windows Server, clustering, Storage, Hyper-V, SQL Server, and multi-site clusters at user groups and conferences of all sizes, including SQL Saturdays, SQL PASS Summit, Microsoft TechEd, and the Microsoft MVP Summit.</description>
      <twitter>@MSteineke</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelsteineke</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.michaelsteineke.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MSteineke</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11732</importID>
      <name>Clint Kunz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Clint Kunz is a Data Platform Technology Specialist working for Microsoft Corporation in Southern California. He has been working with SQL Server and in the Business Intelligence and Data Warehousing field for over 11 years. Clint focuses on helping customers adopt and deploy Microsoft tools to solve their analysis, reporting, and information management challenges. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>31920</importID>
      <name>Mitchell Bottel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mitchell Bottel is a senior database administrator with Sutter Physician Services, owner of Innovative IT Consulting and President of the Sacramento SQL Sevrer User Group. He has 14 years of IT experience, focusing on SQL Server for the last ten years with an emphasis on database administration and high availability solutions. He has authored blog posts on the SQLServerPerformance website and written White Papers on using Dynamic Management Views.</description>
      <twitter>@SacSQLDude</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mitchespitch.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SacSQLDude</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16578</importID>
      <name>Jeremiah Peschka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeremiah sees the magic in technology. He knows how to do things now, and he also knows how to think about possibilities. Jeremiah likes to imagine new kinds of indexes, new kinds of teams, new kinds of applications — this means when you need to reinvent something, or get unblocked, you should talk to Jeremiah.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://brentozar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9012</importID>
      <name>Benjamin Nevarez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Benjamin Nevarez is a SQL Server independent consultant based in Los Angeles, California, who specializes in SQL Server query tuning and optimization. He is the author of “SQL Server 2014 Query Tuning amp; Optimization” and “Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer” and co-author of “SQL Server 2012 Internals.quot; Benjamin has also been a speaker at many SQL Server conferences, including PASS Summit, SQL Server Connections, and SQLBits. His blog can be found at http://www.benjaminnevarez.com.</description>
      <twitter>@BenjaminNevarez</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.benjaminnevarez.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BenjaminNevarez</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32436</importID>
      <name>Randy Knight</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Randy Knight is a data professional who has worked with Microsoft technology for over 25 years, focusing on SQL Server since 1997. He has worked in a variety of settings, including 6 years as a database architect for match.com. In 2010, he founded SQL Server Solutions Group LLC, a boutique SQL Server consultancy.  A Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) in SQL Server, he speaks often at events all over the country including the  PASS Summit, SQLIntersections, and numerous SQL Saturday and User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>randy_knight</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/randyknight</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlsolutionsgroup.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=randy_knight</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30270</importID>
      <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Grant Fritchey is a Data Platform MVP with over 20 years’ experience in IT, including time spent in support and development. He has worked with SQL Server since 6.0 back in 1995. He has also developed in VB, VB.NET, C#, and Java. Grant has written books for Apress and Simple-Talk. Grant presents at conferences and user groups, large and small, all over the world. He joined Redgate Software as a product evangelist in January 2011.</description>
      <twitter>@gfritchey</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/scarydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://scarydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@gfritchey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14945</importID>
      <name>Harry Chandra</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Harry Chandra is a SQL Server, VMWare and PowerShell enthusiast working with various releases of SQL Server for over 10 years. His main focus is in Administration and High Availability for SQL Server, although he has always strived to expand his knowledge into other area of SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>HarryChandraPDX</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.HarryChandra.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=HarryChandraPDX</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14051</importID>
      <name>Eddie Wuerch</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eddie Wuerch has 20 years of experience as a SQL Server specialist in a much-longer IT career. A Microsoft Certified Master, Eddie spends his days in the Salesforce Marketing Cloud, focusing on performance, scale, and uptime for the massive SQL Server backend. These SQL Servers churn billions of transactions daily against trillions of rows of data in a 24x7 continuously-available online system accessed by millions worldwide every day.</description>
      <twitter>@EddieW</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/eddiewuerch</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.indydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@EddieW</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32437</importID>
      <name>Randy Knight</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Randy Knight is a data professional who has worked with Microsoft technology for over 25 years, focusing on SQL Server since 1997. He has worked in a variety of settings, including 6 years as a database architect for match.com. In 2010, he founded SQL Server Solutions Group LLC, a boutique SQL Server consultancy.  A Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) in SQL Server, he speaks often at events all over the country including the  PASS Summit, SQLIntersections, and numerous SQL Saturday and User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>randy_knight</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/randyknight</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlsolutionsgroup.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=randy_knight</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23013</importID>
      <name>Rick  Morelan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick has worked more than 12 years at Microsoft and has attained over 30 Microsoft technical including certifications in applications, networking, databases and .NET development (MCDBA, MCTS, MCITP, MCAD, MOE, MCSE, MCSE+I). He has also provided training for NW University, Volt Technical Education, The DigiGirlz, and Microsoft. Rick is the Author of the 5 volume SQL Joes 2 Pros book series.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>8871</importID>
      <name>Aaron Nelson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Aaron Nelson is an author, public speaker, blogger, and leader in the community.  He has over 15 years of experience in architecture, Business Intelligence, development, and performance tuning of SQL Server. Aaron has received many certifications and is a six time winner of the Microsoft MVP Award.

Aaron leads the PowerShell Virtual Group of PASS (SQLPS.io), is a board member of PowerShell.org, and is a volunteer at his PASS Local Group, AtlantaMDF.</description>
      <twitter>SQLvariant</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlvariant</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlvariant.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLvariant</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14053</importID>
      <name>Eddie Wuerch</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eddie Wuerch has 20 years of experience as a SQL Server specialist in a much-longer IT career. A Microsoft Certified Master, Eddie spends his days in the Salesforce Marketing Cloud, focusing on performance, scale, and uptime for the massive SQL Server backend. These SQL Servers churn billions of transactions daily against trillions of rows of data in a 24x7 continuously-available online system accessed by millions worldwide every day.</description>
      <twitter>@EddieW</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/eddiewuerch</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.indydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@EddieW</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32017</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denny Cherry is the owner and principal consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates Consulting and has over a decade of experience working with platforms such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Microsoft SQL Server, Hyper-V, vSphere, and Enterprise Storage solutions. Denny’s areas of technical expertise include system architecture, performance tuning, security, replication, and troubleshooting. Denny currently holds several Microsoft Certifications related to SQL Server 2000 through 2019, including being a Microsoft Certified Master, Microsoft MVP and VMware vExpert Award.</description>
      <twitter>mrdenny</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrdenny</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.dcac.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mrdenny</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9014</importID>
      <name>Benjamin Nevarez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Benjamin Nevarez is a SQL Server independent consultant based in Los Angeles, California, who specializes in SQL Server query tuning and optimization. He is the author of “SQL Server 2014 Query Tuning amp; Optimization” and “Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer” and co-author of “SQL Server 2012 Internals.quot; Benjamin has also been a speaker at many SQL Server conferences, including PASS Summit, SQL Server Connections, and SQLBits. His blog can be found at http://www.benjaminnevarez.com.</description>
      <twitter>@BenjaminNevarez</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.benjaminnevarez.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BenjaminNevarez</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29024</importID>
      <name>Benjamin Muller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben is an accomplished business and technology professional with significant management experience and hands-on involvement in a wide variety of business areas, including Finance, Marketing, Operations, and Information Systems. He is skilled at designing, implementing, and managing complex business information systems.

Ben leads the Business Intelligence and Productivity practice at CSG Professional Services, Inc.  He has overseen and participated in many DW/BI projects for clients ranging in size from small manufacturers to regional utilities and national banks.

Ben has given dozens of presentations and workshops on DW/BI and Productivity concepts and practices, and he loves to both teach and learn.</description>
      <twitter>@benjmuller</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@benjmuller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32019</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denny Cherry is the owner and principal consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates Consulting and has over a decade of experience working with platforms such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Microsoft SQL Server, Hyper-V, vSphere, and Enterprise Storage solutions. Denny’s areas of technical expertise include system architecture, performance tuning, security, replication, and troubleshooting. Denny currently holds several Microsoft Certifications related to SQL Server 2000 through 2019, including being a Microsoft Certified Master, Microsoft MVP and VMware vExpert Award.</description>
      <twitter>mrdenny</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrdenny</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.dcac.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mrdenny</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9015</importID>
      <name>Benjamin Nevarez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Benjamin Nevarez is a SQL Server independent consultant based in Los Angeles, California, who specializes in SQL Server query tuning and optimization. He is the author of “SQL Server 2014 Query Tuning amp; Optimization” and “Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer” and co-author of “SQL Server 2012 Internals.quot; Benjamin has also been a speaker at many SQL Server conferences, including PASS Summit, SQL Server Connections, and SQLBits. His blog can be found at http://www.benjaminnevarez.com.</description>
      <twitter>@BenjaminNevarez</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.benjaminnevarez.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BenjaminNevarez</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29025</importID>
      <name>Benjamin Muller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben is an accomplished business and technology professional with significant management experience and hands-on involvement in a wide variety of business areas, including Finance, Marketing, Operations, and Information Systems. He is skilled at designing, implementing, and managing complex business information systems.

Ben leads the Business Intelligence and Productivity practice at CSG Professional Services, Inc.  He has overseen and participated in many DW/BI projects for clients ranging in size from small manufacturers to regional utilities and national banks.

Ben has given dozens of presentations and workshops on DW/BI and Productivity concepts and practices, and he loves to both teach and learn.</description>
      <twitter>@benjmuller</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@benjmuller</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16581</importID>
      <name>Jeremiah Peschka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeremiah sees the magic in technology. He knows how to do things now, and he also knows how to think about possibilities. Jeremiah likes to imagine new kinds of indexes, new kinds of teams, new kinds of applications — this means when you need to reinvent something, or get unblocked, you should talk to Jeremiah.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://brentozar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9013</importID>
      <name>Benjamin Nevarez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Benjamin Nevarez is a SQL Server independent consultant based in Los Angeles, California, who specializes in SQL Server query tuning and optimization. He is the author of “SQL Server 2014 Query Tuning amp; Optimization” and “Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer” and co-author of “SQL Server 2012 Internals.quot; Benjamin has also been a speaker at many SQL Server conferences, including PASS Summit, SQL Server Connections, and SQLBits. His blog can be found at http://www.benjaminnevarez.com.</description>
      <twitter>@BenjaminNevarez</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.benjaminnevarez.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BenjaminNevarez</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23014</importID>
      <name>Rick  Morelan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick has worked more than 12 years at Microsoft and has attained over 30 Microsoft technical including certifications in applications, networking, databases and .NET development (MCDBA, MCTS, MCITP, MCAD, MOE, MCSE, MCSE+I). He has also provided training for NW University, Volt Technical Education, The DigiGirlz, and Microsoft. Rick is the Author of the 5 volume SQL Joes 2 Pros book series.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>33856</importID>
      <name>Warren Sifre</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warren Sifre has been in the IT community since 1998 and has worked in a variety of industries deploying solutions utilizing MS SQL Server in one capacity or another. In 2003, he decided to make SQL Server his mastery and has since developed skills in most defined disciplines of MS SQL.  Currently he is a Principal Consultant and Technology Leader with Moser Consulting.  He is responsible for BI Solution Architecture and the mentorship of team members.  He has been a SQL Saturday Speaker since 2012, Azure Global Bootcamp, and many user groups in 2015 alone.  He has a passion for knowledge transfer and solutions architecture, with a keen interested in Info Security.</description>
      <twitter>WAS_SQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/wsifre</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.broadstrokeconsulting.com/blog/, http://www.allegient.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=WAS_SQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10309</importID>
      <name>Ben Aminnia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben Aminnia is a database architect / .NET developer / consultant at Pointer Corporation with over 25 years of experience in developing database systems and managing a team of SQL Server developers and DBAs. He's also the architect of Virtual Information Portal (VIP) System and the past-president of Los Angeles SQL Server Professionals Group.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.pointercorp.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12870</importID>
      <name>Doug Barrett</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Douglas Barrett draws on 15 years of data warehouse experience, including 10 years as a Consultant and solution specialist for Microsoft and WhereScape, delivering data warehouse projects using agile tools and techniques.   Major data warehouse projects have included Basel II Credit Risk for a Retail Bank, Airline Travel Agent, Hospital Episode of Care, Hotel Occupancy and Utility companies.  </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29201</importID>
      <name>Brent Greenwood</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brent Greenwood, MS, MCITP, CBIP, is a PowerPivot junkie and long-time Microsoft BI Pro with 13+ years of experience in the data analysis, data warehousing, and business intelligence crafts.  He's delivered solutions and worn lots of different hats in a variety of verticals, including Investment Management, Brokerage, Insurance Services, Healthcare, and Higher Education. Most importantly, Brent is a cycling enthusiast and loves riding and building prototypes with AdventureWorks cycling data.</description>
      <twitter>@YoungMSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/brentgreenwood</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://brentgreenwood.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@YoungMSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29562</importID>
      <name>Matt Hollingsworth</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt Hollingsworth has spent over twenty years in various roles in the database industry and is currently a Microsoft data platform architect covering the Microsoft South West district including Hawaii. Prior to his current role Matt spent over ten years in the Microsoft SQL Server development team in Redmond as a Program Manager for Always On, Replication, Log Shipping, Mirroring and the annual Oracle competitive review. Matt got married a week ago, so go easy on him.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14052</importID>
      <name>Eddie Wuerch</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eddie Wuerch has 20 years of experience as a SQL Server specialist in a much-longer IT career. A Microsoft Certified Master, Eddie spends his days in the Salesforce Marketing Cloud, focusing on performance, scale, and uptime for the massive SQL Server backend. These SQL Servers churn billions of transactions daily against trillions of rows of data in a 24x7 continuously-available online system accessed by millions worldwide every day.</description>
      <twitter>@EddieW</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/eddiewuerch</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.indydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@EddieW</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>9015</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9015</id>
          <name>Benjamin Nevarez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Top Query Optimizer Topics for Better Performance</title>
      <description>This session, updated for SQL Server 2012, will show you how a better understanding of how the Query Optimizer works can help you to improve the performance of your queries. I will show you the top 10 Query Optimizer topics that can give you the most benefit by focusing both on concepts and practical solutions. Several areas of the query processor will be covered, everything from troubleshooting query performance problems and identifying what information the Query Optimizer needs to do a better job to the extreme cases where, because of the its limitations, the Query Optimizer may not give you a good plan and you may need to take a different approach.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16578</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16578</id>
          <name>Jeremiah Peschka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Rules, Rules, and Rules</title>
      <description>Computers are governed by the rules of physics: electrons, drive heads, and disk platters can only move so fast. Understanding how these rules operate and interact leads to insights into application performance. Understanding why something might perform a certain way makes it much easier to understand the tradeoffs of a specific design.

Database systems are built according to those rules: memory is faster than disk which is faster than the network. Database schemas and queries are built within the rules of database systems. You will hit the limitations of these rules. If you know what the rules are and why they are in place, you'll know when it's time to break them... and how to succeed.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27564</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27564</id>
          <name>Warren Sifre</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>AlwaysOn – Way to get your 9’s?</title>
      <description>We are always being told 9’s, 9’s  and more 9’s, but when implementation time comes to take action, technology / budget limitations get in the way, especially in the High Availability and Disaster Recovery (HA/DR) technology space.  Clustering and Mirroring are great and meet many of our needs, but there are some things we have wished for, such as a mirror database that is usable. AlwaysOn solves this limitation by merging both Mirroring and Multi-Node Multi-Subnet Clustering (True Geo-Clustering Support!!!).  AlwaysOn also allows the replica database to be used in a Read-Only capacity, so we can use it for reporting purposes. (Imagine that!)  Join us in providing a warm welcome to this new functionality with extensive demos.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11322</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11322</id>
          <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Preparing Data for Analysis as Tabular Models</title>
      <description>The new Tabular Model in SQL Server 2012 is being touted as a powerful analytic engine that is faster and easier to implement than traditional cubes using Analysis Service.  In this session Carlos Bossy will demonstrate how to develop analytic models using your existing data sources and will discuss best practices for preparing data so that it can be effectively used as a Tabular database.  In addition to creating the model, Carlos will show you how to quickly add measures, hierarchies, and calculated columns to provide a rich user experience.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32019</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32019</id>
          <name>Denny Cherry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Table Indexing for the .NET Developer</title>
      <description>In this session we will be looking at the best and worse practices for indexing tables within your SQL Server 2008 databases.  We will also be looking into the new indexing features that are available in SQL Server 2008 (and SQL Server 2005) and how you the .NET developer can make the best use of them to get your code running its best.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>8871</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>8871</id>
          <name>Aaron Nelson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>PowerShell for Data Professionals</title>
      <description>You’ve heard it said, “If you have to do it twice, automate it.” Cut the learning curve and get a real handle on this powerful automation tool. This session walks you through a dozen scripts to simplify and easily automate time-consuming and tedious elements of your day to day job. This isn’t stuff you’ll use SOMEDAY, these are scripts you can use when you get home tonight. Harness the power of Power Shell to easily find Servers short on space. Script out tables and constraints across all of your databases at once. Backup databases and restore them to a different environment. These tricks and many others will allow PowerShell to simplify your job like no other tool.
</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11323</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11323</id>
          <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Real-time Data Warehouse and Reporting</title>
      <description>This session will present a Database and ETL Architecture that allows you to smoothly move data from your application databases across the enterprise in real-time to your data warehouse.  Carlos Bossy will show you how to use SQL Server features such as Replication, Change Data Capture, SSIS and other techniques to extract, transform and load data fast and dependably and view a real demonstration of the system in action.  Finally, Carlos will show how to use Reporting Services to present data with a minimum amount of latency.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11468</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11468</id>
          <name>Chris Dickey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Extended Events in SQL Server 2008 and 2012</title>
      <description>I will demonstrate practical examples of how to use Extended Events to figure out details of what SQL Server is doing when problems are occuring. You can dig deep into the internals of SQL Server with Extended Events since they track operations at a very low level. Extended Events were first introduced in SQL Server 2008 but have not been used that much because of the learning curve. SQL Server 2012 has promoted Extended Events to a much more important level. The feature is now ready to replace Profiler as the primary tool to gather real time details of query execution. The majority of my presentation will be demoing real world problem solving.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9958</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9958</id>
          <name>Audrey Hammonds</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Performance Impact of Database Design</title>
      <description>Time-travel stories all have one common plot element - some action done in the past has big impact on the future. Sometimes you get lucky… Hoverboards! Sometimes, not so much... Morlocks! The same holds true in your database. Design decisions have a huge impact on how you’re going to get data into and out of your database. This session illustrates the performance impact of common database design issues and proposes design alternatives that will help your database avoid an H.G. Wellsian future.
</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32030</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32030</id>
          <name>Michael Steineke</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL 2012 HA/DR Enhancements  Overiew</title>
      <description>Overview of new features and enhancements in SQL Server 2012 ‘Denali’ to help support High Availability and Disaster Recovery. Breakdown of AlwaysOn Feature set, and design considerations. What are Availability Groups, and Readable Secondary’s, and how do they work. Multi-Subnet SQL clustering, what no more stretched VLAN? Including demo’s and working systems to review configurations.
</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>31921</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>31921</id>
          <name>Mitchell Bottel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Art of Networking and Self Promotion</title>
      <description>Self-promotion is often times the best promotion you can get. In this session, we will talk about how to promote yourself, your brand and your career. We will discuss Social Medias, communities, volunteering and other ways to get your name out… What are the first steps? Come find out. We will hit some of the basic techniques to the advanced strategies.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>12870</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12870</id>
          <name>Doug Barrett</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Warehouse Best Practices</title>
      <description>This session will describe the best practises for designing a data warehouse to get the most out of SQL Server.  Doug has worked in data warehousing for 12 years and will blend experience, with best practises and recommendations from Microsoft's Fast Track program.  Each version of SQL Server introduces new features specifically for data warehousing - by applying the correct technique, feature, hint, modelling approach and layout the data warehouse will be faster and more scalable.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23014</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23014</id>
          <name>Rick  Morelan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Avoid Errors on Errors</title>
      <description>Did you know that when SQL encounters an error of Severity 11 (or higher), there a 4 different ways it can react? Learn how to predict the Error Action or control it. This is possible with or without structured error handling. See both ways to control the outcome. This is a very common workplace faux pas and a Microsoft Certification topic for Dev and Admins. We will use lessons from SQL Programming Joes 2 Pros Vol4.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30269</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30269</id>
          <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Common Backup Problems and How to Deal With Them</title>
      <description>SQL Server backups can be burdensome to set up and maintain. All sorts of different problems can occur. This session targets the most common problems encountered while working with SQL Server backup and shows you how to identify these issues in your environment. In fact, I’ll walk you through how to prevent these common issues from ever cropping up within your systems in the first place. Be prepared for information you can take back to the office and put to work right away making your system backups more reliable. With backups running correctly all the time, you’ll be protecting your systems better, and feeling a lot less stress when it times to perform an emergency restore.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16581</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16581</id>
          <name>Jeremiah Peschka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Rewrite your T-SQL for Great Good!</title>
      <description>Refactoring SQL is not like refactoring application code. This talk will demonstrate proven SQL refactoring techniques that will help you identify where performance gains can be made, apply quick fixes, improve readability, and help you quickly locate places to make sweeping performance improvements. Jeremiah Peschka has years of hands on experience tuning SQL applications for performance, throughput, and concurrency.
</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13091</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13091</id>
          <name>Denise McInerney</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Women in Technology Un-Panel</title>
      <description>There are a variety of issues that affect women working in tech today, both as individuals and as a group. What concerns you as a WIT or someone who supports WIT? Bring your questions and ideas to a WIT un-panel.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29024</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29024</id>
          <name>Benjamin Muller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Discussion-Time Analytics: BI for smart meetings</title>
      <description>Tired of supposedly data-driven discussions that quickly devolve into anarchy, finger pointing, and second guessing? This session will show you how to use new and improved SQL Server 2012 BI capabilities, including PowerPivot v2 and Power View to clear the FUD and get your meetings back on track.  We will discuss principals for creating effective, business-oriented BISM models, and visualization techniques that emphasize clarity and usability. </description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>31920</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>31920</id>
          <name>Mitchell Bottel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Easily Manage your Servers with Policy Based Mgmt</title>
      <description>In this session, you will learn how to setup and implement Central Management Server (CMS) to run queries against multiple SQL servers in your environment. We will also cover Policy Based Management (PBM) and how to use out of the box best practices and create custom policies to maintain your environment. We will then look at using both CMS and PBM in conjunction with each other to monitor your environment.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13395</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13395</id>
          <name>Douglas Barrett</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Agile Data Warehousing with WhereScape RED</title>
      <description>This session will demonstrate how to build, iterate, document and deploy a data warehouse very quickly without compromising quality using WhereScape RED.  WhereScape RED is a data warehouse development environment that automates many time consuming steps, generating tables, processing code, indexes, workflow and documentation as a single process.  The resulting development speed and the ability to make changes extremely efficiently makes it the ideal tool for agile projects.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29025</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29025</id>
          <name>Benjamin Muller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Self-service BI with Power View</title>
      <description>In this session Benjamin Muller, Practice Manager, Business Intelligence at CSG Pro will discuss Microsoft's upcoming Business Intelligence tool, Power View. Packaged with the SQL Server 2012 release, Power View lets users of all skill levels quickly create dynamic and compelling reports and analyses which can be instantly published to SharePoint.  Ben will review the features and functionality of Power View, and talk through some common Power View scenarios.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10309</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10309</id>
          <name>Ben Aminnia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>From Zero to SQL Azure in 10 Cloudy Steps</title>
      <description>This is my diary of the adventurous road I traveled for exploring the new world of SQL Azure. It spans a time period of about 18 months, with a mix of failures, success stories, and lessons learned.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>31531</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>31531</id>
          <name>Lynn Langit</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>noSQL - why do I care, when  how should I use it?</title>
      <description>Are you confused (and concerned) by all the talk about noSQL solutions?  Are you uncertain as to which solution is right for your situation? (if any).  Come to this demo-filled session to understand the noSQL landscape.  Includes info about cloud-based BLOB storage from all of the big vendors, i.e. Amazon, Google, Microsoft,  Also includes info about Hadoop and other open source databases, such as MongoDB.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32017</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32017</id>
          <name>Denny Cherry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Table Partitioning from the ground up</title>
      <description>In this session we will be looking at the SQL Server table partitioning features which were introduced in SQL Server 2008.  We will 

look at how to create partitioned tables and indexes as well as the internals of the table.  We will also look at how to move data 

from one partition to another and from one table to another with minimal to no impact to the users.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9959</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9959</id>
          <name>Audrey Hammonds</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Shiny New T-SQL for SQL Server 2012</title>
      <description>There has been a lot of fanfare for some of the new features of SQL Server 2012. (AlwaysOn and T-SQL Windowing, I’m looking at you.) But there are a few other shiny little gems hidden between the replicas and frame clauses. The good folks at Microsoft have given T-SQL a few new features and functions, and it’s time to dig in and take a look at what presents they’ve brought us. T-SQL enhancements for 2012, including Result Sets, paging support, metadata discovery, new scalar functions, and the THROW clause for error handling are demonstrated in this session. Shiny!</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23013</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23013</id>
          <name>Rick  Morelan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Basic Performance Tips and Gotchas</title>
      <description>Forget Profiler for a second, I have seen one poorly placed index bring an enterprise database to its knees. We will cover the basic tips of performance which always work and the ones which always fail. What can you do – and what should you do –when it comes to the most common types of indexes so you always make the right move. We will use lessons from SQL Architecture Joes 2 Pros Vol3.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10310</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10310</id>
          <name>Ben Aminnia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 8</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Journey through New Features of SQL Server 2012</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2012 promises to be another milestone in improved performance, security, self-service BI, and migration to the cloud.  Among the enhancements in SQL Server 2012 are 14 new functions in T-SQL as well as SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT) and the new talk of the town: "AlwaysOn!"  Additional topics within the presentation will cover different viewpoints of DBAs, Developers, and IT Managers, both before and after the decision to upgrade to SQL Server 2012 and required planning steps.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30270</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30270</id>
          <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL Deployment and CI Best Practices</title>
      <description>While most T-SQL developers focus on writing quality T-SQL code and efficient queries, what they often forget is how it should best be deployed. This includes deployment of new applications, as well as upgrades and bug fixes. In this session, you will learn many best practices involving the principles of continuous integration, such as maintaining a code repository, automating builds, self-testing, auditing, automated deployment, and much more. This session is designed for both DBA administrators and developers who want to optimize their T-SQL deployment process.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18091</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18091</id>
          <name>Kendra Little</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server First Responder Kit</title>
      <description>When your SQL Server is critically injured, you need a first responder kit to help you diagnose the problem and apply emergency aid. In this session, Kendra Little introduces you to queries, built-in tools, and processes for triaging an emergency. If you have one year's experience with database administration, this session will set you up to triage like a pro.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32437</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32437</id>
          <name>Randy Knight</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding Transaction Isolation Levels</title>
      <description>SQL Server offers several isolation levels beyond the default "READ COMMITTED".  But understanding when to use each one can be daunting.  Whether you are a developer who needs to understand how isolation works and  and why NOLOCK is not an appropriate hint in most cases, or a seasoned DBA who needs to understand the less commonly used isolation methods, this session is for you.  We will look at each level, how it impacts the engine, and examine appropriate (and inapproriate) use cases for each.
</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29201</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29201</id>
          <name>Brent Greenwood</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dimensional Modeling Fundamentals </title>
      <description>In this session, we will walk through the fundamentals of dimensional modeling that are at the core of Kimball method data warehousing.  We will cover theory and real world applications of the following:
- The modeling process
- Fact table patterns
- Dimension patterns
- Conforming structures
- Advanced modeling patterns and best practices</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9012</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9012</id>
          <name>Benjamin Nevarez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Columnstore Indexes and Data Warehouses</title>
      <description>Columnstore indexes are one of the most exciting new features available in the next release of SQL Server 2012. Combined with new query processing algorithms, columnstore indexes are designed to improve the performance of data warehouses queries by several orders of magnitude providing more business value by allowing users to interactively explore the data. This session explains how columnstore indexes improve the performance of data warehouse queries—focusing on the query processing and optimization aspect of the technology—and identifies limitations of the current product release.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32436</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32436</id>
          <name>Randy Knight</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding SQL Server XML Features </title>
      <description>The XML Functionality embedded into SQL Server 2005 and 2008 is one of its most powerful yet least understood features.  This seems to be primarily because DBA's shy away from it and developers prefer to work with XML in their code.  In this session we will explore the XML features of SQL Server and how we can bridge these two worlds. Topics covered will include retrieving relational data as XML, storing XML in the database using the XML Datatype, XML indexes, and the XQuery functions included in SQL Server.  We will also look at using XML as stored procedure parameters as a way to pass large amounts of complex data between client and server. </description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9013</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9013</id>
          <name>Benjamin Nevarez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer</title>
      <description>The SQL Server Query Optimizer is a cost-based optimizer: it analyzes a number of candidate execution plans for a given query, estimates the cost of each of these plans, and selects the plan with the lowest cost. In this session I will go into the internals of the Query Optimizer and will show you the steps that it performs in the background covering everything from the time a query is submitted to SQL Server until an execution plan is generated. Why query optimization is an inherently complex problem and why challenges in some of its most fundamental areas are still being addressed today will be covered as well. 
</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14052</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14052</id>
          <name>Eddie Wuerch</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Join Us! Getting Started as a Technical Speaker</title>
      <description>Have you ever thought about speaking at a user group or SQL Saturday, but weren't quite sure how to get started? If so, this session is for you! Technical speaking is loads of fun, great for your career, and you get to hang out with some terrific people. This session will provide the tools necessary to get your first session off the ground, and prep you to be a great speaker. Attend this session and you'll be able to: * Identify your topic and build a killer abstract for it, * Design and build the presentation, and * Prepare and deliver your first session</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29562</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29562</id>
          <name>Matt Hollingsworth</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2012 EIM (SSIS, DQS, and MDS)</title>
      <description>This session will cover the enhancements in SQL Server 2012's Enterprise Information Management Platform (EIM), That includes SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS), the new Data Quality Services Engine (DQS), and Master Data Services new capabilities (MDS). We'll also touch on the publically available information on Project Barcelona - the new Data Lineage and Impact Analysis services under development as well.
</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14051</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14051</id>
          <name>Eddie Wuerch</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>TempDB Performance Troubleshooting and Optimizing</title>
      <description>Every SQL Server instance relies on the tempdb database. Whether through explicit use with #temp tables or @table variables, or implicit use through working space for many other operations, most tempdb databases get quite a workout. This session will dig into many of the otherwise-hidden issues that can kill server performance. After this session, you will be able to spot tempdb performance issues, drill into the causes, and take the steps necessary to solve them.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14945</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14945</id>
          <name>Harry Chandra</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 8</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Log Shipping and Mirroring</title>
      <description>In this introductory session, we will go through an overview of SQL Server Mirroring and Log Shipping.  What are the parts and modes of database mirroring. You will also be introduce to log shipping and how it works. We will have a demo part of the session where we will go through every step of how to set up mirroring and log shipping.  By the end of this session, you should have a general understanding and ability to deploy database mirroring and log shipping to meet your High Availability and Disaster Recovery requirement. 

</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22112</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22112</id>
          <name>Phil Helmer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Up Your Game With OUTPUT</title>
      <description>There are some classic database programming tasks that rely on answering the question "What did I just change?" Prior to SQL Server 2005, we had to use functions like SCOPE_IDENTITY() and some extra tricks for handling multiple rows. Some people even had to resort to triggers. Yikes!! This session focuses on the practical use cases for the T-SQL OUTPUT clause. More importantly, you will find out how you can ditch the tricks of the past for a simpler solution that will help keep you sane.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14053</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14053</id>
          <name>Eddie Wuerch</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Page Latches for Mere Mortals</title>
      <description>Latching is a necessary function of the database engine. Although latching is a topic is normally presented only in expert-level sessions, a good grasp of the problems excessive latching exposes is important even for novice tuners. This session focuses on the PAGELATCH_* and PAGEIOLATCH_* wait types, explaining what is happening, why it is happening, and how to use the exposed information to tune queries and solve performance problems. If you've seen these wait types in Activity Monitor and wonder what they meant, then this session is for you!</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9014</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9014</id>
          <name>Benjamin Nevarez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding Parameter Sniffing</title>
      <description>Parameter sniffing is a good thing: it is used by the Query Optimizer to produce an execution plan tailored to the current parameters of a query. However, due to the way that the plan cache stores these plans in memory, sometimes can also be a performance problem. This session will show you how parameter sniffing works and in which cases could be a problem. How to diagnose and troubleshoot parameter sniffing problems and their solutions will be discussed as well. The session will also include details on how the Query Optimizer uses the histogram and density components of the statistics object and some other advanced topics. </description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30360</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30360</id>
          <name>Ike Ellis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Azure Federations</title>
      <description>SQL Azure Federations is an amazing way to scale-out relational database applications.  You will learn about new T-SQL keywords and why SQL Azure is uniquely suited to solve the relational scale-out problem.  Come discover how you can use SQL Azure Federations to handle scale problems of any size!</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29980</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29980</id>
          <name>Diana Dee</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Security 101</title>
      <description>Securing SQL Server requires an understanding of how a SQL Server instance and its objects are accessed and how permissions for access are granted or not allowed.

This presentation will cover the entire spectrum from service accounts, logins, and users, to granular permissions and encryption.  You should acquire enough understanding to be able to apply the "principle of least privilege" in your own SQL Server environment.

Content:
•	Service accounts
•	Logins and Users
•	Permissions
•	Encryption
•	Some new security features of SQL 2012
</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30481</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30481</id>
          <name>Janis Griffin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Don't Panic, DBAs!  Databases on VMware made easy.</title>
      <description>More and more companies are virtualizing with VMWare, and databases are the next logical step. This presentation will explore the fundamentals of monitoring databases running in a VMWare environment because it can be much different than when running on a physical machine. You will learn business and technical benefits of virtualization, master new terms and concepts, pick up useful planning tips and tricks, and cover best practices for maintaining optimum performance in a VMWare environment. </description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11732</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11732</id>
          <name>Clint Kunz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing your BI Semantic Model for Power View</title>
      <description>Power View is the new ad-hoc data visualization tool coming in SQL Server 2012. Power View runs on a Business Intelligence Semantic Model created in either PowerPivot for Excel, or in Visual Studio 2010 for publishing to SQL Server Analysis Services. In this session we will go through the complete process for creating several (BISM) models from scratch, and working up in complexity using the Data Analysis Expresssion Language (DAX) to provide a functional and usable experience for your end-users that will use Power View. </description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30483</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30483</id>
          <name>Janis Griffin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 8</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance Management – 2008 MDW - How  Why</title>
      <description>Management Data Warehouse (MDW) which was introduced in 2008 can provide DBAs with useful performance information about Disk Usage, Server Activity and Query Statistics. This presentation will explore how to set up MDW, look at its underlying schema / statistics and point out some of its shortcomings in comparison with other performance tools.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>33855</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>33855</id>
          <name>Warren Sifre</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Contained DB?  Did it do something wrong?</title>
      <description>Imagine an environment where moving a database from a SQL Instance to another is as simple as just restoring the database. (Yes, no other steps!) SQL Server 2012 RC0 now supports Partial Contained databases.  We will cover the different levels of containment, configuring SQL Server to support it, and much more (i.e. Demos).</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21463</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21463</id>
          <name>Nitin Salgar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 8</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Azure Data Sync</title>
      <description>This session is to discuss the data synchronization strategies. We'll go over setting up a Data Sync service between On Premise and Clound,cloud to cloud and other topologies offered. Will discuss one time data transfer options such as dacpac, Migration wizard and bcp</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>33856</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>33856</id>
          <name>Warren Sifre</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to FileTables in SQL 2012</title>
      <description>What are FileTables?  How do they work?  What are their limitations?  These questions and more will be answered in this demo filled presentation.  We will walkthrough the configuration and implementation of this feature.  We will show you some use cases on how this fucntionality can help you manage your data in whatever forms it exists.</description>
      <startTime>3/24/2012 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/24/2012 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>