<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #198 - Vancouver, BC 2013</name>
    <startDate>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>400</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-06:00) Saskatchewan</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat198</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>British Columbia Institute of Technology (BCIT)</name>
      <street>3700 Willingdon Avenue</street>
      <city>Burnaby</city>
      <state>British Columbia, Canada</state>
      <zipcode>V5G 3H2</zipcode>
      <longitude>-123.00259</longitude>
      <latitude>49.24973</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>13</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/sqlsaturday/eventsponsors/Quest_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>8</importID>
      <name>FusionIO</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.fusionio.com/solutions/microsoft-sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/files/18b704b1-226d-48fe-b0b8-f7b4d3443b3d.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1</importID>
      <name>Confio</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.confio.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/resized-confio_logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1105</importID>
      <name>SQLNotes</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlnotes.info</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/cdf462de-6e93-4601-9224-e7311dfd8cdc.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>6</importID>
      <name>Melissa Data Corp.</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.melissadata.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/931/EventSponsor_14597.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>567</importID>
      <name>DevTeach</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.devteach.com/Index.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://devteach.com/images/devteachlogo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1128</importID>
      <name>Robert L Davis</name>
      <label>Personal Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlsoldier.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsoldier.com/imgs/SQLSoldierdotcom.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>137</importID>
      <name>Steve Stedman</name>
      <label>Personal Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://DatabaseHealth.SteveStedman.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://stevestedman.com/wp-content/uploads/SteveStedman-Database-Health-Reports.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>299</importID>
      <name>SQLvariant</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://sqlvariant.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlvariant.com/BlogSupport/Images/SQLvariant_Logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1317</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Canada</name>
      <label>Titanium</label>
      <url>https://technet.microsoft.com/en-ca</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/e403d21e-948f-4fa5-accf-5c0dd8a24c5f.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13363</importID>
      <name>Donabel Santos</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Donabel Santos (MCITP, MCT) is a SQL Server MVP and is the senior SQL Server Consultant/Trainer at QueryWorks Solutions in Vancouver, BC. She has worked with SQL Server since version 2000 in numerous development, tuning, reporting, and integration projects with ERPs, CRMs, SharePoint, and other custom applications. She is the author of SQL Server 2012 with PowerShell V3 Cookbook from Packt Publishing.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmusings.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34676</importID>
      <name>John Huang</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Huang, SQL MCM and MVP, has been working with SQL Server since 1994. He is an independent SQL Server consultant in Vancouver specialized in complex data processing, data warehouse, and performance tuning. </description>
      <twitter>@sqlnotes</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.sqlnotes.info</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlnotes.info</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlnotes</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15379</importID>
      <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niko Neugebauer is a Data Platform Consultant. A SQL Server MVP with over 20 years of experience in IT, he is passionate about the Microsoft Data Platform and community. Founder of the Portuguese SQL Server User Group and the main organizer of the first SQLSaturday event outside of North America (#78 Portugal), Niko speaks regularly at events such as PASS Summit, SQLRally, SQLBits, and SQLSaturday events around the world. Niko loves sharing information and knowledge and has authored over 130 blog posts on Columnstore Indexes, and regularly contributes to the open-sourced CISL library focused on Columnstore Indexes.</description>
      <twitter>NikoNeugebauer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pt.linkedin.com/in/webcaravela/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.nikoport.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=NikoNeugebauer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9251</importID>
      <name>Allan Hirt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQLHA, LLC founder, consultant, trainer, author, and business continuity, infrastructure, and virtualization expert Allan Hirt has been working with SQL Server since 1992 when it was still a Sybase product. He has also been clustering in Windows Server since the late 1990s when it was known as Wolfpack. Currently a dual Microsoft MVP (Data Platform; Cloud and Datacenter Management) as well as a VMware vExpert, Allan works with all sizes of customers, no matter if they are on premises or in the public cloud. He also delivers training and speaks at events over the world.</description>
      <twitter>SQLHA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/allan-hirt/1/b72/673</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlha.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLHA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17613</importID>
      <name>Jean Rene Roy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jean-Ren#233; Roy has been developing IT solution for large and small enterprises since 1987. In 1991 he founded the consulting firm Technologies SoftDesign Inc. 

Since that time he has worked on projects for House of Commons, Innovapost, Bell Canada, CGI, CNSC, Kraft, and many other clients assuming the responsibility of Business Analyst, Software Architect,ETL and BI Architect, Software Developers, Analyst, Team leader and mentor.  Jean-Ren#233; Roy is a SQL Server Microsoft MVP.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/#!/DevTeachConfere</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jeanreneroy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.softdesign.ca/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/#!/DevTeachConfere</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11760</importID>
      <name>Colin Stasiuk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Colin Stasiuk is a SQL Server DBA and published author (quot;Pro SQL Server Policy Based Managementquot;) with over 17 years of experience. He is a current SQL Server MVP, the founder of EDMPASS (the Edmonton PASS Chapter), and a former Regional Mentor for PASS in Canada.

Colin is an independent consultant providing support to customers on multiple projects with scopes ranging from SQL Server design and implementation, performance tuning to the implementation of high availability solutions.
</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ColinStasiuk</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/colinstasiuk</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://benchmarkitconsulting.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ColinStasiuk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10260</importID>
      <name>Ben Miller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben has been a member of the SQL Server Community since 2000. He loves a challenge and has fixed many SQL Servers and helped hundreds of people get more out of their DBA jobs.  He is a Data Platform MVP a SQL Server Certified Master (MCM). He has worked at various companies throughout the USA, as well as at Microsoft for 7 years. He is passionate about SQL Server Infrastructure, High Availability, Automation and Integration using SMO and PowerShell. He teaches DBAs how to use PowerShell to do their job and teaches SQL Server Internals. He is @DBAduck all around the web (Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, Blog) so let's catch up.</description>
      <twitter>DBAduck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dbaduck/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbaduck.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAduck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12145</importID>
      <name>Damir Bersinic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Damir is a Datacenter Solutions Specialist at Microsoft Canada. He is a sought-out speaker who has presented on virtualization and private cloud computing at key industry conferences including TechNet North America, Microsoft SharePoint Conference, TechDays Canada, as well as many others.  Damir has also delivered sessions at user group and community events including SQL Saturday, SharePoint Summit, DevTeach/SQLTeach, and Prairie IT  DevCon.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://technet.microsoft.com/en-ca</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20444</importID>
      <name>Michael DeFehr</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael DeFehr is an independent SQL Server consultant based in Winnipeg, Canada. He is focused on database administration and development using Microsoft SQL Server.
A SQL Server MVP, Professional Engineer and MCITP in both Database Development and Administration, Mike has spent the past 15 years producing and maintaining database solutions. Mike specializes in the relational and storage engines and his solutions emphasize performance and simplicity.</description>
      <twitter>@mdefehr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/mdefehr</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mikedefehr.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mdefehr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25133</importID>
      <name>Thomas LaRock</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thomas LaRock is a Head Geek at SolarWinds and a Microsoft Certified Master, Data Platform MVP, VMware vExpert, and a Microsoft Certified Trainer. He has over 15 years’ experience in the IT industry in roles including programmer, developer, analyst, and database administrator.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLRockstar</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlrockstar/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://thomaslarock.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLRockstar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17492</importID>
      <name>Joseph Verftido</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A Data Quality Analyst at Melissa Data, Joseph has worked with numerous clients in understanding their business needs for data quality, analyzing their architecture and environment, and recommending strategic solutions to successfully integrate data quality within their infrastructure. He gives frequent webinars for implementing different techniques for data quality and also manages the MVP Program – a network that provides resources to community leaders, speakers, consultants and other experts.</description>
      <twitter>/melissadata</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/company/melissa-data</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.melissadata.com/data-quality-authority/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=/melissadata</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15077</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo is co-founder and RD lead of perFact BV, a Dutch company that improves analysis methods and develops computer-aided tools to generate completely functional applications from the analysis deliverable. The platform for this development is SQL Server. In his spare time, Hugo likes to share and enhance his knowledge of SQL Server by frequenting newsgroups and forums, reading and writing books and blogs, and attending and speaking at conferences.
Hugo is also a SQL Server MVP since 2006.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25132</importID>
      <name>Thomas LaRock</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thomas LaRock is a Head Geek at SolarWinds and a Microsoft Certified Master, Data Platform MVP, VMware vExpert, and a Microsoft Certified Trainer. He has over 15 years’ experience in the IT industry in roles including programmer, developer, analyst, and database administrator.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLRockstar</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlrockstar/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://thomaslarock.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLRockstar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24079</importID>
      <name>Scott Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Scott Klein is a senior consultant with SQL Solutions Group with over two decades of experience working with Microsoft SQL Server. Prior to SSG, Scott spent almost 10 years at Microsoft, traveling the globe as a technical evangelist training and speaking about SQL Server and Microsoft’s Azure data services. Scott’s recent focus has been on advanced analytics, including big data and IoT, providing real-world training to help bring intelligence to your data. Scott has authored several books focusing on data and data analytics. Scott is continuously striving and looking for ways to help developers and companies grok the wonderful world of data.</description>
      <twitter>SQLScott</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/sqlscott</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLScott</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11438</importID>
      <name>Robert Davis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robert is a SQL Server Certified Master, MVP, and has spent 17+ years honing his skills in security, performance tuning, SQL development, high availability, and disaster recovery. He served as PM for the SQL Server Certified Master Program at Microsoft Learning, and in various roles at Microsoft specializing in SQL Server administration, development, and architecture. He currently works as a Database Engineer at BlueMountain Capital Management where he spends a vast majority of his time tuning massively parallel queries. Robert feeds his passion for security by acting as co-leader of the PASS Security Virtual Chapter.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLSoldier</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/robertldavis/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlsoldier.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLSoldier</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17515</importID>
      <name>Josh Fennessy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Josh Fennessy, Solution Architect at BlueGranite, has been building solutions with the SQL Server BI stack for 8 years. He is a Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert in Business Intelligence. Josh#39;s passions include manipulating data in novel ways to open analytic possibilities not before possible.

Josh is active in the SQL Server and Open Source communities. Beyond relational and OLAP data projects, Josh is also involved in projects using cluster computing platforms such as Hadoop.</description>
      <twitter>@joshuafennessy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuafennessy/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.joshuafennessy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@joshuafennessy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>8853</importID>
      <name>Aaron Nelson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Aaron Nelson is an author, public speaker, blogger, and leader in the community.  He has over 15 years of experience in architecture, Business Intelligence, development, and performance tuning of SQL Server. Aaron has received many certifications and is a six time winner of the Microsoft MVP Award.

Aaron leads the PowerShell Virtual Group of PASS (SQLPS.io), is a board member of PowerShell.org, and is a volunteer at his PASS Local Group, AtlantaMDF.</description>
      <twitter>SQLvariant</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlvariant</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlvariant.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLvariant</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34719</importID>
      <name>Mark Tabladillo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Tabladillo Ph.D. works for Microsoft as a Cloud Solution Architect for the US CTO Customer Success Team.  He has a science doctorate from Georgia Tech.  Based in Atlanta, GA, Mark provides cloud enterprise solutions for companies in the US for Microsoft's strategic clients. He is a chapter leader for the PASS Data Science virtual chapter. </description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/MarkTabNet</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marktab</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://marktab.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/MarkTabNet</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17514</importID>
      <name>Josh Fennessy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Josh Fennessy, Solution Architect at BlueGranite, has been building solutions with the SQL Server BI stack for 8 years. He is a Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert in Business Intelligence. Josh#39;s passions include manipulating data in novel ways to open analytic possibilities not before possible.

Josh is active in the SQL Server and Open Source communities. Beyond relational and OLAP data projects, Josh is also involved in projects using cluster computing platforms such as Hadoop.</description>
      <twitter>@joshuafennessy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuafennessy/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.joshuafennessy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@joshuafennessy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17884</importID>
      <name>Karen Lopez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Karen Lopez is a Sr. Project Manager and Architect for InfoAdvisors. A frequent speaker at conferences and local user groups, she has 20+ years of experience in project and data management on large, multi-project programs. Karen is a chronic volunteer, a Data Platform MVP, and an active advocate for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education and data quality.

Karen’s presentations are known for their lively and interactive approach to learning. Her motto: “Love Your Data!”</description>
      <twitter>datachick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/karenlopez</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datamodel.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=datachick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25741</importID>
      <name>Steve Stedman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Stedman is the Leader of a PASS Local Group in Bellingham WA USA. Steve runs his own SQL consulting firm Stedman Solutions, LLC. He has 29 years of programming and SQL experience.  He has written the book on SQL Common Table Expressions.  He teaches, speaks at conferences, writes, and has taught SQL server classes at Western Washington University.  Steve has previously spoken at PASS Summit, TechEd, DevTeach Vancouver, many SQL Saturdays, and more.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlemt</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stevestedman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SteveStedman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlemt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11800</importID>
      <name>Constantin Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Constantin is working at Syntax Systems GmbH  Co. KG. He mainly deals with the design and development of solutions based on Microsoft products and technologies. Since 2010 he was each year designated Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for the Microsoft Data Platform. In addition he is member of the board of Just Community e.V. (http://www.justcommunity.de) and PASS Deutschland e.V. (http://www.sqlpass.de). He also leads the .NET User Group Frankfurt/Germany (http://dnug-frankfurt.de). Find his blog at: http://kostjaklein.wordpress.com</description>
      <twitter>KostjaKlein</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://kostjaklein.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=KostjaKlein</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20048</importID>
      <name>Medhat Elmasry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Medhat Elmasry is an instructor at BCIT in the Computing department, a SharePoint contractor at T4BI, and a founder and leader of the .netBC user group. Medhat is a regular speaker at .netBC, DevTeach, and TechDays conferences. He likes to dabble in various technolgies in the .NET and Java spaces.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.medhat.ca</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24759</importID>
      <name>Yaroslav Pentsarskyy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Involved in SharePoint solution architecture  implementation since 2003 and a Microsoft MVP since 2009, Yaroslav frequently presents online, locally and at worldwide tech events. He's an avid blogger and writer, offering a fresh perspective on the latest SharePoint innovation. Yaroslav has also published several books on SharePoint including, Top 60 custom solutions built on SharePoint 2010, SharePoint 2010 branding in practice, and Microsoft SharePoint 2010 and PowerShell 2.0: Expert Cookbook.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sharemuch.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16913</importID>
      <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Koesmarno, MCSE Data Platform, and MCSE Business Intelligence, MCT, is a Senior Program Manager at Microsoft, with a Bachelor’s degree in IT. She has over 10 years of experience working with SQL Server for large-scale and multi-million-dollar OLTP and ETL projects as a SQL Server developer and system analyst/designer. Her past projects include delivering a SQL Server 2012 data warehouse and BI solutions in the US and Australia. She now works with hybrid, cloud and on-prem SQL projects.</description>
      <twitter>@mssqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliekoesmarno</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mssqlgirl.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mssqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24684</importID>
      <name>Stacia Varga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stacia Varga is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and SSAS Maestro with a Bachelor’s Degree in Social Sciences. A consultant, educator, author, and principal of Data Inspirations, her career spans more than 30 years, with a focus on improving business practices through technology.

Since 2000, Stacia has provided consulting and education services for Microsoft's Business Intelligence technologies. As Stacia Misner, she also authored several books covering the Microsoft BI stack.</description>
      <twitter>@_StaciaV_</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/staciavarga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.datainspirations.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_StaciaV_</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14813</importID>
      <name>Greg Larsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Greg Larsen has been working with SQL Server since version 6.5. He works for the State of Washington and does part-time consulting for DesignMind, a San Francisco–based consulting company. Greg has written over 175 articles related to SQL Server. He manages the website www.sqlserverexamples.com. Greg is also an adjunct professor at South Puget Sound Community College. He has been an MVP since 2009. In his spare time, he races and cruises on his sailboat. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserverexamples.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22996</importID>
      <name>Rick  Morelan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick has worked more than 12 years at Microsoft and has attained over 30 Microsoft technical including certifications in applications, networking, databases and .NET development (MCDBA, MCTS, MCITP, MCAD, MOE, MCSE, MCSE+I). He has also provided training for NW University, Volt Technical Education, The DigiGirlz, and Microsoft. Rick is the Author of the 5 volume SQL Joes 2 Pros book series.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24766</importID>
      <name>Mladen Prajdić</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mladen Prajdić is a Data Platform MVP from Slovenia. He's been programming for 20 years, developing diﬀerent types of applications in .Net (C#) and SQL Server, ranging from standard line-of-business, image-processing applications to high performace and IoT applications. He's a regular speaker at various conferences and usergroup meetings, really likes to optimize slow SQL statements, analyze performance, and find unconventional solutions to difficult SQL Server problems. In his free time, he also develops a very popular add-in for SSMS, called the SSMS Tools Pack (www.ssmstoolspack.com).</description>
      <twitter>@MladenPrajdic</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mladenprajdic</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/mladenp</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MladenPrajdic</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17574</importID>
      <name>John White</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John P White is the Chief Technical Officer at UnlimitedViz Inc. He holds a Master’s degree in Engineering from the University of Guelph and is a Microsoft SharePoint MVP.

Over the past decade, he has been focused on the Microsoft SharePoint and Business Intelligence platforms and has become an expert with the latest that these platforms have to offer. He blogs as actively as possible at http://whitepages.unlimitedviz.com.</description>
      <twitter>diverdown1964</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/diverdown1964</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://whitepages.unlimitedviz.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=diverdown1964</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>8911</importID>
      <name>Aaron Bertrand</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Architect at Wayfair. Long-time MVP and bad habits attacker.</description>
      <twitter>AaronBertrand</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlblog.org</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AaronBertrand</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11245</importID>
      <name>Cathy Dumas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cathy Dumas is the Director of Program Management, Analytics at Simba Technologies in Vancouver, BC. She previously spent seven years in Redmond working at Microsoft, finishing as a Program Manager on the SQL Server Analysis Services team (home of PowerPivot).  She has expertise in products across the BI stack, including experience with Oracle, Teradata OLAP, Tableau, Cognos, SAP, and more.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://cathydumas.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24683</importID>
      <name>Stacia Varga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stacia Varga is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and SSAS Maestro with a Bachelor’s Degree in Social Sciences. A consultant, educator, author, and principal of Data Inspirations, her career spans more than 30 years, with a focus on improving business practices through technology.

Since 2000, Stacia has provided consulting and education services for Microsoft's Business Intelligence technologies. As Stacia Misner, she also authored several books covering the Microsoft BI stack.</description>
      <twitter>@_StaciaV_</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/staciavarga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.datainspirations.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_StaciaV_</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21542</importID>
      <name>Oliver Engels</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Oliver Engels is CEO of oh22data AG, a Microsoft Gold Partner in Germany specializing in CRM and BI. His special interests are Azure, Data Governance and Integration, Visualisation Tools like SSRS, Power BI, Tableau, R, and SharePoint. He has worked with SQL Server since version 6.5 and is a founder and Board member of PASS Germany, a PASS Regional Mentor, and runs the Frankfurt PASS Local Group. For more than seven years he is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and a Microsoft pTSP.</description>
      <twitter>@oengels</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ssis-components.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@oengels</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21831</importID>
      <name>Paul Turley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul is a Principal Consultant for Pragmatic Works, a Mentor and Microsoft Data Platform MVP. He consults, writes, speaks, teaches  blogs about business intelligence and reporting solutions. He works with companies around the world to model data, visualize and deliver critical information to make informed business decisions; using the Microsoft data platform and business analytics tools. He is a Director of the Oregon Data Community PASS chapter  user group, the author  and lead author of Professional SQL Server 2016 Reporting Services and 14 other titles from Wrox  Microsoft Press.  He holds several certifications including MCSE for the Data Platform and BI.</description>
      <twitter>paul_turley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pturley</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserverbiblog.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=paul_turley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14915</importID>
      <name>Guy Bowerman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Guy Bowerman is a Program Manager in the SQL Server Cloud Infrastructure team at Microsoft. He works with SQL Server virtualization, cloud computing, and SQLOS.</description>
      <twitter>@gbowerman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.msdn.com/b/sqlosteam/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@gbowerman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22997</importID>
      <name>Rick  Morelan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick has worked more than 12 years at Microsoft and has attained over 30 Microsoft technical including certifications in applications, networking, databases and .NET development (MCDBA, MCTS, MCITP, MCAD, MOE, MCSE, MCSE+I). He has also provided training for NW University, Volt Technical Education, The DigiGirlz, and Microsoft. Rick is the Author of the 5 volume SQL Joes 2 Pros book series.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27113</importID>
      <name>Richard Baumet</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Richard Baumet has been a SQL Server DBA for teh last 12 years at RBC Global Asset Managment delaing mostly in infrastructure and performance tuning. He is has been the Vancouver PASS Chapter Leader for a few year now and has spoken at many technical engaements in Canada.  He is also looking forward to the Canucks first Stanely Cup this year!</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23032</importID>
      <name>Rohan Joackhim</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rohan has been working with SQL Server since 2001. His experience includes SQL Server projects dealing with HP Europe, financial institutions in Canada and data centers in the Dutch Caribbean. He is currently  dealing with databases in 24/7 high availability environments . He was an active member and a presenter of the PASS chapter Toronto. Rohan holds a Bachelor of Computer Engineering degree and he is MCDBA SQL Server 2008 and ITIL V3 certified.</description>
      <twitter>@rohanjoackhim</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/pub/rohan-joackhim/4/76a/342</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@rohanjoackhim</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10115</importID>
      <name>Edwin Sarmiento</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Edwin Sarmiento is a SQL Server MVP from Ottawa,Canada specializing in high availability,disaster recovery  system infrastructures running on the Microsoft server technology stack.He is very passionate about technology but has interests in music,professional  organizational development,leadership  management matters when not working with databases.He lives up to his primary mission statement -“To help people and organizations grow and develop their full potential as God has planned for them."</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://bassplayerdoc.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12781</importID>
      <name>David Eichner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Eichner is a licensed CPA and is also CEO of ICAN Software Corporation, a Microsoft Dynamics amp; Acumatica ERP partner firm that sell and implements ERP and CRM software, develops software solutions and provides technology consulting.  He is the host of a radio show called Business In The Cloud that airs weekly on KLAY 1180AM.  He is skilled in building integrated cloud app solutions. His career spans more than 20 years in various technical/managerial positions within industries as diverse as military service,  engineering/construction, municipal government, consulting and certified public accounting.  Additionally, he holds various national certificates in technology (MCDBA, MCSE, CNE, CITP, Dynamics CRM and ERP, Acumatica CRM and ERP)</description>
      <twitter>@ICANSoftware</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/icansoftware</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ICANSoftware</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21744</importID>
      <name>Pat Sinthusan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pat Sinthusan is currently working for NetApp as a Reference Architect responsible for validating new SQL Server Solutions on the NetApp storage platform.  In the past, he worked as a Sr. Database Administrator for 15 years with Hasbro and the City of Seattle. Pat has designed and implemented database infrastructures for the entire range of environments (development and production) using various storage technologies, and he#39;s been working with SQL Server since 4.21B.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://communities.netapp.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>12145</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12145</id>
          <name>Damir Bersinic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW9 - Room 110</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Large SQL Workloads on Microsoft's Private Cloud</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn about the capabilities in Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V that allow you to take large-scale SQL Server workloads and migrate them to Microsoft’s Private Cloud.  You will find out how to configure the key resources – memory, CPU, network, and disk – to help enable the largest SQL Server implementations to perform well.  You will see how System Center 2012 SP1 helps you deal with performance and other issues allowing you to respond more quickly to elements that may impact the applications your users depend on.  Finally, we will demonstrate how implementing SQL Server on a Private Cloud helps to more easily deal with routine maintenance of both SQL Server and the infrastructure supporting it.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15077</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15077</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1710</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>UDFs, or: How to kill performance in one easy step</title>
      <description>User-defined functions in SQL Server are very much like custom methods and properties in .Net languages. At first sight, they seem to be the perfect tool to introduce code encapsulation and reuse in T-SQL. So why is this feature mostly avoided by all T-SQL gurus?
The reason is performance. In this session, you will learn how user-defined functions feed the optimizer with misleading and insufficient information, how the optimizer fails to use even what little information it has, and how this can lead to shocking query performance.
However, you will also see that there is a way to avoid the problems. With just a little extra effort, you can reap the benefits of SQL Server and still get good performance.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17514</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17514</id>
          <name>Josh Fennessy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1840</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Demystifying BISM and Tabular Mode SSAS</title>
      <description>With the release of SQL 2012, Analysis Services (SSAS) has seen some major changes.  An entire new method of modelling analytic data has emerged and it's called Tabular Mode Analysis Services.  In addition to that, a new semantic layer has been added to the tool, the Business Intelligence Semantic Model (BISM), which will help to bring the two modes -- Multidimensional and Tabular -- into one level playing arena.

In this session, attendees will gain understanding of what Multidimensional and Tabular modelling IS, as well as how the BISM layer helps to translate user requests to ensure no confusion is made. Attendees will also learn how to BUILD a Tabular model, and will help design a solution live during the presentation. </description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17515</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17515</id>
          <name>Josh Fennessy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1840</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Essential 8: Narrative Reporting Techniques</title>
      <description>Providing boring static reports is no longer acceptable in today's business culture.  Analytics are expected to be highly visual, interactive, and should tell a meaningful story.  The latest version of Microsoft Excel is designed to perform those duties and more.  Narrative reporting goes far beyond the tabular format and eliminates the need for comments.

Learn how to craft narrative style reporting in this unique session.  Join Josh Fennessy and Julie Koesmarno as they guide you through several design scenarios that are often asked of a business analyst.  You'll learn Excel reporting techniques that will enable you to build highly visual and interactive reports without the need for heavy infrastructure requirements. </description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14813</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14813</id>
          <name>Greg Larsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1850</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Profiling with SSIS Data Profiling Task</title>
      <description>Profiling data allows you to understand various aspects of new you receive. By profiling data you can make sure it meets your data quality standards. During this session we will be exploring the SSIS Data Profiling task to quickly analyze your data. Each of the eight different profiles available will be reviewed. A number of demos will be shown so you understand how to use and configure the different profiles. You will learn how to use the Data Profiling task output to control your SSIS data flow. Additionally you will be shown how to store the profiling output in SQL Server, so you can produce trend reports based on past profiling output information.
 </description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24683</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24683</id>
          <name>Stacia Varga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1205</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Taking BI to the Next Level: Collaboration</title>
      <description>Self-service BI is usually an independent activity. But when individuals discover interesting information that they want to share, they need a centralized location to do that. When people work together, new insights are possible, and that’s what collaboration is all about. As more people see the benefits of the solution, they become more likely to use it. As individual products, SQL Server 2008 R2, SharePoint 2010, and Excel 2010 expand your options for enabling BI in your organization, but collectively they create a solid platform for collaborative BI. Knowing which tool to use for which job can be tricky. Come to this session to learn how to use these tools to foster collaboration.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22996</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22996</id>
          <name>Rick  Morelan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW9 - Room 110</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introducing SQL Server Data Tools! (Project Juneau</title>
      <description>Data Dude gone wild!!! Your final scripts deployed to the live database a few months ago and almost everything went perfectly. Since then you have heard there were few index patches needed maybe even a new column in one or the tables. The live database has drifted just a little from your deployed SQL scripts. How would you like to update your next baseline code to already resemble the current state of the production database? This is just one of the incredible features you can do with SSDT. Take the statefull nature of your database to create and test your code automatically and declaratively. Database developers can use the SQL Server Object Explorer in VS to easily. See how the new scripting and automation tools are used in SQL 2012.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>8853</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>8853</id>
          <name>Aaron Nelson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1750</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>PowerShell for Data Professionals</title>
      <description>You’ve heard it said, “If you have to do it twice, automate it.” Cut the learning curve and get a real handle on this powerful automation tool. This session walks you through a dozen scripts to simplify and easily automate time-consuming and tedious elements of your day to day job. This isn’t stuff you’ll use SOMEDAY, these are scripts you can use when you get home tonight. Harness the power of Power Shell to easily find Servers short on space. Script out tables and constraints across all of your databases at once. Backup databases and restore them to a different environment. These tricks and many others will allow PowerShell to simplify your job like no other tool.
</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16913</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16913</id>
          <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1840</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power View for Geographical Analysis</title>
      <description>Geographical Analysis is now made easy with Power View and Excel 2013. Simple yet powerful data exploration and segmentation analysis on geography can be performed, without the need of expensive hardware or software. In this session, you’ll learn how to create visually appealing and meaningful maps using Power View.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11245</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11245</id>
          <name>Cathy Dumas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1840</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>What Excel 2013 really means for BI</title>
      <description>Excel 2013 was silently packed with a slew of new BI features, including native integration of the PowerPivot and Power View add-ins. 

Come see some demos of how these new features work. Although you will see some pretty visualizations, there's more to Excel 2013 than dancing bubbles. There are some serious implications to taking advantage of these new technologies. Learn some of the trade-offs involved in taking advantage of these new features, especially when working with multiple data sources.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24766</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24766</id>
          <name>Mladen Prajdić</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1750</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Impossible: Restoring/Undeleting a table </title>
      <description>Yes, you read the title right. 
No, it's not about the usual "one table per partition" and "restore full backup then copy the data over" methods.
No, there are no 3rd party tools involved. Just you and your SQL Server. 

Yes, it's crazy. No, it's not for production purposes. And yes, that's why it's so much fun.
Prepare to dive into the world of data pages, log records, deletes, truncates and backups and how it all works together to get your table back from the endless void.
 
Want to know more? Come and see!</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34676</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34676</id>
          <name>John Huang</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1025</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>DBCC WritePage and Data Recovery</title>
      <description>DBCC WritePage is an undocumented command that allows users to modify physical pages directly. It can only be useful for database repairing when there are extreme situations where nothing can help you recover your data. It makes troubles in most of the time. But it's a good tool for learning other stuff. More importantly, you need to know this when others have already known.

In this 500 level session, We will explore some internals, use this command or other ways to break the database integrity, and use this tool to recover it. I will also demonstrate you how to keep yourself safe from using this command. </description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24759</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24759</id>
          <name>Yaroslav Pentsarskyy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1205</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building apps for SharePoint 2013 and Profiting!</title>
      <description>New marketplace is a great opportunity for developers to get rapid exposure on a growing platform. SharePoint 2013 introduces a new app model that brings the best of web development to SharePoint. This session will use a series of demos to walk through the developer getting started experience for apps for SharePoint and will highlight development tools such as Napa and Visual Studio. Whether you're a .NET developer or a SharePoint developer come learn how to build apps for SharePoint and submit them to Office marketplace.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11800</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11800</id>
          <name>Constantin Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW9 - Room 110</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>StreamInsight: Complex Event Processing by MS</title>
      <description>The number of sensors is growing and growing and brings us closer to the "Internet of things". Applications, that have to process a big amount of data from event streams are a logical consequence. Some developers might have heard from Reactive Extensions (Rx) already, but Microsoft offers with StreamInsight (SI) another comprehensive platform for these scenarios.

In this session you will learn what a great addition for your toolbox StreamInsight is, if you have to develop applications, that have to handle complex events (CEP- Complex Event Processing). See how you can start with this technologie and how easy it is to jump in for .NET developers.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22997</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22997</id>
          <name>Rick  Morelan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW9 - Room 110</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>New SQL 2012 Functions</title>
      <description>Using a Function is quick and easy if you know they are there. Functions always do or return something useful. When you send data into a function, it does its work and then sends you back some information.  Each version of SQL server adds new functionality and 2012 continues that tradition. Many things you may not even have to build since more system supplied functions now ship with SQL Server 2012. This session will focus on the new string, time and logical functions added to SQL Server 2012.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20048</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20048</id>
          <name>Medhat Elmasry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1205</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Entity Framework 5</title>
      <description>Never tried Entity Framework before? Or long term Entity Framework developer? Come learn how Entity Framework 5 makes it very simple to keep both your code and database in sync as you make changes using Code First and Migrations. Plus learn about many other enhancements including Designer improvements and support for new Enums and Spatial types.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10115</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10115</id>
          <name>Edwin Sarmiento</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1205</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing SharePoint Performance thru SQL Server</title>
      <description>The health and performance of your SharePoint farms are directly related to how your SQL Server databases perform.  If the SQL Server databases are not performing well, that will translate to poor SharePoint performance.Check out this session to learn how to properly configure a SQL Server instance for maximum SharePoint performance. We will look at understanding the underlying storage, proper database files placement, tuning the tempdb database database and other configuration settings that will help your SharePoint databases achieve optimum performance.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13363</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13363</id>
          <name>Donabel Santos</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1840</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Reporting Services 2012 Jumpstart</title>
      <description>Jumpstart your way with SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services! This session will cover the basics – and some intermediate topics – on designing reports with SSRS 2012. We will start with basic reports, and build our way to adding parameters, interactive components, charts and subreports. This session will be jampacked with demos.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15379</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15379</id>
          <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW9 - Room 110</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Inheriting a database for Developers, version 2</title>
      <description>There are very few applications which are being developed from zero, the most are apps are simply inherited from previous development teams. This session serves to show some easy implementable practices to follow after inheriting a database. Those practices allow to check some if the database design was done in regards to the actual data, or if while implementing some of the constraints and checks some tables were left behind. :) The practices shown in this session will allow to check the database design and identify some of the possible performance degradations.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25741</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25741</id>
          <name>Steve Stedman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1710</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Exploring the TSQL Enhancements in SQL Server 2012</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2012 adds many new enhancements to TSQL. Learn how to use the windowing functionality of the OVER clause to create sliding aggregation. Find out about the new SEQUENCE object and when you should or should not use it to replace an IDENTITY.  Learn the IIF function and CHOOSE function to replace a common simple CASE functions.  OFFSET / FETCH will be covered to show you how to eliminate cursors or CTEs for data paging.  With CONCAT you have an easier time building strings in your TSQL statements independent of the data type, and without concern over nulls.  With these and other new TSQL enhancements you will be able to take full advantage of the power of TSQL in SQL Server 2012.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24684</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24684</id>
          <name>Stacia Varga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW9 - Room 110</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power View: A Peek Behind the Curtain</title>
      <description>Power View is the new data visualization and self-service BI tool that debuted in SQL Server 2012 and is  now available as part of Excel 2013. To successfully roll-out this technology to your user community, you need to understand its architecture and data dependencies. Come to this session to get past the razzle dazzle that most Power View sessions offer, and peek behind the curtain to learn how to properly configure your environment to support Power View and how to prepare data for user consumption within Power View .
</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25132</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25132</id>
          <name>Thomas LaRock</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1710</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Design Throwdown</title>
      <description>Karen and Tom debate about options and best practices of common and advanced design issues, such as: * Natural vs. Surrogate keys *NULL vs NOT NULL * Agile Database Design * Database Refactoring * How much does Size Matter? * Who Calls the Shots and Who Does What? ...and others. Bring your votes, your debates, and your opinions.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17884</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17884</id>
          <name>Karen Lopez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1840</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Model-Driven Database Design</title>
      <description>Model-Driven Database Development: Myths, Magic and Methods.  In this presentation, Karen discusses data model-driven database development from the point of view of the Data Architect, the DBA, and the Developer. She will cover topics such as "Who does what?", "Why are we doing this?", "Do I have to Use a GUI?"  and "Just who do you think you are?". Demos, too.  Finally, 10 tips for making model-driven database development successful in your organization's culture and environment.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21542</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21542</id>
          <name>Oliver Engels</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1850</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Quality rulez! Go best practise</title>
      <description>With the new Data Quality Services (DQS) Microsoft has an offering for Data
Quality Management. This session gives you insights how to use DQS efficiently.
In demos you will understand best practises in setting up a knowledge base,
correct matching rules and how to integrate DQS to your processes as DQS is
never an island solution. DQS performance aspects and how to report your
quality improvements will round up the session. The session assumes that you
have already tested DQS and want to get further with this toolset.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21831</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21831</id>
          <name>Paul Turley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1025</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Visualization Choices: What, When, and How?</title>
      <description>When do you use a sparkline, column, or line chart? How do you create a business scorecard – and with what tool? Using Excel, Power View, and Report Builder, this session will guide you through the choices and help you apply the right visual to your business data. Come see what well-known industry experts have to say about the correct use of visualization choices and techniques, colors, backgrounds, borders, and 3-D effects. Then see demonstrations of how to create those rich visuals in the different reporting tools, used with PowerPivot and tabular semantic models.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23032</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23032</id>
          <name>Rohan Joackhim</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1710</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deep Dive to SQL Server Parallel Query Processing</title>
      <description>During query optimization, SQL Server is looking for queries or index operations that might benefit from parallel execution. This session will start with the basics of parallelism in SQL Server. Then lead you to understand what is under the hood of parallel query execution. How you can avoid or benefit from parallelism in OLTP or OLAP environment.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27113</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27113</id>
          <name>Richard Baumet</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1025</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2012: AlwaysOn</title>
      <description>Go through the artichecture for setting up AlwaysOn talking about the differnt technogies involved and how you can leverage them to divide up workloads among different replicas.  You'll quickly know why this HADR solution is one of SQL Server 2012's biggest feature</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9251</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9251</id>
          <name>Allan Hirt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1025</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Demystifying Clustering for the DBA</title>
      <description>The word cluster is used a lot in the IT world, especially when it comes to SQL Server. We have clustered instances of SQL Server, availability groups that require Windows failover clustering ... but how does a DBA make sense of it all? Wonder no more! This session will explain all the forms of clustering as they relate to SQL Server (including how Windows fits into the picture) and give you some of the top keys to success whether you are using an older version of Windows and SQL Server, or you're looking to deploy the latest and greatest.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34719</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34719</id>
          <name>Mark Tabladillo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1850</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Applied Enterprise Semantic Mining</title>
      <description>Text mining is projected to dominate data mining, and the reasons are evident:  we have more text available than numeric data.  Microsoft introduced a new technology to SQL Server 2012 called Semantic Search. This session's detailed description and demos give you important information for the enterprise implementation of Tag Index and Document Similarity Index. The demos include a web-based Silverlight application, and content documents from Wikipedia. We'll also look at strategy tips for how to best leverage the new semantic technology with existing Microsoft data mining.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>8911</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>8911</id>
          <name>Aaron Bertrand</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1710</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL : Bad Habits and Best Practices</title>
      <description>The session will cover a collection of minor bad habits that can occasionally lead to major problems.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25133</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25133</id>
          <name>Thomas LaRock</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1710</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Design: Size DOES Matter</title>
      <description>Great database performance starts with great database design. During the database design process it is important to select your datatypes wisely. The wrong choices will often lead to wasted space, increased response times, and less stability. Additionally you run the risk of having your design not scale as well as it should. Leave this session armed with the knowledge you need to help your databases perform at their peak efficiency. </description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20444</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20444</id>
          <name>Michael DeFehr</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1750</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Plans and Indexes in SQL Server</title>
      <description>Data access can be easy to set up in your applications with wizards and ORMs, but sometimes your queries are just not as fast as you think they should be – especially on those tables that are getting bigger and bigger. In this session, we will take a peek under the hood and see how SQL server answers the questions you ask of it. This is an introductory session, but it will be jam-packed with demos and useful tips that you will be able to use to make your applications more responsive.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>12781</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12781</id>
          <name>David Eichner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1850</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SRS Report Builder for Business Intelligence</title>
      <description>Learn how easy it is to utilize the free download from Microsoft that allows users to create maps, charts, dashboard objects and reports against any kind of data easily without having to use Visual Studio.  See how SQL Report Builder makes creating executive dashboards easy!</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21744</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21744</id>
          <name>Pat Sinthusan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1025</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2012 in Virtualization World</title>
      <description>Microsoft SQL Server is one of the most commonly virtualized application.  In order for SQL Server to run well in a virtual environment, the virtualized host must be properly configured and managed.  We will discuss some of the benefits of virtualization that particularly apply to virtualized SQL Server environments which include: easier failover, hardware abstraction and simpler capacity planning.  This session will demonstrate how to setup SQL Server storage in a virtual environment as well as best practices, caveats, and performance of SQL Server database.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17492</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17492</id>
          <name>Joseph Verftido</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1850</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Quality Services Approach to Cleansing</title>
      <description>Learn about Microsoft’s Data Quality Services (DQS), what it is and how it works. We'll show you how DQS sets itself apart from conventional data cleansing routines that we’re used and go through examples on how to begin your own Data Quality Project. But what really makes DQS unique and powerful is its ability to access shared knowledge. In this presentation, we will also go through how to access and use that shared knowledge. </description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17574</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17574</id>
          <name>John White</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1205</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Configuring SharePoint for Business Intelligence</title>
      <description>This session is will help the SQL DBA or the SharePoint farm administrator understand what is required from the "other side" to get BI features up and running in SharePoint. We will outline the SharePoint farm and services architectures, and then walk through configuration scenarios that will get BI assets such as Reporting Services in SharePoint mode, PowerPivot for SharePoint, Power View, and PerformancePoint up and running.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11760</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11760</id>
          <name>Colin Stasiuk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1750</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Doing More With Less-SQL Server Policy Based Mgmt</title>
      <description>Do more with less… sound familiar? In this demo rich introduction to Policy Based Management presentation we will be going over what Policy Based Management is and how you can use Policy Based Management and a Central Management Server to evaluate your daily, weekly, and monthly checklists against your entire SQL Server environment.  We will be reviewing some of the “out of the box” policies as well as creating some custom policies that you might be interested in evaluating against all of your SQL Server instances.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10260</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10260</id>
          <name>Ben Miller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1750</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server TDE</title>
      <description>Have you ever wanted to know how Transparent Database Encryption (TDE) works or how you set it up? This session will go over all the steps and caveats that go with this technology. This is a topic that is an Enterprise Feature, but allows you to have your database encrypted on disk. We will discuss the Encryption Hierarchy as well as how it relates to SQL Server TDE.
</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14915</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14915</id>
          <name>Guy Bowerman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW3 - Room 1750</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>New Backup and Deployment features in SQL Server 2</title>
      <description>Cumulative update 2 introduces new features to SQL Server backup and Sysprep which enable important hybrid scenarios. In this session you’ll learn how to use and troubleshoot the new features.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11438</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11438</id>
          <name>Robert Davis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1205</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Implementing Contained Databases</title>
      <description>Contained Databases is a new feature introduced in SQL Server 2012. We will take a look at the security implications of contained databases and why it considered only “partially” contained. This technical dive into the feature will demonstrate how to implement contained databases, how to migrate a contained database, and
what “gotchas” to be aware of.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17613</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17613</id>
          <name>Jean Rene Roy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW5 - Room 1850</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS Configurations in SQL Server 2012</title>
      <description>Before SQL Server 2012, SSIS configuration was a Rocket science. Since then Microsoft has been working nonstop to get this aspect of SSIS more simple.  A large amount of enhances in SQL Server 2012 have been done to SSIS and if you know how difficult it was to configure SSIS packages in SQL Server 2008, you need to see this session.  If you are new to SSIS you also need to see all enhances to SSIS and see how simple it is to use it.
</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24079</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24079</id>
          <name>Scott Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SW1 - Room 1025</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Kung Fu Migration to Windows Azure SQL Database</title>
      <description>As cloud computing becomes more popular and cloud-based solutions the norm rather than the fringe, the need to efficiently migrate your database is crucial. This demo-filled session will discuss the tips and tricks, methods and strategies for migrating your on-premises SQL Server databases to Windows Azure SQL Database, AKA SQL Azure. Focusing primarily on SQL Server Data Tools and the DAC Framework, this session will focus on how these tools can make you a kung-fu migration master.</description>
      <startTime>2/16/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/16/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>