<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #747 - Timisoara 2018</name>
    <startDate>6/9/2018 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>60</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Harare, Pretoria</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatTimisoara</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Biblioteca Centrală a Universității Politehnica Timișoara</name>
      <street>Bulevardul Vasile Pârvan 2b, Timișoara, Romania</street>
      <city>Timișoara</city>
      <state>Timiș County, Romania</state>
      <zipcode>300223</zipcode>
      <longitude>21.2274767</longitude>
      <latitude>45.746849</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>77051</importID>
      <name>Liviu Ieran</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>More than 9 years of SQL Server experience working for Microsoft currently as a Support Escalation Engineer. 
My main area of expertise is SQL Server Performance where I helped optimize numerous query's and environments.</description>
      <twitter>@Liviu_Ieran</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/IeranLiviu</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Liviu_Ieran</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83775</importID>
      <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mihail Mateev is a technical consultant, community enthusiast, PASS Regional Mentor for CEE, chapter lead, Microsoft Azure MVP, Microsoft Regional Director. He works as a Senior Solutions Architect at EPAM Systems, focused on Data Platform, IoT and cloud related solutions. He also worked many years like a Technical evangelist in the Infragistics. Last years Mihail was focused on various areas related to technology Microsoft: Data Platform, Visual Studio, ASP.Net, Windows client apps, Data Platform, and Microsoft Azure. Michael also has a PhD in cloud computing area. He is a university lecturer on Smart Homes and Smart Energy IoT Solutions.</description>
      <twitter>mihailmateev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mihail-mateev/1/6b3/4b1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mmateev.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mihailmateev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>83291</importID>
      <name>Dragos-Cristian Furdui</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>N/A</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>75795</importID>
      <name>Cristian Lefter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cristian Lefter is Principal of Esential Training and one of the SQL Server MVPs. His primary competence is training. He is also a consultant, author, speaker and community leader. 
As his main expertise is Microsoft SQL Server, which resulted in founding an official PASS chapter, writing books and articles, contributing at the development of Microsoft Official Courseware, authoring certification exams, speaking at technical events and working as a Subject Matter Expert in various projects.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cristianlefter</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82186</importID>
      <name>Ozana Buse</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am Support Engineer SQL Server Core, at Microsoft, and at the same time a student. I am passionate about learning new things and teaching others.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>78628</importID>
      <name>Laurentiu Codorean-Onea</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a data enthusiast that used to manage a Data Team and now I work as a Support Engineer for Microsoft Business Application Platform applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>80597</importID>
      <name>Tobias Koprowski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Founder of Shadowland Consulting. In January 2015 decided to permanently leave Poland and discover new worlds. Actually settled in Hucknall (The Last home of The Byron Family). Community leader focused on SQL Server, SharePoint, security, collaboration and ITIL, DR, BCM, and SLA. Love licensing stuff. 

Microsoft Certified Trainer, freelancer, and consultant. Subject Matter Expert at Microsoft. Member of Microsoft Terminology Community, Friends of RedGate PLUS, PASS, ISSA, ACM and more. Since 1st July 2010 Data Platform MVP. Creator of SQLDAY Conference and Conference CEO 2009-2011. Co-Leader of PASS East Midlands Group. Speaker at group meetings and conferences. STEM Ambassador. 

Traveler. Coffee Addicted.</description>
      <twitter>@KoprowskiT</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/koprowskit</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://koprowskit.eu/geek/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KoprowskiT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>82174</importID>
      <name>Alexandra Ciortea</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>2005-2009  Computer Science - Polytechnic University of Bucharest 
2009-2011 - Master -IT Management - Polytechnic University of Bucharest 

I started working for Microsoft in 2009 as a Support Engineer for Project Server and SQL Server for EMEA.
In 2012 I changed to a  Premier Field Engineer position working onsite for SQL Server and Project Server</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73761</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>73865</importID>
      <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mihail Mateev is a technical consultant, community enthusiast, PASS Regional Mentor for CEE, chapter lead, Microsoft Azure MVP, Microsoft Regional Director. He works as a Senior Solutions Architect at EPAM Systems, focused on Data Platform, IoT and cloud related solutions. He also worked many years like a Technical evangelist in the Infragistics. Last years Mihail was focused on various areas related to technology Microsoft: Data Platform, Visual Studio, ASP.Net, Windows client apps, Data Platform, and Microsoft Azure. Michael also has a PhD in cloud computing area. He is a university lecturer on Smart Homes and Smart Energy IoT Solutions.</description>
      <twitter>mihailmateev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mihail-mateev/1/6b3/4b1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mmateev.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mihailmateev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>73865</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73865</id>
          <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dealing with CosmosDB</title>
      <description>CosmosDB service is a NoSQL is a globally distributed, multi-model database database service designed for scalable and high performance modern applications. CosmosDB is delivered as a fully managed service with an enterprise grade SLA. It supports querying of documents using a familiar SQL over hierarchical JSON documents. Azure Cosmos DB is a superset of the DocumentDB service. It allows you to store and query noSQL data, regardless of schema.
In this presentation, you will learn:
•	How to get started with DocumentDB you provision a new database account. 
•	How to index documents 
•	How to create applications using CosmosDb (using REST API or programming libraries for several popular language) 
•	Best practices designing applications with CosmosDB
•	Best practices creating queries.</description>
      <startTime>6/9/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/9/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83775</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83775</id>
          <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>IoT Duel - Cloud vs. on Premises Solutions</title>
      <description>This talk is a parallel, between IoT solutions, based on premise and systems, build with Microsoft Azure components. The presentation will cover the architecture, technology stack, implementation and best practices. We will consider pluses and deltas in different cases, using both approaches. You will see also many demos, which will help you to build own cloud based or on premises Internet of Things systems.</description>
      <startTime>6/9/2018 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/9/2018 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82174</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82174</id>
          <name>Alexandra Ciortea</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL in GDPR Context</title>
      <description>The session targets positioning SQL Server in the current GDPR context. Different security functionalities as TDE, Always Encrypted, RLS and Dynamic Data Masking can enhance privacy and address certain GDPR requirements.</description>
      <startTime>6/9/2018 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/9/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>78628</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>78628</id>
          <name>Laurentiu Codorean-Onea</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>How powerful is Power BI?</title>
      <description>I will walk attendees through some of the Power BI best practices and limitations, when using it in collaboration with SQL SERVER and SSAS.</description>
      <startTime>6/9/2018 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/9/2018 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>82186</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>82186</id>
          <name>Ozana Buse</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>S (tudent) QL - SQL Server guide for students</title>
      <description>As a student, how can SQL Server help with university projects or personal tech hobbies? 
In the session we will talk about how SQL Server can help you learn, integrate it in your university projects, and many more.</description>
      <startTime>6/9/2018 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/9/2018 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>73761</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>73761</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>If a machine can learn, why can't YOU learn Azure Machine Learning?</title>
      <description>Are you a DBA or Developer and would like to get started with AzureML the EASY WAY?
AzureML isn't just for "data scientists"... Anyone can use it! And after this session you'll be using it too...
Disclaimer: Sadly, AzureML still can't predict what's on your girlfriend's mind. Nothing ever will.</description>
      <startTime>6/9/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/9/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>77051</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>77051</id>
          <name>Liviu Ieran</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2017 - Understanding Statistics</title>
      <description>When analyzing Query plans understanding statistics and what role they play is a very important part. 
The session will be mostly demo based and will show you how to interpret the stats histogram and how SQL estimates the rows returned from a given table.
This will help you troubleshoot query performance at a more deeper level.</description>
      <startTime>6/9/2018 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/9/2018 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>80597</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>80597</id>
          <name>Tobias Koprowski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>AD 2018. 2 AM. A Disaster just Began...</title>
      <description>2AM. We sleeping well. And our mobile ringing and ringing. Message: DISASTER! In this session (on slides) we are NOT talk about potential disaster (such BCM); we talk about: What happened NOW? Which tasks should have been finished BEFORE. Is virtual or physical SQL matter? We talk about systems, databases, peoples, encryption, passwords, certificates and users. In this session (on few demos) I'll show which part of our SQL Server Environment are critical and how to be prepared to disaster. In some documents I'll show You how to be BEST prepared.</description>
      <startTime>6/9/2018 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/9/2018 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>75795</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>75795</id>
          <name>Cristian Lefter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Code Smells</title>
      <description>Can your T-SQL code be improved? 
Where? 
And how? 
Code Smells are indications that your code can be refactored for better design, performance or even better security. 
In this session we will take a look at as many of them (code smells) as sixty minutes will allow us.</description>
      <startTime>6/9/2018 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/9/2018 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>83291</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>83291</id>
          <name>Dragos-Cristian Furdui</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL SERVER - Next station Azure</title>
      <description>This session will cover the main aspects to start or migrate from an OnPremise model  to one of the two architectures available in SQL Server on Azure, providing the keys to select the more suitable environment for our requirements.
We will cover:
1. Red pill or blue pill
       SQL Server on Azure VM (IaaS) vs SQL Azure DB (PaaS) Which one?
2. Always available.
       High availability in Azure
3. Now what ...
       Best practices and configuration connectivity.</description>
      <startTime>6/9/2018 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/9/2018 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>