<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #38 - Jacksonville 2010</name>
    <startDate>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>400</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat38</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>The University of North Florida Campus</name>
      <street>1 UNF Drive</street>
      <city>Jacksonville</city>
      <state>Florida</state>
      <zipcode>32224</zipcode>
      <longitude>-81.507024</longitude>
      <latitude>30.27144</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>23</importID>
      <name>Pragmatic Works</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.pragmaticworks.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/973/EventSponsor_14499.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1184</importID>
      <name>Tek Systems</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.teksystems.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/855/EventSponsor_13925.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>8</importID>
      <name>FusionIO</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.fusionio.com/solutions/microsoft-sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/files/18b704b1-226d-48fe-b0b8-f7b4d3443b3d.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>405</importID>
      <name>Attunity</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.attunity.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/fb42d77f-3037-4b66-8ca0-fc14e274c32a.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1</importID>
      <name>Confio</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.confio.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/resized-confio_logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>710</importID>
      <name>Incepture</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.incepture.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://file.ac/vYU3HOMOkxc/Incepture_full%20color.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>394</importID>
      <name>Apress</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.apress.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/d4c52bf3-c1c0-44c9-aa2a-bdbbb3f4fdab.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>778</importID>
      <name>Kforce</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.kforce.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/951/EventSponsor_14660.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>5</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/947/EventSponsor_14722.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>378</importID>
      <name>Align Networks</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.alignnetworks.com/</url>
      <imageURL>
      </imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>714</importID>
      <name>Pearson-InformIT</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.informit.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/a9fcf6aa-7399-404a-b3dd-53f082cf7f17.gif</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32338</importID>
      <name>Jared  Nielsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jared Nielsen believes that a "Jack of All Trades Is Master of None... Except Himself"™.
His twenty year career has spanned projects in "wires and pliers" networking, database architecting, software design, marketing strategy, sales management, training and documentation, business administration, entrepreneurial investment, public company creation, and strategic analysis and consulting.  Billing himself as "an IT guy that actually speaks English", he has managed to effectively bridge the gap between IT and Sales, IT and Marketing, and IT and Executive Management in a way that multiplies revenue for each project he works on.  Always willing to speak his mind and challenge the status quo, he is featured throughout the world including the front page of the Wall Street Journal, Wired Magazine, the German Financial Times, Slash Dot, CNN (television, CNN.com and iReport.com), and thousands of blogs throughout the Internet.  His work can be seen with companies such as Interline Brands / Barnett (formerly BNTT:NASDAQ), Hughes Supply/ Home Depot / HD Supply (formerly HUG:NYSE), Yahoo! Sports (YHOO:NASDAQ), CBS Television (CBS:NYSE), SAP Andina del Caribe (Caribbean Division), and automotive sector including Tire Kingdom, Big O Tires, Merchants Tire, and NTB, as well as dozens of other high profile projects that have multiplied in revenue due to his influence.
</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30126</importID>
      <name>Eric Wisdahl</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eric Wisdahl is a computer engineer working in the database field.  He has held multiple roles and positions in e-commerce, marketing and insurance industries.  Currently, he is working as a database administrator in a development role for an e-commerce company.  

Eric Wisdahl does not like writing about himself in the third person.  It is kind of creepy. </description>
      <twitter>@EricWisdahl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ericwisdahl</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@EricWisdahl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>28389</importID>
      <name>Aaron Nelson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Aaron Nelson is an author, public speaker, blogger, and leader in the community.  He has over 15 years of experience in architecture, Business Intelligence, development, and performance tuning of SQL Server. Aaron has received many certifications and is a six time winner of the Microsoft MVP Award.

Aaron leads the PowerShell Virtual Group of PASS (SQLPS.io), is a board member of PowerShell.org, and is a volunteer at his PASS Local Group, AtlantaMDF.</description>
      <twitter>SQLvariant</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlvariant</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlvariant.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLvariant</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29341</importID>
      <name>Brandie Tarvin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Database Administrator by day and Author by night Brandie Tarvin sails pirate-populated waters, fights evil robots in disguise and turns kingdoms into chaotic rebellious city-states all while coding ETL processes and protecting real-world data from corruption. If it weren't for her, someone else would have the job and where would be the fun in that?

Brandie's first computer experience was with a State-of-the-Art Commodore 64 brought home by her father, who informed her that "computers are NOT toys" and would not let her use it until she learned how to program. In late 2003, she turned her hobbies of programming, MUSHing and assisting friends with generic tech support into a full time career as a database administrator. She's been stuck in the fabulous and bizarre world of professional IT work ever since.

Currently, Brandie is a Database Administrator  Developer for Allstate Dealer Services in Jacksonville. She has published several articles on SQLServerCentral.com, trains her co-workers in SQL Server, and has previously presented at several SQL Saturday events and JSSUG meetings. She also writes fiction and freelances for Catalyst Game Labs in her spare time. 

</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30060</importID>
      <name>Eric Humphrey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eric Humphrey is a DBA at GameStop in the Dallas area. He earned his B.S. in Computer Science from Louisiana State University – Shreveport in 2004. He has been working in the tech industry since 2003 with companies big and small. His focus is on database development with SQL Server. Eric has a passion for improving his craft while contributing to the development community.</description>
      <twitter>@lotsahelp</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.erichumphrey.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@lotsahelp</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29334</importID>
      <name>Bradley Schacht</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bradley is a consultant at Pragmatic Works in Jacksonville, FL.  He was an author on the book SharePoint 2010 Business Intelligence 24-Hour Trainer.  Bradley has experience on many part of the Microsoft BI platform.  He has spoken at events like SQL Saturday, Code Camp, SQL Lunch and SQL Server User Groups. He is a contributor on sites such as BIDN.com and SQL Server Central as well as an active member of the Jacksonville SQL Server User Group (JSSUG).</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.bradleyschacht.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>31024</importID>
      <name>Jorge Segarra</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jorge Segarra is a senior consultant for Microsoft (Premier Support for Developers) and a former SQL Server MVP. Jorge has co-authored titles including  "SQL 2008 Pro Policy-Based Management" and "SQL Server 2012 Bible" .</description>
      <twitter>@sqlchicken</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jdsegarra</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlchicken.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlchicken</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29878</importID>
      <name>Dean Richards</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dean Richards is a Senior DBA for DBMS Insights and has helped hundreds of companies solve database and virtualization performance issues.  Dean has over 20 years of experience in both development and database administration and has focused his entire career on performance tuning of Oracle and SQL Server environments. Most recently Dean has focused on the trend to virtualize and move databases to the cloud.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/dean-richards/6/167/a90</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30190</importID>
      <name>Michael Flora</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>CompTia A+
CompTia Network+
MCP
Overall IT experience is 9 years with 2 being a DBA</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.linkedin.com/in/mflora</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30353</importID>
      <name>Mustika Nengah</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mustika has over 7 years of experience in designing and developing enterprise scale applications using Microsoft Technologies. He posses several certifications such as, Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS) in WEB/Windows w/Microsoft Visual C# NET, MCTS in MOSS 2007 Implementation and Configuration. CompTia N+ and A+. He also holds MS and BS degrees in Computer Information Science from University of North Florida and Shepherd University.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.linkedin.com/myprofile?trk=hb_tab_pro</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>28512</importID>
      <name>Adam Jorgensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>As President of Pragmatic Works Consulting Adam drives market strategy, sales, partnerships, implementation and thought leadership. He has over 15 years of experience helping companies use their data to fuel their growth. Adam has been wowing audiences around the world for over a decade. He has delivered hundreds of sessions, published over a dozen books and hundreds of online videos and webinars on data and cloud topics. His passion is growing companies and mentoring leaders and companies to help them achieve their dreams.</description>
      <twitter>wadamj</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/wadamjorgensen/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.pragmaticworks.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=wadamj</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29879</importID>
      <name>Dean Richards</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dean Richards is a Senior DBA for DBMS Insights and has helped hundreds of companies solve database and virtualization performance issues.  Dean has over 20 years of experience in both development and database administration and has focused his entire career on performance tuning of Oracle and SQL Server environments. Most recently Dean has focused on the trend to virtualize and move databases to the cloud.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/dean-richards/6/167/a90</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32908</importID>
      <name>Shawn Harrison</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Shawn Harrison is a BI Developer at Community Hospice and Palliative Care. He oversees the data warehouse and works within other levels of the MS BI stack. He also speaks at community events such as SQL Saturday, user group meetings.</description>
      <twitter>@ShawnBHarrison</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.thesqlgoth.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ShawnBHarrison</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30654</importID>
      <name>Jeff Cole</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeff Cole, designing  building IT systems for over 20 years, has experience across many industries including banking/ finance, healthcare  telephony using a variety of mainframe languages  Microsoft development environments. He's currently working in the middleware space developing systems on multiple platforms using integration technology to solve complex connectivity issues  helps Attunity customers modernize legacy systems using the Microsoft technology stack including SQL Server  SSIS.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>33660</importID>
      <name>Timothy McAliley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am currently a Microsoft Cloud Solutions Architect in the Washington, DC area.  Previously, I was a Microsoft Technology Solutions Professional (TSP), a Microsoft Account Technology Strategist and a SQL Server Premier Field Engineer. Prior to Microsoft, I was a Technical Trainer and DBA in the Enterprise Security Group at Symantec . I have been in IT for over 20 years. My particular interests are IT operations, IT auditing, IT audit frameworks, IT service management (ITSM), ITIL, information security, project management, and database/application tier high availability solutions. I also co-run the Northern Virginia SQL Server User Group ( @novasl) and also co-run the Azure Datafest events.</description>
      <twitter>sysframeworks</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothymcaliley/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sysframeworks</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32252</importID>
      <name>Plamen Ratchev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Plamen is an SQL Server MVP specializing in relational database applications analysis, implementation, and tuning. His particular interest is in design patterns, performance and optimization. In the past two decades he has worked in different roles as database developer and architect in medium and large scale enterprise applications. He has been involved on projects utilizing DB2 and Oracle, but his main passion is SQL Server, which he started using at version 4.2. Plamen has master's degree in computer science with specialization in algorithms and compliers. He enjoys sharing his experience with user groups and at various conferences.</description>
      <twitter>@PlamenRatchev</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://pratchev.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@PlamenRatchev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>33835</importID>
      <name>Vikas Hawaldar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vikas is BI Architect at Idea Integration. He has 12 years of experience in Business Intelligence. He has spoken into several SQL Saturday sessions.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32910</importID>
      <name>Shawn McGehee</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Shawn is a DBA and former developer from Northwest Florida. He has over 10 years of experience with Microsoft database systems and application development. He is the co-author of the Pro SQL Server Reporting Services 2008 book from Apress and contributes to several online SQL Server targeting news publications. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.pensacolasql.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30675</importID>
      <name>Jonathon Moorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jon has developed using Sql Server since version 6.0! Easily distracted by shiny objects, he has always been on the bleeding edge of sql development. When not presenting, Jon might be found backpacking, hiking, camping, canoeing, or simply resting at home with a good scifi book.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathonmoorman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>31681</importID>
      <name>Mike Davis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mike Davis, MCITP, is a Consulting Team Lead at Pragmatic Works.  He is an author with books covering Business Intelligence and SSIS.  Mike is an experienced speaker and has presented at many events such as several SQL Server User Groups, Code Camps, SQL Server Launches, SQL Saturday,  and SQL Rally. Mike is an active member at his local user group (JSSUG) in Jacksonville, FL.</description>
      <twitter>@mikedavisSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/mikedavissql</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://MikeDavisSQL.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mikedavisSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29622</importID>
      <name>Sumeet  Bansal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sumeet Bansal is Principal Solutions Architect for Fusion-io. He designs architectural solutions with Fusion-io products that deliver unprecedented levels of scalability, performance and simplicity. 

Sumeet has more than 11 years IT and database-infrastructure experience, including work as vice-president of information technology at MS SQL-based Internet retailer Wine.com, senior database architect for MS SQL-based eVineyard inc., and systems analyst for Akiba Bank Limited.
</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30128</importID>
      <name>Eric Wisdahl</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Eric Wisdahl is a computer engineer working in the database field.  He has held multiple roles and positions in e-commerce, marketing and insurance industries.  Currently, he is working as a database administrator in a development role for an e-commerce company.  

Eric Wisdahl does not like writing about himself in the third person.  It is kind of creepy. </description>
      <twitter>@EricWisdahl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ericwisdahl</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@EricWisdahl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>28390</importID>
      <name>Aaron Nelson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Aaron Nelson is an author, public speaker, blogger, and leader in the community.  He has over 15 years of experience in architecture, Business Intelligence, development, and performance tuning of SQL Server. Aaron has received many certifications and is a six time winner of the Microsoft MVP Award.

Aaron leads the PowerShell Virtual Group of PASS (SQLPS.io), is a board member of PowerShell.org, and is a volunteer at his PASS Local Group, AtlantaMDF.</description>
      <twitter>SQLvariant</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlvariant</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlvariant.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLvariant</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>28730</importID>
      <name>Andy Warren</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andy Warren is a SQL Server consultant and trainer based in Orlando, FL. Focusing on administration, performance tuning, and SQL Server patterns and practices, he’s been a SQL Server MVP since 2008. Andy served two terms on the PASS Board of Directors, was a founding principal in SQLServerCentral, and created both the SQLSaturday and SQLRally event models.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlandy</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlandy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlandy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>31423</importID>
      <name>Devin Knight</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Devin Knight a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and the Training Director at Pragmatic Works. He is an author of seven SQL Server and Business Intelligence books and speaks at conferences like PASS Summit, PASS Business Analytics Conference, SQL Saturdays and Code Camps. He is also a contributing member to several PASS Virtual Chapters. Making his home in Jacksonville, FL, Devin is the Vice President of the local Power BI User Group and SQL Server User Group (JSSUG).</description>
      <twitter>@knight_devin</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/deknight/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://devinknightsql.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@knight_devin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32253</importID>
      <name>Plamen Ratchev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Plamen is an SQL Server MVP specializing in relational database applications analysis, implementation, and tuning. His particular interest is in design patterns, performance and optimization. In the past two decades he has worked in different roles as database developer and architect in medium and large scale enterprise applications. He has been involved on projects utilizing DB2 and Oracle, but his main passion is SQL Server, which he started using at version 4.2. Plamen has master's degree in computer science with specialization in algorithms and compliers. He enjoys sharing his experience with user groups and at various conferences.</description>
      <twitter>@PlamenRatchev</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://pratchev.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@PlamenRatchev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32133</importID>
      <name>Troy Gallant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Troy has been a SQL Server professional for over 18 years, filling various roles as analyst, developer, and for the last decade, DBA.  As a regular speaker at SQL Saturdays up and down the east coast, he’s taught on a multitude of topics from disaster recovery to performance tuning to professional development. Currently residing in Jacksonville once again, he just got back from two years as Sr. DBA for the EDW of a major international insurance company in New York City.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.troygallant.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>33806</importID>
      <name>Elijah Baker</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Elijah Baker is an 18 year veteran using SQL Server with the past 10 years being focused mostly on development. He has worked in all levels of SQL Server development from the JR developer up to the lead and architect positions. Currently he is working a PaySpan Inc. which processes medical payments and data. Elijah has become an expert on Partitioning to allow PaySpan’s largest database, 8TB+ 10 billion+ rows, to continue growing as needed without any significant performance degradation.  </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32546</importID>
      <name>Robby Robertson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robby Robertson is currently the Business Intelligence Architect at Beeline, Inc. He has worked as a database administrator and developer for the past 13 years. He moved to Jacksonville in 1999 and has worked with Beeline now for 7 years in a variety of roles.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>30676</importID>
      <name>Jonathon Moorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jon has developed using Sql Server since version 6.0! Easily distracted by shiny objects, he has always been on the bleeding edge of sql development. When not presenting, Jon might be found backpacking, hiking, camping, canoeing, or simply resting at home with a good scifi book.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathonmoorman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>31804</importID>
      <name>Michael Antonovich</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Antonovich is the assistant director of Web and Technology Services in the Communications Division for Orange County Public Schools in Orlando, FL, where he manages the Internet and intranet infrastructure.  He has published seven books, ranging from an Apple II User Guide to Office and SharePoint 2010 User's Guide. His blog has focused mainly on PowerPivot and Power BI, but for the last year Mike has taken a break to pursue some other activities.  He hopes to restart his blog later this year focusing more on style and presentation. Mike has used SQL Server since 1998 and, for the past 7 years, has been promoting SSAS, PowerPivot, and Power BI for the masses.</description>
      <twitter>@SharePointMikeA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelpantonovich?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sharepointmike.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SharePointMikeA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>32615</importID>
      <name>Rodney Landrum</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rodney Landrum has been architecting solutions for SQL Server for over 12 years. He has worked with and written about many SQL Server technologies, including DTS, Integration Services, Analysis Services, and Reporting Services. He has co-authored 4 books on Reporting Services. He is been a regular contributor to SQL Server magazine, sqlservercentral.com and Simple-talk.com. Rodney is also SQL Server MVP</description>
      <twitter>@SQLBeat</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.simple-talk.com/blogs/author/2133-rodney-landrum/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLBeat</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>33202</importID>
      <name>Steve Schneider</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Speaker Bio:  Steve Schneider is a Business Intelligence developer for the City of Jacksonville (Florida), and has been embedded in SQL for over 20 years.  He is a Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer and a Microsoft Certified Database Administrator.  Along with his passion for SQL, he spends his time running half marathons and sailing.  His current focus of interest is performance tuning, security, and cube building.  He tries to maintain a constant sense of gratitude to God for the wonderful things he has been enabled to do.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/steveschneider1/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlinsight.net/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>31805</importID>
      <name>Michael Antonovich</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Antonovich is the assistant director of Web and Technology Services in the Communications Division for Orange County Public Schools in Orlando, FL, where he manages the Internet and intranet infrastructure.  He has published seven books, ranging from an Apple II User Guide to Office and SharePoint 2010 User's Guide. His blog has focused mainly on PowerPivot and Power BI, but for the last year Mike has taken a break to pursue some other activities.  He hopes to restart his blog later this year focusing more on style and presentation. Mike has used SQL Server since 1998 and, for the past 7 years, has been promoting SSAS, PowerPivot, and Power BI for the masses.</description>
      <twitter>@SharePointMikeA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelpantonovich?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sharepointmike.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SharePointMikeA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29081</importID>
      <name>Brian Knight</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brian Knight, a SQL Server MVP, MCSE, and MCDBA, is the owner and founder of Pragmatic Works. He is also the co-founder of SQLServerCentral.com, BIDN.com, and SQLShare.com. Brian runs the local SQL Server users group in Jacksonville (JSSUG), is a contributing columnist at several technical magazines, and does regular webcasts at PragmaticWorks.com. He is the author of 15 SQL Server books and a frequent speaker at conferences such as PASS Summit, SQL Connections, TechEd, and many Code Camps.</description>
      <twitter>@BrianKnight</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.bidn.com/people/brianknight</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BrianKnight</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>29277</importID>
      <name>Brian McDonald</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brian K. McDonald, MCDBA, MCSD is a Business Intelligence Consultant. Brian has experience in Database Administration, SQL Server Reporting Services, SQL Server Integration Services and Analysis Services. He has worked as an Application Developer, Network Administrator and a Database Administrator throughout his 11 years in the IT industry. He even spent a year on a large Help Desk operation a long, long time ago. Brian takes pride in all his projects and diligently works to not only meet expectations, but greatly exceed them. Brian has written articles for industry websites and continually strives to learn more and become a better version of himself. Brian is an active member of the Jacksonville SQL Server User's Group and has presented at User group meetings, Code Camps, many SQL Saturdays and SQL Rally events across Florida and South Carolina.</description>
      <twitter>@briankmcdonald</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlbigeek.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@briankmcdonald</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>31023</importID>
      <name>Jorge Segarra</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jorge Segarra is a senior consultant for Microsoft (Premier Support for Developers) and a former SQL Server MVP. Jorge has co-authored titles including  "SQL 2008 Pro Policy-Based Management" and "SQL Server 2012 Bible" .</description>
      <twitter>@sqlchicken</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jdsegarra</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlchicken.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlchicken</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>29277</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29277</id>
          <name>Brian McDonald</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence -1102</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to SQL Server Reporting Services 2008</title>
      <description>SQL Server Reporting Services is a fundamental part of Microsoft’s Business Intelligence suite of products which as its name suggests provides a centralized robust reporting solution for organizations. Using a familiar development environment we can create static and interactive reports that can be delivered to consumers in a variety of ways. In this introductory session, I will cover topics like: 
- What is reporting services and what can it be used for? 
- New Features included in 2008 R2 
- Architectural Overview 
- Demonstrations to cover the entire process of developing, deploying and rendering reports using the built in Report Manager and URL Access. </description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29622</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29622</id>
          <name>Sumeet  Bansal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1406</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Accelerating SQL with Solid State Technology</title>
      <description>Solid-state technologies are changing the way that MS SQL users run their databases. DBA’s are achieving significant TCO savings through performance enhancements, reliability improvements, and reduced energy and real estate costs using solid-state technologies.  Solid state is changing the way datacenters look and how MS SQL Servers perform.

This session will address:

1)	On overview of solid state technology options for SQL Server
2)	Why solid state makes a difference?
3)	An comparison of the different types of NAND Flash-based products and the advantages and disadvantages of each:
a.	Disk-based SSDs
b.	Onboard/Embedded PCI Express devices
c.	Host-based PCI Express devices
4)	Customer proof: Wine.com case study
</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32338</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32338</id>
          <name>Jared  Nielsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1402</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL and SEO - Database Design and Web Marketing</title>
      <description>Bringing marketing together with technology is a fine art that involves high tech tools, real life solutions, and most important human buy-in from the marketing and IT departments.  This lecture will delve into the use of the latest SQL Server 2005 and SQL Server 2008 technologies including recursive common table expressions (CTE), hierarchical data models, and CLR stored procedures for the IT side of the house while also delving into the use of analytics, webmaster monitoring tools, web marketing tactics and search engine optimization techniques for the more marketing minded.

Neither SQL nor SEO are four letter words and they go together perfectly!  So too can your IT and marketing departments as you tackle the new age of IT Marketing.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>31805</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>31805</id>
          <name>Michael Antonovich</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1406</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Publishing Access Applications to SharePoint</title>
      <description>This sessions is designed for user with experience developing Access applications.  It will focus on Access 2010 with SharePoint 2010 to explore the different degrees of publishing Access and how it solve issues many IT departments have with Access including: Access databases are never backed up.  Every copy of the XYZ Access database has different data in it.  Publishing form and report updates to dozens or hundreds of users is a nightmare.  We will then dive deep into how IT departments can publish an Access application to Access Services on SharePoint with Web forms, reports, queries, and macros that eliminate the need for Access on the client machine entirely. </description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32253</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32253</id>
          <name>Plamen Ratchev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1202 (Auditorium)</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Refactoring SQL for Performance</title>
      <description>Many people live by the motto “If it’s not broken, don’t fix it”. But if you believe that you are missing all enhancements introduced in newer versions of SQL Server (2005/2008). These new features can help you develop better solutions with improved performance, scalability, and maintainability. Learn how to craft a better query using the new MERGE statement, ranking functions, and more. Practical examples with tips and tricks.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>33660</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>33660</id>
          <name>Timothy McAliley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1400</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>ITIL V3 for the  Database Administrator</title>
      <description>Conducting database administration within an ITIL framework can improve change management, reduce operational risks and stabilize your environment. Learn the conceptual basics of the Information Technology Infrastructure Library, Version 3 (ITIL V3) and review a few examples of scaled deployments of the ITIL V3 process framework.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30128</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30128</id>
          <name>Eric Wisdahl</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1406</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>An Introductory Look at Execution Plans</title>
      <description>In this session we will look at some introductory execution plans, both estimated and actual, to help determine what the query optimizer will do, or has done, with the query presented.  </description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>33202</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>33202</id>
          <name>Steve Schneider</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1400</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Encryption How-To 101</title>
      <description>Learn how to implement SQL 2005 Encryption using 2-way and 1-way encryption and why you would use either.  
Learn what a DBA needs to know and what the developer needs to know.  
Learn how to maintain encryption...backup and restore issues as well as cross-server issues.
This will include a live demonstrations of the concepts presented.

</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>31024</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>31024</id>
          <name>Jorge Segarra</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1400</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Policy-Based Management: Administration Made Easy</title>
      <description>We will be learning an overview of this powerful new feature in SQL 2008 and how you can leverage it to help manage your existing SQL environment. This will include plenty of demos, best practices and QA so by the end you should be able to walk away ready to take control of your SQL Servers!</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32910</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32910</id>
          <name>Shawn McGehee</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1404</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2008 Resource Governor </title>
      <description>Working with limited resources in the hardware and software fields can be troubling for a DBA. Making things work smoothly when sharing servers among many applications can be a difficult and time consuming task. With SQL Server 2008 a new feature has been given to the DBA world that can make the process much easier. We will take a look at the resource governor from the ground up in this session and build a solution to alleviate some of the issues that come with sharing hardware.
</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>31423</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>31423</id>
          <name>Devin Knight</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence -1102</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Data Warehousing</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn how to plan for a Data Warehousing project.  Why you need one, what the key steps are to developing one and designing a plan to have a successful project will all be discussed.  You will learn conceptually how you can leverage the Microsoft BI Stack to design and implement a Data Warehouse.  This session will focus more on the concepts of development rather than demonstrating the development itself.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29081</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29081</id>
          <name>Brian Knight</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence -1102</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Iron Chef Competition: Loading a Data Warehouse</title>
      <description>In this session, you’ll learn how to load a data warehouse using SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS). You'll see a battle between two SSIS experts (Brian Knight and Adam Jorgensen), attempting to load the data warehouse the best way. You'll see varying architectures and best practices from each of the presenters and you decide who wins the Iron Chef competition. </description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32252</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32252</id>
          <name>Plamen Ratchev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1202 (Auditorium)</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Common SQL Programming Mistakes</title>
      <description>Become a better SQL coder by learning the most common pitfalls in the SQL language. Both inexperienced and experienced SQL developers and DBAs can get caught by many of these. Practical examples and internal logical processing explanation will help you understand why mistakes happen and how to develop good SQL coding practices to avoid them.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>28389</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>28389</id>
          <name>Aaron Nelson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1406</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>PowerShell for the Data Professional</title>
      <description>In this session we will learn to perform several everyday DBA tasks like backing up user databases, scripting table objects and evaluating disk space usage with PowerShell. For each task we will explore the benefits of using PowerShell over the standard method. Only a basic understanding of PowerShell or DOS is needed. This session should serve as a good introduction to PowerShell for database users. The goal is to get data professionals feet wet using PowerShell.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30060</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30060</id>
          <name>Eric Humphrey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1400</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>High Anxiety with ORMs</title>
      <description>Object Relational Mappers (ORMs) are often praised by developers and despised by DBAs. I'll show that like most tools, ORMs have their place if used responsibly. Also, how they can get out of hand if not monitored.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29334</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29334</id>
          <name>Bradley Schacht</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence -1102</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to SQL Server Integration Services</title>
      <description>This session will get you past the learning curve of SSIS.  Brad covers creating an end to end package that covers many of the concepts in SSIS. He covers, looping over a set of files, processing each file and then archiving.  This session will be great for anyone who is a beginner to SSIS.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29878</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29878</id>
          <name>Dean Richards</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1202 (Auditorium)</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Response Time Analysis of SQL Server Performance</title>
      <description>Using Response Time Analysis and Wait Types is a newer method for tuning SQL Server instances. As a result, there is often confusion on exactly what the data means. The issue typically centers around the fact the wait time data is analyzed at the wrong level or the collected wait time data is not detailed enough. This presentation will focus on these problems and review several real-life case studies of using SQL Server Wait Type data coupled with Response Time based performance analysis to solve the most difficult performance related issues. Designed for the SQL Server DBA, Developer or anyone concerned with performance. </description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32133</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32133</id>
          <name>Troy Gallant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1404</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Transactional Replication</title>
      <description>SQL Server replication allows DBAs to distribute data to various servers throughout an organization. Some reasons to employ replication include load balancing, offline processing  redundancy. Transactional replication in particular can offer a very flexible solution where data frequently changes. This session will discuss the basics of planning and implementation of a solid transactional replication solution.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>31681</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>31681</id>
          <name>Mike Davis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence -1102</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Building your First Cube in Analysis Services 2008</title>
      <description>In this session Mike builds a cube from a basic data warehouse. He shows also covers the basics of what a data warehouse is and explains dimensional modeling. He shows how to create the cube, including dimensions, hierarchies, and calculations.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32908</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32908</id>
          <name>Shawn Harrison</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1404</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Parameters in SSRS</title>
      <description>In this session, Shawn will cover the basics of using parameters in reports and work up to a more intermediate level such as using parameters in stored procedures and cascading parameters.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32615</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32615</id>
          <name>Rodney Landrum</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1202 (Auditorium)</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Demystyfying SQL Code and Object Deployments</title>
      <description>From everyday movement of code and data, standards must be set and met depending on the size of your company and your available resources. Rodney will discuss SQL deployments best practices using industry standard tools. From SSIS, stored procedures, SQL objects such as tables and indexes, to the data itself, deploying SQL code from one environment to another is not always as straight forward as you may think.
</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>28730</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>28730</id>
          <name>Andy Warren</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1400</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Statistics</title>
      <description>This beginner to intermediate level session will introduce you to statistics, including how to create, manage, troubleshoot, and more! Statistics are a key part of getting solid and repeatable performance and is easily just as important as having indexes. Whether you're a DBA or trying to get by without one, this session will give you the information you need to know. 
</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29341</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29341</id>
          <name>Brandie Tarvin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1404</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL 102: Aliases and Table Joins</title>
      <description>For the beginner and intermediate T-SQL coder, this is a class on how to use aliases and joins to your advantage. This session introduces the topics and throws in a few tips  tricks that can help you find exactly the data you need.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30126</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30126</id>
          <name>Eric Wisdahl</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1402</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS Configurations, Expressions and Constraints</title>
      <description>This session will look in depth at some of the more powerful aspects of Integrations Services: Expressions, Package Configurations, and Precedence Constraints. A short tutorial will show the users how to build up a package structure to allow logging to a remote location determined through configurations as well as capturing errors, destroying the error file if no errors are present and emailing a configurable user if any errors are found. </description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>33806</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>33806</id>
          <name>Elijah Baker</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1202 (Auditorium)</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Table Partitioning: The Basics</title>
      <description>This session will go over what database table partitioning is and what the structures are to implement it. There will also be some general information on partitioning strategies. If you ever looked into table partitioning and just wanted a little more information this session is for you.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>31804</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>31804</id>
          <name>Michael Antonovich</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1406</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>XML 101 for the SQL Developer</title>
      <description>This session defines what XM is and how it differs from regular HTML, It looks at how to define data type variables and columns in SQL to store XML, how to output XML from existing table structures. It also covers how to use OPENXML, how to create and use your own namespaces, and the difference between typed XML and untyped XML. </description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30676</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30676</id>
          <name>Jonathon Moorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1402</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Everything you wanted to know about IDENTITY colum</title>
      <description>From IDENTITY seed and increment, to specifying specific values, we'll look at IDENTITY columns at all angles to find their strengths and limitations.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30675</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30675</id>
          <name>Jonathon Moorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1406</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Basics of Sql Server Profiler</title>
      <description>An introduction to the basic elements of the Sql Server Profiler.  An overview, from a sql developer perspective, of useful events, useful column data, how to apply filters, how to execute, how to search results and a look at canned and custom templates.
</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>32546</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>32546</id>
          <name>Robby Robertson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1402</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS Deployment Strategies</title>
      <description>Now that you've built it, how do you get it out there for consumption? This session will focus on highly configurable and data-driven solutions for SSIS package deployment. We will discuss a variety of topics as they relate to package implementation and delivery, including: The pros and cons of file system vs. SQL Server deployment, package configuration methods, package security, using meta-data to drive package flexibility, deployment and execution automation techniques.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30190</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30190</id>
          <name>Michael Flora</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence -1102</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mini - SSIS for the DBA</title>
      <description>During the brief 15 minutes I will show you how to loop through a list of servers to gather information.  With this knowledge you can build your own SQL server monitoring tool.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>28512</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>28512</id>
          <name>Adam Jorgensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence -1102</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to SharePoint 2010 BI and PowerPivot</title>
      <description>Lets take your BI implementation to the next level with SharePoint 2010 BI and PowerPivot. We'll go through excel services, performancepoint services, and pulling it all together in SharePoint 2010.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30654</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30654</id>
          <name>Jeff Cole</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1400</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Heterogeneous Data Integration with SSIS  CDC</title>
      <description>This session will focus on Microsoft and partner technologies that enable high performance, efficient and real-time data integration using SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS), and that work with data from Oracle, Teradata, and other heterogeneous sources. You will learn how Microsoft high-speed Connectors by Attunity can be leveraged with change-data-capture (CDC) technologies integrated with SSIS to enable data replication. Use cases highlighting real-time data warehousing and operational reporting, as well as maintenance of data consistency between operational databases and applications will also be outlined. </description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>29879</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>29879</id>
          <name>Dean Richards</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1402</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tuna Helper for SQL Server DBA's</title>
      <description>Many DBAs and developers are faced with tuning poorly performing SQL statements. There is no way to learn everything you need to know about SQL tuning in an hour, but you can learn a process to employ when badly written SQLs are ruining database performance. However, many tuning projects fail because the process being used is inefficient. This presentation will walk through a process Confio Software uses with great success and will include topics such as: SQL diagramming, wait type data, column selectivity, and several more that will help you succeed on future tuning projects.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>31023</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>31023</id>
          <name>Jorge Segarra</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1404</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL University 101: Starting the SQL Journey</title>
      <description>On my blog I've started a project called SQL University aimed at folks looking to learn SQL Server from the ground up. This session will start at ground level tasks and resources all database professionals should know. This session is aimed at entry-level folks but anyone is welcome to attend to sharpen up their basic skills and resources!</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>28390</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>28390</id>
          <name>Aaron Nelson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1202 (Auditorium)</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Virtualize This!</title>
      <description>With the list of features of SQL Server growing constantly the need to sandbox and test drive features in a separate environment that can communicate with but not interfere with your existing environment has become vital. With virtualization, setting up consistent test, dev, and even sandbox environments can happen minutes instead of hours AND be consistent with previous/ existing environments. In this session we will focus on Microsoft Virtualization solutions that you can leverage starting with your desktop</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>30353</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>30353</id>
          <name>Mustika Nengah</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1404</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Accessing Cube using ADOMD.NET</title>
      <description>Accessing multidimensional data such as SSAS’s cubes and KPI from .NET client applications using ADOMD.NET . ActiveX Data Objects Multi-dimensional (ADOMD) provides easy access to multi-dimensional data from client applications (Web, Console, or Windows application). This session shows you how to use ADOMD.NET to retrieve data and metadata from an SSAS instance.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>33835</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>33835</id>
          <name>Vikas Hawaldar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>1402</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Data Mining using SQL 2008</title>
      <description>Session will present the development lifecycle of a Datamining engine using SQL Server 2008.</description>
      <startTime>5/8/2010 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/8/2010 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>