<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #316 - Christchurch 2014</name>
    <startDate>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+12:00) Fiji, Kamchatka, Marshall Is</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat316</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Christchurch Polytechnic Institute of Technology (CPIT)</name>
      <street>Madras Street</street>
      <city>Christchurch</city>
      <state>, New Zealand</state>
      <zipcode>8011</zipcode>
      <longitude>172.6426697</longitude>
      <latitude>-43.5358315</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1255</importID>
      <name>Varigence Australia</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.varigence.com.au</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.nz-bi.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Varigence-Logo-Orange-Biml.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>777</importID>
      <name>Kelly IT Services</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.kellyservices.co.nz/</url>
      <imageURL>https://martincatherall.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/KellyServicesLogo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>83</importID>
      <name>PluralSight</name>
      <label>Friends of SQL Saturday #316</label>
      <url>http://www.pluralsight.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.srnimbus.com.br/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Pluralsight_logo_novo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27657</importID>
      <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warwick Rudd is a Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008 and Principal Consultant at SQL Master Consulting. He is a frequent speaker at local SQL Server User Groups and SQLSaturday events in Australia. When not playing with the SQL stack, Warwick likes to get away to the cold and spend time snowboarding.</description>
      <twitter>@warwick_Rudd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/pub/warwick-rudd/0/956/718</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmastersconsulting.com.au/Blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@warwick_Rudd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19783</importID>
      <name>Peter Avenant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter is the Technical Director at Varigence Australia, an SSIS Developer, Trainer and Consultant, and SQL Server data warehouse specialist. His background includes developing a metadata framework that integrates with BimlScript to create dimensional data warehouses. Prior to joining Varigence Australia, Peter was an early adopter of Biml and has given numerous community talks and training sessions on Biml in Australia and New Zealand</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.bimlscript.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23231</importID>
      <name>Rob Farley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob Farley runs LobsterPot Solutions in Australia, where he's a consultant in the Microsoft Data Platform and Analytics space. He's been an MVP since 2006, probably because of his blogging, his presentations around the world, and his dedication to the Adelaide Data  Analytics User Group which he has led since before the release of SQL Server 2005. He's on Twitter at @rob_farley, but you can always email him using rob@lobsterpot.com.au</description>
      <twitter>rob_farley</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/in/robfarley/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.lobsterpot.com.au</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=rob_farley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19785</importID>
      <name>Peter Avenant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter is the Technical Director at Varigence Australia, an SSIS Developer, Trainer and Consultant, and SQL Server data warehouse specialist. His background includes developing a metadata framework that integrates with BimlScript to create dimensional data warehouses. Prior to joining Varigence Australia, Peter was an early adopter of Biml and has given numerous community talks and training sessions on Biml in Australia and New Zealand</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.bimlscript.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27658</importID>
      <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warwick Rudd is a Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008 and Principal Consultant at SQL Master Consulting. He is a frequent speaker at local SQL Server User Groups and SQLSaturday events in Australia. When not playing with the SQL stack, Warwick likes to get away to the cold and spend time snowboarding.</description>
      <twitter>@warwick_Rudd</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/pub/warwick-rudd/0/956/718</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmastersconsulting.com.au/Blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@warwick_Rudd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19784</importID>
      <name>Peter Avenant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter is the Technical Director at Varigence Australia, an SSIS Developer, Trainer and Consultant, and SQL Server data warehouse specialist. His background includes developing a metadata framework that integrates with BimlScript to create dimensional data warehouses. Prior to joining Varigence Australia, Peter was an early adopter of Biml and has given numerous community talks and training sessions on Biml in Australia and New Zealand</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.bimlscript.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10718</importID>
      <name>Brent McCracken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I've been working with SQL Server since v6.5 and nearly completed my MCM qualification. I am the technical lead for the database operations team in a nationwide bank in New Zealand.</description>
      <twitter>@sqldba_nz</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/pub/brent-mccracken/8/510/a34/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqldba.co.nz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqldba_nz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24446</importID>
      <name>Simon Peck</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Simon is a MCSE in data analytics, certified Biml Expert (BimlHero) and co-author of "The Biml Book" he has been working with SQL Server since the 90's.  Simon is a director of Data Engineers a Christchurch based data solutions provider specialising in Microsoft based cloud and on-premise BI and Data Warehousing solutions.  Having worked for 50+ organisations worldwide over last 20 years he has a wealth of experience across many business sectors,  he is also a co-leader of the Christchurch SQL User Group.</description>
      <twitter>@BIGUYNZ</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/monchopper</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@BIGUYNZ</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>8774</importID>
      <name>Reza Rad</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reza Rad is a Microsoft Regional Director, MVP, author, trainer, speaker and consultant. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for nine years from 2011.
Reza wrote many books on Power BI subjects including the Power BI from Rookie to Rock Star, and Pro Power BI Architecture.
Reza is the invited speaker at the world's well-known conferences such as Microsoft Ignite, Microsoft Business Applications Summit, Ignite Tour, PASS Summit, and many other conferences.
Reza is an active blogger and writes regularly about Power BI at https://radacad.com.</description>
      <twitter>Rad_Reza</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/in/rezarad/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://radacad.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rad_Reza</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19780</importID>
      <name>Martin Catherall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin is a data consultant in Melbourne, Australia, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, and PASS Regional Mentor for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region.
Martin founded the Christchurch, New Zealand PASS Local Group and lead the group for a number of years before relocating to Melbourne.
He has been using SQL Server in various roles since 2000. In addition to anything data related, he enjoys playing the guitar and having fun with his family.</description>
      <twitter>MartyCatherall</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/martincatherall</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://martincatherall.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MartyCatherall</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>8774</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>8774</id>
          <name>Reza Rad</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>ETL Architecture for Solving Data Warehouse Challenges</title>
      <description>Data Warehouses are heavily in use nowadays in most of businesses around the world. Data Warehousing brings higher performance, faster and more insightful data analysis out of operational databases. By the way there are some challenges in design and implementing Data Warehouses which needs robust and reliable ETL implementation. In this session you will learn an ETL Architecture implemented by SSIS and MDS to solve couple of most challengeable Data Warehousing scenarios which are Slowly Changing Dimension and Inferred Dimension Member. There will be many demos through this session which helps you to understand design and implementation of the architecture.</description>
      <startTime>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/14/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27658</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27658</id>
          <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hitch Hikers Guide to High Availability</title>
      <description>With the release of SQL Server 2012 the High Availability landscape has moved. Like anything in this world we live in we need to move and keep up with the changes. In this session Warwick will look at what is needed to design and implement a Highly Available solution in your SQL environment.</description>
      <startTime>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/14/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10718</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10718</id>
          <name>Brent McCracken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2014</title>
      <description>Since November 2013, Kiwibank has had SQL Server 2014 running live in Production, despite it only going RTM in April 2014. This session will go over the pros and cons of deploying a pre-release version and also cover some of the things that we did do, didn't do and couldn't do. This deployment is fully supported by Microsoft and I'll share some of the background info on that too. This session will be a beginner to intermediate with some advanced aspects as well.

</description>
      <startTime>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/14/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23231</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23231</id>
          <name>Rob Farley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SARGability</title>
      <description>SARGability is such a significant thing in the database world, and goes far beyond "Keep your columns on the left and functions on the right". In this talk, you'll be able learn principles that will affect not only how easily your data can be located, but also the way that joins are performed and more. You can even learn ways to tune poorly performing queries without having to rewrite anything.</description>
      <startTime>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/14/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27657</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27657</id>
          <name>Warwick Rudd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance Eye for the SQL Guy</title>
      <description>With the release of SQL Server 2014 comes some new features which can provide performance improvements for your SQL Server environment. In this session Warwick will take you through these new features including Buffer Pool Extension, Resource Governor for I/O, InMemory OLTP, InMemory DW,  Managed Lock Priority  Single Partition Online Index Build  that could help improve performance in your SQL Server environment .</description>
      <startTime>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/14/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19785</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19785</id>
          <name>Peter Avenant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BIML</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Fast Track Your BI Projects With Biml</title>
      <description>You’re a business intelligence developer or manager trying to provide quality data in a timely, cost-effective manner. Perhaps you’ve considered Agile methodology, but found that the details of ETL, the plumbing if you will, makes iterative development all but impossible. In just this session Peter will demonstrate a flexible and reusable framework for storing and managing the metadata that you will use as an input to your BimlScripts, alleviating the pain and tedium of data warehouse development.</description>
      <startTime>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/14/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24446</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24446</id>
          <name>Simon Peck</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>(Unusual) Problem solving with SSIS scripts</title>
      <description>Every once in a while a client will have an unusual or obscure requirement that is either very difficult or not possible to satisfy with the out of the box tools provided by SSIS.  
What do you do when your data sources aren’t predictable or in a format not easily read by standard SSIS adapters?
This is when scripting “#8 fencing wire” of SSIS really comes to the fore.
During this session we’ll explore and solve some interesting real life scenarios with SSIS scripts.
</description>
      <startTime>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/14/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19784</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19784</id>
          <name>Peter Avenant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BIML</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Real-World Biml Framework (Yours For The Taking)</title>
      <description>Following on from the Metadata driven session Peter will introduce BimlScript transformers and show how they can be used, either interactively or as part of an automatically applied framework. Topics will include transformer syntax, merge modes, target types, execution options, and transformer layering. Peter will also show you how you can enforce these patterns using validators that ensure best practices within your enterprise. This session focus on more advanced Biml features available in Varigence Mist.
</description>
      <startTime>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/14/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19780</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19780</id>
          <name>Martin Catherall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Meet The Masters / Ask The Experts(Rob Farley, Brent McCraken , Warwick Rudd, Dave Dustin, Reza Rad)</title>
      <description>With 2 MCM's and 2 MVP's in Christchurch to present it's an excellent opportunity to have an open forum to pretty much ask any of those SQL related questions that you've always wondered about.
Format will be pretty informal - it you have advance questions please email then through to sqlsaturday316@sqlsaturday.com
Look forward to seeing you all there.</description>
      <startTime>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/14/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19783</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19783</id>
          <name>Peter Avenant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BIML</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Metadata Driven SSIS With Biml</title>
      <description>The power of BimlScript is amplified by the availability of rich metadata to drive the automation of your SSIS solution.  Peter will demonstrate a flexible and reusable framework for storing and managing the metadata that you will use as an input to your BimlScripts. The framework demonstrated will be made available to all attendees and can be used with the free BidsHelper Visual Studio add in. </description>
      <startTime>6/14/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/14/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>