<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #517 - Philadelphia 2016</name>
    <startDate>6/4/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>280</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-06:00) Saskatchewan</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat517</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>45 Liberty Blvd.</name>
      <street>
      </street>
      <city>Malvern</city>
      <state>Pennsylvania</state>
      <zipcode>19355</zipcode>
      <longitude>-75.5222712</longitude>
      <latitude>40.0557312</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1617</importID>
      <name>VMWare</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.vmware.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://bobpusateri.blob.core.windows.net/shared/ChiSQL/vmware.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1590</importID>
      <name>MVP Systems Software</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.jamsscheduler.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.jamsscheduler.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/mvp-logo-transparent.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>386</importID>
      <name>Anexinet</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.anexinet.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.anexinet.com/wp-content/uploads/anexient-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>60</importID>
      <name>EMC</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://community.emc.com/community/connect/everything_microsoft</url>
      <imageURL>
      </imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>13</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/sqlsaturday/eventsponsors/Quest_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>398</importID>
      <name>Aspect Consulting</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.aspect-consulting.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.aspect-consulting.com/images/logo1.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1686</importID>
      <name>People 2.0</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.people20.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://yt3.ggpht.com/-b5fX9A2AgtE/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAAAAA/0E4bQX91eSU/s100-c-k-no-rj-c0xffffff/photo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1128</importID>
      <name>Robert L Davis</name>
      <label>Personal Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlsoldier.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsoldier.com/imgs/SQLSoldierdotcom.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>126</importID>
      <name>T and K Creative Solutions Group</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://clarkcreations.net/blog/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/933/EventSponsor_14233.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>47056</importID>
      <name>Kevin Howell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>As a SQL Server DBA and Developer for USLI (United States Liability Insurance Group) in Wayne, PA, Kevin concentrates on driving SQL performance, security and integrity initiatives, along with leading development efforts on various .NET projects. Kevin started programming in Fortran and C++, then moved to Visual Basic and began developing full n-tier applications for the medical and insurance sectors. Kevin began working with SQL Server in 1999 (v6.5) and since that time, he has focused his attention on best practices for both developers and DBA’s to strike a balance between each discipline and find the best solutions for scalable, enterprise applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/KevinHowellDBA</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlpsi.com/blog.html</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50500</importID>
      <name>Bill Emmert</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>William Emmert, Technical Director/Technology Architect, Microsoft Technology Center, Microsoft Corporation 
Bill is a Data Platform Architect in the Philadelphia Microsoft Technology Center (MTC). He started his career at Microsoft in 1998 in Consulting Services focusing on design, development, testing, deployment and troubleshooting SQL Server OLTP and OLAP solutions. In 2007, he worked on the SQL Server product group for 1 year as a member of the SQL Server Customer Advisory Team (SQLCAT) returning back to consulting in 2008. In 2010 he worked in the New York MTC as a SQL Architect before taking on his current roles in the Philadelphia MTC in 2011. Bill has worked in the computer industry for 30 years.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48838</importID>
      <name>Carlos L Chacon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Chacon is the managing partner of SQL Data Partners LLC and co-host of the popular SQL Data Partners Podcast.  While getting his start as a typical accidental DBA, Carlos has sat on Microsoft exam review panels, served as regional mentor and chapter leader.  He enjoys traveling and has been to four continents, speaks Spanish and can eat his weight in raspberries (not yet proven).  He and his family live in Richmond, Virginia.</description>
      <twitter>@CarlosLChacon</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/carloslchacon</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldatapartners.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@CarlosLChacon</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45124</importID>
      <name>Steve Hood</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I#39;m a DBA who has gone through most of my career with few people to learn and unsure of where to find great help until I found a real mentor.  When I started at a company with a great, knowledgeable manager and learned to find others speaking about SQL Server online my skills boomed.  This is especially true in my most passionate area, SQL Server performance.  

Knowing that my knowledge came from others, I now have a second passion of sharing my knowledge with others.</description>
      <twitter>@SteveHoodSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stevehoodsql</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://simplesqlserver.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SteveHoodSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>51166</importID>
      <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joseph D'Antoni is a Senior Consultant and Microsoft Data Platform MVP with over 20 years of experience working in both Fortune 500 and smaller firms. He is a Principal Consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates and lives in Malvern, PA. He is a frequent speaker at major tech events like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and Enterprise Data World. He blogs about all topics technology at joeydantoni.com. He believes that no single platform is the answer to all technology problems. Joseph holds a BS in Computer Information Systems from Louisiana Tech University and an MBA from North Carolina State University, and is the co-author of the Microsoft book "Introducing SQL Server 2016”.</description>
      <twitter>jdanton</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=3997984amp;trk=hb_tab_pro_top</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://joeydantoni.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jdanton</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45838</importID>
      <name>William Wolf</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bill is the Manager of SQL Server Performance Tuning for RDX.  He works with over 400 customers on solutions within the SQL Server environment and specialized in code tuning and mentoring the team within RDX. He has become a SQL Saturday veteran speaking at nearly 40 SQL Saturdays in the last 3 years.  He has also spoken at Summit and is an Idera Ace class of 2018. Bill is active in the Pittsburgh SQL Server User Group.  He is also the chapter lead for the DevOps Virtual User Group. He is passionate about educating users on SQL Server and mentoring others.</description>
      <twitter>sqlwarewolf</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamjwolf</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlwarewolf.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlwarewolf</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48592</importID>
      <name>Ray Kim</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ray Kim is an advocate for documentation and technical communication. He is a co-founder of the Albany, NY SQL group (CASSUG), a member of STC and the AlbanyUX user group, and has spoken at numerous SQLSaturdays and at PASS Summit. He has worked various positions in technology, including as a developer, webmaster, analyst, technical writer, and instructor. He holds an MS in technical communication from Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute and a BS in computer science from Syracuse University.

A musician in his spare time, Ray plays four different instruments. He also enjoys going to ball games and doing CrossFit, and is a two-time SQLServerCentral.com fantasy football champion. He lives in Troy, NY with his wife, Lianne, and their two cats.</description>
      <twitter>PianoRayK</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pianorayk</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://pianorayk.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=PianoRayK</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46379</importID>
      <name>Alex Grinberg</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have more than 20 years of IT experience. My primary focus is with the latest Microsoft technologies including .NET (VB and C#), SSRS and SSIS. I provide services in tuning, optimization, analysis and development for the creation of new applications, converting legacy technologies (SQL Server, VB.NET and C# ) and site training. I have worked for CSC, VerticalNet, IDP, LSAC , and TMNAS (to name a few) and I am currently employed with Cox Automotive. I am Apress author book "XML and JSON Recipes for SQL Server", also wrote number of articles for Simple-Talk and SQLServerCentral.com</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-grinberg-36773a6/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49924</importID>
      <name>Mark Wojciechowicz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Wojciechowicz is a Business Intelligence Solutions Architect with a passion for process improvement.  He has spoken to the Philly user group in the past about continuous integration, continuous delivery, SSDT, and a myriad of other business intelligence related topics.</description>
      <twitter>@MarkW_BI</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-wojciechowicz-8030542</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MarkW_BI</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48643</importID>
      <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wayne Sheffield, a Microsoft Certified Master in SQL Server and Microsoft Most Valuable Professional, started working with xBase databases in the late 80’s. With over 25 years in IT, he has worked with SQL Server (since 6.5 in the late 90’s) in various dev/admin roles, with an emphasis in performance tuning. He is the author of several articles at www.sqlservercentral.com, a co-author of “SQL Server T-SQL Recipes”, and enjoys sharing his knowledge by presenting at SQL events worldwide and blogging at http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</description>
      <twitter>@DBAWayne</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/WayneSheffield</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DBAWayne</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48791</importID>
      <name>Robert Pearl</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robert Pearl is a 5-year SQL Server MVP and creator of the award-winning database and monitoring alert system, SQLCentric. Author of the HealthySQL - Comprehensive Guide to Healthy SQL Server Performance. He’s the founder of Pearl Knowledge Solutions. As a SQL Server community evangelist, he covers local SQL Server events in the New York City area and maintains the Pearl Knows blog. Voted TOP BLOGGER in 2011.</description>
      <twitter>@PearlKnows</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/pearlknows/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@PearlKnows</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45115</importID>
      <name>David Patrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave has been developing database applications for over 25 years. An MCT since 2001, he has taught many classes from Intro to Visual Interdev to Advanced SharePoint Development. Dave runs two user groups, the Maryland and Pennsylvania Microsoft Developers User Group, www.mapamdug.com, and MAD SharePoint, www.madsharepoint.com. Dave does SharePoint training and development for DSA, Inc., a DoD contractor that does great work for the Army over at Aberdeen Proving Ground. Dave is also an MVP.</description>
      <twitter>DavidEPatrick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidepatrick</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.madsharepoint.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DavidEPatrick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50931</importID>
      <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joseph D'Antoni is a Senior Consultant and Microsoft Data Platform MVP with over 20 years of experience working in both Fortune 500 and smaller firms. He is a Principal Consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates and lives in Malvern, PA. He is a frequent speaker at major tech events like Microsoft Ignite, PASS Summit, and Enterprise Data World. He blogs about all topics technology at joeydantoni.com. He believes that no single platform is the answer to all technology problems. Joseph holds a BS in Computer Information Systems from Louisiana Tech University and an MBA from North Carolina State University, and is the co-author of the Microsoft book "Introducing SQL Server 2016”.</description>
      <twitter>jdanton</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=3997984amp;trk=hb_tab_pro_top</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://joeydantoni.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jdanton</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46991</importID>
      <name>Karen Lopez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Karen Lopez is a Sr. Project Manager and Architect for InfoAdvisors. A frequent speaker at conferences and local user groups, she has 20+ years of experience in project and data management on large, multi-project programs. Karen is a chronic volunteer, a Data Platform MVP, and an active advocate for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education and data quality.

Karen’s presentations are known for their lively and interactive approach to learning. Her motto: “Love Your Data!”</description>
      <twitter>datachick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/karenlopez</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datamodel.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=datachick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48127</importID>
      <name>Denis McDowell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denis McDowell is a Microsoft Data Professional with over 20 years of experience with SQL Server, scripting, virtualization, IT operations, and Cloud implementations across multiple industries. He currently works as the Solutions Engineering Manager for SentryOne and owns a consulting practice in the Charlotte, NC area. Denis has been a regular presenter at local, regional, and national conferences and events, including PASS Summit, Microsoft Hosting Summit, and numerous SQL Saturday and SQL User Groups around the U.S. In his free time, Denis enjoys traveling with his family, playing and recording in his home music studio, and catering to the needs of his three dogs.</description>
      <twitter>mcdowell_is</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/preview?vpa=pubamp;locale=en_US</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mcdowell_is</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50930</importID>
      <name>Dominic Falso</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dominic is the Data Architect with The Reinvestment Fund in Center City Philadelphia. He has studied OO programming since 1995 and database software since 1999 (SQL Server since 2001). He currently works with SQL Server 2017 and .NET C#, doing data analysis and manipulation, as well as writing code management software.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50106</importID>
      <name>Niran Even-Chen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niran Even-Chen (@niranec) is a Staff Solution architect at VMware Inc. In his role as a Microsoft enterprise applications architecture specialist Niran is responsible for developing solutions for SQL Server with VMware solutions, writing white papers and is also a frequent speaker in different venues such as VMUG conferences, SQL Saturday user groups, VMworld conferences and more. 
Niran is certified as VMware certified design expert (VCDX) #142 for datacenter virtualization  and Cloud with 15 years of experience in the industry designing and architecting enterprise level solutions.
</description>
      <twitter>@niranec</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://cloud-abstract.com </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@niranec</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49380</importID>
      <name>Ayman El-Ghazali</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ayman is a passionate SQL Server DBA, Developer, and BI Developer. His passion for technology started when he was a young boy playing DOS games on his father's computer. He can be reached via his blog or twitter handle and is looking forward to connecting with other SQL Geeks.</description>
      <twitter>thesqlpro</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aymansqldba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.thesqlpro.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=thesqlpro</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48646</importID>
      <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Wayne Sheffield, a Microsoft Certified Master in SQL Server and Microsoft Most Valuable Professional, started working with xBase databases in the late 80’s. With over 25 years in IT, he has worked with SQL Server (since 6.5 in the late 90’s) in various dev/admin roles, with an emphasis in performance tuning. He is the author of several articles at www.sqlservercentral.com, a co-author of “SQL Server T-SQL Recipes”, and enjoys sharing his knowledge by presenting at SQL events worldwide and blogging at http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</description>
      <twitter>@DBAWayne</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/WayneSheffield</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.waynesheffield.com/wayne</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DBAWayne</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49354</importID>
      <name>Slava Murygin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Started working with SQL Server 7.0 as DBA and Developer. Since then went through all SQL Server versions, migrations and multiple companies of different sizes and industries. Currently working as a  contractor with all aspects of SQL Server, including, but not limited to: troubleshooting performance, designing/developing: databases, systems, processes, data warehouses,  cubes, reports, ETLs; Refactoring old code; Migrating data from other systems to SQL Server; Securing the data on enterprise level.</description>
      <twitter>SlavaSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/slava-murygin/9/b95/858</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://slavasql.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SlavaSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49192</importID>
      <name>Sharon Dooley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sharon Dooley has worked with SQL Server since its first release. Her major areas of specialization are database design and performance tuning. She has a consulting practice and teaches and writes courses for Learning Tree International, where she is SQL Server Curriculum Architect. Sharon is an active member of PASS and leads the DBA Virtual Chapter. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49349</importID>
      <name>Allan Hirt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQLHA, LLC founder, consultant, trainer, author, and business continuity, infrastructure, and virtualization expert Allan Hirt has been working with SQL Server since 1992 when it was still a Sybase product. He has also been clustering in Windows Server since the late 1990s when it was known as Wolfpack. Currently a dual Microsoft MVP (Data Platform; Cloud and Datacenter Management) as well as a VMware vExpert, Allan works with all sizes of customers, no matter if they are on premises or in the public cloud. He also delivers training and speaks at events over the world.</description>
      <twitter>SQLHA</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/allan-hirt/1/b72/673</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlha.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLHA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49628</importID>
      <name>Kerry Tyler</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kerry Tyler is a SQL Server, Business Intelligence, and Azure consultant. His initial IT experience was in network engineering and Windows system administration before moving into the data realm. This infrastructure background builds a firm foundation for performance tuning and cloud infrastructure design and implementation. Kerry has full-time DBA experience in SQL Server since version 2000 and business intelligence architecture since SQL Server 2005. In addition to consulting work, he delivers presentations and training on SQL Server administration, business intelligence, and Azure data and infrastructure components.</description>
      <twitter>AirborneGeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kerrytyler</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://airbornegeek.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AirborneGeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45146</importID>
      <name>Deji Akomolafe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Deji Akomolafe (a member of the Office of the CTO Ambassador Program and Staff Solutions Architect within VMware#39;s Global Field and Partners Readiness Group) specializes in the virtualization of Microsoft Business Critical Applications on VMware#39;s vSphere platform. Deji is a regular speaker at VMworld, Partners Exchange Conference, VMUG, SQL Saturday and EMCWorld, presenting technical subject matters related to Microsoft Applications virtualization and providing technical guidance to help clients enhance their expertise and ability to optimally virtualize and operate their critical applications.</description>
      <twitter>@dejify</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.vmware.com/apps</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dejify</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45556</importID>
      <name>Robert Davis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robert is a SQL Server Certified Master, MVP, and has spent 17+ years honing his skills in security, performance tuning, SQL development, high availability, and disaster recovery. He served as PM for the SQL Server Certified Master Program at Microsoft Learning, and in various roles at Microsoft specializing in SQL Server administration, development, and architecture. He currently works as a Database Engineer at BlueMountain Capital Management where he spends a vast majority of his time tuning massively parallel queries. Robert feeds his passion for security by acting as co-leader of the PASS Security Virtual Chapter.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLSoldier</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/robertldavis/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlsoldier.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLSoldier</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49023</importID>
      <name>Andy Galbraith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I’m a forty-something Microsoft SQL Server DBA of 18+ years, a devoted husband, and a father of three young boys (all aged eight and under!) I have been a DBA at a public university, at a major bank, at a healthcare system, and I now work as a consultant with customers across the United States. I write and speak primarily about the tips and tricks that I discover along my SQL Server journey.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/DBA_ANDY</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/andy-galbraith/5/149/98b</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://nebraskasql.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/DBA_ANDY</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45135</importID>
      <name>Thomas Grohser</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thomas Grohser has spent most of the past 26+ years exploring the deeper inner workings of SQL Server and its features while working for entertainment, pharmaceutical, and financial services industries. His primary focus is to architect, plan, build, and operate reliable, highly available, secure, and scalable infrastructures for SQL Server. Over the years he has managed thousands of SQL Server instances, processing trillions of rows, taking up petabytes of storage. Thomas has been a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for 9 years and has spoken regularly at conferences, SQLSaturdays, and user groups for 12 years.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomasgrohser/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49454</importID>
      <name>Sebastian Meine</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sebastian Meine, Ph.D. is the SQL Stylist behind sqlity.net llc. In 2010 he founded sqlity.net to fully engage in his passion for SQL Server.
Armed with a Ph.D. in Computer Science and years of experience in architecting DBs for a global Fortune 50 company, Sebastian now provides training and consulting services for his clients, specializing in SQL Server Security, Test Driven Development and Performance. Sebastian is an experienced public speaker, published author, president of the Philly PASS Chapter, PASS Regional Mentor and coauthor  lead developer of tSQLt.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlity</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sebastianmeine</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlity.net/en/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlity</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49432</importID>
      <name>Kevin Goff</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin S. Goff (http://www.kevinsgoff.net) is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP 

Database architect/developer/speaker/author 

Regular columnist for CoDe Magazine on .NET, SQL Server, and Business Intelligence topics 

Frequent speaker at community events in the Mid-Atlantic region. 

Host of BDBI Radio (http://www.bdbiradio.com), a weekly webcast on SQL/BI topics </description>
      <twitter>@KevinSGoff</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.KevinSGoff.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KevinSGoff</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45185</importID>
      <name>Dan Clark</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dan Clark is a senior data analytics consultant. He is focused on all things data analytics and training others how to get value from their data. Dan has published several books and numerous articles on .NET programming and data analytics. He is a regular speaker at various developer and database conferences and user group meetings and enjoys interacting with the Microsoft developer and database communities. His latest book Beginning Power BI published by Apress is a will get you up and running with self-service data analytics on the Power BI platform in no time.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dxclark/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://drclarkblog.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49623</importID>
      <name>Adam Machanic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adam Machanic is a Boston-based SQL Server developer, writer, and speaker. He focuses on large-scale data warehouse performance and development, and is the author of the award-winning SQL Server monitoring stored procedure, quot;sp_WhoIsActive.quot; He has contributed to several books on SQL Server, including quot;T-SQL Queryingquot; (Microsoft Press, 2015). He is a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>@AdamMachanic</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/adammachanic</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/adam_machanic</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@AdamMachanic</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45393</importID>
      <name>James Serra</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>James Serra is a big data and data warehousing solution architect at Microsoft.  He is a thought leader in the use and application of Big Data and advanced analytics. Previously, James was an independent consultant working as a Data Warehouse/Business Intelligence architect and developer. He is a prior SQL Server MVP with over 35 years of IT experience. James is a popular blogger (JamesSerra.com) and speaker. He is the author of the book “Reporting with Microsoft SQL Server 2012”.</description>
      <twitter>www.twitter.com/JamesSerra</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/JamesSerra</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.JamesSerra.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=www.twitter.com/JamesSerra</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46831</importID>
      <name>Justin Dearing</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Justin Dearing has been working in IT in 2002. He started as a night shift AS/400 operator and rose through the ranks at a series of companies. He currently works as a developer in the capital markets industry.

Justin has served in both the development and production side of the house on Windows, Unix and Midrange Platforms. His database experience includes MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres and Microsoft SQL server. These days he programs in C#, PowerShell and PHP.</description>
      <twitter>zippy1981</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/justindearingnyc</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.justaprogrammer.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=zippy1981</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45678</importID>
      <name>Andy Mallon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>--</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49627</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denny Cherry is the owner and principal consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates Consulting and has over a decade of experience working with platforms such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Microsoft SQL Server, Hyper-V, vSphere, and Enterprise Storage solutions. Denny’s areas of technical expertise include system architecture, performance tuning, security, replication, and troubleshooting. Denny currently holds several Microsoft Certifications related to SQL Server 2000 through 2019, including being a Microsoft Certified Master, Microsoft MVP and VMware vExpert Award.</description>
      <twitter>mrdenny</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrdenny</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.dcac.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mrdenny</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>47351</importID>
      <name>Chris Bell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Bell offers a unique view of how we live and work with data, both now and as we head into the future. Having braved many roles, lifecycles, and battles in the IT world, he has honed his DBA (Database Administration or Do 'Bout Anything) skills in Information Systems and development, focusing on SQL Server. Currently, he serves as the lead DBA at The Motley Fool. You can keep up with Chris' thoughts and technical community activities at WaterOxConsulting.com.</description>
      <twitter>@cbelldba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/christopher-bell/19/a08/93/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.wateroxconsulting.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cbelldba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>48425</importID>
      <name>Jim Donahoe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jim is a Premier Field Engineer for Microsoft in the Data/AI space.  He lives in Pittsburgh in a small suburb.  He loves working with all things Azure(ARM templates, DBaaS, SQL on IaaS).  He is an avid collector of retro video games! He is a member of the Idera ACE program for 2018.</description>
      <twitter>SQLFlipFlopsDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlflipflopsdba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLFlipFlopsDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>47453</importID>
      <name>Gigi Bell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Known across the country as the SQL Registration Princess, Gigi Bell actually has vast experience in training and development. Being married to a SQL DBA, she knows enough about SQL to be dangerous, but her real passion is helping people learn and achieve their true potential. She has spoken at SQL Saturdays across the country since 2014.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlspouse</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gehan-bell-bab55293</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlspouse</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>50792</importID>
      <name>Vince Napoli</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vince is a Business Intelligence Architect with Anexinet in Blue Bell.  He has worked with Data Warehousing and Business Intelligence since 1996, with a focus and specialty on SQL Sever since 1999, and an BI Architect since 2001.  Vince is a frequent presenter at PSSUG, former president and current board member of PSSUG, and has presented at several SQL Saturdays and also a Code camp presenter in the Philadelphia area.   </description>
      <twitter>@Napoli_V </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/vince-napoli-777691</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Napoli_V </imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49287</importID>
      <name>Randy Knight</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Randy Knight is a data professional who has worked with Microsoft technology for over 25 years, focusing on SQL Server since 1997. He has worked in a variety of settings, including 6 years as a database architect for match.com. In 2010, he founded SQL Server Solutions Group LLC, a boutique SQL Server consultancy.  A Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) in SQL Server, he speaks often at events all over the country including the  PASS Summit, SQLIntersections, and numerous SQL Saturday and User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>randy_knight</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/randyknight</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlsolutionsgroup.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=randy_knight</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>49391</importID>
      <name>Daniel Bowlin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a data integration developer at Time Warner Cable.  I have been working with SQL Server technologies since the late 90s.  About 6 years ago I specialized in the SQL Server BI stack.  Lately I have been almost exclusively working in SSIS.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLBI_Dan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=33119347amp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.danielbowlin.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLBI_Dan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>45192</importID>
      <name>Greg Moore</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Greg Moore is a graduate of RPI. There, he majored in CompSci, but probably spent as much time hiking, canoeing, caving and rock-climbing as he did studying.
He started working with SQL Server 4.21a in 1995 and has survived numerous upgrades.
He's been a Director and later VP of IT at several startups including PowerOne Media, TownNews and Traffiq and now consults. These days, when he's not busy with playing with SQL Server or spending time with his family, he can often be found underground caving or teaching cave rescue with the NCRC.
While his focus is on the operations side of DBA, his interests include DR, performance and general IT problem solving.
He is the author of: IT Disaster Response: Lessons Learned in the Field.</description>
      <twitter>@stridergdm</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gregdmoore</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blog.greenms.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@stridergdm</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46782</importID>
      <name>Tamera Clark</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tamera Clark has been involved in the IT industry for greater than ten years, with experiences ranging from systems analysis/engineering to SQL Server and SSRS administration/development. She is an active member of the SQL Server community, participating in the Women in Technology Virtual Chapter, Co-leading the Nashville BI Chapter, assisting the Nashville PASS Chapter and serving as a Regional Mentor.  Tamera is also the event chair of SQLSaturday Nashville.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/tameraclark</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/tameraclark/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tameraclark.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/tameraclark</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>45192</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45192</id>
          <name>Greg Moore</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>30th Street</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tips that have saved my bacon</title>
      <description>In this session, I propose to share some of the tricks I've used on the operational side of being a DBA.

There's saying, never perform small miracles, people to rely on them, but isn't it useful to have a few in your back-pocket. 

Everyone knows log-shipping is great for DR recovery, but what about using it for minor issues, like a delete or update gone bad? Want to move a large table someplace else (like that "oh it'll just be a small audit table, it won't grow large because we'll write the functionality later to keep it small" and they never do? UNC backups... an often overlooked but useful option for making a backup AND getting it off your server. Run a small operation where too many fingers have access to the operational DB and you want to catch them? These are some of the tricks I've picked up over the years and used more than once to perform small miracles and have saved my bacon or the bacon of others</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45185</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45185</id>
          <name>Dan Clark</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure/Misc</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRPIII</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning – Bringing Advanced Analytics to the Masses</title>
      <description>While Machine Learning is not new, it has never been easy to implement. Azure Machine Learning (AML) aims to provide a set of tools that are easier to use and once a model is created easier to consume by client applications. At the core of AML is ML Studio. ML Studio provides an easy to use graphical tool that allows you to control the process from pre-processing the data, to applying learning algorithms, testing the model, and finally deploying the model for use by client applications. This session guides you through the process of creating and deploying a ML model. In addition it will demonstrate how client applications can easily use the model once it is deployed.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45146</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45146</id>
          <name>Deji Akomolafe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP II</name>
      </location>
      <title>Successfully Virtualizing SQL Server on vSphere - Straight from t</title>
      <description>Over the years, virtualization has matured from the exotic black magic realm to become a mainstream standard IT practice. "Virtualize First" is now a well-accepted default practice in most enterprises and any deviation is now considered an anomaly. In spite of this trend, many IT administrators and architects still have some reservations about virtualizing SQL Server workloads. They consider SQL too "critical" to be virtualized; they wonder and worry about scale about performance; they are looking for guidance and reassurance. If this is where you (or your clients) are today, be sure to attend this session. You will gain valuable insights from what others have done to successfully undertake similar tasks in their environments. We will talk about configuration pitfalls to avoid and also review the configuration and current performance data for some of the most demanding applications in customers environments. Got an SQL virtualization or performance question? Bring it!</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45393</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45393</id>
          <name>James Serra</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP III</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big data architectures and the data lake</title>
      <description>With so many new technologies it can get confusing on the best approach to building a big data architecture.  The data lake is a great new concept, usually built in Hadoop, but what exactly is it and how does it fit in?  In this presentation I’ll discuss the four most common patterns in big data production implementations, the top-down vs bottoms-up approach to analytics, and how you can use a data lake and a RDBMS data warehouse together.  We will go into detail on the characteristics of a data lake and its benefits, and how you still need to perform the same data governance tasks in a data lake as you do in a data warehouse.  Come to this presentation to make sure your data lake does not turn into a data swamp!</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48127</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48127</id>
          <name>Denis McDowell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wynnewood</name>
      </location>
      <title>DevOps Is Coming to an Enterprise near You</title>
      <description>Companies are creating more and more technology service offerings, but they are often throttled by IT. To address this, many IT departments are adapting a new concept called DevOps. DevOps is a concept that has risen quickly from niche to mainstream within the IT enterprise. At its core, DevOps represents a way to leverage people, processes, and tools to remove barriers and improve service delivery. An understanding of scripting and automation platforms is becoming a critical skill for SQL Server professionals. This session discusses how technologies such as virtualization, the cloud, and software-defined datacenters have blurred the lines between developers and sysdmins. We also talk about the competencies and tools required to succeed in an increasingly data-driven workplace.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48592</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48592</id>
          <name>Ray Kim</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stafford</name>
      </location>
      <title>Disaster Documents: The role of documentation in disaster recovery</title>
      <description>I was an employee of a company that had an office in the World Trade Center on Sept. 11, 2001.  Prior to that infamous date, I had written several departmental documents that ended up being critical to our recovery.  In this presentation, I provide a narrative of what happened in the weeks following 9/11, and how documentation played a role in getting the organization back on its feet.

While other disaster recovery presentations talk about strategies, plans, and techniques, this presentation focuses on the documentation itself.  We will discuss the documents we had and how they were used in our recovery.  We will also discuss what documents we didn't have, and how they could have made the process better.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48791</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48791</id>
          <name>Robert Pearl</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stafford</name>
      </location>
      <title>Social DBA</title>
      <description>What is a socal DBA?  It's a DBA that uses social media to excel in his or her DBA career!  Social media includes, but not limited to Twitter, LinkedIn, Google, SQL Server forums,community sites, and more! By using various aspects of social media to one's advantage, you can become a DBA star.  Whether you're an accidental, junior or senior DBA, if you're not using social media, then you're missing out on the vast array of resources at your fingertips.  Can't solve a problem, or issue? Before you call Microsoft Support, come to my session, and I will provide a ton of useful tips on how to get the answers immediately! This session is a Database Professional Development track to boost your ability to get answers when you need them!</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49454</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49454</id>
          <name>Sebastian Meine</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stafford</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Phenomenal IT Consultant</title>
      <description>Whether you are just starting out or have been in business as an IT consultant for a while, if you desire more clients or wonder how to finally achieve success online, you are not alone.
In this session we’ll cover how to identify your target market and your niche. You will learn why a strong brand is vital to your success. You will discover how to make your ideal client want to work with you and pay you what you are worth, even if you hate the selling part.
This session is for you…
- if you are struggling to find enough new clients,
- if you feel like you are the best-kept secret in your field or if prospects love you but don’t buy from you,
- if you feel like you are treading water when it comes to marketing.
Join this session and get started on your way to becoming a Phenomenal IT Consultant.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49023</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49023</id>
          <name>Andy Galbraith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>30th Street</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting Started with Extended Events</title>
      <description>Few subjects in Microsoft SQL Server inspire the same amount of Fear, Uncertainty, and Doubt (FUD) as Extended Events.  Many DBA's continue to use Profiler and SQL Trace even though they have been deprecated for years.  Why is this?

Extended Events started out in SQL Server 2008 with no user interface and only a few voices in the community documenting the features as they found them.  Since then it has blossomed into a full feature of SQL Server and an amazingly low-impact replacement for Profiler and Trace.

Come learn how to get started - the basics of sessions, events, actions, targets, packages, and more.  We will look at some base scenarios where Extended Events can be very useful as well as considering a few gotchas along the way.  You may never go back to Profiler again!</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48646</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48646</id>
          <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wynnewood</name>
      </location>
      <title>Table Vars and Temp Tables – What you NEED to Know!</title>
      <description>Almost every SQL Developer is familiar with Table Variables and Temporary Tables. While each of these objects represents temporary storage, there are also substantial differences between them. Understanding the differences between Table Variables and Temporary Tables, and the ramifications that those differences cause, is essential to being able to properly select the appropriate object for use in your development tasks. In this code filled session, we’ll discover the differences and similarities of Temporary Tables and Table Variables, dispel some widespread myths about each, and answer the most important questions of them all, "When do I use one or the other and what are the various impacts of doing so?"</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50106</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50106</id>
          <name>Niran Even-Chen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRPII</name>
      </location>
      <title>Architecting virtual SQL server for performance </title>
      <description>Today, many enterprise organizations have already virtualized most of their non critical applications, these organizations are now employing a "Virtual First" policy, harnessing the efficiency and cost savings of virtualization for their most critical applications. 
Still, many IT architects and DBA's are hesitant of virtualizing their SQL workloads, they are worried about  performance, scale, availability and support for what is usually considered their most critical applications.  In this session we will review the guidance for successfully virtualizing critical SQL databases, we will cover the best practices, real world customer experience  and what to watch out for when virtualizing the most critical SQL databases. The session is delivered by the author of the official SQL server on VMware best practices guide.  </description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45556</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45556</id>
          <name>Robert Davis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP II</name>
      </location>
      <title>10 Things Administrators of BI Systems Should Know</title>
      <description>Conversations about SQL Server administration tends to be all about administering OLTP systems. If you administrer BI systems, you can't apply everything you know about administering OLTP systems to BI systems. BI systems usually end up being administered by OLTP DBAs or by BI developers and architects. Where does one even find a BI Administrator?

Fortunately, I've been administering BI systems for several years, and I have learned the hard way the difference between administering OLTP and BI systems. This session will cover the top 10 things that I think an administrator of BI systems need to know.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49623</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49623</id>
          <name>Adam Machanic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL Server 2016</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP I</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 "Hidden Gems"</title>
      <description>By far the most important SQL Server release since the heady days of 2005, SQL Server 2016 represents a huge leap forward in a number of key areas. You've no doubt heard plenty about such features as Query Store, JSON support, Polybase, and the other big-ticket items. But there are also a number of very cool features that don't usually make the top 10 lists. In this talk you'll learn about enhancements to indexing (including both Columnstore and traditional b-tree indexes), DMVs, compression, string handling, encryption, configuration, and even timezone support. These smaller features may not be highlighted in the latest glossy ads from Microsoft's marketing department, but they're the kinds of things that add up to make your life easier. Attend this session to learn all sorts of new and different reasons to upgrade as quickly as possible.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49349</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49349</id>
          <name>Allan Hirt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP II</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deploy Highly Available SQL Server for Virtualization  the Cloud</title>
      <description>While most of us still have some physical, on premises deployments of SQL Server, many of us are moving towards, or already have started deploying SQL Server instances and databases en masse either in virtual machines or in the public cloud. This session will discuss how you should approach availability in this new paradigm when things are both similar to the way we used to do things, but in other ways completely different. You will learn best practices for clustering SQL Server (both FCIs and AGs), how to think about quorum, and more.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49628</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49628</id>
          <name>Kerry Tyler</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL Server 2016</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP III</name>
      </location>
      <title>New Engine Features in SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 brings with it a flood of new capabilities over previous versions. Between improved functionality in existing components and outright new functionality, nearly every part of the product has received attention in this release. This session will focus on the new and improved Engine features in 2016. Whether you have Standard Edition deployed or utilize every last feature available in Enterprise, there are new items to explore and contemplate in SQL Server's latest and greatest.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45678</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45678</id>
          <name>Andy Mallon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP II</name>
      </location>
      <title>Demystifying Data Compression</title>
      <description>High-end storage is expensive, and SQL Server data compression can make your database smaller. So compress all the tables! No--unfortunately, it's not that easy. We'll talk about how data compression actually works, and the differences between ROW and PAGE compression. As part of this, we'll look at the costs and benefits associated with each type of compression. By the end of this session, you'll have a better idea of when compression is the right solution, as well as what type of compression to use. </description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49627</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49627</id>
          <name>Denny Cherry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP II</name>
      </location>
      <title>Table Indexing for the .NET Developer</title>
      <description>In this session we will be looking at the best and worse practices for indexing tables within your SQL Server 2012 databases.  We will also be looking into the new indexing features that are available in SQL Server 2012 (and SQL Server 2005-2008) and how you the .NET developer can make the best use of them to get your code running its best.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45115</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45115</id>
          <name>David Patrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wynnewood</name>
      </location>
      <title>3 Ways for Getting Data from SharePoint : SSIS, Excel and Access</title>
      <description>Need to report on some data from SharePoint? We'll look at three different techniques to pull data from a SharePoint Server. We'll start with SSIS and the SharePoint List Source and Destinations. Next, we'll use Excel to connect to various SharePoint lists (both online and on premise), and finally we'll use Microsoft Access to do the same thing (and throw in the capability to do updates as well). At the end of the talk, we'll have three different ways to get data from SharePoint.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50931</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50931</id>
          <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP II</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing SQL Server on VMWare</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn about best practices for running SQL Server on VMWare from two VMWare vExperts who have a combined 20 years of experience with SQL Server and virtualization. You will learn about things like file systems, optimal storage drivers and configuration to make your virtual servers perform at their best. </description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50792</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50792</id>
          <name>Vince Napoli</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP I</name>
      </location>
      <title>Row Level Security in the BI Environment</title>
      <description>Implementing Row Level Security in SQL Server, and also even Cell level security in SSAS, to mask data from other users is a common request and a component in your security and data access model for a data warehouse and BI environment.   Information is valuable, but will be a double edge sword if not protected, and should only made visible to only those that should receive it.   In this session, we describe the design considerations, highlight multiple scenarios for querying and reporting, and demonstrate how to apply Row Level Security in both pre-SQL 2016, and implementing it using the new Row Level Security feature in SQL 2016.    We will also touch on briefly cell level security in SSAS.              </description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50500</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50500</id>
          <name>Bill Emmert</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL Server 2016</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP III</name>
      </location>
      <title>Security Investments in SQL Server 2016  Azure SQL Database Service</title>
      <description>Session Objective(s): 
Get a closer look at the latest investments Microsoft is making in security across the SQL Platform
Gain an understanding for how these features can be used to keep data secure and compliant
Key Takeaways:
Microsoft is focused on delivering industry-leading, differentiated, and ambitious security features that integrate with the latest technologies including Azure Active Directory, Stretch Database, and Hekaton
The SQL Platform provides a secure and trusted platform for all database applications
</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49432</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49432</id>
          <name>Kevin Goff</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL Server 2016</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP I</name>
      </location>
      <title>In-Memory Technology in SQL 2016 (Columnstore Indexes and In-Memory Tables)</title>
      <description>Some presentations cover the columnstore index and some cover in-memory optimized tables.   In this presentation, I'll cover both!   I'll demonstrate some actual examples of data warehouse, BI, and OLTP applications where the columnstore index and in-memory optimized tables in SQL 2016 can yield tremendous performance enhancements.
</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49192</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49192</id>
          <name>Sharon Dooley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL Server 2016</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP I</name>
      </location>
      <title>The New SQL Server 2016 Query Store</title>
      <description>The query store is a new feature in SQL Server 2016 that gives you extensive performance monitoring and auditing capabilities. In this presentation you will learn
•	Use cases for the query store
•	How to enable the query store
•	How to extract information from the query store
•	Best practices for taking advantage of the query store
This presentation assumes a knowledge of database performance tuning, query plans and Transact-SQL.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>47056</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>47056</id>
          <name>Kevin Howell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>30th Street</name>
      </location>
      <title>Always-On Availability Groups: Replicas, Listeners  Quorums, Oh My!</title>
      <description>Would you like to leverage the advantages of an Availability Group within your Enterprise environment to provide high availability and disaster recovery?  This discussion will cover different scenarios where an Availability Group could (and should) be implemented, along with a full demonstration of the setup of an Availability Group.  We will explore the concepts that are critical to a successful AG deployment and look at the evolution of Availability Groups from SQL 2012 through 2016.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>50930</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>50930</id>
          <name>Dominic Falso</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wynnewood</name>
      </location>
      <title>Parsing T-SQL using the TransactSql.ScriptDom library (C#)</title>
      <description>T-SQL is a very complicated language to parse, so it can be intimidating to get started. We'll go over basic concepts of what a lexer/parser is and what to expect from it. Then, using the TransactSql.ScriptDom library in the SQL Server SDK, we'll do some examples to get our feet wet.
</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>47453</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>47453</id>
          <name>Gigi Bell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stafford</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dealing With Difficult Co-Workers</title>
      <description>Having problems at work dealing with difficult co-workers and end-users? Are these difficult people stressing you out and making you dislike your job? Learn two golden rules to live by that can help ease this stress!
Through case studies and open discussion, we will help you determine how (and if) you should deal with these difficult people.  We will identify and categorize different types of behaviors that your co-workers exhibit so that you can effectively deal with them.  Mastering these skills can lead to future success and team management.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46379</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46379</id>
          <name>Alex Grinberg</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stafford</name>
      </location>
      <title>DMVs and system objects that every DBA should know</title>
      <description>This session will cover monitoring, performance tuning, trouble shooting, generating SQL scripts, and many other daily activities and tasks for the DBA position. In the lecture "DMVs and system objects that every DBA should know", a session presenter will demonstrate the Dynamic Management Object and system tables that help DBAs simplify their role. The presenter will also go into details regarding returned result values and demonstrate examples using real-case scenarios.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45135</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45135</id>
          <name>Thomas Grohser</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRPIII</name>
      </location>
      <title>Optimizing SQL Server and Databases for large Fact Tables</title>
      <description>A session full of demos demonstrating how SQL Server startup parameters, trace flags and the create database and alter database command when used correctly for the underlying hardware can make scanning your fact tables much faster.

We will also as a side effect explore the Mary Go Round query feature and find ways to bulk load data faster and how to load from an OLTP system with zero impact to it.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49924</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49924</id>
          <name>Mark Wojciechowicz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP III</name>
      </location>
      <title>Extending PowerBI</title>
      <description>This will be a Co-presentation with Ed Bunt and Mark Wojciechowicz.

With PowerBI, we can easily create intuitive reports and dashboards.  This highly customizable environment can be extended in many ways, even outside its own environment.  In this session, we will look at how to create a custom visual, how to embed PowerBI in a custom application, how to integrate PowerBI with Cortana in windows 10, and, if we can think of anything else before June, we’ll do that too.
</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49380</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49380</id>
          <name>Ayman El-Ghazali</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL Server 2016</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP III</name>
      </location>
      <title>PolyBase: I now pronounce you SQL and Hadoop</title>
      <description>If you thought the Royal wedding of 2011 was a big deal, then you're about to be blown away! This is a match made in Data Heaven. You're all invited, no need to RSVP, there is plenty of food for thought in this session. There will be some background talk and a demo for querying and creating data on HDFS (using Azure Blobs). As a special gift to the happy couple, we will also have a special demo with JSON documents. This will be the greatest coming together of 2016! See you there! </description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45124</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45124</id>
          <name>Steve Hood</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP II</name>
      </location>
      <title>Buffer Pool Memory Management</title>
      <description>Understand what's in memory, why it's there, and how to reduce the footprint if that's reasonable.  Find your large queries with several techniques, justify them, and tune them. Find indexes to drop, consolidate, or create.  Finally, purge your data, because even our accounts hire pyromaniacs with scissors!</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>51166</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>51166</id>
          <name>Joseph D'Antoni</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure/Misc</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP III</name>
      </location>
      <title>MVP Systems Software--Jams Tool</title>
      <description>A look at the advantages of leveraging an enterprise job scheduler instead of SQL Agent. We’ll take a closer look at the added features available with a scheduler and how we can use them to tie our SQL jobs to processes outside of the SQL environment.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49287</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49287</id>
          <name>Randy Knight</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wynnewood</name>
      </location>
      <title>But it worked great in Dev!  Perfomance for Devs</title>
      <description>If you've ever found yourself stating the above, this session is for you.  For many developers, writing T-SQL that works is not the challenge.  But too  often, functional T-SQL is not the same as good T-SQL.  In this session, we  will examine why "SQL that works" is not good enough.  Understanding  indexes, exectuion plans, sargability, and more are all critical to writing  good T-SQL.  We will also examine several real-world examples of T-SQL that  "worked great in dev" but caused major issues when it hit production. 
</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48838</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48838</id>
          <name>Carlos L Chacon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Azure/Misc</track>
      <location>
        <name>30th Street</name>
      </location>
      <title>Disaster Recovery Options with Azure</title>
      <description>Recovery in the cloud is now easier and more convenient than ever.  This session describes some common scenarios and reviews the steps needed to prepare for a disaster with a recover in Azure.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49391</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49391</id>
          <name>Daniel Bowlin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>30th Street</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS Optimization techniques</title>
      <description>There are number of things you can do to optimize SSIS packages to improve overall performance and shorten load times.  This session will review 3 areas: common mistakes developers make, settings and tweaks, and design pattern improvements.  Some of the things you will see can make dramatic improvements in speed, while others are for those seeking to pull every last bit of performance out of your packages.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46991</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46991</id>
          <name>Karen Lopez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP I</name>
      </location>
      <title>Who's Pissing in Your Data Lake?</title>
      <description>The new data terms of Data Lake, Data Reservoir, and Data Swamp have left me with more questions than answers. In this presentation, Karen discusses the types of data anomalies that organizations can run into when they use external data, the wrong datasets for the right reasons and the right datasets for the wrong reasons.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48425</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48425</id>
          <name>Jim Donahoe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>DBA</track>
      <location>
        <name>30th Street</name>
      </location>
      <title>New Instance, Now what?</title>
      <description>Congratulations, you’re now our DBA!  For new DBA's a new SQL instance is like a blank canvas, you stare at it and wonder where to start.  As an accidental DBA, this session will help you learn how to survive in your new role.

In this session, you will be supplied with the beginning brush strokes to make your server a master piece. To do so, we will review best practices for standard configurations, backups, maintenance, and disaster recovery. 

By the end of this session, you will have developed a pallet of tools to help you create your SQL Server Masterpiece and be able to use it as a print for others.
</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>47351</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>47351</id>
          <name>Chris Bell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Business Intelligence</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP III</name>
      </location>
      <title>Would You Just Load Already?!  Maximizing Your SSIS Data Load</title>
      <description>Loading data via SSIS is great! It’s fast too! Until you hit a bad record. Then things aren’t so great. Now you probably have to waste time dumping and reloading all the data, or worst figure out where the bad record is and try a partial load.

In this session you will learn a simple method to load data via SSIS and identify, remove, and record those bad records allowing you to maximize the amount of data loaded while ensuring data integrity.
</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46831</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46831</id>
          <name>Justin Dearing</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL Server 2016</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP I</name>
      </location>
      <title>An Introduction to Always Encrypted</title>
      <description>This will be an introduction to the new SQL Server 2016 Always Encryption feature. Unlike Transparent Data Encryption Always Encrypted provides encryption in transit as well as encryption at rest. This will be a survey overview of both the operations and development side of Always Encrypted, but will be mainly operations focused. Considerations for porting existing databases to Always Encrypted will also be discussed.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>48643</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>48643</id>
          <name>Wayne Sheffield</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wynnewood</name>
      </location>
      <title>Crazy Things Developers Do</title>
      <description>Throughout my career, I've seen developers do some pretty crazy things to databases (and truth be told, I've done some of these myself!). Come to this session to learn about SQL Injection attacks and how SQL can use Referential Integrity to optimze queries. Trust me... your DBA will love you for making these changes.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46782</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46782</id>
          <name>Tamera Clark</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>SQL Server 2016</track>
      <location>
        <name>MRP I</name>
      </location>
      <title>Microsoft Business Intelligence 2016 – More Love for Your Data</title>
      <description>Heartbroken over Microsoft’s neglect of SSRS over the years? Well the 2016 release might start healing that broken heart. This upcoming release boast a handful of great new items; from connecting SSRS  PowerBI to mobile report publishing. Join me while I walk you through the best of 2016 for Business Intelligence and help you fall in love with Microsoft BI again. </description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>45838</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>45838</id>
          <name>William Wolf</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Wynnewood</name>
      </location>
      <title>Common Coding Mistakes and How to Mitigate them</title>
      <description>Let the Big Bad Wolf huff, puff and blow your bad queries away.

There are several programming design patterns that work great in object oriented code that do not scale well inside of SQL Server.

In this session we will focus some of these patterns and show you how to make them scale in the database engine. We will touch on Scalar-Value functions, Union, CTE, RBAR and more.

After this session, you can go back to your office Monday morning and be the code tuning rock star!</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>49354</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>49354</id>
          <name>Slava Murygin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Stafford</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Professional: How to get a new job?</title>
      <description>Do you have an Automobile insurance? 
Do you have a Medical insurance? 
Do you have a Life insurance?
Do you have a Job insurance?
Would you like to have one?
On that session we will be talking about a situation when you have to search for a new job.
You have to be always ready for it and I will show you how.</description>
      <startTime>6/4/2016 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/4/2016 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>