<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #657 - Gothenburg 2017</name>
    <startDate>9/23/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Sarajevo, Skopje, Warsaw, Zagreb</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSatGothenburg</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Lindholmen Science Park, Svea</name>
      <street>Lindholmspiren 5</street>
      <city>Gothenburg</city>
      <state>Västra Götalands Län, Sweden</state>
      <zipcode>402 78 Göteborg</zipcode>
      <longitude>11.9364855184937</longitude>
      <latitude>57.7062946039383</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1473</importID>
      <name>SQL Service Nordic AB</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlservice.se</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14826.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1069</importID>
      <name>SolidQ Nordic</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.solidq.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14821.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2013</importID>
      <name>Acando</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.acando.se</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.acando.com/globalassets/sweden/pictures/ir/acando_logo_black.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1951</importID>
      <name>dbWatch AS</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dbwatch.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1015/EventSponsor_14931.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>89</importID>
      <name>Profisee</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.profisee.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.profisee.com/Portals/0/lp/assets/img/logo_profisee.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/908/EventSponsor_14257.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1401</importID>
      <name>Wedham Solutions AB</name>
      <label>Blog Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.wedham.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://wedham.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/wsabcolor.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69650</importID>
      <name>Peter Larsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Larsson is a key player for performance written code. He can turn a 10 hour query into a 3 minute piece of code. Peter is also a SQL Server MVP since 2009. He often hangs out at SQLTeam.com (27k+ posts) and other various sites where he helps all people understand SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>SwePeso</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqltopia.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SwePeso</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64428</importID>
      <name>John Martin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Martin is a Data Platform Engineer working in the financial sector, as well as Vice President Marketing for the PASS organization and currently a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Previously John has worked as a product manager for SentryOne and a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft UK.

John has over a decade of experience working with SQL Server and the Microsoft Data Platform. Working as a DBA, developer and consultant for Microsoft, he has been lucky enough to see how best, and how not, to use SQL Server and the Data Platform effectively.</description>
      <twitter>SQLDiplomat</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/johnqmartin/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mssqltips.com/sqlserverauthor/291/john-martin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLDiplomat</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66963</importID>
      <name>Nico Jacobs</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dr. Nico Jacobs is a Microsoft Business Intelligence and SQL Server trainer at the U2U training center since 2004. Before that, he was a machine learning researcher at the university of Leuven, Belgium.
At U2U, Nico creates and delivers courses on the SQL Server business intelligence stack (Integration Services, Analysis Services, Reporting Services …), Power BI, the traditional relational database environment (database development and administration) and the Azure AI and Big Data stack (Azure Data Factory, Machine Learning, Synapse Analytics,...)</description>
      <twitter>sqlwaldorf</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://be.linkedin.com/in/sqlwaldorf</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.u2u.be/u2u/author/Nico-Jacobs.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlwaldorf</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65173</importID>
      <name>Alexander Arvidsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alexander is a principal solutions architect at Solution Xperts in Linköping, Sweden. Nobody really knows what it means to be a principal solutions architect, but he spends his days helping clients of all shapes and sizes to take better care of their data. 

He has spent the last 23 years toying with databases and related infrastructure services such as storage, networking and virtualization, occasionally emerging from the technical darkness to attend a Star Wars convention somewhere in the world.  

He is a frequent international speaker, a Data Platform MVP, podcaster, blogger and a Microsoft Certified Trainer, focusing on SQL Server, the Azure data stack and Power BI.</description>
      <twitter>arcticdba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexanderarvidsson</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.arcticdba.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arcticdba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64367</importID>
      <name>Remko de Boer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Remko de Boer has been a SQL Server enthousiast since SQL 2000. He has been an MCT for many years and works primaraly as a SQL Server Database consultant or as a SQL Server Business Intelligence consultant. From the inner workings of the database engine to building dynamic generated Reports, almost any aspect of SQL Server will spark an interest.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>?https://nl.linkedin.com/in/remko-de-boer-6155a52?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>68716</importID>
      <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Uwe Ricken is working with IT systems since the 90’s. The primary passion for developments with Microsoft SQL Server expanded in 2007 with his engagement as a DBA for Deutsche Bank AG in Frankfurt am Main. After 6 years of operational experiences as a DBA and over 14 years as a developer of complex database models he achieved the “Microsoft Certified Master – SQL Server 2008” certification which “was” the highest technical certification. In the same year he earned his first award as a Data Platform MVP for his support to the Microsoft SQL Server community in Germany and Europe. Uwe Ricken is a speaker on many international conferences and events and preferred topics are “Database Internals”, “Indexing” and “Development”.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dbBerater</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=270775013amp;trk=tab_pro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmaster.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dbBerater</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65340</importID>
      <name>David Williams</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David is a cross product DBA (SQL Server, DB2, Oracle, Informix, Sybase) who has worked for 25 years as a DBA for both private, 
local/central government customers including a Fortune 50 investment bank. Certifications include MCSE 2014 Data Platform, MCTS SQL Server 2008 DBA and Developer as well as certifcations in other products. 
David has spoken at multiple SQL Saturdays as well as local usergroups and is a regular volunteer at events including SQLBits.</description>
      <twitter>@smooth1x1</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/justdaveinfo?trk=nav_responsive_tab_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://justdave.info</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@smooth1x1</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64375</importID>
      <name>Rob Sewell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob was once a production SQL Server DBA, but is now generally found automating the Data Platform and providing training for clients. He has a passion for PowerShell, Data, and DevOps. He is an MVP, an officer for the DevOps PowerShell VG, and has spoken and volunteered at many PowerShell and Data events. He is a member of the committee that organises Data In Devon and the European PowerShell Conference. He is a proud supporter of the Data and PowerShell communities. 
 
He relishes sharing and learning and can be found doing both via Twitter @sqldbawithbeard and his blog sqldbawithabeard.com. He spends most of his time looking at a screen and loves to solve problems.</description>
      <twitter>sqldbawithbeard</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/robsewellsqldba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldbawithabeard.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqldbawithbeard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69475</importID>
      <name>Håkan Winther</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>H#229;kan Winther is a senior SQL server specialist at SQL Service Nordic, with SQL server experience since 1995 and passion for T-SQL development, performance tuning, large databases and BI Solutions.  
He contributes to the SQL server community by sharing his experience as an active member of ask.sqlservercentral.com, mentor at LabCenter and as a speaker at TechDays, Microsoft Sommarkollo and the Swedish PASS Chapter.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLWinther</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://se.linkedin.com/in/hakanwinther</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservice.se/blogg/?person=145</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLWinther</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64411</importID>
      <name>Alexander Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alexander Klein is a senior Business Intelligence consultant with more than 15 years of experience. He focuses on Business Intelligence and Data Warehouse projects with Microsoft technologies like SQL Server, Power BI, Azure ML or Cortana Intelligence. 

Since 2008, he has been a self-employed consultant in large and medium-sized projects in all sectors across Europe. He has been visiting SQL Saturdays and other Data Conference all over Europe since 2013. Speaker at national and international events since 2017.</description>
      <twitter>@SQL_Alex</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-klein-13a04b3a</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQL_Alex</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65030</importID>
      <name>Torsten Strauss</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Torsten (MVP, MCSE, MCT) has been working with Microsoft SQL Server since the turn of the millennium and is specialized in performance optimization for large SQL Server environments. He has been with bp as a database engineer for over two decades and collaborates closely with Sarpedon Quality Lab as a Principal Microsoft SQL Server Consultant. Torsten is the founder of inside-sqlserver.com and has given more than 120 presentations on Microsoft SQL Server performance optimization at national and international conferences and user groups. Torsten has been recognized as a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional for Data Platform since 2018.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64355</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66329</importID>
      <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Martorana Tusa is a Business Intelligence Team Manager at Würth Phoenix,  the IT and consulting company of the Würth-Group. 
He is awarded as MVP in the Data Platform category

Former BI Specialist at Widex, a Danish manufacturing company, and BI Developer in the IT department of an Italian banking group. 20+ years of experience working with data. 
He is focused on the entire BI stack: database development, data warehousing, data analysis, reporting, etc. 
Andrea is a usual speaker at many events: SQLSaturdays, conferences in Europe and PASS Summit, and for PASS Virtual Groups. 

Andrea is an author for sqlshack.com, sqlservercentral.com, and UGISS (User Group Italiano SQL Server).</description>
      <twitter>bruco441</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bruco441</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64352</importID>
      <name>Britton Gray</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Britton Gray is a veteran of database development, data management, business intelligence, analytics, and data privacy in BI. He has successfully completed projects in a variety of technologies in different technology stacks. Coming from a family full of teachers, he thoroughly enjoys the opportunity to share knowledge and insights; it's an extension of "getting the right information to the right people at the right time" mantra of BI.  He lives near Indianapolis, Indiana, and is the Director of BI for Project Lead The Way, a nonprofit organization providing transformative learning experiences in computer science, engineering, and biomedical sciences.</description>
      <twitter>IDreamInSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/brittongray/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=IDreamInSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66256</importID>
      <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erland Sommarskog is an independent consultant based in Stockholm, working with SQL Server since 1991. He was first awarded SQL Server MVP in 2001, and has been re-awarded every year since. His focus is on systems development with the SQL Server Database Engine and his passion is to help people to write better SQL Server applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sommarskog.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>66676</importID>
      <name>Daniel Hutmacher</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior database developer with a long-running passion for performance tuning on SQL Server. I run my own consultancy business where I help companies with database development, ETL work, performance tuning and technical training on SQL Server.
Board member of the Swedish SQL Server usergroup 2017-2019, organizer of SQL Saturday Stockholm, and co-organizer of GroupBy.org.</description>
      <twitter>@dhmacher</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://se.linkedin.com/in/danielhutmacher</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlsunday.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dhmacher</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64559</importID>
      <name>Stijn Wynants</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Stijn is a Microsoft Premier Field Engineer on Data  AI and a DataMinds core member. He is also one of the organizers of the local user group sessions  the yearly event called DataMinds Connect (SQL Server Days). He is a speaker at various international events (SQL Saturday,PASS Summit,Difinity,...).  He spends his days tuning SQL Servers  solving problems with the full data platform. His focus is primarily on sql server core, but has also done various BI  ETL projects. He gets his kicks out of Columnstore indexes  tuning queries but shivers at the sight of an SSAS cube.

When Stijn is not working with SQL Server, you can probably find him enjoying the local cuisine  local beers or enjoying time with his wife and his dog.</description>
      <twitter>SQLStijn</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/stijn-wynants-ba528660?trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://swyssql.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLStijn</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64929</importID>
      <name>Mike Byrd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Former rocket scientist and USAF Fighter Pilot -- now a SQL Server geek (24 years)! Past opportunities include free-lance technical writer for PC Magazine, Senior Software Manager for government sponsored munitions effectiveness committee, and insurance company CTO.  Currently senior database engineer consultant for several Austin companies.  

Presenter at many SQL Saturdays over last 6 years in United States, Europe, and Australia.

Specialize in SQL Server performance tuning; database (OLTP  OLAP) architecture; trouble-shooting; teaching TSQL (Basic through Advanced).

Video presentations (for local SQL Server user groups or SQL Saturdays) can be found at http://usergroup.tv/videos/category/speaker/mike-byrd</description>
      <twitter>ByrdNest_TX</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-byrd/1/aa0/bbb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://logicalread.solarwinds.com/?s=byrd, www.TSQLMentoring.com and SQLServerCentral.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ByrdNest_TX</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>67173</importID>
      <name>Emanuele Zanchettin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Emanuele Zanchettin, after studying in Computer Engineering, began his career with DB2 in the banking sector in 1998. After a few years and a change of scope of application, he encountered Access and Oracle with which he subsequently worked for several years in data access tuning and database design for new application features. Since 2007 he has also launched into the SQLServer world 2K, 2005, 2008* and 201* and more importantly, since 2011, into Azure SQL Database (SQL Azure). In order to have a greater capacity for assessment and familiarity with the various technologies that the market offers, he has deepened his knowledge to include MySQL and DocumentDB. Today Emanuele is mainly involved in IT projects and database management.</description>
      <twitter>@_thinkIT_</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://it.linkedin.com/pub/emanuele-zanchettin/18/921/34/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_thinkIT_</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64376</importID>
      <name>Sergiy Lunyakin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sergiy Lunyakin (MCSA, MCSE, MCTS) is a Big Data Architect at SoftServe, Inc.
He has extensive experience in designing and developing Big Data Analytics, Data Warehouse, and BI solutions, using both on-premises and cloud products. In 2016, Sergiy became Microsoft Data Platform MVP and has since maintained his MVP status. Sharing knowledge is another one of his passions. He regularly speaks at international conferences such as SQLSaturday, SQLDay, SQLNexus, and SQLBits. He also runs the Lviv SQL Server User Group in Ukraine and organizes SQLSaturday Lviv.</description>
      <twitter>slunyakin</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/slunyakin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://slunyakin.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=slunyakin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65028</importID>
      <name>Torsten Strauss</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Torsten (MVP, MCSE, MCT) has been working with Microsoft SQL Server since the turn of the millennium and is specialized in performance optimization for large SQL Server environments. He has been with bp as a database engineer for over two decades and collaborates closely with Sarpedon Quality Lab as a Principal Microsoft SQL Server Consultant. Torsten is the founder of inside-sqlserver.com and has given more than 120 presentations on Microsoft SQL Server performance optimization at national and international conferences and user groups. Torsten has been recognized as a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional for Data Platform since 2018.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69673</importID>
      <name>Mohamed Mawla</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Trilingual Principal Consultant amp; Team Tech lead at a global Tech Consulting Mohamed had worked with large SQL server environments such as financials and gov of hundreds of SQL server instances and enormous amounts of data. His favorite subjects are Cloud Analytics, performance tuning, High Availability, especially Replication and Disaster recovery. Certified Google Cloud and Azure Data Engineer.

When not working, Mohamed carries his cameras and takes a trip somewhere.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64468</importID>
      <name>Rudi Bruchez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>(same as before)</description>
      <twitter>nepasderanger</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://fr.linkedin.com/in/rudibruchez</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.babaluga.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=nepasderanger</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64825</importID>
      <name>Arne Bartels</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Master of physic in Germany 2000, worked as MS Flightsimulator Expert on the side. Employed at OLTEC Windamp;Solar as C++/Web/PHP/MySQL -Programmer. Company bought by Vestas 2004 shifting to MS-SQL,SSIS until now.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=207669359amp;trk=nav_responsive_tab_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>64355</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64355</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hacking SQL Server</title>
      <description>How easy is it to hack a SQL Server? 
In this session we'll see examples on how to exploit SQL Server, modify data and take control, while at the same time not leaving a trace.
We'll start by gaining access to a SQL Server (using some "creative" ways of making man-in-the-middle attacks), escalating privileges and tampering with data at the TDS protocol level (e.g. changing your income level and reverting without a trace after payment), hacking DDM, and more. 
Most importantly, we'll also cover recommendations on how to avoid these attacks, and take a look at the pros and cons of new security features in SQL Server 2016.
This is a demo-driven session, suited for DBAs, developers and security consultants.
Disclaimer: No actual crimes will be committed. Please do not send agents to my house again</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64375</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64375</id>
          <name>Rob Sewell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Green is good, Red is bad - Turning your Checklists into Pester Tests</title>
      <description>This session is for DBAs specifically, but will be relevant to any technicians who use checklists

I was required to prove that I had successfully installed and configured a backup solution across a large estate. I had a number of success criteria that had to be met. Checking all of these by hand (eye) would have been error prone, so I wrote a test to do this for me and an easy for management to read HTML report using PowerShell and Pester.

The session has come from that situation and is about enabling you to provide an easy to read output to quickly and repeatedly show that infrastructure is as expected for a set of checks, also known as  Operational Validation using Pester. There are many use cases for this type of solution; DR testing, installation, first line checks, presentation setups

After this session you will have a basic understanding of how Pester works and the capability to examine your checklists and create your own validation tests and provide some reporting for manager</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64428</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64428</id>
          <name>John Martin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>Always On Multi-Site Patterns</title>
      <description>Building robust and resilient Data Platform solutions can be complex and costly, building out for both High Availability and Disaster Recovery. The Always On technologies incorporated in the Microsoft SQL Server stack help Data Platform Engineers to do just this. Creating solutions that span multiple locations, in an effort to protect the data that we are tasked to manage on a daily basis.

Together we will walk through the architecture patterns, technology requirements, and configuration options that you need to know in order to build a solid Data Platform. Understanding the implementation differences between on-premises and cloud based deployments is important. Especially as there are specific requirements that need to be met for up-time SLAs to be applicable, as well as mitigating for region failures.

All of these elements mean that it is more than just simple wizards to follow in order to have a solid, reliable, and robust SQL Server Data Platform.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65340</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65340</id>
          <name>David Williams</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server on Linux - SQL Server goes cross platform!</title>
      <description>- How it started - Project Drawbridge, Slava with his brother!

- SQL PAL (SQL Platform Abstraction Layer)

- SQLOSv2

- The (very small) host extension which is platform specific

- Installation with demo,yes that fast!

- Backups and Restores cross platform

- Clustering on Linux

- AlwaysOn Availability Groups cross platform

- SQL Agent for Log Shipping 

- Compiling/Deploying CLR code for both platforms with demo

- How the Linux layer is compiled

- Debugging a combined Windows PE and Linux ELF execution including getting a stack dump

- New DMVs for Linux and DMVs which are replaced as they are not cross platform

- Performance goals

- Limitations with the current implementation</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>67173</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>67173</id>
          <name>Emanuele Zanchettin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>JSON before and after SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>The JavaScript Object Notation format, known simply as JSON, has now become a standard in data interchange between client-server applications, it is also used to store information in non-relational databases and the SQL Server 2016 engine handles it natively . However, today, not everyone has passed to the latest version of SQL Server, however, it is possible to process the JSON format even with earlier versions: in this session, it is confident with this format and illustrates the non-native mode that allows you to be ready in the moment of the upgrade to 2016 (or later) with a few simple moves. Finally, with a few simple examples, you will find some tips on how to use JSON in an advanced way with SQL Server 2016.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66676</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66676</id>
          <name>Daniel Hutmacher</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>Management Studio level-up</title>
      <description>Move up to Management Studio Superstar with these great productivity tips! We’ll explore stuff like keyboard shortcuts, configuration options, how to keep your SSMS settings synchronized across multiple environments and other really useful everyday tricks and hacks. Think “hey, wait, how’d you do that!?”

Some of the things I’ll cover:

* Previewing and quick-reference stuff you can do with keyboard shortcuts
* Quickly navigating your code to find errors or bookmarks

No undocumented stuff, no registry editor, and nothing you wouldn’t put into production. Just really clever productivity tips that will take some of the burden off your everyday work.

But I’m not going to sugarcoat it. Your code may still run slow, and you’ll probably write just as many bugs – but you’ll write them a lot quicker and with so much more style and panache.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64352</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64352</id>
          <name>Britton Gray</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>MPP – Master Parallel Productivity in Azure SQL DW</title>
      <description>We will discuss and demonstrate the MPP (massively parallel processing) architecture of Azure SQL DW and how to make best use of this exciting technology, including:
•	Getting up and running
•	Loading and migrating data
•	Designing tables and optimizing queries to extract maximum performance

This session will also include some benchmarks and Power BI demos  with different DWU and storage options on a very large data set.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66256</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66256</id>
          <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>When Things go Wrong - Error Handling in SQL Server</title>
      <description>In an ideal world, we would not need any error handling, because there would be no errors. But in the real world we need to have error handling in our stored procedures. Error handling in SQL Server is a most confusing topic, because there are such great inconsistencies. But that does not mean that we as database developers can hide our head in the sand.

This presentation starts with a horror show of the many different actions SQL Server can take in case of an error. We will then learn how should deal with this - what we should do and what we should not and that with SET XACT_ABORT we get better consistency. We will learn how TRY-CATCH works in SQL Server, and we will get a recipe for how to write CATCH blocks. More generally, we will learn why it pays off to be simple-minded to survive in this maze. The session mainly looks at traditional T-SQL code, but the session ends with a quick look at natively compiled stored procedures, where everything is different.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66329</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66329</id>
          <name>Andrea Martorana Tusa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI behind the scene: security and user management</title>
      <description>Power BI is a great suite of tools for business analytics and reporting. You use it to create reports and dashboard to deliver insights throughout your company. 
But, what about the new licensing model recently introduced for Power BI? How it can fits to your needs?
Every organization is a complex system with rules and limitations. Users belong to groups each with visibility profile. 
So you need to know how security in Power BI works: how to configure and restrict access, how to filter data based on the logged user, how to implement static and dynamic Row-level security (RLS), how to control usage of specific features. 

Furthermore you deal with a large number of users you can’t leverage by hand. Power BI provides an admin portal that allows you to manage users and groups in the Office 365 admin center. 
Come to this session to discover what’s behind the scenes in Power BI and how to implement a solution compliant to your security and governance model.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>68716</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>68716</id>
          <name>Uwe Ricken</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Are Temporal Tables a useful feature?</title>
      <description>Temporal Tables are a new feature in SQL Server 2016. This session will start with an overview of the basic functionality of Temporal Tables based on a real world scenario. After the core concepts of Temporal Tables have been implemented the session will dive deeper into the functionality of it with all its really great benefits but there is no lunch for free. This session will demonstrate what's not working fine with Temporal Tables and its common drawbacks when you will work with this feature of SQL Server 2016. Fasten seat belts and get an overview of the core concept of Temporal Tables and decide for yourself, whether you would use it or kick it away :)</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64411</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64411</id>
          <name>Alexander Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Playground of cognitive services - Even big kids play here</title>
      <description>Microsoft offers a large playground for young and old with the cognitive services. Here can be tested according to your heart's content which will be maybe tomorrow all in use. With the various building kits such as Bot Framework, Emotion, Face, Text Analytics or Recommendations, to put together in a short time Impressive applications. Come on a little trip with on this playground.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64929</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64929</id>
          <name>Mike Byrd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Change Tracking: A Near Bullet-Proof ETL Synchronization Control</title>
      <description>Change Tracking came out with SQL Server 2008, but SS2012 almost eclipsed it with Change Data Capture. Change Tracking is now the red-headed step child, but in many cases may be the best solution for data ETL movement from an SQL Server OLTP database to a data warehouse or reporting database. This session will provide a review of change tracking syntax and implementation with detailed demos. It will then dive into an actual ETL subset implementation from the AdventureWorks database to a data warehouse solution (modified AdventureWorksDW) with detailed code discussion and demos using TSQL only (no SSIS).</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69673</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69673</id>
          <name>Mohamed Mawla</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL DataFactory for heterogenous data source</title>
      <description>Explore Usage of Azure Datafactory to mesh data from various cloud/On-Premises offerings such as AWS and Google Cloud. Many vendors would have more than one cloud/On-Premises and the want to bring data together. We will explore stategies to connect data from various sources, obstacles, workarounds, trobleshooting and best practices. All hands-on.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69475</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69475</id>
          <name>Håkan Winther</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>GDPR for SQL Server</title>
      <description>What is GDPR, who is affected and how does it affect me as a database professional? This session will explain the general data protection regulation at a high level and how to make SQL Server and Azure SQL Databases compliant to the new regulation. Different techniques like Row level security, data masking, transparent data encryption will be demonstrated.  The session will also cover some basic tools for finding data breaches.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>66963</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>66963</id>
          <name>Nico Jacobs</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <description>Azure Machine Learning plays a central role in Cortana Intelligence: discovering useful patterns in all the collected data is essential in advanced analytics.
To get started with Azure machine learning you don't need to be  an expert: Microsoft provides ready made models that can be used immediately (Cognitive Services). For other business problems (e.g. churn) Microsoft provides a template, but we need to tune this template to our business data. And for some analysis problems we need to build machine learning solutions from scratch.
In this demo-oriented session you will see demonstrations of these three ways of working with Machine Learning in the Azure cloud.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64376</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64376</id>
          <name>Sergiy Lunyakin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL DWH: Tips and Tricks for developers</title>
      <description>Azure SQL DWH is based on MS SQL Server and supports T-SQL. It helps to DB/DWH developers start using it without many efforts. Unfortunately, there are several limitations that could bring difficulties in your job. For example, we can't use MERGE statement for Upsert tasks in DWH, there is no IDENTITY or SEQUENCE, differences in implementing partition switching  and so on. In this session, I'm going to cover several tips and tricks how we can handle with this limitations using available possibilities.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 2:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64825</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64825</id>
          <name>Arne Bartels</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS Custom Pipeline Component</title>
      <description>SSIS custom components can help to reuse code. The session shows step by step to program a custom pipeline component to query directory structures for files and present them as a continuous stream to e.g. FILESTREAM destinations. Only free tools will be used. C# knowledge is helpful.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 3:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 4:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65030</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65030</id>
          <name>Torsten Strauss</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Index Fragmentation</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn the difference between the internal and external index and heap fragmentation and how to detect it.
You will get a deep understanding of the reasons of fragmentation like

-	page split
-	index fill factor
-	ghost record
-	forwarding record
-	heap PFS insert algorithm
-	batch insertions
-	database shrink / auto growth</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64559</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64559</id>
          <name>Stijn Wynants</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Problem Tombola</title>
      <description>During this session we will be having a tombola which contain several SQL Server issues you might face. After a volunteer has picked a problem, we will continue by handling this issue. We will show you how it appears, what impact it has on your performance and the way you are able to solve the issue. The issues inside the tombola will consist out of the most frequent SQL Server issues as seen in the field.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65028</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65028</id>
          <name>Torsten Strauss</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room D</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database tuning advisor vs. database management views</title>
      <description>Tuning your SQL queries is one of the most important task of your daily business but how can we achieve this for existing execution plans?
This session is about the difference of the database tuning advisor and the missing index database management views of the query engine. 
You will learn the limitations of both approaches in order to avoid applying wrong indexes.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65173</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65173</id>
          <name>Alexander Arvidsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Abusing your SQL Server for fun and profit</title>
      <description>SQL and SQL Server has a lot in common with Othello - fairly easy to learn, but takes a lifetime to master. Many times overt abuse is not even necessary - an incorrectly configured database is surprisingly capable of destroying any semblance of performance all by itself. 
The database is very good at doing some things - and exceptionally bad at others. Combine these facts with a general lack of understanding of the database engine and the road to perfomance hell is truly plotted. 
Join Alexander for a session of examples how developers can and do abuse SQL Server - both intentionally and unintentionally.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64468</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64468</id>
          <name>Rudi Bruchez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Discover the new graph features of SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>In this session, we’ll see in detail how to create nodes and edges tables designed for graphs traversal in SQL Server 2017. After a summary of the underlying graph theory and its implementation in databases, we’ll see how to create graph tables in SQL Server 2017, and how to query them with the match operator. This session will give you a kickstart on using graphs in SQL Server 2017.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 4:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>69650</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>69650</id>
          <name>Peter Larsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Idling for Performance?</title>
      <description>When it comes to performance, we often focus on waits and how to solve them.
However, in most cases, solving the real problem with the code, gives you the performance you want.
In this presentation I will show you how to spot the performance blockers.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64367</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64367</id>
          <name>Remko de Boer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room C</name>
      </location>
      <title>Master Data Services: Unknown thus unloved</title>
      <description>Master Data Services (MDS) has been around since SQL 2008, but it's hardly ever used. Mainly because of the unfamiliarity of MDS. MDS can resolve many management issues. And especially with the new features introduced with SQL Server 2016. This session will show the important new features and  several scenario's how MDS can strengthen your BI solutions.</description>
      <startTime>9/23/2017 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/23/2017 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>