<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #596 - Denver - BI Edition 2017</name>
    <startDate>2/25/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>80</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-07:00) Mountain Time (US and Canada)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatDenverBIEdition</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>University Hall - 3rd Floor, University of Denver</name>
      <street>2197 S. University Blvd</street>
      <city>Denver</city>
      <state>Colorado</state>
      <zipcode>80210</zipcode>
      <longitude>-104.960563257337</longitude>
      <latitude>39.676853888297</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14586.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>58263</importID>
      <name>Steve Jones</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Jones is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and has been working with SQL Server since version 4.2 on OS/2. After working as a DBA and developer for a variety of companies, Steve co-founded the community website SQLServerCentral.com in 2001.
Since 2004, Steve has been the full-time editor of the site, ensuring it continues to be a great resource for SQL Server professionals. Over the last decade, Steve has written hundreds of articles about SQL Server for SQLServerCentral.com, SQL Server Standard magazine, SQL Server Magazine, and Database Journal.</description>
      <twitter>way0utwest</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/way0utwest</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.voiceofthedba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=way0utwest</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56543</importID>
      <name>Jonathan Stewart</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jonathan Stewart is a Business Intelligence consultant specializing in data visualization, data warehousing, and data management technologies. An advocate for educating others, he is a public speaker, teacher and blogger, continually teaching people about the Microsoft BI Stack. Since 2000, he has been working in the database field with industry leaders in healthcare, manufacturing, financial, insurance and federal, state and local governments.

Jonathan is very active in the community. He has presented on SQL Server, SSIS, Reporting Services, Power BI and Business Intelligence at numerous SQLSaturday events, local user groups, and conferences throughout the United States and around the world. He participates in webcasts, podcasts, and on</description>
      <twitter>sqllocks</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqllocks/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqllocks.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllocks</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56568</importID>
      <name>Steve Wake</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Wake is currently the Principal BI Developer at Brown and Caldwell and has experience in consulting, advertising, media, manufacturing, retail, charities, telecommunications and financial services organizations using the full on-premises Microsoft BI stack. Recent experience with the Azure services: Analysis Services, Logic Apps,  Data Factory, Databricks, Snowflake and Power BI. Steve is also very involved in the SQL community, speaking at events around the world.</description>
      <twitter>stevewake</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/b5lurker</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.wakebi.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=stevewake</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56605</importID>
      <name>Cher Fox</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cher Fox has 30 years of programming experience, including 25 years in analytics  technical writing, and 15 years specializing in DW  BI in multiple industries.  She has held the corporate positions of Customer Services Manager for an international SW development group, IT Manager for a national risk management company,  is currently the CEO/Principal Consultant of Fox Consulting, a Denver based firm specializing in high level management process re-engineering, DW  BI consulting.  

Ms. Fox is passionate about reverse engineering BI challenges to improve data quality  reliability, improving performance in DW/BI processes as well as automating clients out of spreadsheet madness  time consuming manual processes.</description>
      <twitter>TheDatanista</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cherfox</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://foxconsulting.co</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TheDatanista</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>58254</importID>
      <name>Peter Myers</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Myers is a consultant, trainer and presenter, and has worked with Microsoft database and development products since 1997. Today he specializes in all Microsoft Business Intelligence products and also authors training course content for Microsoft products and services.

He has a broad business background supported by a bachelor’s degree in applied economics and accounting, and he extends this with extensive experience backed by current MCSE certifications. He has been a Data Platform MVP since 2007.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/peterjsmyers</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>58255</importID>
      <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Bossy (MCTS, MCP BI, CBIP) is a data and cloud analytics architect with 25 years of experience in software and database development. As a principal of Datalere, Carlos focuses on developing BI, Data Science, and Advanced Analytics solutions, including modeling data warehouses and delivering predictive models, integration, and visualization. He has developed warehouses and BI solutions for a variety of industries and state agencies, including health insurance, solar energy, foster care, telecom, and manufacturing.</description>
      <twitter>@carlosbossy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin/in/carlosbossy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.carlosbossy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@carlosbossy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>58256</importID>
      <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Bossy (MCTS, MCP BI, CBIP) is a data and cloud analytics architect with 25 years of experience in software and database development. As a principal of Datalere, Carlos focuses on developing BI, Data Science, and Advanced Analytics solutions, including modeling data warehouses and delivering predictive models, integration, and visualization. He has developed warehouses and BI solutions for a variety of industries and state agencies, including health insurance, solar energy, foster care, telecom, and manufacturing.</description>
      <twitter>@carlosbossy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin/in/carlosbossy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.carlosbossy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@carlosbossy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57515</importID>
      <name>Peter Myers</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Myers is a consultant, trainer and presenter, and has worked with Microsoft database and development products since 1997. Today he specializes in all Microsoft Business Intelligence products and also authors training course content for Microsoft products and services.

He has a broad business background supported by a bachelor’s degree in applied economics and accounting, and he extends this with extensive experience backed by current MCSE certifications. He has been a Data Platform MVP since 2007.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/peterjsmyers</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>58262</importID>
      <name>Steve Jones</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Jones is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and has been working with SQL Server since version 4.2 on OS/2. After working as a DBA and developer for a variety of companies, Steve co-founded the community website SQLServerCentral.com in 2001.
Since 2004, Steve has been the full-time editor of the site, ensuring it continues to be a great resource for SQL Server professionals. Over the last decade, Steve has written hundreds of articles about SQL Server for SQLServerCentral.com, SQL Server Standard magazine, SQL Server Magazine, and Database Journal.</description>
      <twitter>way0utwest</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/way0utwest</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.voiceofthedba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=way0utwest</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57772</importID>
      <name>Melissa Coates</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Melissa Coates is a data architect with a background in data warehousing and business intelligence. Her current professional focus is enterprise-level Power BI governance, deployment, security, and administration. As the owner of Coates Data Strategies, Melissa produces training and consults to help companies strengthen and sustain their data-driven initiatives. Melissa is big supporter of the technical community, and has been a Microsoft Data Platform MVP since 2013. You can visit Melissa's website at CoatesDataStrategies.com, which includes community resources like diagrams, blogs, and videos.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/SQLChick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/melissacoatesprofile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.CoatesDataStrategies/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/SQLChick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>56568</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56568</id>
          <name>Steve Wake</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Small</name>
      </location>
      <title>Date Dimension: One Script for All</title>
      <description>All data warehouses need a date and time dimension to enable proper analysis across time. Most data warehouse designers use one that is provided by tools or create one in Excel. But what if you need to set up custom holidays or want different calendars, such as Fiscal or Julian? You can have any date and time dimension you need by using a single SQL script that can be modified and rerun as necessary. Learn what it takes to design a date and time dimension that does all the calculations and formatting up front so that reports are easier to create. A sample script is provided; it creates the date and time dimensions and can be reused as often as necessary without breaking your data warehouse--and it takes only seconds to run!</description>
      <startTime>2/25/2017 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/25/2017 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57515</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57515</id>
          <name>Peter Myers</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Large</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning: From Design to Integration</title>
      <description>Machine Learning is a subfield of computer science concerned with systems that learn from data. So this isn’t about systems that follow explicitly programmed instructions, but rather about systems that find patterns and trends within datasets, and use them to deliver insight and predictions.

In this session, you will learn how an Azure Machine Learning solution comes to life: From the creation of a workspace, to the preparation of data, to experimentation with Machine Learning algorithms, and then finally to the integration and embedding of predictive insights into applications.

This session has been specifically designed to describe Machine Learning fundamentals, and to help enable and inspire existing data professionals taking their first steps to leverage cloud-based predictive models delivered with Azure Machine Learning. It is guaranteed to thrill you with potential, and excite you with the relative ease by which it can be accomplished.</description>
      <startTime>2/25/2017 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/25/2017 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>58256</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>58256</id>
          <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Thoughtful Track</track>
      <location>
        <name>Large</name>
      </location>
      <title>Business Intelligence Overview - Architecture and Management</title>
      <description>Business Intelligence is an essential component for any business today and a successful BI implementation has the power to change the way your organization functions.  In this non-technical session industry consultants and leaders, including Matt Smith from EMC, Shannon Holck from NCM, Marc Beacom of Datalere, and consultant Carlos Bossy  will show you what their current BI projects are all about.  This session will cover the purpose of the projects, the tools being used, the makeup of the team, and the architecture being implemented.  This session will show you to define the success of a BI implementation, and how to evaluate your BI  Analytical Strategy.  You should leave this session with better knowledge of how to plan, build and deploy effective Business Intelligence solutions.</description>
      <startTime>2/25/2017 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/25/2017 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>58255</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>58255</id>
          <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Thoughtful Track</track>
      <location>
        <name>Large</name>
      </location>
      <title>Practical Data Science using R and SQL</title>
      <description>The practice of Data Science has arrived and as data professionals we're on the forefront of this change. The data we collect can now be used in new and exciting ways, providing more value than ever before. To get started in this field, a number of tools and methodologies must be employed to help you achieve predictive analytics success with your data. In this session, Jeff Renz will start by providing an introduction to R, the defacto programming language for data scientists.  Carlos Bossy will then cover predictive analytics using R, providing a practical understanding of what it takes to develop your own predictive models. The session includes an overview of definitions, concepts and terminology, successful applications of predictive analytics, and how predictive analytics fits into a BI environment.</description>
      <startTime>2/25/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/25/2017 3:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>58262</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>58262</id>
          <name>Steve Jones</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Technical Track</track>
      <location>
        <name>Small</name>
      </location>
      <title>Lunch</title>
      <description>Lunch on your own in the DU area.</description>
      <startTime>2/25/2017 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/25/2017 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56605</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56605</id>
          <name>Cher Fox</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Small</name>
      </location>
      <title>Test Automation: Agile Enablement for DW and BI Teams</title>
      <description>Test automation is one of several key technical enablement practices that allows data warehouse and  business intelligence teams to be more successful in their agile journeys. While there are lots of test practices and automation tools out there for software development teams to leverage, very few are targeted to data-related development and testing. Agile analytics practitioner Lynn Winterboer and DW/BI architect Cher Fox will share essential agile test foundations and data-focused test automation technologies to help data warehousing and business intelligence teams get a leg up on this important agile practice, including a demo of how this works!</description>
      <startTime>2/25/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>58263</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>58263</id>
          <name>Steve Jones</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Thoughtful Track</track>
      <location>
        <name>Large</name>
      </location>
      <title>Lunch</title>
      <description>Lunch on your own in the DU area. Take advantage of the time to network with someone new and spend an hour sharing a meal.</description>
      <startTime>2/25/2017 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/25/2017 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56543</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56543</id>
          <name>Jonathan Stewart</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Large</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Visualization:  How to truly tell a great story!</title>
      <description>We have more information available to us today than ever before.  So much so that we run the risk of not being able to tell concise stories.  There's a lot more to creating that story than just getting the correct information.  Come learn not just the do's and don'ts, but the whys…</description>
      <startTime>2/25/2017 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/25/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>58254</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>58254</id>
          <name>Peter Myers</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Technical Track</track>
      <location>
        <name>Small</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI for the Developer</title>
      <description>This session covers the Power BI REST API, Power BI Embedded, Custom Visuals, and Stream Analytics.</description>
      <startTime>2/25/2017 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/25/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>