<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #688 - Istanbul 2017</name>
    <startDate>11/4/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>
    </timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatistanbul</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Turkey</name>
      <street>Bellevue Residences, Levent Mahallesi, Aydin Sokak, No7, Levent, Istanbul</street>
      <city>Istanbul</city>
      <state>Istanbul, Turkey</state>
      <zipcode>34340</zipcode>
      <longitude>29.0205434</longitude>
      <latitude>41.0679766</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69689</importID>
      <name>Daron Yondem</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Daron is a Microsoft Regional Director and an Azure MVP. He is a regular speaker at international conferences focusing on Microservices, Serverless and IoT. Daron currently works as a CTO in XOMNI Inc, a cloud company building PAAS offerings for retailers and XOGO where they are building a decision signage platform.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/daronyondem</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/daronyondem/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://daron.me</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/daronyondem</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69734</importID>
      <name>İbrahim Kıvanç</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ibrahim KIVANC is Software Development Engineer at Microsoft, CSE (Commerical Software Engineering) delivers programs ensuring latest Microsoft technologies and platforms are accessible and implemented. Prior to this role he was responsible for Middle East and Africa HQ over 4 years. After that worked in Microsoft Turkey for 2 years and now he's covering Microsoft Middle East region. He is responsible with the latest development technologies at Microsoft.
 
Ibrahim received his bachelor' degree in Computer Engineering and holds a master's degree in Management and Infromation System with his thesis on "Cross Platform Development Strategies for Enterprise Companies" . He's also a former Microsoft Student Partner and winner of Imagine Cup in</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/ikivanc</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ibrahimkivanc/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ibrahimkivanc.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/ikivanc</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69524</importID>
      <name>Ozgur Ozluk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Associate Prof. Ozgur Ozluk obtained his Ph.D. in Operations Research from UNC Chapel Hill in 1999. Thereafter, he spent three years in Silicon Valley working for the revenue management division of Manugistics, Inc. He taught courses on Data Analytics at San Francisco State University between 2003 and 2014, in addition to several executive MBA courses and workshops/seminars in companies such as Gap, Banana Republic. In Fall 2014, he founded the Big Data Analytics and Management program at Bahçeşehir University. In Fall 2015, he  started a predictive analytics enterprise, Verite Analytics.  Now, he is the director of the Big Data Analytics Masters program at MEF  University.</description>
      <twitter>@OzgurOzluk</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@OzgurOzluk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69731</importID>
      <name>Levent Oktar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Before Microsoft Levent has worked for several Microsoft Partners and Government Offices as Database Administrator and Systems Engineer. He has worked on Database Migration Projects, SQL Server Database Systems Design and Architecture and HA/DR Projects for Government Offices. He#39;s been working at Microsoft Customer Services and Support Team as Support Engineer and Senior Premier Field Engineer since 2010.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69341</importID>
      <name>Sinem Oğuz Körpüz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Big Data Engineer in Hürriyet since December 2015. Previosly worked in Turkcell as BI/Data Consultant.
Graduated from Bahcesehir University with double degrees; Maths  Computer Science and Computer Engineering 
Had Data Analytics Master's degree in Sabanci University.
Dreamer.Wanderlust.Cycling and Sailing fan. Animal lover.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sinemoguz/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69490</importID>
      <name>Tuna Çakar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tuna Çakar graduated from Biological Sciences and Bioengineering Program of Sabancı University in 2004. He has worked on the 3-D modelling of proteins with perturbation technique in his undergraduate thesis project. He received his master's degree from Cognitive Science Program at Boğaziçi University in 2009. Çakar obtained his Ph.D. from Cognitive Science Program at the Informatics Institute in Middle East Technical University in 2015. In his thesis, he has worked on the identity judgments and he performed several different models including mathematical, neurophysiological (EEG/ERP, optic brain imaging) and biometrics (Eye-tracker) in order to understand the decision-making processes at various levels.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tuna-%C3%A7akar-819b3b26/?ppe=1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69320</importID>
      <name>Emrah Uslu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Emrah Uslu is currently working as DX (Developer Experience) Lead at PeakUp Information Technologies. My business areas includes Cloud Solutions, IoT Solutions, chatbots and advanced analytics

I have a bachelor degree in Statistic from Hacettepe University. I've been named as Microsoft MVP last four consecutive years.

Before PeakUp, worked as a freelance senior software developer, consultant and trainer for 1 year. In this time frame, I completed 4 enterprise level web projects, 2 advanced software training and finished an architectural consultancy.

He worked as a manager of software department in TCM until April 2016. Before joining TCM, I worked for 4 companies -Microsoft Turkey, Turkuvaz Group, Netron Technology and Dogan Holdin</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/usluemrah23</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/emrahuslu/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.emrahuslu.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/usluemrah23</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69512</importID>
      <name>Altan Cakir</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Altan Çakır received his M.Sc. degree in theoretical particle physics from Iztech in 2006 and then went straight as a to graduate school at the Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, Germany, from which he earned a Ph.D. in experimental high energy and particle physics in 2010. During his Ph.D., he was responsible for a scientific research based on new physics searches in the CMS detector at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) at European Nuclear Research Laboratory (CERN). Thereafter he was granted as a post-doctoral research fellow at Deutsches Elektronen-Synchotron (DESY), a national nuclear research center in Hamburg, Germany where he spent roughly 6 years, and then recently got his present faculty position at ITU.</description>
      <twitter>@altan_cakir</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://tr.linkedin.com/in/altan-cakir-11446446</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://akademi.itu.edu.tr/cakirmua/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@altan_cakir</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69324</importID>
      <name>Ismail Adar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ismail Adar, Computer Engineer, Microsoft Certified Trainer, MCSE and MCSA. Focused on the SQL Server relational engine at performance troubleshooting, OLTP scalability and defining and implementing reliable high availability environments. Also Author of quot;SQL Server 2012 Programming and Administrationquot; and quot;Data Warehouse Desing with SQL Server Interation Servicequot;</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ismailadar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69462</importID>
      <name>Faruk Celik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Faruk is working as Senior Support Escalation Engineer in Microsoft Support SQL BI team since 2006. He's expert on Data Access layer components and technologies developed by Microsoft.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/faruk_celik_</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/farukc</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.msdn.com/farukcelik</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/faruk_celik_</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69702</importID>
      <name>Ahmet KALAFAT</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working in Information Technologies for about 18 years. 4.5 years of training, 5.5 years of software development, and then I have been working in the business intelligence for the last 8 years. I took part in the team that developed the first microsoft fast track data warehouse in Turkey. Then, I made 2 datawarehouse upgrade project. Our team developt of the largest MS OLAP cube in Turkey. I developed etl framework for dwh data collection processing and managing olap cube. I am responsible for Businnes Intelligence Development Team(7 developer).</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmet-kalafat-b4bb6b59/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69740</importID>
      <name>Yavuz Filizlibay</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working in the sector for 17 years. I am a consultant and trainer on Sql Server. I also write articles about Sql Server and give seminars.</description>
      <twitter>@yavuzfilizlibay</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.yavuzfilizlibay.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@yavuzfilizlibay</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69484</importID>
      <name>Zeynep Akin Sahin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>2008 Yıldız teknik üniversitesi -Bİlgisayar teknolojileri ve programcılığı
2013 Beykent üniversitesi Endüstri mühendisliği
10 yıldır profesyonel hayat içerisinde bulunup son 5 yıldır Koçsistem'de kıdemli iş zekası danışmanı olarak çalışmaktayım.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69303</importID>
      <name>Mustafa Acungil</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mustafa Acungil had been working on data since 2001. He is an expert on SQL Server, Business Intelligence, and Machine Learning.
As a trainer, consultant, and manager he has been working in Bilgeadam for more than 10 years.
He is also a writer and last title he has published is 24 Kariyer Tuzağı. (http://www.dr.com.tr/Kitap/24-Kariyer-Tuzagi/Egitim-Basvuru/Is-Ekonomi-Hukuk/Yonetim-Is-Gelistirme-Kalite/urunno=0001693784001)</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/acungil</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/acungil/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.linkedin.com/today/author/acungil</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/acungil</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69496</importID>
      <name>Yalcin Gulas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SQL Server DBA 
Working on SQL Server from versions 6.0 to SQL 14 
Experienced on mixed environments , Consolidation, datawarehouse FastTrack</description>
      <twitter>ygulas</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://tr.linkedin.com/pub/yalcin-gulas/7/b3a/334/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ygulas</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69321</importID>
      <name>Selçuk USTA</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I'm a Technical Team Lead at Hurriyet.com.tr

I am responsible for developing and supporting infrastructure of web applications which Hürriyet products. As a Scrum Master, I developed coding standards, test plans, review processes, sprint planning, integration and deployment life-cyles.

I've recently graduated from Okan University, Institute of Science with degree in Computer Engineering. I have 8 years experience on different compaines such as Bilge Adam, Lynx S.p.A, Hürriyet.</description>
      <twitter>ustasoglu</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/selcukusta/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://medium.com/@selcukusta</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ustasoglu</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69344</importID>
      <name>Abdullah ALTINTAŞ</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Abdullah Altıntaş currently works at Bilge Adam Corporate Solutions as Solution Architect and he is Team Leader of “Data Management and Productivity Solutions”.
 
Altıntaş shares about recent technological developments and his corporate experiences by trainings, seminars, and technical articles. He has MCT, MCSE (DPamp;BI) certificates.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://tr.linkedin.com/pub/abdullah-altintas/62/23a/553</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.abdullahaltintas.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69699</importID>
      <name>Erdem Avni SELÇUK</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Since 1999, I have been working in software and IT sector with the effort of being as efficient and valuable in production and designing the necessity and need collaboration of time and management of the ordering and offering.   
I am continuing giving briefs, sharing data and establishing and working as a key speaker at Universities and local groups on SharePoint and software.</description>
      <twitter>@eravse</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://tr.linkedin.com/in/eravse</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.eravse.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@eravse</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>69737</importID>
      <name>Pelin Atici</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>https://tr.linkedin.com/in/pelin-atıcı-1b965253</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://tr.linkedin.com/in/pelin-atici-1b965253</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
</GuidebookXML>