<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #337 - Oregon 2014</name>
    <startDate>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-06:00) Saskatchewan</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatOregon</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Mittleman Community Center</name>
      <street>6651 SW Capitol Highway</street>
      <city>Portland</city>
      <state>Oregon</state>
      <zipcode>97219</zipcode>
      <longitude>-122.704406</longitude>
      <latitude>45.476885</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>70</importID>
      <name>Tegile Systems</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.tegile.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/SQLSaturday/EventSponsors/Tegile_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>85</importID>
      <name>Pyramid Analytics</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.PyramidAnalytics.com</url>
      <imageURL>http://pages.pyramidanalytics.com/rs/pyramidanalytics/images/logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>80</importID>
      <name>DH2i</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.dh2i.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://dh2i.com/images/DH2i_Logo_SQLSat_170x60.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1066</importID>
      <name>SolarWinds</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.solarwinds.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/956/EventSponsor_14566.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>13</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/sqlsaturday/eventsponsors/Quest_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1355</importID>
      <name>SolidQ</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.solidq.com/es</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/921/EventSponsor_14422.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1033</importID>
      <name>Serverlogic</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.serverlogic.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.serverlogic.com/sites/default/files/styles/panopoly_image_original/public/serverlogic-logo-170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>89</importID>
      <name>Profisee</name>
      <label>Venue/Badging</label>
      <url>http://www.profisee.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.profisee.com/Portals/0/lp/assets/img/logo_profisee.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>7</importID>
      <name>SIOS Technology</name>
      <label>Morning Refreshments</label>
      <url>http://us.sios.com/company/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/956/EventSponsor_14655.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>7</importID>
      <name>SIOS Technology</name>
      <label>Afternoon Refreshments</label>
      <url>http://us.sios.com/company/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/956/EventSponsor_14655.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Reception</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>869</importID>
      <name>MSSQLTips</name>
      <label>In-Kind</label>
      <url>http://www.mssqltips.com/index.asp</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/e507d990-c152-464a-98f0-a5e6eb75d319.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>343</importID>
      <name>Widmer Brothers Brewing</name>
      <label>In-Kind</label>
      <url>http://widmerbrothers.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/files/1abc1a06-8a17-445a-a8ad-0d5d877aab50.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9796</importID>
      <name>Argenis Fernandez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Argenis is a Principal Architect at Pure Storage. He works with customers around the world to make sure they don’t have to worry much about their infrastructure for Data.
He is a former Data Platform MVP, former VMware vExpert, Microsoft Certified Master, and more recently worked in the Microsoft Azure Data/SQL Server engineering team as a Principal PM in the Tiger team.</description>
      <twitter>DBArgenis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/argenis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.purestorage.com/author/argenisfernandez/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBArgenis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27431</importID>
      <name>Victor Isakov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Victor Isakov (MCA, MCM, MCSM, MCT, MVP) is a Database Architect and trainer who provides consulting and training services to various organizations in the public, private, and NGO sectors globally. He regularly speaks at international conferences such as Microsoft TechEd/Ignite, PASS Summit, IT/Dev Connections, and SQLSaturdays.
Victor has written a number of books on SQL Server and has worked with Microsoft to develop the SQL Server exams and certification. In 2017 he authored "Exam Ref 70-764 Administering a SQL Database Infrastructure (1st Edition)".
He is one of only three non-Microsoft, Microsoft Certified Architects in the world.</description>
      <twitter>@victorisakov</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/victorisakov</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.victorisakov.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@victorisakov</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15861</importID>
      <name>Jason Horner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hi, my name is Jason. I spend most of my day helping clients solve business problems mostly in the Data and Advanced Analytics spaces. Sometimes this involves various and sundry cloud technologies including Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Data Lake Store, Azure Databricks, HDInsight and Azure SQL Database. I'm fluent in several languages including: SQL, C#, Python, and PowerShell.

I'm a Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server (MCM) and have been recognized for my technical excellence and evangelism efforts by Microsoft by being awarded the Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for the last 5+ years.

In my off hours I like to snowboard, karaoke, ride roller coasters, and play arcade games</description>
      <twitter>jasonhorner</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonhorner</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.jasonhorner.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jasonhorner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19012</importID>
      <name>Leila Etaati</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leila Etaati is the First Microsoft AI MVP in New Zealand and Australia, as well as a Data Platform MVP. She has a Ph.D. from the University of Auckland and is the co-director and data scientist in RADACAD company with many clients around the world. Additionally, she is the co-organizer of Microsoft Business Intelligence and Power BI Use group in Auckland with more than 1300 members. Leila has also co-organized 3 main conferences in Auckland: SQL Saturday Auckland (from 2015), Difinity (from 2017) and Global AI Bootcamp. She is a data scientist, BI consultant, trainer, and speaker. She is a well-known International speaker to many conferences such as MS Ignite, SQL PASS, Data Platform Summit, SQL Saturday, Power BI World Tour and in Europe, USA, Asia, Australia, and NZ. She has over 10 years’ experience with databases and software systems. Leila is an active Technical Microsoft AI blogger in RADACAD.</description>
      <twitter>@leila_etaati</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://nz.linkedin.com/pub/leila-etaati/36/46/b03</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.radacad.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@leila_etaati</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>8780</importID>
      <name>Reza Rad</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reza Rad is a Microsoft Regional Director, MVP, author, trainer, speaker and consultant. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP for nine years from 2011.
Reza wrote many books on Power BI subjects including the Power BI from Rookie to Rock Star, and Pro Power BI Architecture.
Reza is the invited speaker at the world's well-known conferences such as Microsoft Ignite, Microsoft Business Applications Summit, Ignite Tour, PASS Summit, and many other conferences.
Reza is an active blogger and writes regularly about Power BI at https://radacad.com.</description>
      <twitter>Rad_Reza</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nz.linkedin.com/in/rezarad/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://radacad.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Rad_Reza</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27378</importID>
      <name>Vern Rabe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vern Rabe is an independent SQL Server consultant and contract trainer in Portland, OR, and leader of the Oregon Data Community user group, formerly OregonSQL. He has attained MCSE, MCITP (both Administration and Development), and MCT certifications, among others. Vern has been passionate about databases since 1992 and has worked with SQL Server since version 4.21a. He provides broad technical SQL Server knowledge gained from the mixture of academic and practical experiences acquired from his classroom instructing and varied consulting contracts. Vern regularly presents technical sessions at SQL Server user group meetings, SQLSaturdays, and PASS Summit.</description>
      <twitter>@VernRabe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/vern-rabe/a/ba3/980</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.rabedata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@VernRabe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9856</importID>
      <name>Thomas Norman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tom Norman is a Database Architect at KPA with a strong fervor to protect data. He works daily to review and improve data protection methodologies while reviewing governing laws affecting finance, healthcare, and personal data. His areas of expertise include encryption, auditing, data identification, and database object deployment. He is the current leader of the PASS Virtualization Group and Vice President of the TRIPASS user group. You can read his blog at https://armordba.com/ and reach him on twitter at @armordba. Tom speaks at a number of SQLSaturday events and SQL Server user groups.</description>
      <twitter>ArmorDba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armordba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://armordba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ArmorDba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12804</importID>
      <name>David Eichner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Eichner is a licensed CPA and is also CEO of ICAN Software Corporation, a Microsoft Dynamics amp; Acumatica ERP partner firm that sell and implements ERP and CRM software, develops software solutions and provides technology consulting.  He is the host of a radio show called Business In The Cloud that airs weekly on KLAY 1180AM.  He is skilled in building integrated cloud app solutions. His career spans more than 20 years in various technical/managerial positions within industries as diverse as military service,  engineering/construction, municipal government, consulting and certified public accounting.  Additionally, he holds various national certificates in technology (MCDBA, MCSE, CNE, CITP, Dynamics CRM and ERP, Acumatica CRM and ERP)</description>
      <twitter>@ICANSoftware</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/icansoftware</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ICANSoftware</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21729</importID>
      <name>Sebastian Meine</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sebastian Meine, Ph.D. is the SQL Stylist behind sqlity.net llc. In 2010 he founded sqlity.net to fully engage in his passion for SQL Server.
Armed with a Ph.D. in Computer Science and years of experience in architecting DBs for a global Fortune 50 company, Sebastian now provides training and consulting services for his clients, specializing in SQL Server Security, Test Driven Development and Performance. Sebastian is an experienced public speaker, published author, president of the Philly PASS Chapter, PASS Regional Mentor and coauthor  lead developer of tSQLt.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlity</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sebastianmeine</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlity.net/en/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlity</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18445</importID>
      <name>Kathi Kellenberger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kathi Kellenberger is the editor of Simple Talk at Redgate and a Data Platform MVP. She has worked with SQL Server for over 20 years and has authored, co-authored, or tech edited over a dozen technical books. Kathi is the co-leader of the PASS Women in Technology Virtual Group and a volunteer at LaunchCode. When Kathi isn’t working, she enjoys spending time with family and friends, cycling, singing, and climbing the stairs of tall buildings. Be sure to check out her courses on Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>auntkathi</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kathikellenberger</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://auntkathisql.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=auntkathi</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24859</importID>
      <name>David Moutray</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Database Administrator with five years experience in database design, business intelligence, application development, performance tuning and day-to-day administration with SQL Server.  Experience covers administration of both transactional and data-warehouse databases, application development and database design for business applications.  Certifications include MCITP Database Administrator and Developer.  Passionate about database security and promoting data integrity through rock-solid database design and good development practices.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15120</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo is co-founder and RD lead of perFact BV, a Dutch company that improves analysis methods and develops computer-aided tools to generate completely functional applications from the analysis deliverable. The platform for this development is SQL Server. In his spare time, Hugo likes to share and enhance his knowledge of SQL Server by frequenting newsgroups and forums, reading and writing books and blogs, and attending and speaking at conferences.
Hugo is also a SQL Server MVP since 2006.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27353</importID>
      <name>Damu Venkatesan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Damu Venkatesan is a Business Intelligence Consultant with over 25 years of IT experience including architecting and implementing BI/DW solutions  using Microsoft SQL Server, PDW, SSIS, SSAS, SSRS, and Power BI. He  has been speaking at many SQL Saturdays and user groups on data analytics and is actively involved in the Atlanta SQL community for several years. He has successfully delivered several BI/DW solutions and data migrations to various clients. He is also currently serving as President of DAMA Georgia chapter in Atlanta.  He is the co-organizer of BI SQL Saturday in Atlanta.</description>
      <twitter>@vdamu</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/damuvenkatesan/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@vdamu</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22246</importID>
      <name>Piotr Palka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Piotr Palka has been working with high volume data processing systems since 1999. Piotr implemented and maintained multiple systems for telecommunication companies, including call records processing, billing and customer relationship management and operation support systems. Now he is lead data warehouse developer for Washington State Department of Corrections. He regularly delivers technical presentations at Olympia, WA, PASS chapter.</description>
      <twitter>@PiotrPalka</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@PiotrPalka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10600</importID>
      <name>Bob Pusateri</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Pusateri is a Microsoft Certified Master, DBA, and systems architect with over 10 years of experience on SQL Server. His interests involve internals, performance optimization, and cloud technologies. He is an active member of two Chicago-area PASS Local Groups, a community speaker, and maintains a web presence through both Twitter (@SQLBob) and his blog (bobpusateri.com).</description>
      <twitter>@SQLBob</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/bobpusateri</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.BobPusateri.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLBob</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21393</importID>
      <name>Neil Hambly</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Neil Hambly is a SQL Server consultant, founder and consultant at Datamovements, a Gold Microsoft Data  Analytics Consulting company.
Neil has 20+ years in a variety of SQL Server roles and is an MCT. He is a regular presenter (200+ events) at user groups, and PASS events, including PASS Summit and SQLSaturday, and many UK events (SQLBits, SQLRelay). Neil is the leader of PASS London (UK), a Professional Development VC, a Melissa Data MVP, and a SQL Cruise Technical Lead, who loves Guinness, whisky, and dancing.</description>
      <twitter>Neil_Hambly</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://uk.linkedin.com/in/neilhambly</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataidol.com/NeilHambly</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Neil_Hambly</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20617</importID>
      <name>Mike Tutor</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mike Tutor has been in the IT industry for over 30 years. He has worn many hats, including developer, systems admin, and project manager, but he has worked almost exclusively as a SQL Server DBA since the late 90s. He has worked as a development DBA in the medical research industry for many years, but is currently working as a Sr. consultant at SQL Solutions Group in Lehi UT.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlsolutionsgroup.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10286</importID>
      <name>Ben Miller</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben has been a member of the SQL Server Community since 2000. He loves a challenge and has fixed many SQL Servers and helped hundreds of people get more out of their DBA jobs.  He is a Data Platform MVP a SQL Server Certified Master (MCM). He has worked at various companies throughout the USA, as well as at Microsoft for 7 years. He is passionate about SQL Server Infrastructure, High Availability, Automation and Integration using SMO and PowerShell. He teaches DBAs how to use PowerShell to do their job and teaches SQL Server Internals. He is @DBAduck all around the web (Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, Blog) so let's catch up.</description>
      <twitter>DBAduck</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/dbaduck/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbaduck.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAduck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24948</importID>
      <name>Phil Robinson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Phil Robinson is an independent consultant focused on developing Business Intelligence solutions using Microsoft Reporting Services and Power BI. He is founder of the San Diego SQL Business Intelligence Group and co-founder of SQL Saturday – San Diego.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16847</importID>
      <name>Jimmy May</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jimmy May is a Principal Architect in Microsoft IT. He's formerly a Senior Program Manager for the SQL Server Customer Advisory Team (SQL CAT) where he managed the Customer Lab which hosts the biggest, fastest,  most interesting SQL Server apps from all over the world. He is a Microsoft Certified Master (MCM). Visit his SQL Server performance  personal productivity blog at http://blogs.msdn.com/jimmymay. Jimmy tweets at www.twitter.com/aspiringgeek.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/jimmy_may</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23350</importID>
      <name>Rob Volk</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob Volk is a SQL Server DBA in the Metro Atlanta area since 2001. He also moderates and answers the forums on SQLTeam.com. While an old-time cranky DBA, he no longer considers quot;business intelligencequot; an oxymoron or quot;the cloudquot; as merely atmospheric moisture, and is delightedly dipping his toes into both of these new oceans, and loves to do things in new and and unusual ways.</description>
      <twitter>sql_r</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rob-volk-134ba81</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/robv/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sql_r</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22286</importID>
      <name>Prakash Heda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Prakash Heda works as Manager (Data-IT) at SSC Advent. His expertise encompasses the work of automation, performance tuning/troubleshooting, high availability, san configuration and windows administration.  Heda has 13+ years of experience managing enterprise-wide data needs in both high volume transactional and data warehouse environments. Heda holds certifications for MCDBA and MCITP. His background includes administration  development using VB/ASP/SSIS with SQL server 2000 to 2017. He is an active member of PASS, SQLSaturday, and as well a frequent presenter at user groups, SQLSaturdays, and other community events. He is also an avid tweeter, blogger and runner.</description>
      <twitter>@prakashheda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/prakash-heda/8/a60/b77</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlfeatures.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@prakashheda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10696</importID>
      <name>Brandon Leach</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A Microsoft Data Platform MVP, Brandon manages the DB Operations team for financial company x. With a data estate of several petabytes, he puts a high focus on performance tuning and automation. He is a frequent speaker at events like conferences and user groups.</description>
      <twitter>SQLServerNerd</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlservernerd</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLServerNerd</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20406</importID>
      <name>Mickey Stuewe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mickey Stuewe has been working with SQL Server since 6.5. That gives her over 20 years of experience. She has not only been a database developer, but also an application developer, even before Visual Studio existed. She is now thankful to be focusing on database design, t-SQL development, and query optimization. She also has a habit of enjoying SSIS and data warehouse design.

She blogs regularly on her website mickeystuewe.com and contributes to sites such as SQL Server Central and SQL Server Pro. She enjoys presenting at PASS Summit, SQL Saturdays, User Groups and other events.

When she is not immersed in SQL related activities, she enjoys action movies, art, reading, and laughing. She laughs loudly and often...just ask her children.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLMickey</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/mickeystuewe/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.MickeyStuewe.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLMickey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19733</importID>
      <name>Martin Cairney</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Martin has 20 years’ experience in SQL Server technologies. His experience spans both the Database Engine and infrastructure requirements, and Data Warehousing and BI implementations. 
He has worked across many industry sectors including London’s global financial institutions and both State and Federal Government Departments. 
He is a SQL Server MVP, MCT and an experienced conference presenter, having presented at PASS Summit, SQLBits, and SQL Saturday events and User Groups round the world</description>
      <twitter>martin_cairney</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://au.linkedin.com/in/martincairney</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=martin_cairney</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25719</importID>
      <name>Steve Wake</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Wake is currently the Principal BI Developer at Brown and Caldwell and has experience in consulting, advertising, media, manufacturing, retail, charities, telecommunications and financial services organizations using the full on-premises Microsoft BI stack. Recent experience with the Azure services: Analysis Services, Logic Apps,  Data Factory, Databricks, Snowflake and Power BI. Steve is also very involved in the SQL community, speaking at events around the world.</description>
      <twitter>stevewake</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/b5lurker</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.wakebi.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=stevewake</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34788</importID>
      <name>Michael Fal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mike is a specialist in data management technologies. As a community advocate, public speaker, and blogger, Mike is a practicing thought leader for data and automation. He is passionate about DevOps and data, building platforms to optimize, protect, and use data efficiently.

Since 1999, Mike has been working in the database field, focusing primarily on SQL Server and specializes in automating data solutions to improve the reliability and efficiency of his environments. He has been caught playing trombone in public on more than one occasion.</description>
      <twitter>@Mike_Fal</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelfal/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mikefal.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Mike_Fal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26992</importID>
      <name>Tom Roush</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tom is a master storyteller, known to translate Geek into plain English in a single bound. His wry sense of humor, life experiences and vivid descriptions are skillfully combined with his expertise as a DBA to have you understanding SQL in ways you never thought you would. Tom’s explanations of why to do something are insightful, why *not* to do something enlightening, and the stories behind them, both tech and non-tech, will leave you laughing to the point you forget you’re learning something. </description>
      <twitter>@geeql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/tomroush</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.geeql.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@geeql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11203</importID>
      <name>Carlos L Chacon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Chacon is the managing partner of SQL Data Partners LLC and co-host of the popular SQL Data Partners Podcast.  While getting his start as a typical accidental DBA, Carlos has sat on Microsoft exam review panels, served as regional mentor and chapter leader.  He enjoys traveling and has been to four continents, speaks Spanish and can eat his weight in raspberries (not yet proven).  He and his family live in Richmond, Virginia.</description>
      <twitter>@CarlosLChacon</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/carloslchacon</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldatapartners.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@CarlosLChacon</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17158</importID>
      <name>John McAllister</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John McAllister co-founded Stratature, an Independent MDM software vendor, in 2001. Following Microsoft’s acquisition of Stratature in 2007 John served as Group Program Manager for MDS and oversaw the incorporation of MDM into SQL Server. John now serves as the Regional Sales Director for Profisee, Inc. which provides enterprise-class MDM Solutions built on top of Microsoft’s MDS offering. John has worked with 100’s of organizations around the world in all phases of MDM projects. </description>
      <twitter>@jmcallis64</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/johnbmcallister</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.profisee.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@jmcallis64</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17519</importID>
      <name>Josh Fennessy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Josh Fennessy, Solution Architect at BlueGranite, has been building solutions with the SQL Server BI stack for 8 years. He is a Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert in Business Intelligence. Josh#39;s passions include manipulating data in novel ways to open analytic possibilities not before possible.

Josh is active in the SQL Server and Open Source communities. Beyond relational and OLAP data projects, Josh is also involved in projects using cluster computing platforms such as Hadoop.</description>
      <twitter>@joshuafennessy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuafennessy/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.joshuafennessy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@joshuafennessy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16925</importID>
      <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Koesmarno, MCSE Data Platform, and MCSE Business Intelligence, MCT, is a Senior Program Manager at Microsoft, with a Bachelor’s degree in IT. She has over 10 years of experience working with SQL Server for large-scale and multi-million-dollar OLTP and ETL projects as a SQL Server developer and system analyst/designer. Her past projects include delivering a SQL Server 2012 data warehouse and BI solutions in the US and Australia. She now works with hybrid, cloud and on-prem SQL projects.</description>
      <twitter>@mssqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliekoesmarno</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mssqlgirl.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mssqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34744</importID>
      <name>Mark Tabladillo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Tabladillo Ph.D. works for Microsoft as a Cloud Solution Architect for the US CTO Customer Success Team.  He has a science doctorate from Georgia Tech.  Based in Atlanta, GA, Mark provides cloud enterprise solutions for companies in the US for Microsoft's strategic clients. He is a chapter leader for the PASS Data Science virtual chapter. </description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/MarkTabNet</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marktab</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://marktab.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/MarkTabNet</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26889</importID>
      <name>Theresa Iserman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Theresa Iserman is a SQL Server Premier Field Engineer at Microsoft.  She’s been working with databases for over 15 years and has held roles working with transactional amp; data warehouse systems, web application development, amp; technical project management. Theresa tweets at www.twitter.com/theresaiserman
</description>
      <twitter>@TheresaIserman</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/theresaiserman/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TheresaIserman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11168</importID>
      <name>Carl Berglund</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carl Berglund has 20+ years of experience helping businesses source and implement sophisticated datacenter infrastructures. Carl has held senior business development roles at HP and PolyServe, where he helped drive enterprise organizations’ SQL Server consolidation, virtualization and optimization projects. As a technology evangelist, Carl helps organizations reduce spend on overall SQL Server lifecycle costs while reducing risk. He is a regular speaker and author on Windows datacenter issues.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dh2i.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14804</importID>
      <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Grant Fritchey is a Data Platform MVP with over 20 years’ experience in IT, including time spent in support and development. He has worked with SQL Server since 6.0 back in 1995. He has also developed in VB, VB.NET, C#, and Java. Grant has written books for Apress and Simple-Talk. Grant presents at conferences and user groups, large and small, all over the world. He joined Redgate Software as a product evangelist in January 2011.</description>
      <twitter>@gfritchey</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/scarydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://scarydba.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@gfritchey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22564</importID>
      <name>Randy Knight</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Randy Knight is a data professional who has worked with Microsoft technology for over 25 years, focusing on SQL Server since 1997. He has worked in a variety of settings, including 6 years as a database architect for match.com. In 2010, he founded SQL Server Solutions Group LLC, a boutique SQL Server consultancy.  A Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) in SQL Server, he speaks often at events all over the country including the  PASS Summit, SQLIntersections, and numerous SQL Saturday and User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>randy_knight</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/randyknight</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlsolutionsgroup.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=randy_knight</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21154</importID>
      <name>Michael Swinarski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>As an enthusiastic technical leader with over fifteen years of experience in Information Technology, I can attest to the notion that IT is not about technology as much as it is about people and the relationships that are formed to create collaborative teams that are able to address the needs of businesses, communities, and our environment.  By leveraging the diversity of the team, we are able to make use of technical assets to construct highly available solutions that enable customers </description>
      <twitter>@MichaelSwina</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/mswinarski/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@MichaelSwina</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24381</importID>
      <name>Sergey Olontsev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working with SQL Server since SQL Server 2000 version as a database administrator, developer, consultant and trainer, focusing on high availability and disaster recovery solutions, ETL, troubleshooting and performance tuning, developing high performance solutions . I'm a regular speaker at SQL Server user group meetings, SQL Saturday events and other conferences. An owner of MCM certification and MVP award on SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>SergeyOlontsev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/sergeyolontsev</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SergeyOlontsev.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SergeyOlontsev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10371</importID>
      <name>Benjamin Nevarez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Benjamin Nevarez is a SQL Server MVP and independent consultant based in Los Angeles, California who specializes in SQL Server query tuning and optimization. He is the author of “SQL Server 2014 Query Tuning  Optimization”, “Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer” and has contributed to other SQL Server books including “SQL Server 2012 Internals”. Benjamin has also been a speaker at many SQL Server conferences, including the PASS Summit, SQL Server Connections and SQLBits.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.benjaminnevarez.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17304</importID>
      <name>John McAllister</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John McAllister co-founded Stratature, an Independent MDM software vendor, in 2001. Following Microsoft’s acquisition of Stratature in 2007 John served as Group Program Manager for MDS and oversaw the incorporation of MDM into SQL Server. John now serves as the Regional Sales Director for Profisee, Inc. which provides enterprise-class MDM Solutions built on top of Microsoft’s MDS offering. John has worked with 100’s of organizations around the world in all phases of MDM projects. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.profisee.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14008</importID>
      <name>SIOS Technology</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>SIOS Technology Corp. makes software products that protect data and applications from downtime, while eliminating complexity, and reducing labor costs. SIOS products make clusters in both SAN and #SANLess environments easy to use and easy to own. By removing the configuration limitations of traditional clusters, SIOS products give enterprise data managers the freedom to run applications in the environment that best meets their needs -- physical, virtual,  cloud or any combination thereof.</description>
      <twitter>@SIOSTech</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/company/1319388</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://us.sios.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SIOSTech</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>9796</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9796</id>
          <name>Argenis Fernandez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Secure Your SQL Server Instance Without Changing Any Code</title>
      <description>Secure your SQL Server infrastructure and your Windows installations to enhance resiliency and minimize exposure to attacks -- all without touching a single line of code! In this session you will learn about Transparent Data Encryption, IPSec, Database Firewalls, Contained Databases and many other technologies that help you lock down your systems and close attack vectors. This talk puts great emphasis on the biggest threat to your database: SQL injection, offering many remediation techniques to prevent such attacks. During the demos, you will learn techniques to deal with vendors who require SA accounts to run their applications. Protect your SQL Servers without having to wait for your Developers or Vendors to make changes!</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10371</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10371</id>
          <name>Benjamin Nevarez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Query Processing in In-Memory OLTP (Hekaton)</title>
      <description>In-Memory OLTP (code name: Hekaton) is the most important new feature in SQL Server 2014, and this session will teach you how query processing and optimization work with this new database engine. After explaining the basics, we will discuss how the query optimizer is used in In-Memory OLTP by both natively compiled stored procedures and by traditional stored procedures accessing memory-optimized tables through the query interop functionality. We will also take a look at how the new hash and range indexes are used, as well as how their performance implications are also covered along with the process of translating the plan created by the query optimizer into C code. Finally, some limitations with the current release will also be explained.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11168</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11168</id>
          <name>Carl Berglund</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Get Your Nights  Weekends Back from SQL Server Planned Downtime</title>
      <description>Major disaster events resulting in unplanned downtime get all the press—but planned downtime constitutes almost 80% of the outages in any IT environment. This downtime is typically for tech refresh, migration projects, and OS/SQL Server patching. And when do you have to schedule the large downtime windows required to accomplish these upkeep tasks? Nights and weekends. Like you don't have better things to do then! In this session, learn how you can get the safety of a parallel deployment with the speed of an in-place upgrade for OS and/or SQL Server as fast as SQL Server can stop  restart, no data migrations for tech refresh, low-impact break/fix, and planned downtime windows of less than 2 minutes.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15120</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15120</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Powerful T-SQL Improvements that Reduce Query Complexity</title>
      <description>We’ve all dealt with them: nightmare queries, huge, twisted monsters that somehow work, despite being ugly and unmanageable. The time has come to tame these beasts, and the solution is available now, in SQL Server 2012.
New T-SQL functions offer out-of-the-box solutions for many problems that previously required complex workarounds. Paging, Running totals, Moving aggregates, YTD, and much more comes at the power of your fingertips in SQL Server 2012. The only thing you need to do is learn the syntax. And that is exactly what this session is all about: a thorough description and explanation of the syntax, and loads of demos to demonstrate how you can use all these new features.
Attend this session to boldly take SQL Server where it has never gone before!</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16925</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16925</id>
          <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>10 Handy Tips On SQL Server Dates</title>
      <description>Are you working with an application supporting different time zones and international date formats? How does your choice of storing date / time values differ if you are using Windows Azure SQL Database instead of on-prem SQL Server database? Did you know that SQL Server Database Engine, Integration Services (SSIS) and Analysis Services (SSAS) all have slightly different date / time data types? How can you bullet proof your system for the ever growing data in your organization with much more date and time data to come?  
 
With time being the one thing that constantly changes, date and time calculations are widely used and essential to all business transactions. Yet, most systems only use one or two date data types; Is this a wise decision? Quite often data retrieval relating to a period of time does performs poorly, or worst of all, is not accurate. These 10 tips will help you bridge the gap, and provide the techniques to build bulletproof systems the users demand and DESERVE! </description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16847</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16847</id>
          <name>Jimmy May</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 8</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Columnstore Indexes in SQL Server 2014: Flipping the DW /Faster Bit</title>
      <description>Columnstore indexes were introduced in SQL Server 2012  have been wholly re-architected  optimized in SQL Server 2014.  Columnstore indexes are optimized for data warehouse workloads  are a hybrid technology leveraging the best of off-disk  in-memory capabilities. Transparent to the app, columnstore has been shown to render queries at subsecond response times which heretofore took many minutes or longer. This presentation includes an overview of SQL Server 2012  a deep dive into SQL Server 2014 columnstore indexes, including a review of the architecture, as well as the challenges, workarounds, travails,  big wins at customer sites  inside MSIT. The presentation is rich in demos, including leveraging IaaS—Columnstore in The Cloud.  Learn whether columnstore can change your users' world  why columnstore may be a compelling reason to upgrade. Learn how columnstore indexes flip the DW faster bit  why columnstore manifests my motto, “Change the world or go home!”</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17158</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17158</id>
          <name>John McAllister</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Enterprise-grade MDM On SQL Server - the Keys to Success </title>
      <description>This session discusses a proven organizational approach and important technical considerations that lead to the successful adoption of Master Data Management (MDM) on SQL Server. Organizational considerations include building buy-in, team capability  expertise, and selling MDM to the rest of the organization while building a subject-area center of excellence. We also discuss approaches to improved time-to-value and to ensure that the technology and staff investment is matched to the expected outcome. Great technology choices will help ensure that your best laid plans succeed and the second half of this session goes over some important technology considerations. In this part of the session we discuss User Experience, Integration Patterns, Matching, Programmability, and Data Quality. </description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19012</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19012</id>
          <name>Leila Etaati</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>“Show Me Potential Customers “ : Data Mining Approach</title>
      <description>In the most marketing departments, the tactical question is about who are going to buy our products.  It is more cost effective to identify and spend money on highly potential customers (than those who are not likely to purchase).  This also affects the advertisement strategy. Potential customers and their traits can be identified by analysing previous purchasing information. Management experts can predict who is going to be their new customers by analysing their current customer purchase information. There are many data mining algorithms which can help with this task.  Microsoft Business Intelligence employs data mining algorithms that are deployed in an easy to use environment.
This demonstration based session will show how to use previous customer purchase information to predict potential customers. We will discuss how to set data sets and use different data mining algorithms to get predictive results and then demonstrate how to find the best predictions.
</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21393</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21393</id>
          <name>Neil Hambly</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Load Testing With SQL Server Tools</title>
      <description>It’s often difficult to know how your SQL Servers will perform under different loads. By performing load testing, we can gain these key insights, perform modifications to existing configurations, and understand the impact on performance levels.

Come learn about the native tools at our disposal for performing these important load tests and how we can identify when performance levels begin to drop. Using demos of these native tools – including Distributed Replay Utility (DRU), Database Tuning Adviser (DTA), Perfmon, Extended Events, and Profiler – we’ll see how to plan and perform a load test project, gain an understanding of SQL Server’s performance under varying load scenarios, and discover which tell-tale indicators can help alert us to performance degradation.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20617</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20617</id>
          <name>Mike Tutor</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 8</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Simple things you can do to make the Query Optimizer more efficient!</title>
      <description>On occasion as DBAs we have need to disable the foreign keys and constraints on one or more tables. Guess what, SQL Server no longer trusts those constraints when you re-enable them. What does that mean? In this discussion, we’ll talk about what the impact is to your queries when you have non-trusted constraints, how to find the non-trusted constraints, and how to soothe SQL Servers mistrusting heart so that it will trust your constraints again! How about your foreign keys? Are you using implicit conversions? Are your stats 'stale'? All of these things effect how the query optimizer works and can negatively affect you query performance.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21729</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21729</id>
          <name>Sebastian Meine</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Permission Management: 12 Pitfalls  Misconceptions</title>
      <description>SQL Server comes with a powerful built-in permission management system. However, as most powerful tools, this one too can be difficult to use and get right. 
This is a two-part session. During the first part, we will go through a review of SQL Server security terms and concepts, particularly the GRANT, REVOKE and DENY statements. For the second part, the audience selects topics that we will cover in detail. You will be able to choose from 12 different security pitfalls and misconceptions. All these pitfalls/misconceptions have one thing in common: If you are not aware of them, you might GRANT or DENY more permissions than you intended. 
</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22286</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22286</id>
          <name>Prakash Heda</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Standardize SQL Server Implementations (Dev to Prod)</title>
      <description>You'll learn about a best practice framework that alleviates many of the pain points for deploying, managing, and supporting multiple SQL Server deployments from development to production.  
There are many variables to consider when supporting SQL Servers in the real world, including:  
• Cloud systems (Microsoft Azure/Amazon AWS), virtualization (VMware/HyperV), physical servers
• Different versions of SQL Servers, and different editions (Standard/Enterprise)
• Service packs and specific Hotfixes
• Configuration differences based on OS/Memory/Disk configuration
• Different products need specific configurations and features of SQL Server
• Post installation steps and default access

The best practice framework will get us past the complexities and provide us with the following capabilities and benefits:
• A Process framework configured to support the above requirements
• Flexibility to easily add new configurations
• A consistent experience</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23350</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23350</id>
          <name>Rob Volk</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 9</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tame Your Unruly Data...With Constraints!</title>
      <description>Never given time or care, never forming good relationships, becoming bloated, corrupt and rife with indistinguishable copies, and all so horrifyingly pervasive in society. But enough about the Kardashians, what about YOUR DATA? If you want to straighten it out and prevent it from going too far in the first place, this session is for you. We will cover constraint basics (not null, check, primary key/unique, foreign keys), provide standard use cases, and address misconceptions about constraint use and performance. We will also look at triggers and application logic and why these are NOT substitutes for (but can effectively complement) good constraint usage. Attendees will enjoy learning how to keep THEIR data off the tabloid page!</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>8780</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>8780</id>
          <name>Reza Rad</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Enumerators in SSIS Foreach Loop</title>
      <description>There are different types of enumerators in the SSIS Foreach Loop Container which helps to implement different loop scenarios. In this chapter these different types explained with few case studies, with resort of these different types of enumerators , SSIS Developers can loop through specific files, or through rows of a data table, or items of an array or other kinds of list structures. Variaty of these types will reduce needs of scripting.
In this article these types of enumerators considered:
File Enumerator, Item Enumerator, ADO Enumerator, ADO.NET Schema Rowset Enumerator, From Variable Enumerator, NodeList Enumerator, SMO Enumerator. 
This session is based on the book chapter of SQL Server MVP Deep Dive 2</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25719</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25719</id>
          <name>Steve Wake</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Date and Time Dimensions for Every Day and Time in No Time</title>
      <description>All data warehouses need a date and time dimension to enable proper analysis across time. Most Data Warehouse designers will just use one provided by tools or whip it up in Excel, but what if you need to set up custom holidays or want different calendars, such as Fiscal or Julian? You can have any date and time dimension you need by using a single SQL script that can be modified and rerun as necessary. Learn what it takes to design a date and time dimension that does all of the calculations and formatting up-front so the reports can be easier to create. Sample script will be provided that creates the date and time dimensions and can be reused as often as necessary without breaking your data warehouse and it only take seconds to run!</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24381</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24381</id>
          <name>Sergey Olontsev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Moving applications to SQL Server 2014 In-Memory OLTP</title>
      <description>In-Memory OLTP aka Hekaton aka XTP is without a doubt one of the key features in brand new SQL Server 2014. By placing your data in memory and using native compile stored procedures you can boost and increase you SQL Server performance in times. But it is not so easy to implement as it may seem, you need to make a lot of changes in your code and even in your application architecture. In this session you'll learn what parts of your system can benefit by using In-Memory OLTP and what you should take into consideration before starting. As a bonus, I'll share my own experience of implementing In-Memory OLTP into a real production system.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24859</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24859</id>
          <name>David Moutray</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Quality:  Boosting Software Performance and Business Profit</title>
      <description>If "Data is the Lifeblood of Modern Business," then most businesses are walking corpses with sludge in their veins, because 10% to 25% of all data records in the average enterprise are wrong.  Until the dramatic problems of Data Quality Management are addressed, SQL can never fulfill its original promise to eliminate application "silos", enable systems to communicate and provide useful, actionable information to the modern business.  I believe that we are on the cusp of a revolution in Data Quality that is even greater in scope and impact than the revolution in manufacturing quality that began over 40 years ago.  Businesses that make the transition will survive and thrive.  Those that don't will finally stop shambling about and lay down to die.What is this revolution in Data Quality?  How can you be a part of it (and avoid the headman's ax)?!?  This presentation will change the way you think about your jobs as Database Administrators and Application Developers.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26889</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26889</id>
          <name>Theresa Iserman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Not So Basic Backup and Restore</title>
      <description>You’re taking basic backups and you know how to restore them. Things have been running smoothly in your environment but you want to be confident that you’re equipped with the backup and restore tools, techniques, and options that you’ll need to adapt your strategies as business needs change. You’ve heard about piecemeal restores, filegroup backups, and backing up to multiple files, and now you’re ready to dig into learning more about these topics. In this demo-rich presentation, we’ll review scenarios using these options and you'll gain an understanding of some intermediate and advanced options related to backup performance, corruption detection, and the new SQL Server 2014 hybrid backup scenarios. You'll return to the office inspired to validate your backups and test your restore processes regularly, and you'll have references to great tools the SQL community has shared to help you get started.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26992</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26992</id>
          <name>Tom Roush</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Life Lessons in Communication</title>
      <description>Communicating. We all do it, every day. But can you do it better? You present to management, share with peers, advise your direct reports. A common thread of success or failure here is how well you get your message across. 
Can you share bad news and soften the blow with humor while respecting the nature of the news you have to deliver?
Can you support your direct reports when they make a very human mistake?
Do you know how you communicate your support without micromanaging them can make a huge difference in the quality of their work for years to come? 
These questions and more will be answered, with stories, with humor, and with experience (both good and bad).
Once you've figured these things out, how do you communicate your own skills to the world? 
After attending, you’ll be on the road to better, more direct communication, whether it’s with your management, your peers, or your reports.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17519</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17519</id>
          <name>Josh Fennessy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Visual Analytics with HDInsight and Power View</title>
      <description>BIG DATA!  There, I've said it.  But, what exactly does it mean for YOU?

This session will help to dispel some of the Big Data confusion.  This session will focus on HD Insight, Microsoft's Hadoop based implementation.  Loading data and querying a database is one thing and that will certainly be covered. Exploring how we can integrate data from HD Insight into our existing analytic solutions is one of the real world implementations this session will be focused on.  This is one of the keys to successfully selling management on the needs for a Big Data solution. It's not just another database, it's a tool to enhance existing analytic structures.

During this session, we'll start with a brief overview of Hadoop and HDFS. Next we'll take a look at HD Insight, and explore some of the features therein.

Finally, integration with SSAS and Power View (using Excel 2013) will be shown, which will close the loop on Big Data visualizations. 
</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24948</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24948</id>
          <name>Phil Robinson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>”Delivering Reports - Report Manager and Beyond”</title>
      <description>SQL Server Reporting Services Report Manager provides a great web platform for managing and delivering many types of reports. We will review delivering reports with Report Manager and look at the options for integrating SSRS as the report presentation engine within web and windows applications. We will also explore creating a standalone application to navigate and display reports using the reporting services database.
 </description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11203</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11203</id>
          <name>Carlos L Chacon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 8</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Judge, Jury,  and Executioner--A First Look At Execution Plans</title>
      <description>When a query is run against a database, a plan is formed to do the work.  This session will serve as an introduction on how to read and interpret execution plans.  We will also take a look at the execution plan that won the 'Hairy' Execution Plan contest on SQLCruise Miami in 2013!  Take a peek at http://sqlcruise.com/winner-of-the-2013-caribbean-landlubber-sql-sentry-hairy-execution-plan/</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27353</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27353</id>
          <name>Damu Venkatesan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>DAX 101</title>
      <description>In this session, we will look at the new BI query language for PowerPivot and Tabular - DAX. This session will give you an introduction to Data Analysis eXpressions (DAX) and will provide you the necessary understanding to start using in your environment for data analysis. No prior experience with DAX is needed to attend this session.
</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14008</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14008</id>
          <name>SIOS Technology</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Clusters Your Way - #SANLess clustering</title>
      <description>Microsoft Cluster MVP Dave Bermingham will discuss how to create #SANLess clusters in environments where traditional shared storage clusters are impractical or impossible. He will also be discussing high performance clusters leveraging SSD and Flash-based PCIe storage for faster SQL application response times - no SAN (or SAN Admin required) - and be touching on HA protection and native Windows Failover Clustering in cloud environments.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27431</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27431</id>
          <name>Victor Isakov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding SQL Server 2014's In-Memory OLTP Table Technology</title>
      <description>Microsoft's new In-Memory OLTP Tables ("Hekaton") promise to seriously change the performance of database solutions that you can design and implement or refactor. In this session, we will examine this new technology's architecture and internals, new T-SQL syntax, and various use cases. We'll then discuss how it affects your SQL Server environment, including performance considerations, troubleshooting, administration, and high-availability design considerations. </description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18445</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18445</id>
          <name>Kathi Kellenberger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Writing Better T-SQL Queries with Window Functions</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2005 and later versions introduced several T-SQL features that are like power tools in the hands of T-SQL developers. If you aren’t using these features, you’re probably writing code that doesn’t perform as well as it could. 

This session will teach you how to get great performance, avoid cursor solutions, and create simpler code by using the window functions that have been introduced between 2005 and 2012. You'll learn how to use the new functions and how to apply them to several design patterns that are commonly found in the real world. </description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17304</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17304</id>
          <name>John McAllister</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Master Data Management - Getting Started with SQL Server MDS</title>
      <description>This session will provide an introduction to Master Data Management (MDM). We explore the basic concepts, types of MDM solution, and the basics for a successful MDM Implementation. With a working definition in hand, we'll discuss strategies for beginning a successful MDM pilot in your organization and look at some of the pitfalls to avoid. We'll wrap the business discussion up with some tips for selecting the right domains to solve and some tips for managing the politics of MDM. After we've set the stage for what, how and why you need MDM, we'll take a brief look at SQL Server MDS through the Excel add-in and talk about the Architecture of MDS</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21154</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21154</id>
          <name>Michael Swinarski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Ignored Best Practices</title>
      <description>As a Database Administrator, one will find that there are plenty of ways to implement SQL Servers, and develop code for applications.  While there is plenty of debate on how best to do things, there are some agreed upon practices that should be found in any implementation of a database project.  When these practices are ignored, the longevity of that server may be compromised.  This session will define the phrase "best practices", and discuss several things that should be found in any SQL Server implementation to avoid issues in the long run.
</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10286</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10286</id>
          <name>Ben Miller</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 9</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>TSQL Best Practices for SQL Engine Kindness</title>
      <description>This session will take a look at things that you should regularly know and use when coding TSQL. How can you be really friendly to SQL? The items covered will show you things that will help ensure that your code is readable, efficient and maintainable. We will look at query semantics, datatypes, things to avoid as well as how to be super friendly to the SQL Engine and allow things to work well.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22246</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22246</id>
          <name>Piotr Palka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 8</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS - manage concurrent processing using SQL Server Broker</title>
      <description>In this session we will do a case study for a typical situation in industries like telecommunication or healthcare. We have a stream of multiple relatively small files incoming from external system and we need to load them to SQL Server database in near-real-time. Typical examples are CDR billing files, HL7 diagnostic results or medical claims.
In this session we will cover how we can use WMI event watchers to monitor for incoming files and we examine option for managing worker treads loading the files. We will look into SQL Server broker queues, conversations between treads and activation to achieve robust solution.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19733</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19733</id>
          <name>Martin Cairney</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automating Deployments with Powershell</title>
      <description>Some aspects of SQL Server installations are easily repeatable using things like config files and command line installs.    However, so much of the preparation and post-install configuration still needs to be done manually.

This session will show how Powershell can be used to prep the servers (including how easy it can be to deploy a cluster) and how Powershell can then be used to deploy and configure SQL Server according to your company standards.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15861</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15861</id>
          <name>Jason Horner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 5</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dimensional Modeling Design Patterns: Beyond Basics</title>
      <description>This session will provide a deeper dive into the art of dimensional modeling. We will look at the different types of fact tables and dimension tables, how and when to use them. We will also some approaches to creating rich hierarchies that make reporting a snap. This session promises to be very interactive and engaging, bring your toughest Dimensional Modeling quandaries.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>12804</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12804</id>
          <name>David Eichner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 9</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SRS Report Builder for Business Intelligence</title>
      <description>Learn how easy it is to utilize the free download from Microsoft that allows users to create maps, charts, dashboard objects and reports against any kind of data easily without having to use Visual Studio.  See how SQL Report Builder makes creating executive dashboards easy!</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9856</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9856</id>
          <name>Thomas Norman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Converting Unreliable Deployments Into Consistent Releases</title>
      <description>The deployment process is frustrating; an object is missing, an object is 
deployed in the wrong order or the incorrect version. Each database is 
made up of a lot of objects in different environments. When you create an 
object like a table or stored procedure, you need to get this object deployed 
into each environment. Together we will discover how to separate each 
object for proper order deployment while releasing only objects which have 
changed. Deployments can cause you trouble but we will provide a reliable 
deployment and version control process.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22564</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22564</id>
          <name>Randy Knight</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 8</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Locks, Blocks, and Deadlocks Oh My!</title>
      <description>Managing concurrency is one of the most challenging aspects of working with any enterprise DBMS. There is much confusion out there about locking, blocking, and deadlocks. In this demo heavy session we will clear up the confusion.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27378</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27378</id>
          <name>Vern Rabe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Significance of Choosing the Right Data Types</title>
      <description>It's an all too common occurrence to have table columns or variables that have been assigned less than ideal data types. My goals in this presentation are to show you the importance of choosing the proper data type; show you some guidelines in determining what an appropriate data type would be; and once chosen, give you some tools for proper usage and management. I will demonstrate several performance and accuracy issues, along with their possible solutions, caused by either the assignment of imappropriate data types or improper usage of them. In addition, I will cover serveral data type related functions and point out caveates in their usage.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14804</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14804</id>
          <name>Grant Fritchey</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tune Queries By Fixing Bad Parameter Sniffing </title>
      <description>Parameter sniffing is a misunderstood issue on SQL Server. Most of the time, parameter sniffing is helping performance on your servers. But sometimes, circumstances change, and what was helping you is now hurting you – bad. In this session, we’ll gain an understanding of what exactly parameter sniffing is and why it’s usually so helpful. Then we’ll explore how parameter sniffing can go wrong and look at seven different ways you can deal with it when it does. You’ll take away a wealth of knowledge that will help you identify and resolve bad parameter sniffing in your own environment.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34788</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34788</id>
          <name>Michael Fal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 7</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Exposing the Core: SQL 2012 on Server Core</title>
      <description>Everything that's old is new again, as Windows Server moves back to the terminal interface.  With SQL 2012, we can now run our SQL Servers on Server Core, a version of the Windows OS that is smaller and more secure.  This presentation will introduce you to Server Core, how to prepare it for a SQL installation(including using Powershell for management), and how to actually install SQL 2012 on to it.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10600</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10600</id>
          <name>Bob Pusateri</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>VLDBs: Lessons Learned</title>
      <description>VLDBs (Very Large Databases) play in a different league: common maintenance operations can take much longer to run, and some settings and features that work well on smaller databases become much less effective. These downsides generally have a negative impact on users, however through some creativity and changes in our game plan we can have highly performant VLDBs. This session will cover a wide variety of tips and tricks assembled from years of working with databases up to 40TB in size.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10696</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10696</id>
          <name>Brandon Leach</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 6</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Treating Tables Like Legos, Partitioning Basics</title>
      <description>Partitioning allows us to isolate parts of our table as small chunks called partitions.  In turn, these partitions allow us to do some really cool tricks for manageability and performance.  In this session we'll look at the concepts surrounding partitioning and how we can apply them.  We'll reinforce what we cover with some cool demo's showing some really neat tricks.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20406</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20406</id>
          <name>Mickey Stuewe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 9</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Changing Your Habits to Improve the Performance of Your T-SQL</title>
      <description>Do you dread handing your T-SQL over for code review? Do your queries run slower than you expect? Does the DBA always want to tweak your T-SQL? In this demo heavy session, we’ll take a look at various ways to improve your T-SQL. You’ll learn about formatting T-SQL for readability and why top down design is not the best solution for writing T-SQL. You’ll learn why implicit conversions slow queries down and how to leverage simple techniques for minimizing the performance impact of explicit conversions. By changing some of your T-SQL writing habits you can improve performance of queries from the very beginning.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34744</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34744</id>
          <name>Mark Tabladillo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track> 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Secrets of Enterprise Data Mining</title>
      <description>If you have a SQL Server license (Standard or higher) then you already have the ability to start data mining.  In this presentation, you will see how to scale up data mining from the free Excel 2013 add-in to production use.  Aimed at beginning to intermediate data miners, this presentation will show how mining models move from development to production.  We will use SQL Server 2014 tools including SSMS, SSIS, and SSDT.  Also included is an overview of Microsoft Azure Machine Learning.</description>
      <startTime>11/1/2014 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>11/1/2014 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>