<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #607 - Calgary 2017</name>
    <startDate>4/29/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>70</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-07:00) Mountain Time (US and Canada)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatCalgary</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>IBM Calgary Building</name>
      <street>227 11 Avenue SW</street>
      <city>Calgary</city>
      <state>Alberta, Canada</state>
      <zipcode>T2R1R9</zipcode>
      <longitude>-114.06765</longitude>
      <latitude>51.04227</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1833</importID>
      <name>Born SQL</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://bornsql.ca</url>
      <imageURL>https://bornsql.ca/LogoBornSqlWhite.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1834</importID>
      <name>SelectStar</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://selectstar.io/</url>
      <imageURL>https://madpass.pass.org/portals/85/sidebarimages/selectStar_logo_RGB.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/908/EventSponsor_14257.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>5</importID>
      <name>Quest Software</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.quest.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/947/EventSponsor_14722.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>19</importID>
      <name>MSSQLTips.com</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.mssqltips.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/mssql_logo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1892</importID>
      <name>AMTRA Solutions Ltd.</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://amtrasolutions.com/amtrasolutions/</url>
      <imageURL>https://bornsql.ca/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/AMTRALogoFinal_FullColor_Small.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63365</importID>
      <name>Sebastian Meine</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sebastian Meine, Ph.D. is the SQL Stylist behind sqlity.net llc. In 2010 he founded sqlity.net to fully engage in his passion for SQL Server.
Armed with a Ph.D. in Computer Science and years of experience in architecting DBs for a global Fortune 50 company, Sebastian now provides training and consulting services for his clients, specializing in SQL Server Security, Test Driven Development and Performance. Sebastian is an experienced public speaker, published author, president of the Philly PASS Chapter, PASS Regional Mentor and coauthor  lead developer of tSQLt.</description>
      <twitter>@sqlity</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/sebastianmeine</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlity.net/en/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sqlity</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57702</importID>
      <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Flynn is a Senior Database Administrator with 10 years experience in large 24 x 7 enterprise environments. He is a certified master for SQL Server and a regular attendee of the PASS Summit.

Has presented at SQLSaturday events in Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane and Auckland, Edmonton and Calgary, Oslo and Cambridge</description>
      <twitter>sqllensman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqllensman.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllensman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61057</importID>
      <name>Mohit Gupta</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Microsoft SQL Server PFE for 6+ years; focusing primary on PTO amp; HADR.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sqlcan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/guptamohitk</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlcan.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sqlcan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57446</importID>
      <name>Rushabh Mehta</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rushabh Mehta is a Business Intelligence Mentor with SolidQ and the Managing Director for Solid Quality India Pvt. Ltd. He served as PASS President for 2010/2011 term.

Rushabh has worked with MS Data Platform since 1998 and has designed and developed BI systems since 2001. He has been the lead architect for many large-scale and complex BI solutions for clients such as Publix, Raymond James, Jackson Hewitt, US Dept. of Defense, and Microsoft. He is an MVP with Microsoft, Damp;B amp; Melissa Data

</description>
      <twitter>@rushabhmehta</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rushabhbmehta</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/RushabhMehta</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@rushabhmehta</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61143</importID>
      <name>Mohit Gupta</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Microsoft SQL Server PFE for 6+ years; focusing primary on PTO amp; HADR.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sqlcan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/guptamohitk</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlcan.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sqlcan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57634</importID>
      <name>Chris Wood</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>He has been an MS SQL DBA since 1997 starting with 6.5. Worked with 7/2000/2005/2008/2008R2/2012/2014/2016 and 2019 during those 23 years. He has attended 14 Pass Summits, 3 SQLCruises and 2 SQLConnections conferences. He has been the Communications Director for EDMPASS chapter since its inception in 2008. Spoken at 6 SQL Saturdays including the keynote at SQL Saturday 710 Edmonton in 2018. Passionate about SQL and educating himself to know more about it. 
He has migrated systems while always attempting to take advantage of any new features from 7.0 all the way to 2014 and 2016 and now 2019
He has learned and implemented lots of best practices from SQL Server MVPs.</description>
      <twitter>ChrisAVWood</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ChrisAVWood</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>62990</importID>
      <name>Pinal Dave</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pinal Dave is a SQL Server Performance Tuning Expert and an independent consultant. He has authored 12 SQL Server database books, 30 Pluralsight courses and has written over 5000 articles on the database technology on his blog at a https://blog.sqlauthority.com. Along with 16+ years of hands-on experience, he holds a Masters of Science degree and a number of database certifications.</description>
      <twitter>pinaldave</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pinaldave</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blog.sqlauthority.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pinaldave</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63403</importID>
      <name>Ron Huizenga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ron Huizenga is the Senior Product Manager for the ER/Studio product family. Ron has over 30 years of experience as an IT executive and consultant in Enterprise Data Architecture, Governance, Business Process Re-engineering and Improvement, Program/Project Management, Software Development and Business Management. His experience spans multiple industries including manufacturing, supply chain, pipelines, natural resources, retail, health care, insurance, and transportation.</description>
      <twitter>@DataAviator</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/ronhuizenga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@DataAviator</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57436</importID>
      <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Flynn is a Senior Database Administrator with 10 years experience in large 24 x 7 enterprise environments. He is a certified master for SQL Server and a regular attendee of the PASS Summit.

Has presented at SQLSaturday events in Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane and Auckland, Edmonton and Calgary, Oslo and Cambridge</description>
      <twitter>sqllensman</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqllensman.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqllensman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>62989</importID>
      <name>Pinal Dave</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pinal Dave is a SQL Server Performance Tuning Expert and an independent consultant. He has authored 12 SQL Server database books, 30 Pluralsight courses and has written over 5000 articles on the database technology on his blog at a https://blog.sqlauthority.com. Along with 16+ years of hands-on experience, he holds a Masters of Science degree and a number of database certifications.</description>
      <twitter>pinaldave</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pinaldave</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blog.sqlauthority.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pinaldave</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61785</importID>
      <name>Scott Stauffer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Scott Stauffer (@SQLSocialite) is very PASSionate about data and enjoys meeting with like-minded data geeks. He started the Vancouver PASS Chapter in 2004. In 2008, Scott was recognized by Microsoft with a SQL Server MVP award. In 2009, Scott started a PASS BI Chapter in Vancouver, and was also at one time the PASS Regional Chapter Mentor for Canada. For over 10 years he has been an independent consultant working with clients to solve their data woes and extract insight from their business data.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLSocialite</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/scottstauffer</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://scottstauffer.ca</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLSocialite</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>63365</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63365</id>
          <name>Sebastian Meine</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Unit-Testing in SQL Server</title>
      <description>It’s bad enough to spend hours finding and fixing database defects, explaining to the rest of the team what went wrong and trying to clean up the mess. It’s even worse when a defect causes the end-user to make a bad decision. Database defects are far too costly and most testing practices do not adequately detect or prevent them.

In this session you’ll learn techniques to write SQL code that is resilient to defects and is easier to change and maintain. We will cover writing simple unit tests and look into more advanced topics such as faking tables and spying procedures. We will also look at how unit testing improves code quality and maintainability.

You will leave this session ready to write unit tests for your own environment to get started on the way to a defect-free and maintainable SQL Server code base.</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>62990</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>62990</id>
          <name>Pinal Dave</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>Performance in 60 Seconds - SQL Tricks Everybody MUST Know</title>
      <description>Data and Database is a very important aspect of application development for businesses. Developers often come across situations where they face a slow server response, even though their hardware specifications are above par. This session is for all the Developers who want their server to perform at blazing fast speed, but want to invest very little time to make it happen. We will go over various database tricks which require absolutely no time to master and require practically no SQL coding at all. After attending this session, Developers will only need 60 seconds to improve performance of their database server in their implementation. We will have a quiz during the session to keep the conversation alive. Developers will walk out with scripts and knowledge that can be applied to their servers, immediately post the session.</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>62989</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>62989</id>
          <name>Pinal Dave</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Secrets of SQL Server - Database Worst Practices</title>
      <description>“OMG! What did I do?” Chances are you have heard, or even uttered, this expression. This demo-oriented session will show many examples where database professionals were dumbfounded by their own mistakes, and could even bring back memories of your own early DBA days. The goal of this session is to expose the small details that can be dangerous to the production environment and SQL Server as a whole, as well as talk about worst practices and how to avoid them. In this session we will focus on some of the common errors and their resolution. Developers will walk out with scripts and knowledge that can be applied to their servers, immediately post the session.</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57702</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57702</id>
          <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Adding Power to the DBA toolkit!</title>
      <description>Interested in being able to manage, monitor and document your SQL Environment from a single location? Want to be able to produce modern interactive reports and dashboards that can be viewed on both desktop and mobile devices? 

By adding a little "Power" to your DBA toolkit you can!

By combining PowerShell and PowerBi with the more traditional DBA tools I will show how to query and document your entire environment and produce rich interactive reports that can be consumed by all levels of your organisation.

This is a constantly evolving Presentation based around latest features in PowerBI and PowerShell</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 1:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 2:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61143</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61143</id>
          <name>Mohit Gupta</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server In-Flight Recorder Deep-Dive</title>
      <description>How to leverage in-flight recorder (Query Data Store) to tune workloads that are performing poorly?</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61785</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61785</id>
          <name>Scott Stauffer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI for the Faint of Heart - Building an Interactive Report Step-by-Step!</title>
      <description>You've heard about Power BI, and you've seen it, but you haven't yet rolled up your sleeves and got your hands dirty. It looks like it is really easy, but sometimes it helps to have someone step you through it the first time to help you hit the ground running. We will grab various public data sources, join them together in a model and build an interactive pièce de ré·sis·tance on the visual design surface!</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 3:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 4:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63403</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63403</id>
          <name>Ron Huizenga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Using Models as the Blueprints for Enterprise Data Governance</title>
      <description>Data governance is becoming increasingly important to corporations who must demonstrate compliance to industry and corporate regulations. This is occurring against a backdrop of continuously evolving technology, an explosion of diverse data sources, and exponential growth in volume. Data professionals are tasked with ensuring data quality, enforcing data security, tracking model changes, and complying with audits. We will discuss a practical, model-based approach to enterprise data governance, with a focus on Master Data Management (MDM).</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 12:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 1:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57436</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57436</id>
          <name>Patrick Flynn</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server on Linux - The How, the What and the Why?</title>
      <description>In this Demo Heavy Session we will explore the recently released SQL Server on Linux

Join me as we try to understand questions like?
How do we install and run SQL Server on Linux?
What is different, what is the same?
What may be better? What might be worse?
Why would it be useful? 
What new skills will you need?

The presentation will be based around experience gained in evaluating the Public CTP and will help introduce you into the brave new world of SQL Server on Linux</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57634</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57634</id>
          <name>Chris Wood</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Monitoring SQL 2016 on-premise for performance and stability</title>
      <description>You have an on-premise instance of SQL 2016 but what-if performance sucks every now and again
Have you looked in the plan cache?
What to look for in saved plans
Keep you plan cache trim
Are your indexes being used as you expect?
Do you have table/index hot-spots?</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 2:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 3:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61057</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61057</id>
          <name>Mohit Gupta</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Security Enhancements</title>
      <description>Microsoft SQL Server 2016 introduced multiple new security enhancements that can help make your environment more secure.  In this session we will cover these options and brief demo on how they are implemented.</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57446</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57446</id>
          <name>Rushabh Mehta</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room B</name>
      </location>
      <title>PowerQuery Tips and Tricks for Power BI</title>
      <description>In this session, we will first learn how to expose organizational data using the data management gateway to Power BI. We will then look at how to use PowerQuery to acquire and cleanse data from organizational and external sources. As part of the session, we will also look at some tips and tricks to facilitate data acquisition and cleansing.</description>
      <startTime>4/29/2017 9:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/29/2017 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>