<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #1000 – Oregon – Virtual 1000</name>
    <startDate>10/24/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>500</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-08:00) Pacific Time (US and Canada); Tijuana</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatoregon</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Franz Hall, University of Portland</name>
      <street>5000 North Willamette Blvd</street>
      <city>
      </city>
      <state>Canada/US</state>
      <zipcode>97203</zipcode>
      <longitude>-122.727686983328</longitude>
      <latitude>45.5726154474771</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>813</importID>
      <name>Marquam Group</name>
      <label>Marquee Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.marquam.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1000/EventSponsor_14763.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1000/EventSponsor_14833.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2678</importID>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://cloud.google.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1000/EventSponsor_14834.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2696</importID>
      <name>Melissa</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>http://www.melissa.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1000/EventSponsor_14901.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2689</importID>
      <name>Red Hat</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://www.redhat.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/1000/EventSponsor_14835.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107915</importID>
      <name>Paul Turley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul is a Principal Consultant for Pragmatic Works, a Mentor and Microsoft Data Platform MVP. He consults, writes, speaks, teaches  blogs about business intelligence and reporting solutions. He works with companies around the world to model data, visualize and deliver critical information to make informed business decisions; using the Microsoft data platform and business analytics tools. He is a Director of the Oregon Data Community PASS chapter  user group, the author  and lead author of Professional SQL Server 2016 Reporting Services and 14 other titles from Wrox  Microsoft Press.  He holds several certifications including MCSE for the Data Platform and BI.</description>
      <twitter>paul_turley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/pturley</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserverbiblog.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=paul_turley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108114</importID>
      <name>Ondrej Aubrecht</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ondrej has been working with SharePoint, O365 (cloud) and security in the industry for more than 12 years. Working on various projects maximalize the benefits, improvements and reduce the cost in the big enterprise and governments.

Ondrej takes data into a new level of challenges and setting Precision and organize system specifically in IT technology which he is passionate about. He is also running Wellington PowerShell user group.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.pwsh.org.nz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105571</importID>
      <name>Amit R S Bansal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Amit R. S. Bansal is a SQL Server Specialist at SQLMaestros. He leads the SQL Server practice with a focused team providing consulting, training, and content development services to more than 160+ SQL customers globally. He frequently speaks at international conferences on SQL Server performance tuning, which is his core expertise. Amit is also honored with Microsoft Regional Director status, MVP award, and Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server credential. Amit has been working with SQL Server since 1999 and has been part of countless mission-critical SQL deployments. Performance Tuning in SQL Server is his core area of expertise. To learn more about Amit, visit http://sqlmaestros.com/amit-bansal.</description>
      <twitter>A_Bansal</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/AmitBansal2010</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=A_Bansal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108322</importID>
      <name>Dennes Torres</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dennes Torres is a Data Platform MVP with more than 25 years of experience in the IT area. He improves Data Platform Architectures and turns data into knowledge. As a Brazilian living in Malta, Dennes works as a software developer and leads the Malta MDP User Group. Having the MCSE Data Platform, Business Intelligence, and Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) certifications, Dennes has been in love with database servers since he was  introduced to SQL Server 6.5, more years ago than he would like to admit.</description>
      <twitter>Dennes</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennestorres/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/dennes-torres/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Dennes</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105524</importID>
      <name>David Patrick</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dave has been developing database applications for over 25 years. An MCT since 2001, he has taught many classes from Intro to Visual Interdev to Advanced SharePoint Development. Dave runs two user groups, the Maryland and Pennsylvania Microsoft Developers User Group, www.mapamdug.com, and MAD SharePoint, www.madsharepoint.com. Dave does SharePoint training and development for DSA, Inc., a DoD contractor that does great work for the Army over at Aberdeen Proving Ground. Dave is also an MVP.</description>
      <twitter>DavidEPatrick</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidepatrick</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.madsharepoint.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DavidEPatrick</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105725</importID>
      <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julie Koesmarno, MCSE Data Platform, and MCSE Business Intelligence, MCT, is a Senior Program Manager at Microsoft, with a Bachelor’s degree in IT. She has over 10 years of experience working with SQL Server for large-scale and multi-million-dollar OLTP and ETL projects as a SQL Server developer and system analyst/designer. Her past projects include delivering a SQL Server 2012 data warehouse and BI solutions in the US and Australia. She now works with hybrid, cloud and on-prem SQL projects.</description>
      <twitter>@mssqlgirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/juliekoesmarno</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mssqlgirl.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mssqlgirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105042</importID>
      <name>Kevin Boles</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kevin Boles is a SQL Server expert, working exclusively with the product since v6.5. With over 25 years of database experience and over 45,000 man hours of SQL Server engine experience, he holds many related certifications, is an MCT and was a SQL Server MVP from 2007 to 2012. Kevin has been a very successful independent consultant for over 20 years. His passion is the relational engine, especially designing, building, analyzing and tuning high-performance database applications.</description>
      <twitter>@TheSQLGuru</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/thesqlguru</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TheSQLGuru</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105535</importID>
      <name>Ramesh Satya</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>will update soonSatya Ramesh has credible experience working with SQL Server. As a Senior Consultant for SQLMaestros (a business unit of eDominer Systems), he has worked on countless projects involving SQL Server  Azure SQL Database. He has presented numerous webinars and delivered multiple sessions as part of his community work with DataPlatformGeeks. He was also a speaker at Data Platform Summit 2018  2017 edition. Other than DataPlatformGeeks, his also got selected in New Stars Of Data 2020. Satya frequently records SQL videos for the community and hosts them on SQLMaestros YouTube channel.</description>
      <twitter>satyaramesh230</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramesh-satya-a87a5385/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=satyaramesh230</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105815</importID>
      <name>Mark Runyon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark Runyon works as a principal consultant for Improving Atlanta. He focuses on systems architecture and development of enterprise web and mobile applications. As a full stack programmer, he primarily works with Microsoft technologies, leveraging the cloud through Azure and AWS. He is a contributing writer at InformationWeek, The Enterprisers Project and Business2Community.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/aspprogrammer</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/softwarearchitect/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://markrunyon.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/aspprogrammer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107635</importID>
      <name>William Assaf</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>William Assaf is a senior content developer on the SQLDocs team at Microsoft. Formerly a Data Platform MVP and a consultant for SQL Server, and before that a .NET developer, William currently works with Microsoft product groups on content related to the SQL database platform, specifically for SQL performance, Big Data Clusters, and Azure SQL DB. As a consultant for 13 years he worked with clients on SQL Server and Azure SQL platform optimization, management, disaster recovery and high availability, and led a crack multi-city team of consulting SQL DBA's. William has written for Microsoft SQL certification exams since 2011 and was the team lead author of the 2017 and 2019 editions of "SQL Server Administration Inside Out" by Microsoft Press. William is a past lead of the annual SQLSaturday Baton Rouge Planning Committee and supports the Baton Rouge User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>william_a_dba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamdassaf/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqltact.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=william_a_dba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108320</importID>
      <name>Dennes Torres</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dennes Torres is a Data Platform MVP with more than 25 years of experience in the IT area. He improves Data Platform Architectures and turns data into knowledge. As a Brazilian living in Malta, Dennes works as a software developer and leads the Malta MDP User Group. Having the MCSE Data Platform, Business Intelligence, and Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) certifications, Dennes has been in love with database servers since he was  introduced to SQL Server 6.5, more years ago than he would like to admit.</description>
      <twitter>Dennes</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennestorres/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/dennes-torres/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Dennes</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105534</importID>
      <name>Ramesh Satya</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>will update soonSatya Ramesh has credible experience working with SQL Server. As a Senior Consultant for SQLMaestros (a business unit of eDominer Systems), he has worked on countless projects involving SQL Server  Azure SQL Database. He has presented numerous webinars and delivered multiple sessions as part of his community work with DataPlatformGeeks. He was also a speaker at Data Platform Summit 2018  2017 edition. Other than DataPlatformGeeks, his also got selected in New Stars Of Data 2020. Satya frequently records SQL videos for the community and hosts them on SQLMaestros YouTube channel.</description>
      <twitter>satyaramesh230</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramesh-satya-a87a5385/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=satyaramesh230</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105797</importID>
      <name>Rahat Yasir</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rahat Yasir is selected as Canada's top 30 software developer under 30 in 2018. He is five times Microsoft Most Valuable Professional Award holder in Artificial Intelligence category. He is the author of the first eBook on Windows Phone 8.1 app development "Windows Phone 8.1 Complete Solution" and "Universal Windows Platform - Complete Solution". He was the lead AI developer at Immersive Design Studios and developed world's first AI video upscalling tool. He worked as AI Engineer at Intact Financial Corp and designed production graded AI applications that are serving millions of requests everyday. He is currently working as the Lead AI Developer at OSEDEA and designing the next generation AI solutions for manufacturing industry.</description>
      <twitter>Anind0</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rahat-yasir/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://learnwithbddevs.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Anind0</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107629</importID>
      <name>Scott Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Scott Klein is a senior consultant with SQL Solutions Group with over two decades of experience working with Microsoft SQL Server. Prior to SSG, Scott spent almost 10 years at Microsoft, traveling the globe as a technical evangelist training and speaking about SQL Server and Microsoft’s Azure data services. Scott’s recent focus has been on advanced analytics, including big data and IoT, providing real-world training to help bring intelligence to your data. Scott has authored several books focusing on data and data analytics. Scott is continuously striving and looking for ways to help developers and companies grok the wonderful world of data.</description>
      <twitter>SQLScott</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/sqlscott</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLScott</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108068</importID>
      <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>José Manuel Jurado currently works as SQL Escalation Engineer and Subject Matter Expert in Azure SQL Database at Microsoft Spain. With over 20+ years of experience in SQL Server environments (administration and database development), he is a speaker for internal events at Microsoft and for public events such as SQLSaturday, SQL Nexus, SQLBits, Pass Summit, SQL Server Konferenze, TechReady, DotNetConference, and Azure BootCamp. In the past, he worked as Project Manager for large global retail company for more than 10 years developing projects using different Microsoft Technologies.</description>
      <twitter>jmjuradodiaz</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-manuel-jurado-diaz-5a586014/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jmjuradodiaz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107199</importID>
      <name>Itshak David</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Yitzhak has over 24 years of experience with SQL Server, Oracle, and Sybase. He is an applicative  infrastructure DBA for relational and Nosql solutions (MongoDB, Redis), Hadoop CDH and Spark. David is a specialist in HA and DRP solutions, tuning, Machine learning , security, High Performance Computing, replication (Oracle  SQL Server), BI infrastructure and system engineering. David Yitzhak holds 3 Degrees from Technicon (Israel Institute of Technology): BSC Information System , MBA and ME (System engineering) and research associate in one of the enterprise Organizations. He presents in Oracle open world 2010, Organize Oracle ILOUG for 3 years , SQL Server forums, Microsoft BI forums, Sqlsaturday Israel 2016/17/18/19 , 3rd Israeli</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>Global Hebrew Virtual PASS Chapter : Data virtualization with SQL Server 2019 PolyBase https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ixfwdZUj_A8feature=youtu.be https://globalhebrew.pass.org/MeetingDetails.aspx?EventID=15457    SQL Server 2019 Big Data Cluster BDC and Spark from Zero to an hero by David Yitzhak https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iKgMqyPOVS0   David Izhak: Performance Improvements in SQL 2014 – lessons from the field  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x4hGjYGBfkc   David Itzhak: Practical SQL 2014 Data Mining</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107514</importID>
      <name>Reid Havens</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reid Havens is the founder of Havens Consulting Inc. He has a formal background in technology and organizational management, having obtained separate Master's Degrees in Organizational Development and Business Analytics. Reid has experience working with many of the Fortune 50, 100, and 500 companies. Reid is also an avid content developer, having authored numerous articles and videos on various blog sites and video platforms. He's also written multiple training curriculums, online video courses, and college level classes. Additionally, he guest lectures at the University of Washington and other universities, teaching Business Intelligence, Reporting, and Data Visualization.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/HavensBI</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/reidhavens/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.havensconsulting.net/blog-and-media/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/HavensBI</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105926</importID>
      <name>Steve Jones</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Jones is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and has been working with SQL Server since version 4.2 on OS/2. After working as a DBA and developer for a variety of companies, Steve co-founded the community website SQLServerCentral.com in 2001.
Since 2004, Steve has been the full-time editor of the site, ensuring it continues to be a great resource for SQL Server professionals. Over the last decade, Steve has written hundreds of articles about SQL Server for SQLServerCentral.com, SQL Server Standard magazine, SQL Server Magazine, and Database Journal.</description>
      <twitter>way0utwest</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/way0utwest</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.voiceofthedba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=way0utwest</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107573</importID>
      <name>Will Velida</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Will Velida is a Software Engineer working at ASB Bank in Auckland New Zealand. While at ASB Bank, he has worked in a variety of teams, including working in the Big Data team, Data Science and Analytics team and in the Payments team doing some awesome things in the cloud using Azure Functions and Cosmos DB! In his down time, he likes to hike around New Zealand and do the odd kayaking when the opportunity arises.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/willvelida/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107634</importID>
      <name>William Assaf</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>William Assaf is a senior content developer on the SQLDocs team at Microsoft. Formerly a Data Platform MVP and a consultant for SQL Server, and before that a .NET developer, William currently works with Microsoft product groups on content related to the SQL database platform, specifically for SQL performance, Big Data Clusters, and Azure SQL DB. As a consultant for 13 years he worked with clients on SQL Server and Azure SQL platform optimization, management, disaster recovery and high availability, and led a crack multi-city team of consulting SQL DBA's. William has written for Microsoft SQL certification exams since 2011 and was the team lead author of the 2017 and 2019 editions of "SQL Server Administration Inside Out" by Microsoft Press. William is a past lead of the annual SQLSaturday Baton Rouge Planning Committee and supports the Baton Rouge User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>william_a_dba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamdassaf/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqltact.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=william_a_dba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108098</importID>
      <name>Edward Pollack</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ed Pollack has over 20 years of experience in database and systems administration, which has developed his passion for performance optimization, database design, and making things go faster. He has spoken at many SQLSaturdays, 24 Hours of PASS, and PASS Summit. This led him to organize SQLSaturday Albany, which has become an annual event for New York’s Capital Region. Sharing these experiences with the community is a top priority, and encouraging everyone to take the leap into public speaking and engaging others, a passion.
In his free time, Ed enjoys video games, traveling, cooking exceptionally spicy foods, and hanging out with his amazing wife and sons.</description>
      <twitter>EdwardPollack</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=81593638</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlshack.com/author/edward-pollack/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=EdwardPollack</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105900</importID>
      <name>Javier Villegas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Javier Villegas is a Database Administrator Manager for Mediterranean Shipping Company. Javier has more than 20 years working with SQL Server on every version from 6.5 to SQL Server 2019, Including SQL Azure Database and SQL Azure Managed Instance. His specialization is Administration, Performance Tuning and High Availability.
He is a Microsoft MVP in Data Platform.
Javier is a frequent speaker in conferences and events such as SQL Saturday , PASS Virtual Groups, 24 Hours SQL PASS , vOpen(NetConf), GroupBy and DataPlatformGeeks.
@sqlargentina</description>
      <twitter>https://www.twitter.com/javier_vill</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://ar.linkedin.com/in/javiervillegas</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sql-javier-villegas.blogspot.com.ar/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://www.twitter.com/javier_vill</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107357</importID>
      <name>Andrea Mascher</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andrea Mascher (she/her) leads the SQL Server DBA team at The University of Iowa (UI). In addition to her experience in the education sector, Andrea previously supported systems in the biotechnology and healthcare fields.

Andrea is an advocate for gender diversity in STEM and co-founded the UI Women In Technology users group to promote a climate of inclusivity and professional growth for women and non-binary individuals in technical fields at UI. Andrea also serves as a member of the UI Council on the Status of Women.

Andrea's undergraduate and graduate coursework at UI was in Computer Science, with a focus on Electronic Voting Systems and Technology Law and Policy.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105851</importID>
      <name>Michael McKinley</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael McKinley is the founder of McKinley Consulting.  Michael has managed projects and workstreams in consulting for the last five years, in areas including data analytics, change management, operations excellence, and supply chain transformation.

Most recently, Mr. McKinley helped HCA build an enterprise-wide analytics model for their Human Resources Group, providing insights into how to retain and promote top talent.  He is currently engaged on his fourth project with HCA.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/Mike_L_McKinley</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaellmckinley</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.mckinley.consulting/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/Mike_L_McKinley</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107114</importID>
      <name>Patrick Gallucci</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Gallucci is a Microsoft Certified Educator, Microsoft Certified Trainer, Microsoft Certified Azure Solution Architect Expert and Azure DevOps Engineer Expert at Quisitive in Dallas/Fort Worth. He has 25+ years’ experience working with data platforms including, Azure Data Services, Microsoft SQL Server, Azure Synapse, Hadoop, Spark, CosmosDB  Azure Data Lake Services. As the Managing Principal, he is responsible for the technical architecture, governance, and service delivery quality for the Data and Analytics Practice at Quisitive.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrickgallucci/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.quisitive.com/conversations/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107582</importID>
      <name>Rui Romano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rui Romano lives in Portugal and he leads the Business Intelligence team at DevScope. 

He has been Developing amp; Architecting software solutions since 2003 always focused in the Business Intelligence area.</description>
      <twitter>RuiRomano</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pt.linkedin.com/in/ruiromano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ruiromanoblog.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=RuiRomano</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105721</importID>
      <name>Harry Chandra</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Harry Chandra is a SQL Server, VMWare and PowerShell enthusiast working with various releases of SQL Server for over 10 years. His main focus is in Administration and High Availability for SQL Server, although he has always strived to expand his knowledge into other area of SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>HarryChandraPDX</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.HarryChandra.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=HarryChandraPDX</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104552</importID>
      <name>Jason Horner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hi, my name is Jason. I spend most of my day helping clients solve business problems mostly in the Data and Advanced Analytics spaces. Sometimes this involves various and sundry cloud technologies including Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Data Lake Store, Azure Databricks, HDInsight and Azure SQL Database. I'm fluent in several languages including: SQL, C#, Python, and PowerShell.

I'm a Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server (MCM) and have been recognized for my technical excellence and evangelism efforts by Microsoft by being awarded the Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for the last 5+ years.

In my off hours I like to snowboard, karaoke, ride roller coasters, and play arcade games</description>
      <twitter>jasonhorner</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonhorner</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.jasonhorner.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jasonhorner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107497</importID>
      <name>Jared Poché</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jared Poche began working with SQL Server as an instructor for certification classes and has a passion for teaching and performance troubleshooting. Jared spent 10 years providing customer support at Microsoft, most recently as a Sr. Support Escalation Engineer. He is currently working as a Database Engineer for ChannelAdvisor and is blogging about his current experiences at sqljared.com</description>
      <twitter>sqljared</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jared-poche-51102797</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqljared.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqljared</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107614</importID>
      <name>Rie Irish</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rie lives with her family just north of Atlanta, Georgia.  She worked as a SQL Server DBA, manager  director for over 20 years.  She's worked in many industries including the non-profit sector, education, big pharma, and e-commerce. She was awarded the MVP in the Data Platform 3 times beginning in 2017 and gave that up to accept her role as a Senior Program Manager with Microsoft in 2019.  She is very involved with the Atlanta MDF User Group, SQL Saturday Atlanta and is co-leader of the PASS Women in Tech virtual group.</description>
      <twitter>IrishSQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rie-irish/2/34a/78/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=IrishSQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108305</importID>
      <name>Wagner Crivelini</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Consultor Sênior da Microsoft, na área de Data  AI para América Latina. Especialista em bancos de dados, é colunista em diversos portais de TI do Brasil e do exterior, com mais de 100 artigos técnicos publicados. É também co-produtor do DatabaseCast, primeiro podcast brasileiro sobre bancos de dados.</description>
      <twitter>@wcrivelini</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/wagner-crivelini-107850</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.databasecast.com.br</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@wcrivelini</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108371</importID>
      <name>Vern Rabe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vern Rabe is an independent SQL Server consultant and contract trainer in Portland, OR, and leader of the Oregon Data Community user group, formerly OregonSQL. He has attained MCSE, MCITP (both Administration and Development), and MCT certifications, among others. Vern has been passionate about databases since 1992 and has worked with SQL Server since version 4.21a. He provides broad technical SQL Server knowledge gained from the mixture of academic and practical experiences acquired from his classroom instructing and varied consulting contracts. Vern regularly presents technical sessions at SQL Server user group meetings, SQLSaturdays, and PASS Summit.</description>
      <twitter>@VernRabe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/vern-rabe/a/ba3/980</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.rabedata.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@VernRabe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108784</importID>
      <name>Adam Saxton</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adam Saxton is just a guy in a cube doing the work! He is on the Power BI CAT team at Microsoft, working with customers to help adopt Power BI. He is based in Texas and started with Microsoft supporting SQL Server connectivity and Reporting Services in 2005. Adam has worked with Power BI since the beginning, on the support side, and with documentation. In addition, he produces weekly videos for his Guy in a Cube YouTube channel.</description>
      <twitter>@GuyInACube</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/guyinacube</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://guyinacube.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@GuyInACube</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108056</importID>
      <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hugo Kornelis is an established SQL Server community expert who spends a lot of time at various conferences. He is author of "the Execution Plan Reference" (sqlserverfast.com/epr), blogger, technical editor of Grant Fritchey's "SQL Server Execution Plans, 3rd edition" and some other books, and Pluralsight author. He was awarded SQL Server MVP and Data Platform MVP 12 times (2006 - 2016, and 2019-present).

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.

When not working for the community, he is busy at his day job: freelance database developer/consultant.

Hugo has over 20 years of SQL Server experience in various roles. He loves to write and tune complex queries, but he also has a strong database design background.</description>
      <twitter>Hugo_Kornelis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://nl.linkedin.com/in/hugokornelis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/hugo_kornelis/default.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Hugo_Kornelis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108178</importID>
      <name>Jamey Johnston</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jamey Johnston is a Senior Data Scientist/Engineer for a large independent OG company. For over 25 years, he has worked for Fortune 500 companies architecting successful platforms in the cloud, on the edge, and on-premises for BI reporting, statistical analysis, ML, and AI. Lately, he spends his time in Azure, Python, R, Power BI, MS SQL, and SAS JMP. He holds a BS in Spatial Analysis from LSU and a Masters of Science in Analytics from Texas AM. He is a professor at the Mays Business School at Texas AM in the MS Analytics program. He is active in his PASS Local Group in Houston, co-leader of the local Power BI users group and data analytics group. He regularly speaks and volunteers at PASS events. He is also a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>STATCowboy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jameyj</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://STATCowboy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=STATCowboy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>108306</importID>
      <name>Wagner Crivelini</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Consultor Sênior da Microsoft, na área de Data  AI para América Latina. Especialista em bancos de dados, é colunista em diversos portais de TI do Brasil e do exterior, com mais de 100 artigos técnicos publicados. É também co-produtor do DatabaseCast, primeiro podcast brasileiro sobre bancos de dados.</description>
      <twitter>@wcrivelini</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/wagner-crivelini-107850</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.databasecast.com.br</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@wcrivelini</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104460</importID>
      <name>Andrew Kalik</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am a Data Engineer at Bind personalized health plans. Over the last ten years or so I have worked as a Data Engineer and Systems Analyst. I have been a member of Oregon Data Community for a few years now, and would like to start giving back through presenting and sharing knowledge in other ways.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107452</importID>
      <name>David Klee</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Klee is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware vExpert with a lifelong passion for technology. David spends his days focusing on the convergence of data and infrastructure as the Founder of Heraflux Technologies. His areas of expertise include cloud, virtualization, performance, and business continuity. David speaks at a number of national and regional technology related events, including PASS Summit, VMware VMworld, SQLBits, SQL Saturday events, and many SQL Server User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>kleegeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidaklee</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://davidklee.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kleegeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107559</importID>
      <name>Joshua Higginbotham</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Joshua Higginbotham, a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, is a Data Services Manager at Republic Bank based out of Louisville, KY.  He's worked in various roles including Software Development, Database Administration, and Business Intelligence.  He’s an active speaker within the SQL community and the Co-Chapter leader of the Louisville SQL Server and Power BI User Group.</description>
      <twitter>codenamesql</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-higginbotham-55625798/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://codenamesql.blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=codenamesql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107621</importID>
      <name>Deepthi Goguri</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Deepthi is a SQL Server Database Administrator with 7+ years of experience in administering SQL Servers. She is a Microsoft certified Trainer and professional with an Associate and Expert level certification in Data Management and Analytics. Deepthi completed her Masters in Computer Technology at Eastern Illinois University. She blog for DBANuggets.com.</description>
      <twitter>dbanuggets</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dbanuggets.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=dbanuggets</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107451</importID>
      <name>David Klee</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Klee is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and VMware vExpert with a lifelong passion for technology. David spends his days focusing on the convergence of data and infrastructure as the Founder of Heraflux Technologies. His areas of expertise include cloud, virtualization, performance, and business continuity. David speaks at a number of national and regional technology related events, including PASS Summit, VMware VMworld, SQLBits, SQL Saturday events, and many SQL Server User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>kleegeek</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/davidaklee</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://davidklee.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kleegeek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107601</importID>
      <name>Matt Gordon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and has worked with SQL Server since 2000. He is the leader of the Lexington, KY PASS local group and a frequent domestic and international community speaker. He's an IDERA ACE alumnus and 2020 Friend of Redgate. His original data professional role was in database development, which quickly evolved into query tuning work that further evolved into being a DBA in the healthcare realm. He has supported several critical systems utilizing SQL Server and managed dozens of 24/7/365 SQL Server implementations. Following several years as a consultant, he is now the Director of Database Management for rev.io, where he is implementing data governance, DevOps, and performance improvements enterprise-wide.</description>
      <twitter>sqlatspeed</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlatspeed</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlatspeed.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlatspeed</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107610</importID>
      <name>Ben Weissman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ben Weissman has been working with SQL Server since SQL Server 6.5, mainly in the BI/Datawarehousing field. He is a Data Platform MVP, MCSE Data Management and Analytics, and a Certified Data Vault Data Modeler. He is also the first BimlHero Certified Expert in Germany and a co-author of  'SQL Server Big Data Clusters' and 'The Biml Book'.
Ben has been involved in more than 150 BI Projects and is always looking for ways to become more productive and make SQL Server even more fun!
Together with his team at Solisyon, Ben provides training, implementation and consultancy for SQL/BI developers and data analysts in upper-mid-market companies around the globe.</description>
      <twitter>bweissman</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://de.linkedin.com/in/weissmanben</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bweissman</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105633</importID>
      <name>Gaston Cruz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Especialista en implementacion de soluciones en Inteligencia de Negocios, con pasion para disenar soluciones corporativas trabajando en equipos distribuidos.

Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) in Data Platform.

Business Intelligence (BI) - Consultorias Estrategicas
BI Arquitectura
Technology Feasibility Analysis 
Data Management /Governance Roadmap 
BI Program Management 
Data Quality Management and Analy

Especializaciones: Business Intelligence Solution / Technical Architect , SSIS , SSRS ,SSAS, SQL Server 2008 R2, 2012 , 2014, Power BI, Power View, Office 365, SharePoint 2013, Power View, Power Pivot ,Power Query, Power Map

Ultimas experiencias en tecnologias Microsoft:
Power BI, Power View, Power Pivot, Power Qu</description>
      <twitter>gastonfcruz</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gaston-cruz-01bb434b/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.gastoncruz.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=gastonfcruz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105862</importID>
      <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Over 30 years in the computing field as a developer and system integrator; over 20 years working with SQL Server since version 6; cross platform experience with Oracle and IBM SQL/DS and DB2; Microsoft Certified Trainer for over 20 years.</description>
      <twitter>arlacerda</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armando-lacerda</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=arlacerda</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104634</importID>
      <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tracy Boggiano is a Senior Database Administrator for DocuSIgn. She has spent over 20 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1999, and is currently certified as an MCSE Data Platform. Tracy has worked on SQL Server since 6.5. She has spoken at local user groups and numerous SQLSaturdays. She is currently a co-leader of a TriPASS Local Group in Raleigh, NC.   

Tracy also tinkered with databases in middle school to keep her sports card collection organized. She blogs at databasesuperhero.com. 

Her passion outside of SQL Server is volunteering with foster children as their advocate in court through volunteerforgal.org and being a mental health advocate as part of the PAIMI NC Advisory Council.</description>
      <twitter>TracyBoggiano</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyboggiano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://databasesuperhero.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TracyBoggiano</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107597</importID>
      <name>Erin Dempster</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erin currently serves as a SQL Developer II at Trean Corporation in Wayzata, Minnesota.  With over 15 years of experience with SQL Server, as a developer and as an administrator, she has dabbled with most areas in the SQL Server realm.  Areas of expertise include database design, query tuning and SQL Server Integration Services.</description>
      <twitter>https://www.twitter.com/em_dempster</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/erin-dempster-55967b6</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.endlessreporting.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://www.twitter.com/em_dempster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>107611</importID>
      <name>Rob Sewell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rob was once a production SQL Server DBA, but is now generally found automating the Data Platform and providing training for clients. He has a passion for PowerShell, Data, and DevOps. He is an MVP, an officer for the DevOps PowerShell VG, and has spoken and volunteered at many PowerShell and Data events. He is a member of the committee that organises Data In Devon and the European PowerShell Conference. He is a proud supporter of the Data and PowerShell communities. 
 
He relishes sharing and learning and can be found doing both via Twitter @sqldbawithbeard and his blog sqldbawithabeard.com. He spends most of his time looking at a screen and loves to solve problems.</description>
      <twitter>sqldbawithbeard</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/robsewellsqldba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqldbawithabeard.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqldbawithbeard</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>104634</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104634</id>
          <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Learning, Certification and Career Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mental Health in IT: Safeguarding our most precious resource</title>
      <description>One in four Americans suffers from a mental health challenge each year. In the tech community, this number rises to 42%. The stigma associated with discussions around mental health, as well as how it can negatively impact your work and home life, make people reluctant to discuss the topic. Now is the time to start discussing mental health in tech and how to take advantage of the opportunity to safeguard our most precious resource: people. We'll discuss how mental health affects job quality, including sharing examples from my professional life. We'll discuss the four primary workplace factors which play a pivotal role in mental health challenges in the tech community. I'll provide tips on what is best to say and not say to people you know whose lives are being affected by their mental health. Lastly, we'll cover how to make your workplace a safe place where mental health can be talked about and how to encourage your company to offer resources to help maintain everyone's mental health.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 6:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105851</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105851</id>
          <name>Michael McKinley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 7</name>
      </location>
      <title>Basic Data Modeling for BI Reporting</title>
      <description>We all start using business intelligence tools by using a single dataset, like a flat file.  Then, we hit a plateau in our learning curve, or we add a second flat file into our BI product, and we get incorrect results.  One reason is that we haven't modeled our solution correctly.

In order to move to the next level of our journey along the BI learning curve, we need to understand how a tool like Power BI works.  Only then will we understand why we design our data models the way we do.

In this session, we will review how tools like Power BI work under the covers and how that impacts the way we construct our data models.  This is an introductory level course, so we will not get too technical, just enough to get us to the next level and moving back up that learning curve!</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 6:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105926</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105926</id>
          <name>Steve Jones</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Tour of Azure DevOps and TFS</title>
      <description>Learning how to orchestrate your software development process can be a challenge, and many people don't know where to start using the tools available. For Microsoft stack developers, Azure DevOps and TFS provide cloud and on-premises tooling to manage your code. 
In this session we will look at the integration of work tracking with Scrum templates and Kanban boards with version control for your code. We will discuss and demonstrate pull requests to help manage the flow of work within a team and explain the build, test, and release tools available for your database and application code. 

At the end of this session, attendees will be more comfortable getting started with their own project in Azure DevOps and using the tools with their own team.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107452</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107452</id>
          <name>David Klee</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Modern SQL Server CPU Architectures for Performance</title>
      <description>Modern CPU architectures are complex and misunderstood, especially as they relate to SQL Server instance configuration and database usage patterns. Default values in virtualization and the SQL Server instance can cause misalignments and improper balance in the way the SQL Server lines up with the CPUs and memory, which results in an immediate (and silent) performance penalty. Come learn as we discuss topics such as physical and virtual NUMA, hyperthreading, query parallelism, public cloud CPU selection, and SQL Server instance settings, and show you how to validate your SQL Server architecture and improve the performance of your critical SQL Servers for both on-prem and cloud-based SQL Servers.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107610</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107610</id>
          <name>Ben Weissman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2019 Big Data Clusters: Make SQL Server your Data Hub for everything</title>
      <description>In the realm of data storage and processing, there are two major technologies which we deal with every day. On one side, we have relational data that is stored inside SQL Server, and on the other side, non-relational or very large datasets that do not fit the relational model which are stored on big data clusters like Hadoop or Spark. 
This introduces challenges when having to combine datasets across both these technologies. SQL Server was never built to process huge datasets in a distributed fashion or to handle non-relational data very well, meaning that in many cases you would have to resort to bringing your relational data into Hadoop or Spark clusters. 
SQL Server 2019 has the answer with Big Data Clusters: it combines SQL Server with HDFS and Spark!

In this session we are going to explore the capabilities of the exciting new feature. How does it work and how can we work with datasets that are non-relational?</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 6:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 7:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107199</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107199</id>
          <name>Itshak David</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data virtualization with  SQL Server 2019  PolyBase and integration with Power BI .</title>
      <description>In this session we will learn about the improvements to PolyBase in SQL Server 2019, which allows you to extend the querying capability to data sources like SQL Server, Oracle, MongoDB, Redis, Hadoop CDH, and other data sources. You also get insights on the design, capabilities, and performance advantages of PolyBase, save ETL Processes as follows: 
•	Installing and Configuring PolyBase Windows  Linux 
•	Connecting to Hadoop 
•	 Using Predicate Pushdown to Enhance Query Performance 
•	Packet Capture With\Without Predicate Pushdown 
•	When to use Predicate Pushdown 
•	Limitations on Pushdown with Complex Filters 
•	Built-In Integrations: Oracle, MongoDB , Radis and More Integrating via ODBC : Apache Spark , Apache Hive, Microsoft Excel Monitor PolyBase with Dynamic Management Views . 
•	PolyBase Query Tuning , Execution Plans and Statistics PolyBase Scenarios : ETL VS ELT jobs 
This is  a demo session only with minimum theory  lessons from the fields   !</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104552</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104552</id>
          <name>Jason Horner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 7</name>
      </location>
      <title>Real-World Data Movement and Orchestration Patterns using Azure Data Factory</title>
      <description>In this session, we will start with an overview of Azure Data Factory concepts, then show you how you can use metadata to quickly build scalable serverless pipelines to move data from disparate data sources including On-Premises and Platform As A Service. Next, we will look at how to integrate the solution using continuous integration and deployment techniques. Finally, we will look at how to schedule, monitor and log our solution.
Whether you are just getting started with Azure Data Factory or looking to make your current data factory robust and enterprise-ready this session will take you to the next level.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107635</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107635</id>
          <name>William Assaf</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Learning, Certification and Career Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Certification Exams Inside Out</title>
      <description>Preparing for Microsoft certification? Do you want insight into how certification exams are written, how questions are designed, and how to follow a logical process of elimination? We'll go through the process of item creation from an item writer's viewpoint, what rules item writers must follow, and why questions sometimes have strange phrasing. For any technical skillset pursuing certification, we'll review non-technical sample questions and walk through the process of using information at your disposal. You'll better understand how to deconstruct the problem statement. We'll leave time for QA with a veteran of the Microsoft certification exam writing process.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 6:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 7:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107629</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107629</id>
          <name>Scott Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 8</name>
      </location>
      <title>The ins and outs of securing SQL Server traffic</title>
      <description>We are frequently hearing of an enterprise-size business being hacked, data being stolen, or data being exploited. Data security has always been important, but it should not be taken for granted. Data is information, and one of the greatest assets to a business, and when it is compromised, things go south quickly.

While there are multiple levels of security (securing data at rest, data in traffic, etc.), this session will focus on securing data that is on the move; ie., securing traffic between a client and server. We'll discuss and look at two solutions: Certificates and IPsec, exploring them in detail, outlining the pros and cons of each, how to set up and configure them, and when to use what.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107573</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107573</id>
          <name>Will Velida</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Developing Cosmos DB for the Enterprise</title>
      <description>Azure Cosmos DB is an awesome multi-model database service that allows us to distribute our data on a global scale. It's fairly easy to get started with Cosmos DB, but when it comes to implementing it for use within our Enterprise applications, there are many things that you will want to consider when developing a Cosmos DB database.

In this session, I'll cover important topics that you'll want to consider when developing and administrating Cosmos DB for Enterprise use, including security considerations, partitioning, provisioning throughput for your databases and collections, distributing your data and much more.

By the end of this session, you should be able to take these learnings and apply them when developing Cosmos DB applications for your business.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 6:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107559</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107559</id>
          <name>Joshua Higginbotham</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 8</name>
      </location>
      <title>Common ETL Patterns using Azure Databricks</title>
      <description>Are you an ETL Developer still working on-premises and trying to figure out where some of the cloud options fit, then come to this session where we will cover some of the common ETL patterns we find on-premises in Azure Databricks.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 6:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 7:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107621</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107621</id>
          <name>Deepthi Goguri</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Engine: Its Working Style</title>
      <description>Many DBA's and Developers work with SQL Server but don’t fully understand how it really works behind the scenes. Join Deepthi on her dive into the internals of SQL Server to explain why knowing what goes on under the covers will help you make better decisions quickly when solving performance problems in SQL Server. This session will cover ACID properties, key components of the Relational Engine, Storage engine, Cache and the Transaction manager. We will also cover what happens  under the covers during read and write operations within SQL Server. 
Deepthi will show you how the SQL engine thinks – enabling you to think like it!</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105725</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105725</id>
          <name>Julie Koesmarno</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Notebooks 101 for SQL People</title>
      <description>Are you a database developer, a DBA or a data analyst? Do you find spending quite a bit of time trying to reproduce analysis or reproduce issues and the troubleshooting techniques? This Notebooks 101 session is for you!

The lack of rigor in being able to reproduce analysis in business context or to reproduce data troubleshooting can lead to confusion and time wasted on work that had been previously done. With Notebooks, Data Professionals can share their techniques and data sources used for the data analysis or troubleshooting for code review and reproducible insights/troubleshooting. 

Azure Data Studio Notebooks support SQL and KQL natively with intellisense; with easy to use charting capabilities. With Notebooks and Jupyter Book (collection of Notebooks) in Azure Data Studio, it’s also easy now for your team to build an onboarding guide (user manual) / documentation on data sources, useful sample scripts and tutorials.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 6:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107497</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107497</id>
          <name>Jared Poché</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Every Millisecond Counts</title>
      <description>Query optimization is relatively easy when you look at a plan and find table scans, hash match joins, and missing indexes. But how do you find opportunities when all the low hanging fruit has been picked?
This session is a case study on improving a procedure that runs 350 million times per day, so any improvement is greatly magnified. We will discuss where we found opportunities to improve a procedure running in 3.1 milliseconds; how effective our attempts were, what didn't work, and the results achieved.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107611</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107611</id>
          <name>Rob Sewell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Jupyter Notebooks for DBAs</title>
      <description>Jupyter Notebooks were once the realm of Data Scientists. New releases of Azure Data Studio, Visual Studio Code, and .NET interactive tooling have brought this tooling into the Operational team's area. The biggest benefit of using Jupyter Notebooks is that you have your documentation, your code __and__ your results in the same source controllable document.

I will share with you all of the knowledge I have gained over the past 12 months implementing Jupyter Notebooks for Data Operation teams.

You will leave  
- with a good understanding of possible use cases for Jupyter Notebooks
- being comfortable in using the different tooling
- with many examples that you can take back to work and start being effective immediately

Enabling collaboration with your team, simplifying common tasks, improving Incident Wash-Up meetings, creating run-books, easily creating code for others to use are some of the benefits that you will take away. 
We will have fun as well.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107451</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107451</id>
          <name>David Klee</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>10 Cloudy Questions to Ask Before Migrating Your SQL Server</title>
      <description>Cloud adoption of database-related services continues to accelerate, but the choices for which service to select – IaaS, DBaaS, and PaaS – all impact the features available to your applications. Selecting a service is a critical first step in the migration process, and selecting poorly can lead to cost overruns and significant time spent going down the wrong path. The questions you do not ask or consider prior to a migration can make or break your cloud experience. The most important ten questions to answer, such as your availability requirements, database-level dependencies, migration strategies, and other critical concerns, will all be discussed so that you are ready to move to the cloud with confidence in your platform of choice.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107514</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107514</id>
          <name>Reid Havens</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Development, Modeling and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 6</name>
      </location>
      <title>Guiding User Experiences With Advanced Reporting Features</title>
      <description>As Power BI continues to innovate with new features that enhance the user experience, it is more important than ever to understand what's available to configure for the report consumer experience. Learn about advanced features such as: bookmark capture states and uses, button configurations and formatting, report tooltip applications, and the wide applicability of measure based formatting.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 10:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107614</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107614</id>
          <name>Rie Irish</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>10 DBA Tasks for Azure SQL: Whats Different from On-Prem</title>
      <description>Adoption of Cloud is at an all time high, with no end in sight. Managing a small fleet of databases on-premises was something you used to understand. In this session, we'll cover the 10 most common tasks a DBA needs to learn to manage in Azure SQL as well as they currently manage their On Prem installs. One of the great things about Azure SQL is that the skill set your team has developed over the years translates well. The tools and technologies you're familiar with are all there. So much is the same but some of the tasks that DBAs do are different.  We'll familiarize everyone with ten of the tasks that are different including demo.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107114</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107114</id>
          <name>Patrick Gallucci</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Build a Complete Azure Data Platform in 1 Hour</title>
      <description>Migrating Data and Analytic workloads to Azure gives organizations the ability to innovate faster with the Azure Data Platform. To unlock the potential, it typically takes months to architect, engineer, and deploy a Modern Data and Analytics Platform in Azure. Even with a prescriptive approach for cloud adoption, many organizations are not equipped to take on the full scope of responsibility required to leverage the all-up capabilities they have acquired as a result of the project.
Patrick Gallucci will share a service delivery approach that helps organizations move large and small data platforms to Azure. He will show you how to leverage proven cloud adoption methodologies, tools, resources, and best practices to enable your organization to simplify and accelerate their move to the cloud.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 5:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107601</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107601</id>
          <name>Matt Gordon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Learning, Certification and Career Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>From Stutterer to Speaker: Overcoming Your Fears</title>
      <description>Are you terrified of public speaking? For 37 years of my life, I was too! That paralyzing fear of public communication held me back and kept me taking from taking advantage of career and community opportunities that came my way - and I've heard this story from many. Now, when I speak at community events, I'm often asked how I got into speaking and how I got over my fears of public speaking. In this free-wheeling session I'll tell you the tips and tricks that I took to heart to go from a kid in speech therapy to somebody that volunteers to speak in front of people and actually enjoys it. Most importantly, I'll talk about how improved personal and public communication can give your career a massive boost in this time of rapid growth in the data professional realm. I sincerely hope this session helps encourage people to overcome their fears of public and small group speaking - or that you at least enjoy making fun of pictures of 6-year-old me in speech therapy headphones!</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108056</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108056</id>
          <name>Hugo Kornelis</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Tuning and Optimization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Execution plans ... where do I start?</title>
      <description>SQL (the language) is not a third generation language, where the developer tells the computer every step it needs to take. It is a declarative language that specifies the required results. SQL Server itself will figure out what steps it takes to get to those results. Most of the time, that works very well.

But sometimes it doesn’t. Sometimes a query takes too much time. You need to find out why, so you can fix it. That’s where the execution plan comes in. In the execution plan, SQL Server exposes exactly which steps it took for your query, so you can see why it’s slow.

However, execution plans can be daunting to the uninitiated. Especially for complex queries. Where do you even start?

In this session you will learn how to obtain execution plans. and how to start reading and understanding them.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108371</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108371</id>
          <name>Vern Rabe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Proper Data Type Usage=Guaranteed Better Performance and Accuracy</title>
      <description>It’s an all too common occurrence to have table columns or variables that have been assigned less than ideal data types. 

In this demo-heavy presentation I will show you the importance of choosing the proper data type; show you some guidelines in determining what an appropriate data type would be; and once chosen, give you some tools for its usage and management. I will demonstrate several performance and accuracy issues, along with their possible solutions, caused by either the assignment of inappropriate data types or improper usage of them. In addition I will cover several data type related functions, and point out caveats in their usage. I expect even advanced T-SQL developers and DBAs to walk away with a useful nugget or two.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105042</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105042</id>
          <name>Kevin Boles</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Tuning and Optimization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Common TSQL Mistakes</title>
      <description>We are going to examine a variety of oopsies MANY developers fall prey too - some obvious, some pretty subtle and some down right sneaky! Lots of code examples with the bad AND good code presented. I GUARANTEE that you will find things here that will either prevent you from getting bad data, throwing unwanted errors or vastly improving your database application's performance.  I have given this talk over 100 times now and it is always very highly rated!</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108322</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108322</id>
          <name>Dennes Torres</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2019: More Intelligent than ever</title>
      <description>After Adaptive Query Processing in SQL Server 2017 now we have Intelligent Query Processing on the preview versions of SQL Server 2019.

What is it? What benefits it brings to us? What's the relation with Adaptive Query Processing, from SQL Server 2017?

Attending this session you will discover these answers and more</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 6:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 7:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108068</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108068</id>
          <name>Jose Manuel Jurado Diaz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 7</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Managed Instance - Experiences from the Field</title>
      <description>In this pre-conference you will learn the best practices, tips and tricks on how to successfully use Azure SQL Managed Instance  on production environments. You will learn how to monitor, configure, restore, backup, VNET, NGS, created a replication environment, etc for Azure SQL Managed Instance. These learnings are fruit of Microsoft CSS support cases, and customer field engagements.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108114</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108114</id>
          <name>Ondrej Aubrecht</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Learning, Certification and Career Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Can you trust the intelligence of Application tracking systems with your CV?</title>
      <description>An applicant tracking system (ATS) is a software application that enables to handle candidate profiles and could scan and analyse the Resumes (CV's).

This session will answer some of the unspoken questions:
    - Can you trust ATS with your CV ?
    - Can ATS analyse your Resume correctly (with Real examples) ?
    - How ATS works?

Come along to this session and find out more about REAL DATA analysis and scanning mechanism by multiple ATS used in the job market and to find out if you can trust AI with your own CV.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108098</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108098</id>
          <name>Edward Pollack</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dynamic SQL: Writing Efficient Queries on the Fly</title>
      <description>Dynamic SQL is a powerful tool that allows for the creation of fast and efficient queries when the specifics may not be known until run-time. This tool can be used to automate complex processes, facilitate reporting on an unknown number of targets, or perform tasks that would otherwise be time-consuming to develop.

This is an often misunderstood tool that is underused in areas where it can provide immense value or abused by applications that it was never intended for. Well-written dynamic SQL can solve seemingly impossible problems while being easy to read and understand.

Applications that will be demonstrated include: mapping database relationships, schema searching, generating large volumes of TSQL, and much more. Explore the many uses for dynamic SQL as well as best practices for writing, testing, debugging, and maintaining it!</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 6:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 7:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107634</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107634</id>
          <name>William Assaf</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Development, Modeling and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 6</name>
      </location>
      <title>Ethics in Modern Data</title>
      <description>This session will explore a variety of considerations that modern data scientists and data practitioners must account for when gathering and presenting data, including topics on bias, construct analysis, and machine learning.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108178</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108178</id>
          <name>Jamey Johnston</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis and Machine Learning</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI dataflows and How to Leverage for Data Science</title>
      <description>This session will give you an introduction to Power BI dataflows and how to leverage the data for data science. Power BI dataflows allow for self service data migration into Azure Data Lake Services gen 2 utilizing Power Query. 

This session will show how to use dataflows, setup Azure Data Lake Services gen 2 and dataflows and how to connect to the resulting data in the Azure Data Lake Services gen 2 to do Data Science with tools like Azure Databricks.

This session will use real data and analytics to demonstrate Power BI dataflows, Azure Data Lake Services gen2 and Azure Databricks utilizing DAX, M and Python.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 6:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105571</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105571</id>
          <name>Amit R S Bansal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Troubleshoot a Slow Running Query in SQL Server</title>
      <description>You always wanted to troubleshoot a slow running query. But you just don’t know where to begin. In this demo-heavy session, I will show you how to troubleshoot a slow running query. You will see an end-to-end query tuning example with a slow running workload. We will capture important metrics while the workload is running and then use the captured data to troubleshoot query performance issues. The technique you will learn can be applied to production straight away. This will be a 100% demo session.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 6:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 7:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108784</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108784</id>
          <name>Adam Saxton</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 8</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI QA/AMA with GuyInACube  Microsoft Leaders</title>
      <description>Join "Guy In A Cube" stars and Microsoft product leaders for this rare "Ask Me Anything" QA session. Adam Saxton and Patrick LeBlanc from Microsoft are bringing their wildly-popular weekly live QA chat to Oregon SQL. Matthew Roche from the Customer Advisory Team (CAT) and Chris Finlan,  Paginated Reports team lead, will answer your questions and provide the inside scoop about the platform direction and best practices. In addition to the CAT team representation, bear sightings are likely.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105535</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105535</id>
          <name>Ramesh Satya</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 8</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding SQL Server Views - The Right Way</title>
      <description>VIEW is one of the programmable objects often used by Developers to build solutions to business problems but if not used without complete implications, there will be data inconsistency issues. This session focusses on how to create VIEWs, what are issues while doing DML operations through the VIEWS and how does INDEXED VIEWs help us.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 6:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105862</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105862</id>
          <name>Armando Lacerda</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 7</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Synapse back to back</title>
      <description>Azure Synapse provides a complete platform to ingest and process data at scale in the cloud. In this workshop we will be learning and applying its features to all stages of data processing and understanding best practices and pitfalls. From ingesting to data lakes to transform data in big data services to apply machine learning models, including data remodeling, this workshop will guide to through a full implementation of Azure Synapse all the way to presentation and reporting.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105534</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105534</id>
          <name>Ramesh Satya</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 6</name>
      </location>
      <title>Understanding NULLs in SQL Server</title>
      <description>SQL Server follows three-valued logic (3VL) (instead of Boolean logic) to evaluate any condition to True or False or Unknown. Unknown value in SQL Server is represented as NULL. NULLs in SQL Server are often misunderstood and causes data inconsistency issues. In this session, we will try to go through different test cases to understand NULLs properly.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105797</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105797</id>
          <name>Rahat Yasir</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Automated machine learning with Azure AutoML</title>
      <description>AutomatedML is the process of automating the time consuming, iterative tasks of machine learning model development. It allows data scientists, analysts, and developers to build ML models with high scale, efficiency, and productivity all while sustaining model quality. Automated ML democratizes the machine learning model development process, and empowers its users, no matter their data science expertise, to identify an end-to-end machine learning pipeline for any problem. In this session, we will talk about Automated Machine Leanring process and also will give step by step demo of Azure AutoML.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104460</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104460</id>
          <name>Andrew Kalik</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Python: Turn your SQL ETL up to 11</title>
      <description>Almost everywhere you look in the data community you see Python being used (job-postings, Azure Services, AWS Service etc…). But what is Python, and why has it become such a popular tool for Data Professionals? During this discussion we will talk about what is Python, why is it being used so heavily, what benefits it provides, and what is in store for future uses of Python. There will be demos using Jupyter Notebooks doing data analysis, importing data into database (ETL), and light visualization.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 6:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108305</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108305</id>
          <name>Wagner Crivelini</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Development, Modeling and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 6</name>
      </location>
      <title>First Steps to Work with Graphs in AZURE SQL DB</title>
      <description>This is an introductory presentation over Graph concepts: modeling, querying, and presenting data in POWER BI. A demo will present how to implement the model in AZURE SQL DB, basic notions of querying data and how to visualize Graphs in a dashboard.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 6:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 7:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105633</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105633</id>
          <name>Gaston Cruz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 5</name>
      </location>
      <title>New waves to Processing Tabular Models</title>
      <description>We are going to cover options to process our models using different methods. Create an app registration to use as a service principal and then link Azure Data Factory, and Logic Apps to process our DB/Tables/Partitions in Azure Analysis Services</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105900</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105900</id>
          <name>Javier Villegas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Monitoring SQL Server using Community solutions (Free)</title>
      <description>In this session we will cover how to monitor and support any SQL Server Environment using free tools created by community members</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108306</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108306</id>
          <name>Wagner Crivelini</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 8</name>
      </location>
      <title>Implementing Cryptography in AZURE SQL DB with Geo-Replication</title>
      <description>Geo-replication assumes you are going to use a redundant architecture to improve availability. This presentation shows what to consider when implementing Transparent Data Encryption (TDE) and Always Encrypted in this scenario.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105721</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105721</id>
          <name>Harry Chandra</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to PowerShell for the DBAs</title>
      <description>In this demo-filled session, we will go through everything you need to start using PowerShell to automate your day-to-day tasks as a DBA. We will go through the tools you need such as PowerShell IDE  Visual Studio Code. We will be using the Microsoft SqlServer PowerShell module and the very popular and powerful community-driven, DBATools module. We will walk through the process of building a script to do a simple task from start to finish. By the end of the session, you will have the confidence, knowledge and tools to start your journey in automating your day-to-day tasks using PowerShell.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 8:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>108320</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>108320</id>
          <name>Dennes Torres</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 7</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why Synapse Analytics is beyond Azure SQL Datawarehouse</title>
      <description>Synapse Analytics is being announced as the new name of Azure SQL Datawarehouse, but it's not only that. There is a broader view in Synapse analytics, beyond Azure SQL Datawarehouse. Let's see in this session what was improved, what changed, and how synapse analytics fits in the data platform.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107357</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107357</id>
          <name>Andrea Mascher</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Learning, Certification and Career Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SELECT Questions FROM Diversity.Inclusion WHERE AfraidToAsk = 1</title>
      <description>In the past several years Diversity, Equity,  Inclusion (DEI) have become more important and visible in the workplace.  Studies have shown that organizations are often more successful when they are more diverse, yet the tech sector is moving slowly to improve representation and inclusion.  Many IT professionals want to improve but don't know where to start.  

This session will cover key concepts in DEI and how they apply to data practitioners.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 7:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 9:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107582</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107582</id>
          <name>Rui Romano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Tips, Tricks  Hacks from the Trenches</title>
      <description>Power BI is an amazing BI platform out of the box, but there' is a lot of things that you can do with Power BI that probably you dont even imagine! 

This session is a collection of my top tips, tricks  hacks gathered over the years from simple tips to advanced hacks to boost your productivity.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107597</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107597</id>
          <name>Erin Dempster</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 8</name>
      </location>
      <title>Navigating Row Level Security</title>
      <description>New to SQL Server 2016 (okay, it's a few years old already, but it still feels new) is Row Level Security, which allows database developers and architects to effectively lock down tables, giving users access to a defined subset of data in the table.  It sounds easy enough, but there are a number of design considerations and pitfalls to be aware of.  This session will work through a few demos to implement RLS and dive into those pitfalls that need to be avoided.  For anyone considering implementing Row Level Security or have tried but have run into issues, this should be a session you want to attend.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>107915</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>107915</id>
          <name>Paul Turley</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Development, Modeling and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 6</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Modeling Solutions for Challenging BI Data Modeling Problems</title>
      <description>Sorry to break the news but the world is not flat and neither is business data. Data modeling is an essential skill in Power BI design and hard problems require creative solutions. In this session, we will enumerate common challenges and demonstrate modeling techniques to resolve them. Session topics: implementing star and snowflake schema essentials, role-playing tables, many-to-many and bi-directional filters, working without relationships, disconnected lookup tables and calculation groups. We will also discuss the composite models and the future of BI data modeling.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 5:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105815</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105815</id>
          <name>Mark Runyon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Learning, Certification and Career Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 6</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Countless Benefits of Mentoring</title>
      <description>Mentoring offers countless benefits to the mentee, mentor and the organization as a whole. In this session, we will map out the benefits to each participant as well as talk about how to find a mentor or how to start a mentorship program in your organization.</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 5:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 6:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105524</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105524</id>
          <name>David Patrick</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Track 7</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to Power BI</title>
      <description>For anyone new to Power BI, we'll cover all the main features and walk through getting data into the tool (using both the desktop and online versions), creating visualizations, turning them into reports and adding them to dashboards. When we're through we'll have several BI components available to share via the Cloud!</description>
      <startTime>10/24/2020 6:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>10/24/2020 7:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>