<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #584 - Colorado Springs 2017</name>
    <startDate>3/25/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-07:00) Mountain Time (US and Canada)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#SQLSATCOS</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Colorado Technical University</name>
      <street>4435 North Chestnut Street</street>
      <city>Colorado Springs</city>
      <state>Colorado</state>
      <zipcode>80907</zipcode>
      <longitude>-104.833662509918</longitude>
      <latitude>38.893326186488</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>607</importID>
      <name>DELL EMC</name>
      <label>Platinum Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.dellemc.com/en-us/index.htm</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/913/EventSponsor_14262.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1431</importID>
      <name>Colorado Technical University</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.coloradotech.edu</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/Portals/444/SponsorImages/ColoradoTechnicalUniversity.PNG</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/908/EventSponsor_14257.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14586.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1005</importID>
      <name>RevGen Partners</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.revgenpartners.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.revgenpartners.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/logo-300x70.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54601</importID>
      <name>Cher Fox</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cher Fox has 30 years of programming experience, including 25 years in analytics  technical writing, and 15 years specializing in DW  BI in multiple industries.  She has held the corporate positions of Customer Services Manager for an international SW development group, IT Manager for a national risk management company,  is currently the CEO/Principal Consultant of Fox Consulting, a Denver based firm specializing in high level management process re-engineering, DW  BI consulting.  

Ms. Fox is passionate about reverse engineering BI challenges to improve data quality  reliability, improving performance in DW/BI processes as well as automating clients out of spreadsheet madness  time consuming manual processes.</description>
      <twitter>TheDatanista</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cherfox</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://foxconsulting.co</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TheDatanista</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59810</importID>
      <name>Michael Fal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mike is a specialist in data management technologies. As a community advocate, public speaker, and blogger, Mike is a practicing thought leader for data and automation. He is passionate about DevOps and data, building platforms to optimize, protect, and use data efficiently.

Since 1999, Mike has been working in the database field, focusing primarily on SQL Server and specializes in automating data solutions to improve the reliability and efficiency of his environments. He has been caught playing trombone in public on more than one occasion.</description>
      <twitter>@Mike_Fal</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelfal/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mikefal.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Mike_Fal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54558</importID>
      <name>Thane Schaffer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thane has over 25 years of IT experience focusing on software development during much of his career.  In recent years has focused on database development, architect/design, modeling, administration, and ETO/MTO focused ERP systems.  His current position, as a DBA at Transcore in Albuquerque NM, provides opportunities to do much of everything that a database generalist would enjoy doing.</description>
      <twitter>@thaneschaffer</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/thane-schaffer-8740041a</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlambassador.blogspot.com/    http://viserpdev.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@thaneschaffer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57553</importID>
      <name>Patrick Geselbracht</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Patrick Geselbracht is a Solution Principal with Slalom Consulting.  His expertise is in Data Warehousing, ETL, Master Data Management, Meta Data Management, Data Governance, Cubes, Reports, Dashboards  Mobile BI.  He specializes on the Microsoft SQL Server Business Intelligence tool suite including SSIS, SSRS, SSAS (multidimensional and tabular), SSRS, DQS, MDS, and Power BI.  As a consultant, Patrick has Industry Experience in Oil  Gas, Healthcare, Telecommunication, Insurance, Restaurant, Media,  Automotive.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/patrick-geselbracht-4b7aa45</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56566</importID>
      <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kellyn Pot’Vin-Gorman is a member of the Oak Table Network and an Idera ACE and Oracle ACE Director alumnus. She is a Data Platform Architect in Power BI with AI in the EdTech group at Microsoft. Kellyn is known for her extensive work with multi-database platforms, DevOps, cloud migrations, virtualization, visualizations, scripting, environment optimization tuning, automation, and architecture design. 

Kellyn has spoken at numerous technical conferences for Oracle, Big Data, DevOps, testing, and SQL Server. Her blog (http://dbakevlar.com) and social media activity under her handle, DBAKevlar, is well respected for her insight and content.</description>
      <twitter>DBAKevlar</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellynpotvin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dbakevlar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBAKevlar</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56297</importID>
      <name>David Brown</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Brown is a huge data nerd. His technical focus is on ambitiously lazy development. He leads the local Seattle Modern Excel user group, and helps local data junkies solve their problems using simple BI technologies. His current focus is on machine learning amp; predictive analytics, and he#39;s helped many companies implement predictive analytics on top of SQL server technology within their organization as a consultant. If you want to figure out how to drive consensus and implement predictive analytics in your organization, he can help.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/browndavebrown</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>60965</importID>
      <name>Reeves Smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Reeves Smith, owner and principal architect of Macer Consulting, is passionate about applying data technologies that empower organizations. Reeves wields his knowledge and experience to lead, design, architect, and teach, working with both data center and business project teams. He approaches every project by first understanding the organization’s business challenges, and then developing a unique approach that targets those business needs accurately and effectively.

Reeves Smith has more than 20 years of experience working on the SQL Server stack. He is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and Microsoft Certified Master, and regularly delivers technical presentations at international, regional, and local conferences and user groups.</description>
      <twitter>SQLReeves</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/reevessmithiii/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://reevessmith.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLReeves</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54542</importID>
      <name>Steve Wake</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Wake is currently the Principal BI Developer at Brown and Caldwell and has experience in consulting, advertising, media, manufacturing, retail, charities, telecommunications and financial services organizations using the full on-premises Microsoft BI stack. Recent experience with the Azure services: Analysis Services, Logic Apps,  Data Factory, Databricks, Snowflake and Power BI. Steve is also very involved in the SQL community, speaking at events around the world.</description>
      <twitter>stevewake</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/b5lurker</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.wakebi.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=stevewake</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56503</importID>
      <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tracy Boggiano is a Senior Database Administrator for DocuSIgn. She has spent over 20 years in IT, using SQL Server since 1999, and is currently certified as an MCSE Data Platform. Tracy has worked on SQL Server since 6.5. She has spoken at local user groups and numerous SQLSaturdays. She is currently a co-leader of a TriPASS Local Group in Raleigh, NC.   

Tracy also tinkered with databases in middle school to keep her sports card collection organized. She blogs at databasesuperhero.com. 

Her passion outside of SQL Server is volunteering with foster children as their advocate in court through volunteerforgal.org and being a mental health advocate as part of the PAIMI NC Advisory Council.</description>
      <twitter>TracyBoggiano</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyboggiano</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://databasesuperhero.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TracyBoggiano</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54567</importID>
      <name>Adam Koehler</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Adam Koehler is the Senior Database Administrator for ScriptPro, LLC.  He has worked with SQL Server from 7.0 to 2017 in various roles throughout his career with the last 14 years in a DBA role.</description>
      <twitter>sql_geek</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/adam-j-koehler</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sql_geek</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59808</importID>
      <name>Michelle Poolet</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michelle Poolet, MCIS and Zachman Certified Enterprise Architect(tm), has been working with Microsoft SQL Server(tm) since version 6.0. She has authored many articles for SQLMag(tm). She created and delivered classes in Database Design, Theory amp; Programming at University of Denver. A founder of Mount Vernon Data Systems, Michelle is currently focusing on SQL Server database administration, OLTP engine performance/tuning, database architecture, and data modeling.
</description>
      <twitter>#SQLinTheCloud</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michellepoolet</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mountvernondatasystems.com/blog.html</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=#SQLinTheCloud</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59710</importID>
      <name>Christopher Wolff</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Wolff has been a developer, report writer, and an admin in Microsoft and SQL Server Space since SQL Server 2000 in industries such as telecommunications, green energy, money transfers, and online accounting. He has been an active member of the Denver SQL User Group since 2011 and enjoys learning new things about computers. His interests includes video games, movies, and enjoying time with his wife and 2 kids.</description>
      <twitter>@tickytong</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/christopher-wolff/11/a07/458</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlred.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tickytong</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61075</importID>
      <name>Rick Lowe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick is a Microsoft Certified Master with more than 20 years of SQL Server experience in a variety of roles. He currently lives in Washington state and works as an independent consultant providing remote performance DBA and performance tuning services for clients in the USA and Canada. His first exposure to SQL Server was as a database developer, but over time he became more and more interested in how the database engine operated... eventually specializing more on performance issues than code.

Rick will work with all things relational, but most enjoys helping smaller companies get better performance from MSSQL, as well as smoothing over relationships between DBA and development teams.</description>
      <twitter>DataFLowe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rick-lowe/a/228/441/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataflowe.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataFLowe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56842</importID>
      <name>Tim Gorman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tim Gorman is a senior technical consultant for Delphix who securely enables masked data virtualization to increase the agility of IT development and testing while ending decades of security risk in SDLC.

Tim has co-authored six books on data warehousing and database administration, has performed technical review on eight more books, and has an author#39;s page on Amazon.com (http://www.amazon.com/Tim-Gorman/e/B00BKCTO5E).</description>
      <twitter>@TimGormanTech</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timgorman</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://evdbt.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@TimGormanTech</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57957</importID>
      <name>Warren Sifre</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warren Sifre has been in the IT community since 1998 and has worked in a variety of industries deploying solutions utilizing MS SQL Server in one capacity or another. In 2003, he decided to make SQL Server his mastery and has since developed skills in most defined disciplines of MS SQL.  Currently he is a Principal Consultant and Technology Leader with Moser Consulting.  He is responsible for BI Solution Architecture and the mentorship of team members.  He has been a SQL Saturday Speaker since 2012, Azure Global Bootcamp, and many user groups in 2015 alone.  He has a passion for knowledge transfer and solutions architecture, with a keen interested in Info Security.</description>
      <twitter>WAS_SQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/wsifre</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.broadstrokeconsulting.com/blog/, http://www.allegient.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=WAS_SQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59831</importID>
      <name>Brian Hansen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brian is a database administrator at Children International in Kansas City.  He has been working with SQL Server technologies since 1998, including roles in report development, application development and database administration.</description>
      <twitter>tf3604</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tf3604.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=tf3604</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59322</importID>
      <name>Steve Jones</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Jones is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and has been working with SQL Server since version 4.2 on OS/2. After working as a DBA and developer for a variety of companies, Steve co-founded the community website SQLServerCentral.com in 2001.
Since 2004, Steve has been the full-time editor of the site, ensuring it continues to be a great resource for SQL Server professionals. Over the last decade, Steve has written hundreds of articles about SQL Server for SQLServerCentral.com, SQL Server Standard magazine, SQL Server Magazine, and Database Journal.</description>
      <twitter>way0utwest</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/way0utwest</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.voiceofthedba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=way0utwest</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56316</importID>
      <name>Susantha Bathige</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Susantha Bathige (MSc, MCITP) is a Microsoft Certified Database Professional specialized in relational database product, MS SQL Server. Having more than 16 years of IT experience including more than 9 years in database development and administration in non-production and production environments. He has experience of other databases systems such Cassandra and MongoDB as well.</description>
      <twitter>@sbathige</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/susanthabathigesql</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservertorque.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sbathige</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61049</importID>
      <name>Jeff Renz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeff Renz is a Senior Architect at RevGen Partners, currently working as the design architect and implementation lead on several projects for a Fortune Top 50 company. Jeff has worked with SQL Server and BI for 15+ years and has 10 years’ experience with data warehouse design and implementation. In addition to consulting, he is joining the University of Denver adjunct faculty and is expected to begin teaching in the ICT program starting in June.  He received his bachelor’s degree in Computer Science, his master’s degree in Operations Research from Colorado School of Mines, and will be graduating from the Harvard Business Analytics Program in December.</description>
      <twitter>jeff_renz</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-renz/29/82a/aa4</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.revgen.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jeff_renz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56728</importID>
      <name>Michelle Haarhues</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michelle is a database administrator and has been working with SQL Server for over 15 years.  She started as a SQL Server developer and is currently a Database Administrator for Denver Health.  In many of her positions over the years, she was the lone SQL DBA\Developer so she loves talking about SQL Server to anyone who will listen.</description>
      <twitter>@mhaarhues</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://witsociety.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mhaarhues</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61130</importID>
      <name>Scot Reagin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>TDWI Certified Business Intelligence Professional
Certified Data Vault Data Modeler

More than thirty years of technology experience serving in a wide variety of roles including: Software Designer, Solution Architect, and Operations and General Manager.  Experience designing and implementing complete analytic solutions for organizations of many sizes and in diverse industries.

Business intelligence specific experience encompasses all aspects of Enterprise Information solutions including: Information Quality, Enterprise Data Warehousing, Business Analysis Data Marts, and comprehensive visualization applications.</description>
      <twitter>@SDIScot</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sjreagin</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sensibledataintegrations.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SDIScot</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>54712</importID>
      <name>Marcus Hopfinger</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marcus has been with Daktronics, Inc. since 2001 where he started doing ColdFusion development and some SQL Server 7 database administration. In late 2003 he was activated and deployed in early 2004 to Iraq with the South Dakota Army National Guard. During this time, he served as a Battalion Communications Officer where he was responsible for redundant voice and data networks including satellite internet and secure internet routing protocol networks. Upon returning to Daktronics in 2005 he moved in into a fulltime database administration position where he gets to work on SQL Server instances on three continents. He is also a Sci-Fi Fan, History buff, Amateur Radio Operator (call sign KA0SQL), but most importantly husband and father.</description>
      <twitter>DakotaDataWrang</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcus-hopfinger-69728121?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dakotadatawrangler.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DakotaDataWrang</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56384</importID>
      <name>William E Pearson III</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bill Pearson created Island Technologies Inc. in 1997, and has developed a large and diverse customer base since. Bill#39;s background as a CPA, Internal Auditor, Management Accountant, and SQL Server MVP (BI) enables him to provide value to clients as a liaison between Accounting / Finance and Information Services. Bill has implemented enterprise business intelligence systems over the years for many Fortune 500 companies and focuses his practice upon the integrated Microsoft Business Intelligence </description>
      <twitter>@Bill_Pearson</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/e/fpf/252170891</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mvp.support.microsoft.com/profile=02C5CD07-7511-4151-A678-3A4A3451F85E</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Bill_Pearson</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61051</importID>
      <name>Julia Renz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Julia is a student of technology with a passion for learning new things.  She loves math, computers and science.  Julia has a passion for dance and softball in her spare time.</description>
      <twitter>@jmr0323</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@jmr0323</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>56751</importID>
      <name>Trayce Jordan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Working with SQL Server for almost 20 years, Trayce is one of the first certified masters, holding an MCM for SQL 2005 and has been working at Microsoft since 2006.   Prior to joining Microsoft, he worked for a major online travel company as well as financial institutions and has served as a consultant working with companies in many different industries.  His specialties include database performance tuning, operations management and support, high availability and disaster recovery.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>59323</importID>
      <name>Steve Jones</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Jones is a Microsoft SQL Server MVP and has been working with SQL Server since version 4.2 on OS/2. After working as a DBA and developer for a variety of companies, Steve co-founded the community website SQLServerCentral.com in 2001.
Since 2004, Steve has been the full-time editor of the site, ensuring it continues to be a great resource for SQL Server professionals. Over the last decade, Steve has written hundreds of articles about SQL Server for SQLServerCentral.com, SQL Server Standard magazine, SQL Server Magazine, and Database Journal.</description>
      <twitter>way0utwest</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/way0utwest</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.voiceofthedba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=way0utwest</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>57133</importID>
      <name>Meagan Longoria</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Meagan Longoria is a business intelligence consultant with Denny Cherry  Associates, and lives in Denver, Colorado. She is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP. Meagan spends a lot of time thinking about how to use data integration, DAX, and data visualization techniques to make data useful for people. She enjoys sharing her knowledge and experiences at conferences and user group meetings, as well as through her blog (DataSavvy.me).</description>
      <twitter>mmarie</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/meaganlongoria/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datasavvy.me</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mmarie</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61473</importID>
      <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Carlos Bossy (MCTS, MCP BI, CBIP) is a data and cloud analytics architect with 25 years of experience in software and database development. As a principal of Datalere, Carlos focuses on developing BI, Data Science, and Advanced Analytics solutions, including modeling data warehouses and delivering predictive models, integration, and visualization. He has developed warehouses and BI solutions for a variety of industries and state agencies, including health insurance, solar energy, foster care, telecom, and manufacturing.</description>
      <twitter>@carlosbossy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin/in/carlosbossy</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.carlosbossy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@carlosbossy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63692</importID>
      <name>Craig Allen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Craig Allen is a Dell EMC mSpecialist (Microsoft Specialist). His role as a technical consultant is to help customers in understanding Dell EMC's products for the Microsoft platform. Craig can assist in the initial planning and evaluation of Dell EMC’s Proven Solutions for Microsoft, including requirements gathering, architectural guidance, and integration considerations. 
　
Craig is located in Dallas, TX and comes to Dell EMC with 25 years of experience in IT.</description>
      <twitter>@msftdude</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/craigdallen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.msftdude.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@msftdude</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61108</importID>
      <name>Gabriel Villa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gabriel is a skilled leader, architect, and technical expert focusing primarily on Microsoft technologies and is passionate about open-source technologies for integration, automation, and development. Gabriel’s versatility extends from systems, data and development and leverages hybrid/SaaS/Cloud integration, proven software engineering platforms, and best-of-breed data management and business intelligence solutions.

Originally from El Paso, Texas, Gabriel lives in Colorado Springs with his wife and kids, where he is an Architect for RevGen Partners, volunteers in the tech community and enjoys the Colorado outdoors.</description>
      <twitter>@extofer</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabevilla</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://extofer.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@extofer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>61117</importID>
      <name>Paul Nielsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paul is the founder of Tejon Technologies, inc, a software company offering a configurable, object/relational graph database solution built on the enterprise power of Microsoft SQL Server. Previously, Paul wrote the SQL Server Bible series, edited the MVP Deep Dives Vol 1 book, presented seminars in database design, and developed SQL Server courseware for Microsoft Learning. He was a Data Platform MVP from 2004 - 2016. IN the Startup Community he serves on the board of Peak Startup and is the chair of the annual Colorado Springs Startup Week.</description>
      <twitter>@PaulNielsen</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulnielsensql</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tejontech.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@PaulNielsen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>54542</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54542</id>
          <name>Steve Wake</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Mobile, Paginated, KPIs, and Power BI, Oh My! SSRS 2016 Reporting</title>
      <description>SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) 2016 is getting the biggest update since SQL Server 2005! This session will define and demo each of the SSRS report types are and how they are developed and supported: Mobile (previously DataZen reports), Paginated (SSRS RDL reports), KPIs (new standalone Key Performance Indicators), and Power BI (now Power BI can be managed in SSRS for an on-premises solution). All of these report types can now be managed in SSRS for a single reporting solution.

We will also look at the new SSRS Web Portal (replacement for Report Manager) and how the development environment will change as well. Sometime will also be spent on how to support all of these report types and the impact it will have on IT.
If you have been curious about what has changed with SSRS in SQL Server 2016 and you want to be ahead of the curve, this is the session for you!</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56842</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56842</id>
          <name>Tim Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Accelerating DevOps and TDM Using Data Virtualization</title>
      <description>DevOps is the merger of app development, testing, and IT ops.  All tasks from coding to testing to operations must be automated so that new features and fixes can be continuously delivered.

Test Data Management (TDM) is the optimization of the process of software quality, ensuring that applications properly work according to their specifications.

Constraining both DevOps and TDM is data, which has grown enormous and complex. "Storage is cheap" is not merely a lie, but beside the point. It takes a lot of time to push terabytes around from place to place, and time is expensive.

Provisioning a full environment for each developer or tester on each task of each project seems unrealistic, when each might require terabytes of storage. So, everyone is limited to working in a small shared dev/test environments that are refreshed only every few months, and code quality suffers, and the pace of delivery fails to live up to requirements.

Data virtualization is the solution.  Come learn.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56384</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56384</id>
          <name>William E Pearson III</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Seeking the Perfect Hybrid:  On-Prem Data with Reports and Dashboards in Power BI</title>
      <description>For many new Power BI implementations, initial self-service and team objectives are soon met, and the natural evolution of Power BI turns to an organizational focus.  In other scenarios, the enterprise seeks to preserve its investments in "classic BI" by integrating Power BI with Analysis Services and the underlying data warehouse.

In this session, Data Platform (SQL Server / BI) MVP and SSAS Maestro Bill Pearson explores the construction of organizational BI solutions, wedding the "traditional" solutions with the reporting and analysis power of Power BI.  We'll focus upon the components of a "traditional" solution, up to the semantic model (with SQL Server Analysis Services as an example), and then explore paths to the implementation of an end-to-end enterprise solution that uses Power BI as the presentation layer.
This session applies, in most respects, to Analysis Services 2012 and above.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56566</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56566</id>
          <name>Kellyn Pot'Vin-Gorman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>2</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Next Frontier-  Opportunities When Migrating to the Cloud with Virtualization</title>
      <description>Cloud is everywhere and the database administrator is caught in the middle. How do you know where to start and what to migrate first? How do you perform consolidation planning and ensure data security? This session builds on a full demonstration, along with tips and tricks to show how the DBA can secure their environment to allow a self-service option so they no longer are the constraints to projects! The attendee will leave with a clear understanding of:
* Principles of virtualization and why it’s the answer to so many challenges we face today.
* How easy it is to secure data in the cloud using data masking features.
* The ease of connecting to the cloud and migrating environments.
* How to troubleshoot when issues arise and the tools available to diagnose issues.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57553</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57553</id>
          <name>Patrick Geselbracht</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI on  Azure Analysis Services</title>
      <description>The level of effort to integrate a tabular SQL Server Analysis Services (SSAS) cube with Power BI became significantly easier with the release of Azure Analysis Services. Setup, configuration and maintenance of an On Premise gateway for direct query and scheduled data refreshes is no longer required. Leveraging the default Azure Analysis Services integration with Power BI, developers can focus on modeling cubes and creating beautiful dashboards and reports. In this session, we will explore the setup of an Azure Analysis Services as compared to the use of as an On Premise Analysis Services data source for Power BI. 

We will discuss modeling  security patterns in Analysis Services in conjunction with Power BI. We will also demonstrate a direct query connection of On Premise and Azure Analysis Services cubes to Power BI. Additionally, we will highlight leveraging Power BI functionality including reports, dashboards, and QA of an Analysis Services data set.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59808</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59808</id>
          <name>Michelle Poolet</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Get Into the Goldilocks Zone: Managing SQL Transaction Log VLF Growth</title>
      <description>Are your transaction logs ballooning? Are the VLF numbers out of control? What can you do about it? 

Let's start with "what's a VLF and why do I care?" and move forward into learning how to shrink VLFs (a temporary solution) and how to resize SQL Server transaction log files (a more permanent solution) for greater server stability, better performance during server startup, backups, and restores, and to minimize storage space requirements.

The SQL Server transaction log is a critical piece of SQL Server's ability to ensure that data is maintained exactly as the user input or modified the data. The transaction log must, at times, grow in size in order to do its job. When a transaction log’s growth gets out of control (too large, too many segments), then SQL Server’s ability to perform as it should is negatively impacted. Too-large transaction log files cause longer database start up, backup and restore times, and will require more storage space on disk. Learn how to control VLF gro</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>60965</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>60965</id>
          <name>Reeves Smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Data Science with R</title>
      <description>Data Science is the gaining popularity but what does it really mean? 
Discovering useful patterns and insight in the enterprise has become more challenging without a new set of tools. Big data has taken center stage in the data warehouse community and with data sets so large and complex that traditional data processing applications are becoming inadequate. Learn about the R language that is at the center of most advanced analytics conversations. R is an open source statistical language that is rapidly gaining popularity due to a robust set of machine learning functionality and a never-ending set of R packages that are used to increase functionality of the core R language.
In this session, we will introduce the R language and review some of the features of the highly interactive environment that are available with just the base install. We will also review some of the upcoming features in the SQL Server 2016.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61130</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61130</id>
          <name>Scot Reagin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Integration: the neglected hero of your information environment</title>
      <description>Every organization struggles to ensure data is up to date and consistent across multiple systems.   Often this results in the development of layers of system to system data integrations or repetitive and manual processes intended to support operational and reporting needs.

Enterprise Data Warehouses and Marts are often the only stores that provide single point access to data sourced from multiple systems - but these stores can be expensive and complicated to build and maintain and tend to lag behind business need.

Data Lakes offer the promise of fast inexpensive data acquisition but without specialized tools lack the structure that makes their data accessible and useful to the business.

A managed Data Integration platform can provide both efficient data management across systems and a shared, single point, store of data sourced from all participating systems.   A Data Integration platform solution is not technology or tool specific and can provide immediate and continuing value.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56728</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56728</id>
          <name>Michelle Haarhues</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>4</name>
      </location>
      <title>On the Doorsteps - Women in Technology</title>
      <description>Women make up over half of the workforce, and yet there are still discrepancies in pay and in the number of women in certain industries. Technology is one of the industries where women are drastically underrepresented. What factors in industry and society have contributed to these outcomes?

In this session, we will discuss the effects of trends in industry such as college graduation of women in technology fields, and women currently in tech or in positions of leadership. And, even important to us, how the contributions of women in PASS affect our community. This will be an open discussion with input from the audience encouraged.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61051</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61051</id>
          <name>Julia Renz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Even I Can Power BI!</title>
      <description>Power BI Desktop is so intuitive when it comes to creating reports that even a 13 year old can do it.  In fact I'm 13 and I can do it! Don't believe me?  Come to my session as I demonstrate how to import data, create dashboards, and publish them to the Power BI service.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56751</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56751</id>
          <name>Trayce Jordan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Finding root cause for unexplained Availability Group failover</title>
      <description>In this session, we will walk you step by step showing how we determine root cause analysis of an unexplained failure in an Availability Group.  Whether the databases simply became unavailable, synchronization stopped, or there was an unexplained failover.   We will show you specifically what we look for in the OS Cluster logs, SQL error logs, Extended Events and other sources of information.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61075</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61075</id>
          <name>Rick Lowe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>6</name>
      </location>
      <title>Weird Stuff I Saw While ... Working With Heaps</title>
      <description>We've all been told at some point that heaps are usually bad for select, update, and delete performance. But how bad are they really? Can they also be problematic for inserts? Are they ever a good idea? For this installment of Rick's "Weird Stuff" series we will take a closer look at why heaps can cause issues and maybe see a deadlock or two.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 8:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61049</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61049</id>
          <name>Jeff Renz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>6</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction To Azure DocumentDB</title>
      <description>Developers are interested in consuming and processing very large amounts of data as quickly as possible. Microsoft Azure DocumentDB is a NoSQL document database service designed for modern mobile and web applications which require fast reads and writes of unstructured data feeds. Azure DocumentDB natively supports JSON documents which is a key performance feature. 

In this session I will demonstrate how to create a DocumentDB instance in Azure, how to work with JSON documents, create Ad hoc queries with familiar SQL syntax, create application logic as stored procedures, triggers and user defined functions (UDFs) using standard JavaScript. Finally, I will compare performance and feature difference between SQL Server 2016 and Azure DocumentDB.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56316</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56316</id>
          <name>Susantha Bathige</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Statistics and New Cardinality Estimator Model</title>
      <description>Statistics in SQL Server plays a major role creating execution plan which essentially decides server performance. If you get a good execution plan the server performance is good otherwise it will impact negatively on the server performance. SQL Server 2014 introduced new Cardinality Estimation (CE) model to improve the quality of the execution plans via quality estimates of row counts. The new CE model is a major redesign to the Query Optimizer since SQL Server 7.0. In this session, I'm going to talk about how statistics is used to generate the execution plan, how execution plan changes with new CE model with demos.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61117</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61117</id>
          <name>Paul Nielsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>4</name>
      </location>
      <title>So you want to launch a software company</title>
      <description>You love working with people and you love delivering solutions, and you want to be your own boss. You think you have a great idea and you're ready to jump. The startup space is a completely different world. MVP means Minimum Viable Product. I took that plunge and converted my SQL MPV to a startup MVP. In this lesson I'll pass on as much as possible about launching a software startup - beginning with the Business Model Canvass. (note: I'm also the chair of Colorado Springs Startup Week and on the board of Peak Startup)</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56297</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56297</id>
          <name>David Brown</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Use Analytics (and Data Science) to Get a Promotion</title>
      <description>Who has difficulty communicating the value of databases across their organization? Who wants to make more of a difference using database systems? Who is dissatisfied with their job and feels under-appreciated?

Welcome to my world. I've worked for years as a consultant, and I started in this situation, but I began making a living helping folks crawl their way out. Along the way, I got my Microsoft MVP, and I've helped many organizations make millions of more dollars through my consulting efforts. I'd like to help you, too.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61108</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61108</id>
          <name>Gabriel Villa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>6</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting Started with Databases on Amazon Web Services</title>
      <description>Are you looking to understand what IaaS or PaaS really mean? Perhaps you are not sure of virtual, high available relational or NoSQL databases. Get started with the basics of managed services and platforms for running databases on AWS. Hear how to use managed relational databases such as MS SQL Server with minimal administration. Also discover other cloud options such as managed NoSQL or scaling your own instances with resizable elastic compute cloud. Take home an introduction from in-memory cache to petabyte-scale data warehouse databases in the Amazon cloud.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59710</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59710</id>
          <name>Christopher Wolff</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Continuous Deployments using SSDT</title>
      <description>Many of us feel pressure to deploy changes to our database more often and more reliably. SSDT gives us a number of options to set up continuous integration and eventually, continuous deployment. Learn how to create and customize DACPACs, Published Profiles, and SQLPackage.exe to automate your deployment process. Whether you want to update QA or smoothly get changes to production, this session will give you the tips and tricks you need to get started.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54712</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54712</id>
          <name>Marcus Hopfinger</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>4</name>
      </location>
      <title>My Top 10 Favorite Replication Tricks</title>
      <description>Replication can be intimidating and a bit confusing. I will show you my ten favorite tricks for working with replication that will show you how you can replicate from multiple sources to multiple destinations, chose the appropriate method of replication and, if desired, put the data in a different schema with a different collation at the destination than it was at the source. I will also cover various methods of managing your publications, agent properties and distribution schedules. This presentation assumes a basic knowledge of configuring distribution and creating a basic publication and subscription.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 12:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54558</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54558</id>
          <name>Thane Schaffer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to SQL</title>
      <description>A fast and furious overview of the fundamentals of SQL (Structured Query Language), its history, language fundamentals of the data definition, data manipulation, data control, and transaction control language aspects.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63692</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63692</id>
          <name>Craig Allen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Performance Best Practices</title>
      <description>Learn tip and tricks for configuring SQL Server for maximum performance, including: metrics, configurations, disk layout, virtualization considerations, and infrastructure.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 12:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 1:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59322</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59322</id>
          <name>Steve Jones</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Bringing DevOps to the Database</title>
      <description>DevOps is a hot topic in today's software development world. However most of the knowledge and experience with DevOps is based around application software and ignores the database. We will examine how the concepts and principles of DevOps can be applied to database development by looking at both automated comparison analysis as well as migration script management. Automated building, testing, and deployment of database changes will be shown.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57957</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57957</id>
          <name>Warren Sifre</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <description>We will discuss what is Azure Machine Learning, how it works, what it can do, and why would you use it.  This session includes demonstration and use case scenarios.  The goal of this session it to provide an understand of what Azure ML can do and how it may apply to business use cases.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59323</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59323</id>
          <name>Steve Jones</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Branding Yourself for a Dream Job</title>
      <description>Everyone wants a dream job that they enjoy going to each week. However finding that job, and getting yourself hired can be hard for most people. Steve Jones will give you practical tips and suggestions in this session that show you how to better market yourself, how to get the attention of employers, and help improve the chances that the job you want will get offered to you. Learn about networking, blogging, and more.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59831</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59831</id>
          <name>Brian Hansen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>6</name>
      </location>
      <title>Visualize Your Transaction Log</title>
      <description>The SQL transaction log can be a mystery to many DBAs.  We live in the age of visualizations, so let#39;s visualize the log!  In this session, we will examine the purpose and organization of the transaction log and will explore the log through a unique visualization tool.  We will consider common performance issues that are related to the logging mechanism and how to overcome these problems.  Finally, we will discuss some techniques to monitor the log so that potential performance problems can be addressed pro-actively.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>59810</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>59810</id>
          <name>Michael Fal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>6</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to Azure SQL Databases</title>
      <description>Azure SQL Databases are still something that is new and not completely understood by many data professionals. There is a definite shift from installing SQL Server on a machine to creating and using a Microsoft's Platform-as-a-Service database. This session will cover the basics of what an Azure SQL Database is, how we create one, and what it takes to access and use this database. After attending this session, you will have a solid understanding of what Azure SQL Database is, how to configure it, and how to use in your own environment.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54567</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54567</id>
          <name>Adam Koehler</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Isolation Levels – Understanding Transaction Temper Tantrums</title>
      <description>In this session we will review Isolation levels and how they affect applications that run on SQL Server.  We will explore what happens when multiple applications accessing the same data use different isolation levels, and how that effects the server as a whole.   We will also explore different ways to relieve these tantrums, and make your applications play nice together.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>57133</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>57133</id>
          <name>Meagan Longoria</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Up Close and Personal with the Tabular SSAS DMVs</title>
      <description>Did you know that we got new Dynamic Management Views (DMVs) for the SQL 2016 SSAS Tabular models that also work with Power BI? They can be used to monitor the health of your database as well as to retrieve useful metadata. In this session, you'll learn how to access and query SSAS DMVs as well as important data points found in the DMVs. Then I'll demonstrate my Tabular Model Documenter based upon the DMVs and explain how I built it. You'll walk away with a tool that automatically documents your tabular model, saving you from tedious manual documentation.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>54601</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>54601</id>
          <name>Cher Fox</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Test Automation: Agile Enablement for DW and BI Teams</title>
      <description>Test automation is one of several key technical enablement practices that allows teams to be more successful in their agile journeys. While there are lots of test practices and automation tools out there for software development teams to leverage, very few are targeted to data-related development and testing. Agile analytics practitioner Lynn Winterboer and DW/BI architect and developer Cher Fox will share essential agile test foundations and data-focused test automation technologies to help data warehousing and business intelligence teams get a leg up on this important agile practice, including a demo of how this works!</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>56503</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>56503</id>
          <name>Tracy Boggiano</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>5</name>
      </location>
      <title>Disaster Recovery Where to Begin</title>
      <description>So you have a good backup strategy in place, but now you have to think about a disaster recovery.  Where do you start and what are your options?  SQL Server offers several options, but then how do you choose the right one to meet your business requirements?  In this session, we will go over some of the common DR options including log shipping, replication, mirroring, clustering, and AlwaysOn.  Then we will talk about how to choose the best one to meet your business needs.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>61473</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>61473</id>
          <name>Carlos Bossy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Business Intelligence in the Cloud</title>
      <description>Is it time to move some of your Business Intelligence framework to the cloud?  With so many cloud-enabled tools and platforms available today, including Azure Data Warehouse, Azure Analysis Services, Azure Data Lake, PowerBI, and many more, it has become a choice to consider for data architects.  In addition to live demonstrations, Carlos will discuss data architectures and strategies that would benefit by using these new technologies.  Come see some of these new features in action, allowing you to determine if it’s right for you and your architecture.</description>
      <startTime>3/25/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>3/25/2017 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>