<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #874 - Timisoara 2019</name>
    <startDate>6/8/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>150</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Harare, Pretoria</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatTimisoara</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Biblioteca Centrală a Universității Politehnica Timișoara</name>
      <street>Bulevardul Vasile Pârvan 2b, Timișoara, Romania</street>
      <city>Timișoara</city>
      <state>Timiș County, Romania</state>
      <zipcode>300223</zipcode>
      <longitude>21.2274767</longitude>
      <latitude>45.746849</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/972/EventSponsor_14605.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>4</importID>
      <name>PASS</name>
      <label>PASS</label>
      <url>http://www.pass.org</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/Portals/_default/Skins/pass-2016/images/pass-logo-2016.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91433</importID>
      <name>Michal Sadowski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior Database Platform Engineer, leader of Krakow chapter of Data Community Krakow (former Polish SQL Server User Group) - PASS Chapter. With more than 10 years of experience in Microsoft technology, helps in advisory for performance optimization on database and application levels. Active speaker on SQL Server related events like SQLSaturday, SQLDay, MCT Global Summit etc. Holds many Microsoft certificates including MCSE: Data Platform, MCSA: SQL Server 2012/2014/2016, MCSA: Windows Server 2008/2012/2016 and MCT.</description>
      <twitter>SadowskiMichal</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/pub/michal-sadowski/4/b33/717</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://sqlplayer.net/michal-sadowski</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SadowskiMichal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94878</importID>
      <name>Damir Bulic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>The founder of Spectral Core, a database tools company with customers in over 90 countries.
Fell in love with computers in high school, didn't stop since.
* Released a 3D Amiga game with a classroom buddy back in 1994 (MC680x0 assembly)
* As a first PC project, ported a 3D modeler Amorphium from Mac to PC in 1998. (C++)
* Reverse-engineered EXE (and ELF) file format, wrote an EXE protector dismantling and a full system loader launching the encrypted apps with trial/rent functionality (with no source code of the protected apps required) in 1999-2001 (C++ on Windows/Mac/Linux)
* Developed many business apps for local companies up to 2003 (Delphi)
* Co-architected a very popular ERP system in 2003-2004 (Delphi)
* Spectral Core ever sinc</description>
      <twitter>spectral_core</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbulic/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://database.blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=spectral_core</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90119</importID>
      <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dejan Sarka, MCT and Data Platform MVP, is an independent trainer and consultant that focuses on development of database and business intelligence applications. Besides projects, he spends about half of his time on training and mentoring. He is the founder of the Slovenian SQL Server and .NET Users Group. Dejan Sarka is the main author or co-author of eighteen books about databases and SQL Server. Dejan Sarka has also developed many courses and seminars for Microsoft, Radacad, SolidQ, and Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>DejanSarka</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/dsarka/Home.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DejanSarka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91830</importID>
      <name>ILIE Mugurel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data warehouse developer on MS SQL Server</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92922</importID>
      <name>Ivan Čuljak</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ivan is a .NET freelance developer in love with Azure, Xamarin, and the idea of automating whatever. When he’s not developing something new, he’s salvaging something inherited, consulting with enthusiasm, and testing and breaking new technologies in a quest for something useful.</description>
      <twitter>@CuljakIvan</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/culjakivan/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.culjak.xyz</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@CuljakIvan</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93006</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90515</importID>
      <name>Dragos Madarasan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Solutions Architect at Amazon Web Services, where he works with companies and their partners in Central and Eastern Europe by transforming their enterprise IT landscape and helping them design reliable, cost-effective cloud architectures. Dragos works with clients to assess their infrastructure and application portfolio while developing a shared vision, leading the customer and partner over the technical and business hurdles of cloud adoption. Before joining Amazon, he worked for Endava and Emerson and is an alumni of the Technical University of Cluj-Napoca.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/dragospm</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dragosmadarasan</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://dragos.madarasan.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/dragospm</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90476</importID>
      <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erland Sommarskog is an independent consultant based in Stockholm, working with SQL Server since 1991. He was first awarded SQL Server MVP in 2001, and has been re-awarded every year since. His focus is on systems development with the SQL Server Database Engine and his passion is to help people to write better SQL Server applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sommarskog.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89928</importID>
      <name>Dennes Torres</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dennes Torres is a Data Platform MVP with more than 25 years of experience in the IT area. He improves Data Platform Architectures and turns data into knowledge. As a Brazilian living in Malta, Dennes works as a software developer and leads the Malta MDP User Group. Having the MCSE Data Platform, Business Intelligence, and Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) certifications, Dennes has been in love with database servers since he was  introduced to SQL Server 6.5, more years ago than he would like to admit.</description>
      <twitter>Dennes</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennestorres/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/dennes-torres/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Dennes</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93021</importID>
      <name>André Melancia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Owner / Principal Consultant at LunarCat.PT
Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) focusing on SQL Server, Azure, IoT and Security.

19+ years' fun developing information and multimedia systems, DBA, project and IT management.

Data Community Portugal, IT Pro Portugal and PowerShell Portugal communities organiser.
IPv6 Portugal, DNSSec Portugal and Windows Development Portugal online communities moderator.
Actively volunteering, organising, speaking or just participating at community meetings and events around the world.

Proud uncle and food devouring expert, with dangerous рuϧϧy cat as companion.

Go to http://Andy.PT and you'll know the same as the NSA...</description>
      <twitter>AndyPT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://LinkedIn.COM/in/AndreMelancia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Andy.PT</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndyPT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93420</importID>
      <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mihail Mateev is a technical consultant, community enthusiast, PASS Regional Mentor for CEE, chapter lead, Microsoft Azure MVP, Microsoft Regional Director. He works as a Senior Solutions Architect at EPAM Systems, focused on Data Platform, IoT and cloud related solutions. He also worked many years like a Technical evangelist in the Infragistics. Last years Mihail was focused on various areas related to technology Microsoft: Data Platform, Visual Studio, ASP.Net, Windows client apps, Data Platform, and Microsoft Azure. Michael also has a PhD in cloud computing area. He is a university lecturer on Smart Homes and Smart Energy IoT Solutions.</description>
      <twitter>mihailmateev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mihail-mateev/1/6b3/4b1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mmateev.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mihailmateev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90120</importID>
      <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dejan Sarka, MCT and Data Platform MVP, is an independent trainer and consultant that focuses on development of database and business intelligence applications. Besides projects, he spends about half of his time on training and mentoring. He is the founder of the Slovenian SQL Server and .NET Users Group. Dejan Sarka is the main author or co-author of eighteen books about databases and SQL Server. Dejan Sarka has also developed many courses and seminars for Microsoft, Radacad, SolidQ, and Pluralsight.</description>
      <twitter>DejanSarka</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.solidq.com/dsarka/Home.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DejanSarka</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>90418</importID>
      <name>Liviu Ieran</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>More than 9 years of SQL Server experience working for Microsoft currently as a Support Escalation Engineer. 
My main area of expertise is SQL Server Performance where I helped optimize numerous query's and environments.</description>
      <twitter>@Liviu_Ieran</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/IeranLiviu</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Liviu_Ieran</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93816</importID>
      <name>Alexandra Ciortea</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>2005-2009  Computer Science - Polytechnic University of Bucharest 
2009-2011 - Master -IT Management - Polytechnic University of Bucharest 

I started working for Microsoft in 2009 as a Support Engineer for Project Server and SQL Server for EMEA.
In 2012 I changed to a  Premier Field Engineer position working onsite for SQL Server and Project Server</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>89939</importID>
      <name>Shehab El-Najjar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Shehab El-Najjar was the ONLY Microsoft SQL Server MVP in Gulf for the past 6 years and the 2nd one all over the Middle East  , he is the founder of SQL Gulf events series (SQL Gulf #1 , #2 and #3 ) where he spent so much time and efforts  to broadcast Microsoft SQL Server technologies all over the Gulf such as  KSA and Emirates and other Gulf cities ahead ..) 

	He is now Professional Services Manager at Saudi  Emircom 

	He was previously COO and business leader in KSA market through his startup WAJA IT for  3 years

	He is an influencing Database community leader all over the region  	
	A senior Database Consultant (SQL Server MVP for 6 years in row) -The 2nd MVP awardee SQL Server all over Middle East and Arabic region</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/MSQLPerformance</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=126446983amp;trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlserver-performance-tuning.net/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/MSQLPerformance</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92591</importID>
      <name>Alexandru Craciun</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>creaTiVe... SQL Expert, IT Architect, gamer, rocker, guerrila minded and laugh a lot about anything</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexandru-craciun-3a829574</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>91769</importID>
      <name>Cristian Lefter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Cristian Lefter is Principal of Esential Training and one of the SQL Server MVPs. His primary competence is training. He is also a consultant, author, speaker and community leader. 
As his main expertise is Microsoft SQL Server, which resulted in founding an official PASS chapter, writing books and articles, contributing at the development of Microsoft Official Courseware, authoring certification exams, speaking at technical events and working as a Subject Matter Expert in various projects.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cristianlefter</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94292</importID>
      <name>Deji Akomolafe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Deji Akomolafe (a member of the Office of the CTO Ambassador Program and Staff Solutions Architect within VMware#39;s Global Field and Partners Readiness Group) specializes in the virtualization of Microsoft Business Critical Applications on VMware#39;s vSphere platform. Deji is a regular speaker at VMworld, Partners Exchange Conference, VMUG, SQL Saturday and EMCWorld, presenting technical subject matters related to Microsoft Applications virtualization and providing technical guidance to help clients enhance their expertise and ability to optimally virtualize and operate their critical applications.</description>
      <twitter>@dejify</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.vmware.com/apps</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dejify</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>92334</importID>
      <name>Miroslav Popovic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Miroslav is senior software architect for .NET and JavaScript, employed as Technical Lead at Seavus. He uses .NET from version 1.0. From Windows Forms, through WPF and Silverlight, all the way to ASP.NET Core. Currently, he is focused on ASP.NET Core, client-side JavaScript development and software craftsmanship. During his career, he worked on a lot of small and big projects, including a couple of local startups. He was one of the members of the development team for the Kicks platform and one of the moderators for https://javascriptkicks.com and https://dotnetkicks.com. Besides that, he is an active community member, conference speaker and one of the leaders of "BLbit Banja Luka" user group.</description>
      <twitter>miroslavpopovic</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/miroslavpopovic/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://miroslavpopovic.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=miroslavpopovic</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>92922</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92922</id>
          <name>Ivan Čuljak</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>R3</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to be polite with databases when going serverless</title>
      <description>Like it wasn't enough that just anyone could use an ORM and start molesting a database, nowadays just anyone can use serverless and communicate with a database... and use ORM...
First of all, we're gonna focus on how to communicate with a database from your serverless system presuming that there aren't any parallel requests to the database. In that way, we'll first polish cold starts, memory/CPU consumption, and basically everything we need to worry about now when we're not running our code on servers with 10+ cores, and tens of GB of RAM.
Once we're done with the first task, we'll end up with something that can quickly and effortlessly communicate with our database. Which is perfect, except in cases where we handle thousands or more of parallel requests to the database which isn't scalable as serverless is.
That brings us to our second task- making sure our serverless system won't DDoS our databases :)
Come and find out how to approach this problems ;)</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 1:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 2:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94878</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94878</id>
          <name>Damir Bulic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>R3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Lightning-fast management of cloud and legacy databases, breaking vendor lock-in</title>
      <description>With the infrastructure increasingly moving to the cloud, developers are stuck with legacy tools, suboptimal for the new workflows. Current reality is slow and unreliable web applications bundled using Electron - or native applications that look like they are made 20 years ago.
We have started from scratch, imagining the ideal database manager for modern times. UI responds to your actions in less than 0.1 seconds and your data stays in the cloud. Connection switching is instant and the workspace is preserved between devices and application restarts.
A sneak peek - state of the art SQL code translation solution - removing vendor lock-in.
This is a work-in-progress report, detailing why it's so hard to get right and why does it take so long to make something seemingly simple - not a sales talk, not a self-congratulatory talk.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 3:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 4:40:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90120</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90120</id>
          <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>AIML Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>R1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Overview and Manipulation – T-SQL, R, Python</title>
      <description>In a real data mining or machine learning project, you spend more than half of the time on data preparation and data understanding. The R language is extremely powerful in this area. The Python language is a match. Of course, you do work with data by using T-SQL. You will learn in this session how to get data understanding with really quickly prepared basic graphs and descriptive statistics analysis. You can do advanced data preparation with many data manipulation methods available out of the box and in additional packages from R and Python. After this session, you will understand what tasks data preparation involves, and what tools you have in SQL Server suite for these tasks.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 11:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 12:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94292</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94292</id>
          <name>Deji Akomolafe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>R2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Successfully Virtualizing SQL Server on vSphere - Straight from the Source</title>
      <description>Over the years, virtualization has matured from the exotic black magic realm to become a mainstream standard IT practice. quot;Virtualize Firstquot; is now a well-accepted default practice in most enterprises and any deviation is now considered an anomaly. In spite of this trend, many IT administrators and architects still have some reservations about virtualizing SQL Server workloads. They consider SQL too quot;criticalquot; to be virtualized; they wonder and worry about scale about performance; they are looking for guidance and reassurance. If this is where you (or your clients) are today, be sure to attend this session. You will gain valuable insights from what others have done to successfully undertake similar tasks in their environments. We will talk about configuration pitfalls to avoid and also review the configuration and current performance data for some of the most demanding applications in customers environments. Got an SQL virtualization or performance question? Bring i</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 3:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90119</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90119</id>
          <name>Dejan Sarka</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>AIML Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>R1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Data Science: Python or R?</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 brought support or the R language. SQL Server 2017 added a new language to the list, the Python language. Both languages target advanced analytics scenarios, popularly known as data science. For a SQL Server professional who wants to move in the data science area, the first question is which language to choose. In this presentation, you will learn basics about both languages. We will try to solve the same problem with both languages. This way, through demos with a lot of explanation, you will realize the most important differences between the two competing languages. You will understand which one is more appropriate for you to start with.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90476</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90476</id>
          <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>R2</name>
      </location>
      <title>When Things go Wrong - Error Handling in SQL Server</title>
      <description>In an ideal world, we would not need any error handling, because there would be no errors. But in the real world we need to have error handling in our stored procedures. Error handling in SQL Server is a most confusing topic, because there are such great inconsistencies. But that does not mean that we as database developers can hide our head in the sand.

This presentation starts with a horror show of the many different actions SQL Server can take in case of an error. We will then learn how should deal with this - what we should do and what we should not and that with SET XACT_ABORT we get better consistency. We will learn how TRY-CATCH works in SQL Server, and we will get a recipe for how to write CATCH blocks. More generally, we will learn why it pays off to be simple-minded to survive in this maze. The session mainly looks at traditional T-SQL code, but the session ends with a quick look at natively compiled stored procedures, where everything is different.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 1:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 2:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89939</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89939</id>
          <name>Shehab El-Najjar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>R2</name>
      </location>
      <title>T-SQL Performance Guidelines for the optimal DB stress powers</title>
      <description>To reach your desired business functionalities, it can be easy using some common T-SQL practices like MTVF , scalar functions , Temp tables, Union…etc and they might perform pretty well on development server coz neither adequate stress of users nor adequate volume of data exist there but actually they seem totally strange once going to live where they become performing badly ending up eventually with and sharp skew of performance and standstill cases sometimes , this is due to the lack of stress powers of T-SQL codes which should be considered largely for critical mission DBs in particular more therefore I am going to talk to you about How to capture expensive queries using different techniques ..?and How to optimize them in the shortest time using scientific ways ..? (10 different T-SQL Practices will be explained within this session)</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 11:20:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 12:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90418</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90418</id>
          <name>Liviu Ieran</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>R3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Data Explorer - Fast and highly scalable interactive analytics</title>
      <description>Azure Data Explorer is one of the newest offerings from Microsoft which went GA on the 7th of February. 
I am going to provide an overview of Azure Data Explorer, an interactive analytics service that will enable you to ask the questions on real time data. You can find answers in rapidly changing data generated by systems such as applications, websites, and IoT devices – anything really that generates volumes of streaming data that has potential to uncover a number of unknowns.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 9:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 10:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>90515</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>90515</id>
          <name>Dragos Madarasan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>R3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Running Microsoft SQL Server on Amazon Web Services</title>
      <description>Amazon Web Services (AWS) has multiple ways to host and support Microsoft SQL Server.  This session will review the Relational Database Service (RDS) offering of Microsoft SQL Server as well as using our virtual machine service (Elastic Compute Cloud, or EC2) to host SQL Server database services.  We will review options for security, availability, and reliability operations in both offerings and how to choose the optimal solution for your existing and new SQL Server workloads.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 10:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 11:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92334</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92334</id>
          <name>Miroslav Popovic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>R2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Visual Studio productivity</title>
      <description>Visual Studio is an excellent tool, praised by many as the best IDE there is. One of the important things that Visual Studio provides is productivity. Besides a plethora of built-in features, even more functionality can be added through extensions. This presentation is a short overview of some integrated features as well as a look into some extensions that improve productivity.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 10:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 11:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91830</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91830</id>
          <name>ILIE Mugurel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>R2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Handling JSONs in SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>Consuming data from JSON is now much easier with the new built-in support introduced in SQL Server 2016!
During this session will talk about JSON representation and will explore the new functions used for handling the content from a JSON file. Based on some examples we'll transform a JSON text to relational table and then will export some data from SQL Server as JSON.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 9:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 10:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91433</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91433</id>
          <name>Michal Sadowski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>R2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Encryption in SQL Server</title>
      <description>An application that you administer stores sensitive data in the database and you would like to keep them safe in Microsoft SQL Server - how to approach this issue? What type of encryption should you use in your environment? On the session I will walk through available options in Microsoft SQL Server and show when to use encryption, how to identify threats, and countermeasure them by using options like Transparent Data Encryption, SSL certificates, Always Encrypted, etc. After this session, you will know a set of best practices that you can apply in your environment.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>89928</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>89928</id>
          <name>Dennes Torres</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>AIML Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>R1</name>
      </location>
      <title>PowerBI: From Zero to Hero</title>
      <description>Starting from the very beginning, in this session we will cross together the main features Power BI has to offer, starting with the powerful self-service ETL using M language when needed,  modeling our tables and finally using powerful features to create a great data visualization, allowing you to better understand all the power and flexibility of this tool and how it will fit into your solution</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 10:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 11:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93021</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93021</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>AIML Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>R1</name>
      </location>
      <title>BI Powers - The A.I. Who Tagged Me</title>
      <description>So everyone knows how to make some nice graphs in Power BI from Excel or SQL Server... But what about getting "intelligent" results from unusual data sources?
Disclaimer: A.I. will eventually take over the world. Unlike Doctor Evil, it won't ask for a ransom.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 9:40:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 10:40:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93006</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93006</id>
          <name>André Melancia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>AIML Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>R2</name>
      </location>
      <title>If a computer can understand, why can't YOU understand Azure Cognitive Services?</title>
      <description>Cognitive services can recognise objects, faces, describe images, understand speech, perform advanced searches and so much more.
If you are a developer and know nothing about Azure Cognitive Services for free, this is a good place to start.
Disclaimer: Cognitive services will never guess a doctor's handwriting. That's just impossible.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 11:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 12:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93816</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93816</id>
          <name>Alexandra Ciortea</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>R3</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Managed Instance - From the ground to the cloud</title>
      <description>The session presents SQL MI features and different tiers. We will also focus on lift and shift SQL onprem databases and objects hosted outside the database context to SQL MI . This also covers common issues, solutions and workarounds from various migration projects.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 11:50:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 12:50:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>91769</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>91769</id>
          <name>Cristian Lefter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>AIML Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>R1</name>
      </location>
      <title>AI in Power BI</title>
      <description>AI and Power BI? Yes! 
Azure Cognitive Service comes with a set of powerful, pretrained models for intelligent applications. At this point, four of them are exposed in Power BI: language detection, sentiment scoring, key phrase extraction, and image tagging. These models can be used on textual data or images.
During the 60 minutes of the sessions we will find out together the answer to the questions WHAT, HOW and the most important one, WHY.
Fun is guaranteed :)</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 1:20:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 2:20:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>92591</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>92591</id>
          <name>Alexandru Craciun</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>R2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server full optimization</title>
      <description>Automation and optimization for all related components to SQL Server: storage, memory, cpu, sql low level design, query plan etc</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 3:40:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 5:10:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93420</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93420</id>
          <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>R3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Connecting IoT data with artificial intelligence at scale</title>
      <description>This talk is about intersection of IoT and artificial intelligence.
IoT solutions to generate more data than traditional systems and users can analyse.
Nowadays, AI enabled software solutions that optimize equipment and process performance for large industrial customers. These solutions use large volumes of real-time, batch data from equipment and processes in real time, and apply AI/ML algorithms to predict failures and anomalies as well as optimize performance.
The concept is explained in the context of Azure IoT and Azure AI platforms.</description>
      <startTime>6/8/2019 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/8/2019 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>