<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #339 - Shanghai 2015</name>
    <startDate>5/9/2015 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>150</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+08:00) Beijing, Chongqing, Hong Kong, Urumqi</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatShanghai</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft (China) Shanghai GGW office </name>
      <street>虹桥路3号</street>
      <city>Shanghai</city>
      <state>Shanghai, China</state>
      <zipcode>200051</zipcode>
      <longitude>121.437217</longitude>
      <latitude>31.194666</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19090</importID>
      <name>Leonard Lobel</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leonard Lobel (Microsoft MVP, Data Platform) is CTO and co-founder of Sleek Technologies, Inc., a New York-based development shop with an early adopter philosophy toward new technologies. He is also a principal consultant at Tallan, Inc., a Microsoft National Systems Integrator and Gold Competency Partner.

Programming since 1979, Lenni specializes in Microsoft-based solutions, with experience that spans a variety of business domains, including publishing, financial, wholesale/retail, health care, and e-commerce. Lenni has served as chief architect and lead developer for various organizations, ranging from small shops to high-profile clients. He is also a consultant, trainer, and frequent speaker at local usergroup meetings, VSLive, SQL PASS, and other industry conferences.

Lenni has also authored several MS Press books and Pluralsight courses on SQL Server programming.</description>
      <twitter>@lennilobel</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/lennilobel</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://lennilobel.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@lennilobel</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15766</importID>
      <name>Janos Berke</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am  an IT professional with over a decade of technical and management experience. I am using SQL Server since version 6.5. Currently I am a  consultant and helping companies in SQL Server design, migrations, operation and developments as well as providing customized training .</description>
      <twitter>@JanosBerke</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://hu.linkedin.com/in/janosberke</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.iamberke.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@JanosBerke</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>19090</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19090</id>
          <name>Leonard Lobel</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Programming T-SQL Enhancements in SQL Server 2012</title>
      <description>As SQL Server evolves, so does Microsoft continue to improve and enhance Transact SQL (T-SQL). In SQL Server 2012, T-SQL remains the primary language for programming the relational database engine. In this informative and demo-packed session, Lenni will guide you through the T-SQL enhancements in the very latest release of SQL Server. We’ll dive into powerful new windowing enhancements with the OVER clause, running and sliding aggregations, new T-SQL functions (all 22 of them!), improved error handling with THROW, server-side paging with OFFSET/FETCH NEXT, sequence generators, and rich metadata discovery techniques. If you want to learn the new T-SQL enhancements in SQL Server 2012, you won’t want to miss out on this session!</description>
      <startTime>5/9/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/9/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15766</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15766</id>
          <name>Janos Berke</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Practical Management Data Warehouse</title>
      <description>MDW is a free monitoring tool provided with SQL Server since version 2008. This session will cover the following topics:
- Data Collection basics
- Data Collector Security
- MDW report security
- Custom collectors and reports
- Multi server/instance monitoring
- MDW vs. Performance Dashboard
- DEMO: Basic troubleshooting scenario
- Real world implementation scenario w/ multi instance monitoring and high availability w/ AAG (Availability Group)
- Other free/commercial tools
</description>
      <startTime>5/9/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>5/9/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>