<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #358 - Albuquerque 2015</name>
    <startDate>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>200</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-06:00) Saskatchewan</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatAlbuquerque</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>5100 Masthead St. N.E.</name>
      <street>
      </street>
      <city>Albuquerque</city>
      <state>New Mexico</state>
      <zipcode>87109</zipcode>
      <longitude>-106.590538</longitude>
      <latitude>35.16394</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>70</importID>
      <name>Tegile Systems</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.tegile.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.pass.org/images/SQLSaturday/EventSponsors/Tegile_170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>89</importID>
      <name>Profisee</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.profisee.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.profisee.com/Portals/0/lp/assets/img/logo_profisee.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1066</importID>
      <name>SolarWinds</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.solarwinds.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/956/EventSponsor_14566.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1115</importID>
      <name>SQL Sentry</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlsentry.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sentryone.com/Images/logos/sentryone-black.svg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1010</importID>
      <name>Robert Half Technology</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.roberthalf.com/technology/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/870/EventSponsor_14188.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15874</importID>
      <name>Jason Horner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Hi, my name is Jason. I spend most of my day helping clients solve business problems mostly in the Data and Advanced Analytics spaces. Sometimes this involves various and sundry cloud technologies including Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Data Lake Store, Azure Databricks, HDInsight and Azure SQL Database. I'm fluent in several languages including: SQL, C#, Python, and PowerShell.

I'm a Microsoft Certified Master of SQL Server (MCM) and have been recognized for my technical excellence and evangelism efforts by Microsoft by being awarded the Most Valuable Professional (MVP) for the last 5+ years.

In my off hours I like to snowboard, karaoke, ride roller coasters, and play arcade games</description>
      <twitter>jasonhorner</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonhorner</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.jasonhorner.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jasonhorner</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25067</importID>
      <name>Melody Zacharias</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Melody is the Sr. Microsoft Solutions Manager at Pure and has been in love with data since 1991. She has been sharing her passion with the community in technical sessions and blogs since 2014. She has been a Microsoft MVP since 2016, including winning Rookie of the year for Canada that year. This last year, she was elected to the board of directors for PASS.org, the professional association for SQL Server and was awarded Regional Director by Microsoft. She has co-authored 3 books, including, SQL Server 2019 Administration inside out by Microsoft Press.</description>
      <twitter>SQLMelody</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/melodyzacharias</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlmelody.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLMelody</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17264</importID>
      <name>John Morehouse</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Morehouse is currently a Consultant with Denny Cherry  Associates living in Louisville, Kentucky. With over 2 decades of technical experience in various industries, John now focuses on the Microsoft Data platform and specializes in Microsoft SQL Server.  He is honored to be a Microsoft Data Platform MVP, VMWare vExpert, Friend of Red Gate, Sentry One PAC member  Community Ambassador, and 2016 Idera Ace.  John has a passion around speaking, teaching technical topics, and giving back to the technical community as much as possible.  He is a user group leader, SQL Saturday organizer, and former PASS regional mentor. He is also a blogger, avid tweeter, and a frequent speaker at SQL Saturday’s as well as other conferences.</description>
      <twitter>SQLrUs</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlrus</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlrus.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLrUs</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24746</importID>
      <name>Matt Smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Matt is currently a Data Platform  Business Intelligence Technology Solution Professional at Microsoft and works heavily with Enterprise level architectural, analytical,  operational solutions. His technical and leadership experience spans numerous industries. He has a strong interest in remaining tactical in while working at the strategic level. His goal is to assist clients in analyzing, cleansing, and presenting their data so they can make more educated decisions about their business.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22927</importID>
      <name>Jeff Renz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jeff Renz is a Senior Architect at RevGen Partners, currently working as the design architect and implementation lead on several projects for a Fortune Top 50 company. Jeff has worked with SQL Server and BI for 15+ years and has 10 years’ experience with data warehouse design and implementation. In addition to consulting, he is joining the University of Denver adjunct faculty and is expected to begin teaching in the ICT program starting in June.  He received his bachelor’s degree in Computer Science, his master’s degree in Operations Research from Colorado School of Mines, and will be graduating from the Harvard Business Analytics Program in December.</description>
      <twitter>jeff_renz</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-renz/29/82a/aa4</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.revgen.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=jeff_renz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9430</importID>
      <name>Amy Herold</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Amy Herold is currently a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft, specializing in APS. Prior to this, she was a Sr. Database Administrator, focusing on PowerShell and automation. She is also currently the Director of Programs for the North Texas SQL Server User Group (NTSSUG). She frequently speaks at SQL Saturday and user group events across the United States and has also participated in numerous Women in Technology sessions as a panelist. Amy currently blogs at sqlkitten.com.</description>
      <twitter>@texasamy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aherold</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlkitten.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@texasamy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25715</importID>
      <name>Steve Wake</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Wake is currently the Principal BI Developer at Brown and Caldwell and has experience in consulting, advertising, media, manufacturing, retail, charities, telecommunications and financial services organizations using the full on-premises Microsoft BI stack. Recent experience with the Azure services: Analysis Services, Logic Apps,  Data Factory, Databricks, Snowflake and Power BI. Steve is also very involved in the SQL community, speaking at events around the world.</description>
      <twitter>stevewake</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/b5lurker</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.wakebi.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=stevewake</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9788</importID>
      <name>Argenis Fernandez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Argenis is a Principal Architect at Pure Storage. He works with customers around the world to make sure they don’t have to worry much about their infrastructure for Data.
He is a former Data Platform MVP, former VMware vExpert, Microsoft Certified Master, and more recently worked in the Microsoft Azure Data/SQL Server engineering team as a Principal PM in the Tiger team.</description>
      <twitter>DBArgenis</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/argenis</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.purestorage.com/author/argenisfernandez/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DBArgenis</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16500</importID>
      <name>Jennifer McCown</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jen McCown is CEO of MinionWare, LLC; a Microsoft Certified Master for SQL Server; and an independent consultant. She is Senior Editor at MidnightDBA.com, where she creates training videos, the DBAs at Midnight webshow, blogs, reviews, and podcasts. Jen is a member, volunteer, and speaker in PASS, and the PASS Women in Technology Virtual Group.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/MidnightDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.MidnightDBA.com/Jen</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/MidnightDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>25939</importID>
      <name>Seth Washeck</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Seth Washeck, SentryOne senior solutions engineer, is a longtime SQL Server DBA, active member of the Denver SQL Server User Group, and frequent speaker at SentryOne events. He was formerly senior SQL Server DBA at OppenheimerFunds, and DBA of Baxter Healthcare.</description>
      <twitter>@swasheck</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://linkedin.com/in/swasheck</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://swasheck.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@swasheck</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24287</importID>
      <name>Sean McCown</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sean McCown is a Certified Master with 23 years of experience in databases. He is also founder and co-owner of the MidnightDBA.com website, where he records free SQL Server training videos. He also writes the popular Minion Maintenance suite, the most configurable maintenance solution on the planet.</description>
      <twitter>@KenpoDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.midnightdba.com/dbarant</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KenpoDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19143</importID>
      <name>Leslie Weed</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leslie Weed is currently a Data and BI Architect with RevGen Partners in Denver, CO. She has been a SQL Professional specializing in Business Intelligence, data analytics, systems implementation, integration, and solutions delivery for the last 20ish years, including a variety of Enterprise Data Warehouses in various industries.</description>
      <twitter>@weederbug</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@weederbug</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26920</importID>
      <name>TJay Belt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>TJay Belt is an outdoorsman at heart who enjoys riding dirtbikes, waterskiing, boating, playing racquetball and spending time with his family. 
When he can't be out playing, TJay loves to tinker with databases. TJay has been an IT professional for over a decade and a half. Currently serving as a Senior Database Administrator with Imagine Learning.  TJay has progressed through several roles in his database career including developer, data guy, database developer, database analyst and DBA.</description>
      <twitter>@tjaybelt</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/tjaybelt/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://tjaybelt.blogspot.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tjaybelt</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24431</importID>
      <name>Lance Tidwell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lance Tidwell, from the Austin, TX, area, has worked as a SQL Server DBA for the last 11 years. During his time as a DBA he has found his passion for all things SQL, but specifically for performance tuning. He has a life-long quest to always be learning new things; currently this quest has lead him to explore more about the Data Analytics/ Data Science areas.</description>
      <twitter>@Lance_LT</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://lancetidwell.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Lance_LT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19239</importID>
      <name>Lori Edwards</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lori Edwards currently holds the position of Solutions Engineer for SentryOne. Prior to working with SQLSentry, she spent 11 years working as a production DBA.  She also has volunteered for PASS since 2009 on the Program Committee, ERC, Nomination Committee and speaking at SQL Saturdays.</description>
      <twitter>www.twitter.com/loriaedwards</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/loriedwards/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservertimes2.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=www.twitter.com/loriaedwards</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26993</importID>
      <name>Tom Roush</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tom is a master storyteller, known to translate Geek into plain English in a single bound. His wry sense of humor, life experiences and vivid descriptions are skillfully combined with his expertise as a DBA to have you understanding SQL in ways you never thought you would. Tom’s explanations of why to do something are insightful, why *not* to do something enlightening, and the stories behind them, both tech and non-tech, will leave you laughing to the point you forget you’re learning something. </description>
      <twitter>@geeql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/tomroush</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.geeql.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@geeql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26641</importID>
      <name>Tim Mitchell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tim Mitchell is a business intelligence architect, author, and trainer. He has worked with SQL Server for over a decade, specializing in data warehousing, ETL/SSIS, and reporting. He holds a Bachelor’s Degree in Computer Science from Texas AM at Commerce, and is recognized as a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.  Tim is a business intelligence consultant and principal at Tyleris Data Solutions.

Tim is an active community speaker and volunteer, having spoken at over 100 events including the PASS Summit, SQLBits, Dev Connections, SQL Intersection, and scores of SQL Saturdays. He blogs at TimMitchell.net, and tweets at @Tim_Mitchell.</description>
      <twitter>@Tim_Mitchell</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timmitchell/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.TimMitchell.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Tim_Mitchell</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>27110</importID>
      <name>Trent Sherman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Trent Sherman has over 25 years of overall IT experience and over 20 years of DBA experience primarily in the telecommunications amp; software industries using Oracle amp; SQL Server.  He is currently an Engineer/DBA with Confio Corporation, recently acquired by Solarwinds. Prior to Solarwinds, Trent worked as a Senior Infrastructure Architect, Technical Manager, DBA, Developer and Design architect in several OLTP amp; VLDB/Data Warehouse database environments. </description>
      <twitter>@dbatrent</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dbatrent</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26140</importID>
      <name>Thane Schaffer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Over 25 years of IT experience focusing on software development during much of his career, Thane has in recent years focused on database development, architect/design, modeling, administration, and ETO focused ERP systems.  His current position as a DBA at Transcore in Albuquerque NM provides a opportunities to do much of everything that a database generalist would enjoy doing.</description>
      <twitter>@thaneschaffer</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/thane-schaffer/1a/4/874</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlambassador.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@thaneschaffer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11753</importID>
      <name>Meredith Ryan-Smith</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description> 
Meredith is the database administrator for The Bell Group.  With more than 10 years of experience in IT, Meredith’s responsibilities have included everything from manning the Help Desk to VAX/VMS cluster administration. Most recently she has served as the production database administrator specializing in cluster administration and performance. Meredith has attended seven PASS Summits, and had volunteered with the WIT Virtual Chapter since early 2009. Most recently Meredith became the chapter leader for the Women In Technology Virtual Chapter, and has kept busy speaking at SQL Saturday events in the western half of the US. </description>
      <twitter>@coffegrl</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://meredithryansmith.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@coffegrl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18947</importID>
      <name>Leslie Andrews</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Leslie Andrews is an IT professional with almost 20 years of experience working with databases, designing databases, as well as designing and developing applications against those databases. 2018-2019 Idera ACE.</description>
      <twitter>landrews5807</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/leslie-andrews-csm/9/491/b89</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.lace.technology/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=landrews5807</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34772</importID>
      <name>Michael Fal</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mike is a specialist in data management technologies. As a community advocate, public speaker, and blogger, Mike is a practicing thought leader for data and automation. He is passionate about DevOps and data, building platforms to optimize, protect, and use data efficiently.

Since 1999, Mike has been working in the database field, focusing primarily on SQL Server and specializes in automating data solutions to improve the reliability and efficiency of his environments. He has been caught playing trombone in public on more than one occasion.</description>
      <twitter>@Mike_Fal</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelfal/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mikefal.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Mike_Fal</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14668</importID>
      <name>Ginger Grant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ginger Grant manages the consultancy Desert Isle Group and shares what she has learned while working with data technology to people around the world.  As a Microsoft MVP in Data Platform, Microsoft Certified Trainer and an instructor on DataCamp, she focuses on guiding clients to create solutions using the entire Microsoft Data Stack, which includes SQL Server, Power BI, and Azure Data Cloud components. When not working, she protypes the latest pre-release data technologies, maintains her blog http://www.desertislesql.com, and spends time on twitter @desertislesql.</description>
      <twitter>desertislesql</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ginger-grant-3a177b157/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.DesertIsleSQL.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=desertislesql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19432</importID>
      <name>Marc Beacom</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Marc Beacom is President of DawaBI, a Data Warehouse and Business Intelligence Consultancy firm focusing on Making Data-Driven Decisions Possible. He has been working with SQL Server for over a decade delivering scalable solutions for organizations of all sizes. He has earned several industry certifications and degrees. Marc is an active member of the community and has volunteered for many organizations such as PASS, Denver SQL, Colorado GiveCamp, Camp To Belong, to name a few.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dawabi.com/blog.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13250</importID>
      <name>B. Diane Blackwood</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Diane Blackwood has spent her 15 year technology career integrating systems and making information available to a wider corporate audience.  She works for Strafford Technology as a senior consultant doing business intelligence/corporate performance management software implementations.  She has been with Strafford since 2008.  </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.blackwood.org</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17163</importID>
      <name>John McAllister</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John McAllister co-founded Stratature, an Independent MDM software vendor, in 2001. Following Microsoft’s acquisition of Stratature in 2007 John served as Group Program Manager for MDS and oversaw the incorporation of MDM into SQL Server. John now serves as the Regional Sales Director for Profisee, Inc. which provides enterprise-class MDM Solutions built on top of Microsoft’s MDS offering. John has worked with 100’s of organizations around the world in all phases of MDM projects. </description>
      <twitter>@jmcallis64</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/johnbmcallister</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.profisee.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@jmcallis64</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23594</importID>
      <name>Russ Thomas</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Prior to focusing full time on IT Management and Database Administration in the Denver Colorado financial sector, Russ spent several years in law enforcement including four as a training Sergeant and Washington CJTC Instructor specializing in Emergency Vehicle Driving at Portland Intl Raceway. An experienced public speaker and trainer, Russ also has two decades of hands on IT work and leadership experience.  Russ is a SQL Server Data Platform MCSE and is active in the SQL Saturday community.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLJudo</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/russ-thomas/59/601/4b2/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqljudo.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLJudo</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>9066</importID>
      <name>Alan Faulkner</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am an IT professional with over 20+ years of progressive technical experience with managing, consulting, software development, data integration architecture, data warehousing, and business intelligence development projects. The focus of my work is to work closely with stakeholders to develop architecture frameworks that align with organizational strategy, processes, and IT assets. Specializing in Business Intelligence (BI), Data Warehousing, database architecture, design and implementation.</description>
      <twitter>#FalconTekNik</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/alan-faulkner/31/b79/932/ </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://falconteksolutionscentral.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=#FalconTekNik</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26563</importID>
      <name>Christopher Wolff</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Wolff has been a developer, report writer, and an admin in Microsoft and SQL Server Space since SQL Server 2000 in industries such as telecommunications, green energy, money transfers, and online accounting. He has been an active member of the Denver SQL User Group since 2011 and enjoys learning new things about computers. His interests includes video games, movies, and enjoying time with his wife and 2 kids.</description>
      <twitter>@tickytong</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/christopher-wolff/11/a07/458</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlred.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tickytong</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17730</importID>
      <name>John Sterrett</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Sterrett is a MCSE: Data Platform, Principal Consultant, and the Founder of Procure SQL LLC.  John has experience presenting at community events, including Microsoft Ignite, PASS Member Summit, SQLRally, 24 Hours of PASS, SQL Saturdays, PASS Chapters, and Virtual Chapter meetings. John is a leader of the Austin SQL Server User Group and is the founder of the HADR Virtual Chapter. John's community activities can be found at https://johnsterrett.com/community/</description>
      <twitter>JohnSterrett</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/johnsterrett</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://johnsterrett.com/community/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=JohnSterrett</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10889</importID>
      <name>Jason Brimhall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jason Brimhall has more than 20 years of experience and has worked with SQL Server 6.5 through SQL Server 2019. He has experience in performance tuning, high transaction environments, and large environments. He is currently a consultant specializing in performance tuning, server analysis, and problem resolution. Jason is a Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) and a Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>sqlrnnr</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbajbrimhall/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://jasonbrimhall.info</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlrnnr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14127</importID>
      <name>Gabriel Villa</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gabriel is a skilled leader, architect, and technical expert focusing primarily on Microsoft technologies and is passionate about open-source technologies for integration, automation, and development. Gabriel’s versatility extends from systems, data and development and leverages hybrid/SaaS/Cloud integration, proven software engineering platforms, and best-of-breed data management and business intelligence solutions.

Originally from El Paso, Texas, Gabriel lives in Colorado Springs with his wife and kids, where he is an Architect for RevGen Partners, volunteers in the tech community and enjoys the Colorado outdoors.</description>
      <twitter>@extofer</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabevilla</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://extofer.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@extofer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>23436</importID>
      <name>Ron Beatty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ron Beatty is currently a Business Intelligence Developer. Ron has been in the trenches developing software solutions with Microsoft technologies for over 12+ years, with 9 years spent as a SQL Server developer. Ron has been working with the Microsoft BI Stack since SQL Server 2005, specializing in SQL Server Analysis Services, data warehousing, and MDX. Ron has a Bachelor’s degree from UNM in mathematics and a Master’s degree from UT in Biomedical Sciences.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17606</importID>
      <name>Jay Robinson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jay Robinson earned his MCSD and MCSE way back in 1999, getting certified on SQL Server 6.5 and 2000 along the way. A nice and quiet career as a developer followed. And then he came to ExactTarget (now the Salesforce Marketing Cloud) in 2008 and found out what real databases were like. Obsessed with speed, he spends his time writing code that makes big data go fast.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://downshiftdata.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10456</importID>
      <name>Bill Fellows</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bill Fellows is a SQL Server MVP and has been a database developer for most of his career, with the past 15 years focused on ETL. He is the organizer of Kansas City's eight SQL Saturdays and a speaker at many other SQL Saturdays, User Groups and the PASS Summit. Bill is the owner of Sterling Data Consulting where he gets to solve interesting data problems.</description>
      <twitter>@billinkc</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/billinkc</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.billfellows.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@billinkc</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16897</importID>
      <name>Jason Kassay</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jason Kassay is a database administrator, software engineer amp; speaker from Colorado with over 12 years of experience. He is passionate about SQL Server, programming, release process, automation amp; performance tuning. Jason is an active member of the SQL Server community amp; volunteers/presents at events such as Colorado User Groups, SQL Saturday amp; Colorado GiveCamp. When not tuning databases or coding, Jason will most likely be found spending time with his family, playing hockey or running.</description>
      <twitter>@jasonkassay</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://linkedin.com/in/jasonkassay</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.JasonKassay.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@jasonkassay</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>11753</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11753</id>
          <name>Meredith Ryan-Smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Women In Tech Panel discussion</title>
      <description>The definition of confidence is “belief in oneself and one’s powers or abilities” but the authors of the new book “The Confidence Code” define confidence as “the quality that turns thoughts into actions.” Traditionally men have been found to have much more confidence in themselves than do women. For example, in a study at Hewlett-Packard, men applied for a promotion when they thought they could meet 60% of the qualifications while women applied only when they thought they could meet 100%.   Attend this WIT session with panelists Melody Zacharias, Ginger Grant, Amy Herold, and Meredith Ryan to learn more about confidence and how it impacts your career and life. To prepare for the session, it is recommended that you complete The Confidence Quiz (http://theconfidencecode.com/confidence-quiz/) before the event and print out the results and recommendation. NOTE: You will not be required to share your results with the other participants during the session.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19432</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19432</id>
          <name>Marc Beacom</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting started with Dimensional Modeling</title>
      <description>Technology has revolutionized the way organizations run today. Rather than a few file cabinets, organizations use many different software packages and applications that are mission critical to running their business. These systems gather a large amount of valuable data that must be used in decision making to maintain a competitive advantage. However, we've all heard and likely been around when mission critical systems have been rendered useless due to long running reports. To solve this and a host of other source system reporting issues we have proven Data Warehousing techniques to store the data in a report friendly way. Dimensional modeling is one of the most widely used set of techniques that will provide source system relief for reporting. In this session, we will take a look at what Dimensional Modeling is along with some key terms and techniques.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23594</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23594</id>
          <name>Russ Thomas</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>PaaF: Performance as a Feature in an ORM World</title>
      <description>A high performing data tier does not happen by accident.  High quality shops understand that performance must be designed as a feature.  While SQL Server remains one of the most popular databases in the world, the modern software engineer would rather learn Entity Framework, Dapper, or ORMLite over straight TSQL.  Since the TSQL keys have in many cases been handed over to a service tier or ORM, maintaining a high performing database in this environment places significant emphasis on fundamental design.  This session will identify the 5 most important factors that every database requires to support "performance as a feature".  This session is for the Software Engineer or DBA/Data Architect/DBE who works with database servers where TSQL has b</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25715</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25715</id>
          <name>Steve Wake</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Date Dimension: Past  Future in One Script</title>
      <description>All data warehouses need a date and time dimension to enable proper analysis across time. Most Data Warehouse designers will just use one provided by tools or whip it up in Excel, but what if you need to set up custom holidays or want different calendars, such as Fiscal or Julian? You can have any date and time dimension you need by using a single SQL script that can be modified and rerun as necessary. Learn what it takes to design a date and time dimension that does all of the calculations and formatting up-front so the reports can be easier to create. Sample script will be provided that creates the date and time dimensions and can be reused as often as necessary without breaking your data warehouse and it only take seconds to run!</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26993</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26993</id>
          <name>Tom Roush</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Life Lessons in Communication</title>
      <description>Communicating. We all do it, every day. But can you do it better? You present to management, share with peers, advise your direct reports. A common thread of success or failure here is how well you get your message across. 
Can you share bad news and soften the blow with humor while respecting the nature of the news you have to deliver?
Can you support your direct reports when they make a very human mistake?
Do you know how you communicate your support without micromanaging them can make a huge difference in the quality of their work for years to come? 
These questions and more will be answered, with stories, with humor, and with experience (both good and bad).
Once you've figured these things out, how do you communicate your own skills to the world? 
After attending, you’ll be on the road to better, more direct communication, whether it’s with your management, your peers, or your reports.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26641</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26641</id>
          <name>Tim Mitchell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Incremental Load Design Patterns</title>
      <description>The volume of data addressed by the typical ETL operation is constantly on the rise.  Not so many years ago, a table with a few million records was considered to be huge.  These days, it's not uncommon to deal with multibillion row tables.  As a result, ETL professionals are frequently tasked with finding efficient ways to incrementally process these large sets of data without resorting to expensive and time-consuming destructive reloads.
 
In this session, we will review the common decision points surrounding incrementally loading data, and will demonstrate some of the methods for incremental processing.  Among the topics of discussion:
--Deciding whether an incremental load is appropriate
--Pick your tool: T-SQL or SSIS?
--Methods for detecting new and changed records
--Common incremental load design patterns</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>27110</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>27110</id>
          <name>Trent Sherman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>An Oracle DBA's Survival Guide to SQL Server Database Administration</title>
      <description>Often times, an Oracle DBA is given the new responsibility of administering SQL Server Instances.   Or, conversely a SQL Server DBA has been given Oracle database instances to manage.   This session provides a general survival guide to assist with the DBA’s journey to the “other-side”.    An overview will be presented on the differences  similarities between Oracle and SQL server in the areas of:  terminology, object structures, memory, storage architecture, back  recovery, basic administration, data transfers, security and performance analysis.   We’ll discuss steps  strategies to help guide you in learning this new database skill set, and also look at common performance analysis tools which can be used across both Oracle and SQL Server databases.   Whether a DBA, developer or manager, this overview will help gain a basic understanding of the key similarities and differences between SQL Server  Oracle.  </description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>23436</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>23436</id>
          <name>Ron Beatty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSIS ETL for Type1 and Type2 SCD</title>
      <description>How to handle and track changes in a data warehouse dimension table is an important dimensional modeling consideration. The dimension tables of a data warehouse need to be designed to appropriately store a history of attribute changes over time. The ETL processes need to detect these changes and correctly update the dimensional table to preserve historical accuracy. Finally, fact records need to be associated with the correct historical version of the dimension. In this presentation, a SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) will be demonstrated that creates an ETL data flow which will load a dimensional table with both Type 1 and Type 2 dimensional attributes.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18947</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18947</id>
          <name>Leslie Andrews</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why Be Normal?</title>
      <description>Is your database normal?  While being different and off-beat can be good for your personal life it is not a happy situation for your database to live in.  Databases like to be normal!  Join me for a fun and informational session on how to create a normal database and find out why it is important.  We will also talk about how to make a database normal using queries so you can benefit from normalcy without having to go through major psychotherapy. </description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9430</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9430</id>
          <name>Amy Herold</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Making the Leap from Developer to DBA</title>
      <description>You are a Developer (.NET, SQL or otherwise) but you have been doing some DBA work and have now decided that is all you want to do - how do you make the transition? What do you need to know? This session will cover this topic from first-hand experience. </description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19143</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19143</id>
          <name>Leslie Weed</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Modeling 101</title>
      <description>Covering the basics for the beginner and those that have been thrown into a modeling role and have been cowboy’n it like the Wild West.  We’ll cover why you should bother with a conceptual model and invest some of your project time in the modeling task.  We will  go over some different modeling techniques around Normalized, Dimensional and Data Vault options.   And lastly, considerations for scalability, sustainability and empowering you with a Data Access Layer so you stay in control of your architecture as opposed to the application beast.  Yee-Haw!

</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17163</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17163</id>
          <name>John McAllister</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Master Data Management - Getting Started with SQL Server MDS </title>
      <description>This session will provide an introduction to Master Data Management (MDM). We explore the basic concepts, types of MDM solution, and the basics for a successful MDM Implementation. With a working definition in hand, we'll discuss strategies for beginning a successful MDM pilot in your organization and look at some of the pitfalls to avoid. We'll wrap the business discussion up with some tips for selecting the right domains to solve and some tips for managing the politics of MDM. After we've set the stage for what, how and why you need MDM, we'll take a brief look at SQL Server MDS through the Excel add-in and talk about the Architecture of MDS</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15874</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15874</id>
          <name>Jason Horner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Tricks from the DBA Inbox: Real World Performance Tuning</title>
      <description>n this heavily demo based session, we show some techniques for performance tuning common problems faced by DBA's Including: how to identify the problem, resolve the issue, and test the solution. Along the way we will also discuss some of theory behind the solutions. We all know there is no such thing as DBCC GO_FASTER but this session is the next best thing.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16897</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16897</id>
          <name>Jason Kassay</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Visual Studio Database Projects and Database Deployment</title>
      <description>How does your shop keep track of changes to your database schema? What are the database deployment procedures? Do you just make changes directly in production? In this beginner level session you will learn how to easily manage your database schema by leveraging SSDT in Visual Studio with Database Projects, create deployment scripts, and generate re-runnable deployment packages called DACPAC's. We will review how source control interacts with database projects as well as discuss how you can use PowerShell to automate your database deployments.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24287</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24287</id>
          <name>Sean McCown</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>DIY Performance Reporting</title>
      <description>Stop relying on vendors to provide you with performance data.  Between Windows and SQL Server you’ve already got all you need to collect and report on server performance.  And it’s far more flexible than you’ll ever get from a vendor.  This is often called a poor man’s method, but it’s so much more than that.  I’m going to show you what your options are for collecting performance data for free and you’ll even walk away with a framework you can plug into your own environment and start using tomorrow with very little effort.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25939</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25939</id>
          <name>Seth Washeck</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Advanced Statistics Management: Setting Up SQL Server For Success</title>
      <description>The optimizer uses statistics to generate a cardinality estimate which, in turn, affects query plan decisions as well as system resources. In this session we're going to step through the process of evaluating the statistics present (or not present) and present a methodology for analyzing the presence of skew, candidate filtered statistics, and their efficacy in an environment. Additionally, we'll look at the impacts of the new Cardinality Estimator in SQL Server 2014 on plan generation This would, ultimately, be an excellent addition to any periodic SQL Server health check.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13250</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13250</id>
          <name>B. Diane Blackwood</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data transformation best practices</title>
      <description>SQL 2012 best practices for data transformation</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14668</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14668</id>
          <name>Ginger Grant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Top 10 SSIS Tuning Tricks</title>
      <description>Interested in making SSIS perform faster? Do you wonder what the best practices for writing Packages really are?   This session reviews how to create SSIS packages to perform as quickly as possible by revealing the Top 10 things you can do to improve the performance of your packages.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9788</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9788</id>
          <name>Argenis Fernandez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Stored Procedures vs. Ad-Hoc SQL: Performance Showdown!</title>
      <description>Still not sure of which is faster? Let us put this matter to rest once and for all. We will measure every single aspect of the execution of a stored procedure vs. its Ad-Hoc query counterpart, and only one will prevail! We will look at raw performance, memory consumption, plan cache usage, and network bandwidth utilization. We will also discuss options for environments on which the code cannot be modified.
</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24746</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24746</id>
          <name>Matt Smith</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data wizardry with the next generation of Power BI!</title>
      <description>This will be an action-packed culmination of entertainment, story telling, jokes, and data wizardry using the next generation of Power BI! </description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10456</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10456</id>
          <name>Bill Fellows</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Type More, Click Less:  Programmatically build SSIS packages</title>
      <description>Developing repetitive strain injury (RSI) from all those mouse clicks in Business Intelligence Development Studio/SQL Server Data Tools? Longing to automate the tedium in SQL Server Integration Services package creation? In this session, we’ll explore the Integration Services object model and learn how to create rich packages without ever clicking our mouse. You’ll learn about the basic object model, the EzAPI wrapper for it, as well as using BIMLScript to build moderately complex packages.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22927</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22927</id>
          <name>Jeff Renz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dashboards - More Than One Way To Visualize Data</title>
      <description>Presenting BI in a sophisticated look that is both user friendly and easy to use can be challenging. In this session I will review the three major types of dashboards (Operational, Strategic, and Analytical).  Using Visio, SSRS, SharePoint and Pyramid Analytics I will demonstrate examples of each of the dashboard types.  </description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10889</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10889</id>
          <name>Jason Brimhall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Murder They Wrote</title>
      <description>Join Microsoft Certified Master, Jason Brimhall, as he examines numerous database design and coding implementations that they have seen over the years.  They will explore these implementations and show how they can be murder on SQL Server in terms of performance, security, storage and even accuracy. You will learn how you can identify these “killers” and how you can implement alternatives that will keep data professionals, management, and end-users happy.  All while keeping your databases happy, secure, turbo-charged and healthy. 

This is the Solo version of the Joint version normally done as an all-day precon</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24431</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24431</id>
          <name>Lance Tidwell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Parameter Sniffing the Good and the Bad</title>
      <description>Parameter sniffing is something that more than often helps performance on your servers; however, there are times when it can hinder performance as well.    In this session we will define exactly what parameter sniffing is, and examine when it is good and when it is bad.  Lastly, we will explore the different options available to fix bad parameter sniffing.  After this session, you will be able to locate and fix bad parameter sniffing when it occurs on your servers.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34772</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34772</id>
          <name>Michael Fal</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Powershell Tips and Tricks for SQL Server Administration</title>
      <description>Have you dipped your toe into the Powershell pool, but are still lost on how you can make it work for you?  Maybe you're just looking for a few more tools to help you better manage SQL Server administration?  In this session, we will cover a handful of useful scripts and patterns in Powershell that will ease your management of SQL Server.  Backups, file management, instance configuration, and several other areas will be covered.  By attending this session, you will learn more about how you can use Powershell effectively in your environment.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19239</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19239</id>
          <name>Lori Edwards</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Let's Get It Started - SQL Server installation and configuration</title>
      <description>We've all installed SQL Server and, most of the times, the default settings work just fine.  This is a beginner session that will help you to understand what those settings mean along with why there might be times that you want to use something other than the defaults and how that might impact your server.  We'll also go through unattended installs, both with and without a config file.  This can really help to standardize your SQL Server installations and save you some precious keystrokes.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17606</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17606</id>
          <name>Jay Robinson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Fast and Furious Dynamic SQL</title>
      <description>We all appreciate a well-defined and well-tuned stored procedure. But sometimes the problem calls for a more dynamic solution. What are those problems and how do you generate SQL to solve them? After attending this session, you will be able to identify situations that call for dynamic SQL and address them with rapid, maintainable, and secure code.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17264</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17264</id>
          <name>John Morehouse</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Social Networking Is Alive!!!</title>
      <description>Social Networking/Media is all over the news today. Did you see that on Facebook?  Johnny 5 said what on Twitter?? Can you believe Susie moved to that company?? Do any of those sound familiar? No?  Never heard of Twitter? Don't have any fear as this session is for you!  Social networking can be a very confusing place and when you don't know where to start, that makes it even worse.  In this session, we will go over different facets of Social Networking/Media and how you can use them to enhance not only your personal lives but just as importantly, your professional one.  We'll be covering Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter. </description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>9066</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>9066</id>
          <name>Alan Faulkner</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SSAS Design and Performance Best Practices</title>
      <description>A journey through best practices in relation to scalable SQL Server Analysis Services cube design.  From dimension design to SSAS engine internals we will explore SSAS multidimensional design patterns that will take you through steps to assist in getting your SSAS cubes better optimized to better match the needs of your organization.  After this session you will be able to take these performance design patterns and apply them to new and existing cubes to tune your SSAS cube environment.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26920</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26920</id>
          <name>TJay Belt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Documentation – you know you love it</title>
      <description>We will discuss some of the most important things that you as a Data Professional can document to make your job much easier, ensure information consistency between groups, and better prepare your organizations for raising the bar on your day to day business.  Think of this as a sort of Database Library that allows you to finally detail the processes you follow currently to perform repetitive tasks.  This Library will also allow you to simply document your systems for your and others knowledge.  </description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17730</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17730</id>
          <name>John Sterrett</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to High Availability with SQL Server</title>
      <description>Have you wondered which high availability features might be best for your shop? In this session we will go over a quick look at log shipping, database mirroring, transactional replication, failover cluster instances and availability groups. John will identify pros and cons for each features and share some tips from the field.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>16500</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16500</id>
          <name>Jennifer McCown</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Designing Stored Procedure Solutions</title>
      <description>In this session, you’ll learn about SQL Server stored procedures (SPs): what they are, when and why you'd use them, and how you'd go about developing a solution with one.  We will address common SP myths and learn about planning for performance. Most of all, we’ll walk through examples to explore the process of solution building in SQL Server.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26563</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26563</id>
          <name>Christopher Wolff</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Fun with Availability Groups</title>
      <description>Follow along as we adventure through the vastness that is Availability Groups in SQL Server.  In this beginners guys we show you how to make an Availability Group from scratch, the new system tables that go along with Availability Groups, and how to troubleshoot your Availability Group using the system tables and SSMS.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14127</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14127</id>
          <name>Gabriel Villa</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>What’s this ‘Scaffolding a CRUD’ all about? Build a Website from your SQL Database</title>
      <description>So you have a SQL Server database, and you want a web site for your tables? Come see how to develop and deploy a simple .NET website against any SQL Server database. See firsthand how to use Microsoft’s Entity Framework, ASP.Net MVC and other tricks to develop a website by writing very little code. Take home the ability to create and deploy a simple website to your own database once this demonstration is seen. </description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>25067</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>25067</id>
          <name>Melody Zacharias</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Become a Backup Tuning Wizard</title>
      <description>Do your backups take too long? Do you know how to determine how long they are taking?  Would you like database backups to run faster without having to ask for faster hardware?  Then come learn some tips and tricks to make your SQL database backups run faster.  In this session, we’ll look at several tangible things that you can take back to your environment and make an immediate measurable difference.</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26140</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26140</id>
          <name>Thane Schaffer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>
      </track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intermediate set theory with demo</title>
      <description>This presentation will compare and contrast set operations with Except, Intersect, and Unions compared with performance of accomplishing the same tasks with inner, outer, and full join queries.
</description>
      <startTime>2/7/2015 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>2/7/2015 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>