<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #988 - Gothenburg 2020</name>
    <startDate>9/5/2020 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>70</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Sarajevo, Skopje, Warsaw, Zagreb</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatGothenburg</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Svea</name>
      <street>Forskningsgången 4</street>
      <city>Göteborg</city>
      <state>Västra Götalands län, Sweden</state>
      <zipcode>417 56 Göteborg</zipcode>
      <longitude>11.9368059</longitude>
      <latitude>57.7062157</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1781</importID>
      <name>Microsoft</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14841.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2678</importID>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://cloud.google.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14839.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2689</importID>
      <name>Red Hat</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Supporter</label>
      <url>https://www.redhat.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14840.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>40</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>100</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1473</importID>
      <name>SQL Service Nordic AB</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sqlservice.se</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14826.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1069</importID>
      <name>SolidQ Nordic</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.solidq.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14821.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1928</importID>
      <name>dbWatch</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://cilbuper.se/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14817.svg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2170</importID>
      <name>Structured Concepts AB</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://strd.co/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14818.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103432</importID>
      <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Erland Sommarskog is an independent consultant based in Stockholm, working with SQL Server since 1991. He was first awarded SQL Server MVP in 2001, and has been re-awarded every year since. His focus is on systems development with the SQL Server Database Engine and his passion is to help people to write better SQL Server applications.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sommarskog.se</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103207</importID>
      <name>Philipp Lenz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Philipp works as a Business Intelligence Senior Consultant at XXXL Digital in Coblenz, Germany. With the advent of Power Pivot for Excel and SQL Server Reporting Services, he has discovered his passion for Microsoft Business Intelligence technologies over 12 years.

Since mid-2016 he has been a founding member of the Power BI Usergroup in Cologne and is Chapter Leader of SQL PASS Mittelrhein, Germany. In 2019 he has also founded the Power Apps and Power Automate Usergroup and he was in the end of 2019 recognized as an Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>lenz_philipp</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.flip-it.de</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=lenz_philipp</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104491</importID>
      <name>Asgeir Gunnarsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ásgeir Gunnarsson is a Data Platform MVP and Chief Consultant at Datheos in Denmark. He works on Business Intelligence solutions using the whole of the Microsoft BI stack. Ásgeir has been working in BI since 2007 both as a consultant and internal employee. Before turning to BI, Ásgeir worked as a technical trainer and currently teaches BI courses at the Continuing Education Department of the University of Iceland. 

Ásgeir speaks regularly at events both domestically and internationally, and is the group leader of the Icelandic PASS Group, as well as the Icelandic Power BI User Group. 

Ásgeir is passionate about data and loves solving problems with BI.</description>
      <twitter>bidgeir</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://is.linkedin.com/in/asgeirgun</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bidgeir</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103015</importID>
      <name>Ted Malone</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ted is currently a Data and AI Solution Architect with Microsoft's Customer Success organization. In this role, he works with large organizations to ensure that they properly and efficiently apply AI, Machine Learning, Data Analytics, and Business Intelligence technologies to achieve their business goals. Prior to taking this role, Ted worked with the US Federal Government to help solve "Big Data" problems through the use of cloud technologies.

Prior to joining Microsoft, Ted was an architect in EMC's CTO organization, and led data development teams for a variety of startup organizations.

Ted has worked with SQL Server since it's inception, and focuses on applying new technologies and techniques to age-old problems.</description>
      <twitter>@tedmalone</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/temalone/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blog.sqltrainer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@tedmalone</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105083</importID>
      <name>Torsten Strauss</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Torsten (MVP, MCSE, MCT) has been working with Microsoft SQL Server since the turn of the millennium and is specialized in performance optimization for large SQL Server environments. He has been with bp as a database engineer for over two decades and collaborates closely with Sarpedon Quality Lab as a Principal Microsoft SQL Server Consultant. Torsten is the founder of inside-sqlserver.com and has given more than 120 presentations on Microsoft SQL Server performance optimization at national and international conferences and user groups. Torsten has been recognized as a Microsoft Most Valuable Professional for Data Platform since 2018.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104147</importID>
      <name>Juan E. Moreno Romo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I was born in IT as a developer. I worked in Data Modeling, as Consultant, Software Architect and Project Manager in a Consultancy Service Company, what leads me to create my own Consultancy Company. I worked on it for almost 15 years till an awesome company, Microsoft, knock my door.

I have delivered training in Developing Technologies, Programming Methodology, Software development process, ALM, different programming languages, Project Managing, Data Modeling, MySQL and SQL among other subjects

Currently I am happily working in Microsoft, based in Madrid (Spain), focused in SQL Server Business as Support Escalation Engineer for SQL Server Core and SQL Server on IaaS in CSS Western Europe Support Team.</description>
      <twitter>DarthSicuel</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/juanemorenoromo?trk=hp-identity-name</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DarthSicuel</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103560</importID>
      <name>Kevin Chant</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior Database Architect originally from the UK and now living in the Netherlands. Data Platform MVP and MCT.

Over 23 years experience in the IT sector, and has supported databases for companies in the top 10 of the fortune 500 list.

In addition to a lot of SQL Server experience also has a fair few Microsoft Certifications. In addition, was probably the last ever person in the world to gain the MCSD Azure Architect certification and has gained the latest Microsoft DevOps Engineer Expert certification. 

Has real life experience with SQL Server and Azure Devops. Currently SQL Server Product Owner of around 1,900 instances. 

In addition, done various things over the years for the Data Platform Community.</description>
      <twitter>kevchant</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-chant/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.KevinRChant.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=kevchant</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>105218</importID>
      <name>Damir Matesic</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>For many years Damir is a passionate programmer and a Microsoft SQL Server developer (ver. 2000+). 
He is a certificated Microsoft professional on various technologies. In 2020 Microsoft awarded him with Data Platform MVP. 
Damir leads the Croatian SQL Server User Group (PASS) and he introduced and organizes SQL Saturday events in Croatia. Founder and organizer of #DataWeekender.
He is working as Senior Database Developer @Span.eu. 
Damir speaks on various community events and conferences like SQLSaturday, Advanced technology days and user groups. 
When free he blogs about SQL @ https://blog.matesic.info.</description>
      <twitter>matesic_damir</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmatesic/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://blog.matesic.info/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=matesic_damir</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104935</importID>
      <name>Dennes Torres</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Dennes Torres is a Data Platform MVP with more than 25 years of experience in the IT area. He improves Data Platform Architectures and turns data into knowledge. As a Brazilian living in Malta, Dennes works as a software developer and leads the Malta MDP User Group. Having the MCSE Data Platform, Business Intelligence, and Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) certifications, Dennes has been in love with database servers since he was  introduced to SQL Server 6.5, more years ago than he would like to admit.</description>
      <twitter>Dennes</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennestorres/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/dennes-torres/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Dennes</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103129</importID>
      <name>Jens Vestergaard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jens performs the traditional BI disciplines from imports in Integration Services through data consolidation in Analysis Services, to report in Power BI or Reporting Services. Jens has worked with The Stack since SQL 2000 and has a core competence in Integration Services and Analysis Services. Along with the certified skills in Microsoft SQL Server, Jens has also worked with Microsoft .Net platform for more than 15 years and currently manages a BI Platform in Azure for the CatMan Solution application(s).</description>
      <twitter>@vestergaardj</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/jvestergaard</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.t-sql.dk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@vestergaardj</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103036</importID>
      <name>Benni De Jagere</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Benni De Jagere is a Senior Data Insights Consultant at Realdolmen, with a strong focus on the Microsoft (BI) Stack. 

On a daily basis he turns (large amounts) of coffee into insights for customers, and references witty British comedy way too often. Overly enthusiastic about anything data related, he’s trying hard to keep up with all things new and shiny.

Rumour has it that he's also involved with a ragtag band of data enthusiasts, enjoying themselves whilst organising cool community things. They go by the name of .. dataMinds!</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/BenniDeJagere</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bennidejagere/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://bennidejagere.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/BenniDeJagere</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>104199</importID>
      <name>Alexander Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Alexander Klein is a senior Business Intelligence consultant with more than 15 years of experience. He focuses on Business Intelligence and Data Warehouse projects with Microsoft technologies like SQL Server, Power BI, Azure ML or Cortana Intelligence. 

Since 2008, he has been a self-employed consultant in large and medium-sized projects in all sectors across Europe. He has been visiting SQL Saturdays and other Data Conference all over Europe since 2013. Speaker at national and international events since 2017.</description>
      <twitter>@SQL_Alex</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-klein-13a04b3a</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQL_Alex</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103012</importID>
      <name>Brent Ozar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brent Ozar loves to make SQL Server faster. He created sp_Blitz and the SQL Server First Responder Kit. He shares what he's learned at BrentOzar.com.</description>
      <twitter>BrentO</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/brentozar</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.BrentOzar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=BrentO</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103103</importID>
      <name>Oskari Heikkinen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have several years of experience in using Azure for data analytics at large scale. I have been implementing numerous projects for some of the largest companies in the Nordics.

I am a Microsoft MVP, and I currently hold the MCSE: Data Management and Analytics certification. As a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT), I hold classes for subject-matter experts and consultants internally as well as give external customer training sessions. I am also an active speaker on community events.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/oskariheikkinen/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>103019</importID>
      <name>Magnus Ahlkvist</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Independent database consultant and certified trainer with a passion for chasing that extra millisecond.
20 years of database development and administration but trying to be humble enough to understand that I'm still learning.</description>
      <twitter>Transmokopter</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://se.linkedin.com/in/magnusahlkvist</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.tsql.nu</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Transmokopter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>103012</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103012</id>
          <name>Brent Ozar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>GAMMA</name>
      </location>
      <title>What's New in SQL Server 2019: 100% Demos</title>
      <description>You haven't installed SQL Server 2019 yet, and you don't want to sit through a bunch of slides. You want to see a series of real-world demos focusing on the features of SQL Server 2019 that will make your users happier with as little work as possible on your part. You don't have time to rewrite all your queries or learn new languages - you just want the database to go faster.

I'm Brent Ozar, and I'll give you the whirlwind tour. I'll focus on just the features that make the biggest bang for the buck, things you can implement right away and see a noticeable difference. I'll show you what kinds of code will benefit the most so you can go back to the office and have an honest discussion with management about what to expect.

No slides here - not even an about-me slide. Let's dive into some queries!</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103036</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103036</id>
          <name>Benni De Jagere</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>BETA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Dataflows? Why you need to implement it!</title>
      <description>Not so long ago, Power BI Dataflows have been added to the Power BI landscape. It is showing great promise, as they have the potential of becoming key in every (large) implementation of a Power BI or Hybrid BI Architecture.

During this session, the core concepts of Power BI Dataflows will be explained, and we'll discuss how Power BI Dataflows could alleviate some of the specific problems you might be experiencing in your current architecture.

How this feature ties into some other cool concepts, like Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 or the Common Data Model, obviously can't be missing from this speech.

Expect to walk out of this session with a decent grasp on the underlying architecture, and some key takeaways to take home with you.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104491</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104491</id>
          <name>Asgeir Gunnarsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>DELTA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Checking in with Power Apps, Flow and Power BI</title>
      <description>In this session we will create an Power App that will allow users to check-in their location. We will then create a Flow that will take that location and write to a Power BI data source and refresh it. We will then create a Power BI report that will display the data on a map.

Power Apps is a great tool that allows you to create a desktop or mobile app with minimal coding. The app we are creating in this session uses the Bing location services to get the users location when a button is pressed. The Power Automate flow we create in this session will take the location and user information and write it to an Excel file. We will also look at the Power BI connector in Power Automate that will allow us to refresh a Power BI data set. In the Power BI report we will create, we will connect to an Excel file with the location information in it and display it in a report including the location on a map.

The audience will take away useful information about Power Apps, Flow and Power BI including</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 9:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 10:10:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103560</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103560</id>
          <name>Kevin Chant</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>DELTA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure DevOps duet (60 minutes version)</title>
      <description>Welcome to Azure DevOps Duet, a tale about how a development team and an operations team have to bond together and start using Azure DevOps for SQL Server related deployments.

This session will cover the process of developing a CI/CD process starting at getting the team on board and ending with making an actual release.

We will discuss

- the challenges of implementing DevOps
- setting up a database solution project
- getting started with source control
- testing your database releases using tSQLt
- setting up your Azure Devops pipelines

After this session you will have the tools and knowledge to get started with DevOps and get your development process to the next level.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104147</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104147</id>
          <name>Juan E. Moreno Romo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>GAMMA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Monitoring SQL Server: from on-premises to Azure</title>
      <description>Have you ever wonder how can you monitor your SQL Server no matter if it is on-premises or on Azure?
In this session we will show you the tools and techniques you could use to monitor your SQL Server environment, nevertheless where it is located on-premises or in Azure.
We will go through DMVs, Wait Stats, Performance Counters, Extended Events, Query Data Store, Management Studio, Azure Portal, SQL Azure Diagnostics, SQL Auditing and more...
We want to share with you what we have learnt from support cases and how we, Microsoft CSS, use these tools to help customers monitor and improve the performance of their SQL Server environments.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 9:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 10:10:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103129</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103129</id>
          <name>Jens Vestergaard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>BETA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI Live Data sets, Monitoring your key metrics</title>
      <description>In this session we will explore options in PowerBI to stream real-time data to the service.
Differences between pushing, streaming and PubNub streaming will be explained and we will dive deep into each of the three methods.
Join this session so learn how to get live data into your PowerBI service. 
The session will be covering basic entry to best practices.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103432</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103432</id>
          <name>Erland Sommarskog</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>DELTA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dynamic Search Conditions</title>
      <description>A common requirement in database applications is that users want a function to search a set of data from a large set of possible search conditions. The challenge is to implement such searches in a way that is both maintainable and efficient in terms of performance. This session looks at the two main techniques to implement such searches and highlights their strengths and limitations.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104935</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104935</id>
          <name>Dennes Torres</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>BETA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why Synapse Analytics is beyond Azure SQL Datawarehouse</title>
      <description>Synapse Analytics is being announced as the new name of Azure SQL Datawarehouse, but it's not only that. There is a broader view in Synapse analytics, beyond Azure SQL Datawarehouse. Let's see in this session what was improved, what changed, and how synapse analytics fits in the data platform.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105218</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105218</id>
          <name>Damir Matesic</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>DELTA</name>
      </location>
      <title>MS SQL New functions, syntaxes, tips  tricks</title>
      <description>In this session we will see what bring us some newly introduced MS SQL functions and syntax's like COMPRESS, STRING_SPLIT, STRING_AGG, DROP IF EXISTS (a.k.a. DIE), UTF8 Support and many more. How are they performing compared to some old solutions? 
Accompanied with multiple examples, this session will show you many interesting topics.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>105083</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>105083</id>
          <name>Torsten Strauss</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>GAMMA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Detect Plan Regression with Query Store</title>
      <description>Microsoft introduced Query Store in SQL Server 2016 and promised that it now becomes easy to analyze the entire query workload and detect plan regressions on a database level.
In this session, you will learn how Query Store works internally and to interpret the available reports to detect plan regression caused by parameter sniffing and by the new cardinality estimator.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 11:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 12:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103207</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103207</id>
          <name>Philipp Lenz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>DELTA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction into Power BI Embedded</title>
      <description>The session gives an overview about Microsoft Power BI Reporting Platform and how this amazing technology can be a game changer at the information delivery to the customer. The session explains what Power BI Embedded is, how to embed reports into ISV application works. Also, the session clarifies the licensing aspect and gives information about the maintenance of this architecture. After the session, the attendees will be able to create her first Power BI Embedded Application</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103019</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103019</id>
          <name>Magnus Ahlkvist</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>GAMMA</name>
      </location>
      <title>My romantic relation with Powershell generally and  DBATools especially</title>
      <description>I was very late to adopt Powershell in my day-to-day work as a DBA. I did some copy/change "programming" with Powershell. But it wasn't until I got in touch with DBATools that I really understood the power of Powershell.
In this session, I will demo some of the reasons I really love Powershell and DBATools.
I will cover a brief overview of DBATools and then jump into some scenarios where DBATools really helped me, including:
- Automatic restore testing
- Homecooked log shipping
- Migration work</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 10:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 11:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>104199</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>104199</id>
          <name>Alexander Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>BETA</name>
      </location>
      <title>BI in Azure two years live</title>
      <description>After more than two years live with BI in Azure Alexander Klein would like to give an honest feedback. 

Which architecture is the right one? Which tools/services should I use ( Azure Data Factory V1 or V2, Azure Stream Analytics, Logic Apps, Azure Functions, Azure SQL DB, Azure SQL DW, Azure Analysis Service, Azure Data Lake, Power BI, Azure Databricks ...) ?
What was good and what wasn't so good? What do you have to pay attention to? What can you possibly do better in the next project?

Alexander Klein will answer all these questions and more in this presentation.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 3:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 4:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103103</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103103</id>
          <name>Oskari Heikkinen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>BETA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Best Practices for building a Data Lake with Azure Databricks</title>
      <description>Databricks is a Unified Analytics Platform making it easier than ever to do big data analytics on cloud. However, there are a lot of things you need to know and take into account before diving head first into a Data Lake. This session is intended for architects and developers who are looking to build a massive scale data storing and processing solution. I will go through the Best Practices for the purpose. In addition, I will demonstrate how to unify real-time and batch processing using Azure Databricks. As a result, you should feel comfortable building your own Data Lake for your big data processing needs.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 9:10:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 10:10:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>103015</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>103015</id>
          <name>Ted Malone</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>GAMMA</name>
      </location>
      <title>Creating Scalable Data Pipelines with Azure Data Factory and Data Flows</title>
      <description>One major challenge that data professionals are faced with in the age of Big Data is ensuring that data is in the proper form at the proper time for downstream analytics. This session will discuss the modern data warehouse architecture, and how Azure Data Factory with Mapping and Wrangling Data Flows can be used to ensure that data pipelines deliver the right data at the right time to data consumers.

This session will be a mix of discussion and demo, and attendees will come away with a solid understanding of how these data pipelines are architected and built.</description>
      <startTime>9/5/2020 1:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/5/2020 2:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>