<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #903 - Johannesburg 2019</name>
    <startDate>9/7/2019 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>250</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Jerusalem</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatJohannesburg</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft head office</name>
      <street>3012 William Nicol Drive</street>
      <city>Bryanston</city>
      <state>Gauteng, South Africa</state>
      <zipcode>2031</zipcode>
      <longitude>28.0181533862305</longitude>
      <latitude>-26.0439415169159</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>846</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation</name>
      <label>Global SQLSaturday Partner</label>
      <url>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/903/EventSponsor_14078.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2571</importID>
      <name>ATS Network Management</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://atsnwm.co.za</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/903/EventSponsor_14170.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2543</importID>
      <name>Cobalt Analytics</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://CobaltAnalytics.io</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/903/EventSponsor_13995.JPG</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1778</importID>
      <name>Tarsus Cloud OnDemand</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.cloudondemand.co.za/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/903/EventSponsor_14035.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>2563</importID>
      <name>Expeditus</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://expeditus.co.za/wp/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/903/EventSponsor_14062.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96715</importID>
      <name>Warren du Toit</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warren is a Senior Solutions Architect focused on Cloud with emphasis on Open Source and Networking and PaaS workloads at Britehouse (Dimension Data). Warren has an extensive Open Source and Cloud Networking background, having built global grids for global cloud providers. Warren consults to Enterprise Customers and System Integrators, with a focus of either assisting customers move to the cloud or helping System Integrators build their own cloud offering.
When Warren is not customer focused, he tries to spend significant time-sharing knowledge on how to drive Open Source and Azure based workloads. Warren has travelled extensively presenting on Microsoft’s behalf at events around the world like Microsoft Ignite. Warren is a multiple year M</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96480</importID>
      <name>Alain Dormehl</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>MCSA and MCT in SQL Data Platforms, I am passionate about all things data. I also have a particular love for new innovative solutions to deal with the big data problem. 

I have been using SQL for 9 years professionally from SQL 2003 and more recently SQL 2016 CTP2.1. I have also been fortunate enough to work and develop extensively on SQL 2012 Parallel Data Warehouse through a Microsoft Analytic Platforms System. </description>
      <twitter>@APSolutely</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://za.linkedin.com/pub/alain-dormehl/7b/903/446</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@APSolutely</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96937</importID>
      <name>Vernon Du Preez</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am an MCSE Certified Data Analyst with a love for SQL. I enjoy learning something new every day, even if it is something unimportant. I like to see most issues as challenges, thus making issues fun to solve.</description>
      <twitter>VernonDuPreez</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/vernon-du-preez-a8001723</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=VernonDuPreez</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96650</importID>
      <name>Anna Hoffman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Anna is a Data and Applied Scientist on the Azure Data (SQL) product team at Microsoft. In her time at Microsoft, Anna has worked in Microsoft Consulting Services, AI Engineering, and now SQL Engineering. She spends most of her time working on Azure SQL and participating in the community to democratize intelligence over all your data, from ground to cloud. You can follow her on Twitter at @AnalyticAnna.</description>
      <twitter>AnalyticAnna</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/amthomas46/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AnalyticAnna</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95998</importID>
      <name>Gail Shaw</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gail Shaw is a Database Specialist focusing on database performance tuning and database recovery, with a particular interest in topics such as indexing strategies, execution plans, and writing T-SQL code that performs well and scales gracefully. Gail holds a Microsoft Certified Master certification for SQL Server 2008 and is a Data Platform MVP. She's a frequent poster on the SQLServerCentral forums, a Pluralsight author, writes articles for both SQLServerCentral.com and Simple-Talk.com, and has spoken at SQLSaturdays, SQL Bits and at the PASS Community Summit. Gail has been responsible for extending the lifespan of many an application, by performance-tuning their databases and providing technical guidance on all things SQL Server related.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLInTheWild</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlinthewild.co.za</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLInTheWild</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96644</importID>
      <name>Bob Ward</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Ward is a Principal Architect for the Microsoft Azure Data SQL Server team, which owns the development for all SQL Server versions. Bob has worked for Microsoft for 26+ years on every version of SQL Server shipped from OS/2 1.1 to SQL Server 2019 including Azure SQL. Bob is a well-known speaker on SQL Server, often presenting talks on new releases, internals, and performance at events such as PASS Summit, Red Hat Summit, Microsoft Ready, SQLBits, SQLIntersection, Microsoft Inspire, and Microsoft Ignite. You can follow him at @bobwardms or linkedin.com/in/bobwardms. Bob is the author of the books Pro SQL Server on Linux and SQL Server 2019 Revealed available from Apress Media.
Twitter: http://twitter.com/bobwardms.</description>
      <twitter>bobwardms</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/bobsql</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bobwardms</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95725</importID>
      <name>Andrew Collier</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Itinerant Data Scientist; Geek; Runner.</description>
      <twitter>DataWookie</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/datawookie/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://datawookie.netlify.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataWookie</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95908</importID>
      <name>Niels Berglund</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niels works as Software Architect at Derivco, where he develops software as well as "dreaming" up new and innovative ways to use existing and new technology. Before joining Derivco, Niels worked as researcher/instructor at Developmentor where he was responsible for the database curriculum. He was a co-author of the first SQL Server 2005 book for developers: quot; A First Look at SQL 2005 for Developersquot;. He has presented at all leading technical conferences; Tech-ED, SQL PASS, DevWeek, Ignite the Tour, etc., and is also a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>nielsberglund</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://za.linkedin.com/in/niels-berglund-0122593</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://nielsberglund.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=nielsberglund</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95999</importID>
      <name>Gail Shaw</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gail Shaw is a Database Specialist focusing on database performance tuning and database recovery, with a particular interest in topics such as indexing strategies, execution plans, and writing T-SQL code that performs well and scales gracefully. Gail holds a Microsoft Certified Master certification for SQL Server 2008 and is a Data Platform MVP. She's a frequent poster on the SQLServerCentral forums, a Pluralsight author, writes articles for both SQLServerCentral.com and Simple-Talk.com, and has spoken at SQLSaturdays, SQL Bits and at the PASS Community Summit. Gail has been responsible for extending the lifespan of many an application, by performance-tuning their databases and providing technical guidance on all things SQL Server related.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLInTheWild</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlinthewild.co.za</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLInTheWild</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96267</importID>
      <name>James McGillivray</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>James McGillivray, Data Management and Analytics MCSE, has been working in Business Intelligence for over a decade. He spends his working hours building solutions that allow people to make informed decisions quickly and accurately. James is a director at Cobalt Analytics.

Before his career in data, James was an avid musical theatre student and musician. This love for performance has developed into a passion for developing and delivering presentations that are informative and enjoyable. James speaks frequently at the Johannesburg SQL User Group, and has delivered sessions at numerous SQL Saturdays, PASS Summit, Power BI World Tour and SQL Bits.</description>
      <twitter>JamesMcG_MSBI</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://za.linkedin.com/in/thejimmyrsa</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://jimbabwe.co.za/blog-posts/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=JamesMcG_MSBI</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96614</importID>
      <name>Sven Vosse</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sven Vosse is the lead consultant at Seidor Analytics, a specialist BI Training and Consulting company based in Jhb.  Seidor Analytics serves clients of all sizes in all industries and focuses mainly on Power BI and SAP Analytics Cloud.

Sven is also the Johannesburg Power BI User Group Leader</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93987</importID>
      <name>Steve Simon</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Steve Simon is a Database Solutions Architect with Business Knowledge Services Inc. He has been involved with database design and analysis for over 35 years. Steve has presented papers at numerous PASS Summits and PASS SQL Rallies. He is also regular presenter on the SQL Saturday circuit and he is a contributor on SQLShack.com</description>
      <twitter>SQLServerBoffin</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/stephenrsimon/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/simon_says/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLServerBoffin</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96726</importID>
      <name>Jody Roberts</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jody Roberts is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP based in Cape Town, South Africa. He specializes in SQL Server architecture, disaster recovery (DR), and server optimization.

Jody serves as a PASS Regional Mentor responsible for the Middle East amp; Africa, Chapter Lead of the SQLCape user group, and Co-Lead of the PASS Cloud Virtual Chapter. Jody is a Principal Consultant at Northern Data.</description>
      <twitter>Jody_Wp</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://za.linkedin.com/pub/jody-roberts/7/b29/193/Edit</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://JodyWP.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Jody_Wp</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95318</importID>
      <name>Angela Henry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Angela is a Solution Architect, living in High Point, NC and loves what she does. She's worked with all versions of SQL Server  worn all the hats that come with dealing with SQL Server throughout the years: developer, administrator, data architect and BI developer. She has her MSCE in Data and Analytics (f.k.a., Business Intelligence), is a Data Platform MVP, and a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT).  She is the former chapter leader for the PASS Triad SQL User Group in Greensboro, NC. In her spare time you can probably find her in or at the pool, she's an avid US Masters Swimmer, Coach and Instructor.</description>
      <twitter>SQLSwimmer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/angelahenrydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SQLSwimmer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLSwimmer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96277</importID>
      <name>Sandesh Nagaraj</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>A Certified Data Architect with around 15 years of experience in Data warehouse, Business Intelligence and Database implementation. Sandesh holds MCITP SQL Server in BI, Data Architect certified from Microstrategy etc. He has worked extensively as BI Consultant/Technical Specialist/BI Architect/Sales Engineer/Manager.  Sandesh actively participates and speaks at Johannesburg SQL Server User and SQL Saturday events.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>http://za.linkedin.com/in/sandeshnagaraj</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96148</importID>
      <name>Kathryn Varrall</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been doing what I love most for the last 15 years and that is working with data, specifically building data warehouse and business intelligence solutions and doing advanced analytics. I now work for Microsoft as a Technical Solutions Professional in the Advanced Analytics and AI space assisting and guiding customers in their data journey</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kathryn-varrall-87212132</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96641</importID>
      <name>Jeanne Combrinck</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Senior BI Developer at Britehouse. In her spare time she can be found spending time with her animals, doing SQL puzzles and writing on her blog http://thesqlgirl.com/.</description>
      <twitter>TheSQLGirl</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://za.linkedin.com/in/jeannecombrinck</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://thesqlgirl.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TheSQLGirl</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95640</importID>
      <name>Arohan Naidoo</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Arohan is a Business Intelligence developer working at Entelect primarily on the Microsoft BI stack who has an interest in using Big Data and IoT to find insights into ways to improve daily life as well as focused research on using technology to enhance learning.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95847</importID>
      <name>Tinus Visagie</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Started my IT career as a software developer just in time for Y2K. After 13 years of software development I moved my focus to data and have been doing data development in various forms for 8 years. 
Currently working at one of the big banks developing data marts and defining best practice development patterns.</description>
      <twitter>@dietinus</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/tinusvisagie</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://tvisagieblog.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@dietinus</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>93950</importID>
      <name>Angela Henry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Angela is a Solution Architect, living in High Point, NC and loves what she does. She's worked with all versions of SQL Server  worn all the hats that come with dealing with SQL Server throughout the years: developer, administrator, data architect and BI developer. She has her MSCE in Data and Analytics (f.k.a., Business Intelligence), is a Data Platform MVP, and a Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT).  She is the former chapter leader for the PASS Triad SQL User Group in Greensboro, NC. In her spare time you can probably find her in or at the pool, she's an avid US Masters Swimmer, Coach and Instructor.</description>
      <twitter>SQLSwimmer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/angelahenrydba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://SQLSwimmer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLSwimmer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>96649</importID>
      <name>Buck Woody</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Born helpless, naked, and unable to provide for himself, Buck Woody overcame these amazing handicaps to become a software developer, data professional, teacher, and a productive invertebrate member of society.</description>
      <twitter>BuckWoodyMSFT</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/buckwoody</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://buckwoody.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=BuckWoodyMSFT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95751</importID>
      <name>Jean-Pierre Voogt</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jean-Pierre is an SQL Developer and Data Analysis Team Lead from South Africa. He is MCSA (Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate) and owner of a bachelor’ degree in Software Engineering with good experience with Database design, Data warehousing and development. He has a great passion for SQL server and he enjoys solving complex business problems.

Jean-Pierre speaks at the Johannesburg SQL User Group, trying to give back to the SQL community as much as possible. He loves to tinker with SQL Server and see how he can approach a problem with a different angle.</description>
      <twitter>@CloudySQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@CloudySQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>95909</importID>
      <name>Niels Berglund</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niels works as Software Architect at Derivco, where he develops software as well as "dreaming" up new and innovative ways to use existing and new technology. Before joining Derivco, Niels worked as researcher/instructor at Developmentor where he was responsible for the database curriculum. He was a co-author of the first SQL Server 2005 book for developers: quot; A First Look at SQL 2005 for Developersquot;. He has presented at all leading technical conferences; Tech-ED, SQL PASS, DevWeek, Ignite the Tour, etc., and is also a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>nielsberglund</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://za.linkedin.com/in/niels-berglund-0122593</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://nielsberglund.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=nielsberglund</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>94196</importID>
      <name>Vanessa Raath</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am determined to bring the ‘Human Element’ back into today’s Recruitment Process as I believe it has been lacking for too long now! I believe that people are the core building blocks of every business but that doesn’t mean that we can treat every ‘block’ the same. I have over 13 years’ experience in the Recruitment Industry and I have specialised in the IT Applications space for most of this time. I have recently decided to flex my entrepreneurial muscle and I have launched my own Sourcing Training Business. I am passionate about raising the standard of Sourcing in Africa.</description>
      <twitter>@Van_Raath</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/vanessaraath</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.vanessaraath.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Van_Raath</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>95751</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95751</id>
          <name>Jean-Pierre Voogt</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Working with data in Python for Beginners</title>
      <description>Data Science is the latest Data Buzz word, but what does this mean for us the Analysts and Developers. Well, this is just another opportunity to grow and learn a new skill. The great thing about the era we live in is that information is everywhere but can be a little overwhelming for someone who is just starting off in a new field or wants to learn a new skill.

In this session, we will use Python in an easy to understand layout by using Notebooks as our Interface and pandas as our data manipulation library in Python. This session is for everyone that is just starting off in Python. We will learn how to import/export data into Python as well as manipulate and analyse data. Finally, we will look at how to bring this back into our SQL Server world.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96644</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96644</id>
          <name>Bob Ward</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2019: The Modern Database Platform</title>
      <description>In this session, we will cover the complete set of features and capabilities in SQL Server 2019. Want your queries to run faster with no application changes or watch your database recover in seconds? Need to connect to Oracle, CosmosDB, or Azure without moving data? Making a move to SQL Server 2019 could be the right choice for you.  SQL Server 2019 represents the next evolution of the leading database platform in the industry. "This is not your grandpa's SQL Server" says Travis Wright. Whether it is Big Data Clusters with Hadoop and Spark, Java, Linux, Containers, or Kubernetes. Pedro Lopes says it still is "Your grandpa's SQL Server" because of Intelligent Performance, Mission Critical Availability, and Security. Who is right? Come to this session and see for yourself.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96614</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96614</id>
          <name>Sven Vosse</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference room 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI + Microsoft Flow + PowerApps = Real Magic</title>
      <description>BI is certainly about interactive reports and clever analysis, but for it to be truly valuable, your insights must easily be turned into actions. 

In this session we’ll explore how combining Power BI and two other Power Platform apps, namely Microsoft Flow and Microsoft PowerApps, we can turn BI into “insights AND action”.

We will walk through a popular use case of a Sales Rep visiting a client, and integrating Flow, PowerApps and Power BI on a tablet one can vastly improve customer satisfaction, significantly reduce workload and administration, and improve sales volumes.

Here are some of the things we’ll cover:
•	Validate stock levels on the spot to avoid ordering an out-of-stock item
•	Place orders directly from Power BI using Flow and PowerApps to integrate with your ERP system
•	Don’t miss out on any lost opportunities by viewing past order history using insightful Power BI visuals
•	Trigger workflows automatically instead of completing the admin later
•	CRM Integration</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96267</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96267</id>
          <name>James McGillivray</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference room 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Design Strategies and Advanced Data Visualization: The Ingredients for a Delicious Data Story</title>
      <description>You’re comfortable with picking the right visualization for a specific data set, and making it look good. You know the basics of design and can craft a report that is pleasing on the eye. Now it’s time to take your data presentation skills to the next level.

In this session, we will learn how to design for accessibility, allowing more people to benefit from our work. We’ll learn the difference between designing for users to explore information, and for users to consume insights. This will lead us into the basics of constructing a data story. From choosing the relevant data points, to removing all unnecessary distractions and constructing a cohesive narrative.

Every data story is unique, but the techniques for effective data presentation are universal. Improve your reports, dashboards, and slide decks by learning the art and science of quality data visualization.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96726</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96726</id>
          <name>Jody Roberts</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Strategy and Architecture</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference room 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Estate Modernization : Taking the guess work out of migrating to the cloud.</title>
      <description>Moving to the cloud should not be difficult. Most organizations make the mistake of wanting to modernize their applications and databases on-prem first before moving to cloud. This is normally very expensive, leads to delays and often abandonment of projects.

In this session we will look at :
How to take the guess work out of developing a cloud roadmap. 
Look at how cost effective cloud will be in a very accurate manner.
How to assess applications and their dependencies.
Reduce time to cloud by telling exactly which lines of code to change in your applications and databases.
Effort estimation to complete each task.
Including 3 migration options in Microsoft Azure for your applications and databases.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>94196</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>94196</id>
          <name>Vanessa Raath</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Are you making sure that you are standing out as a TOP IT Professional in South Africa?</title>
      <description>There is a fight for attention these days in the IT space. Are you doing everything that you could be doing to make sure that you stand out from your peers? Are you sure that you are on the correct path for you to achieve your end career goals? 

In order to be seen as a Thought Leader in your chosen IT discipline these days, you need to be developing and nurturing your personal brand. This is going to be vitally important for you in your next career move.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96650</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96650</id>
          <name>Anna Hoffman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Migrate to Azure SQL</title>
      <description>Migrating SQL workloads to Azure can be a daunting task. Come learn from the SQL product group about the tools and services that are available to help you assess, plan, and migrate your entire SQL Server stack.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96148</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96148</id>
          <name>Kathryn Varrall</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference room 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big Data Analytics with Power BI</title>
      <description>In this session,  we will unpack how to do big data analytics using Power BI,  Azure Databricks and Azure Data Lake. This session with cover a brief introduction to Azure Databricks and Power BI composite models and unpack what it takes to do analytics over trillions of rows of the data.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96715</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96715</id>
          <name>Warren du Toit</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference room 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Always On Availability Groups on Azure Kubernetes Services</title>
      <description>It sounds more difficult than it is, but using Azure's Resource Manager deployment engine and preconfigured templates, we can deploy a fully functional Kubernetes cluster in Azure with persistent storage. The Templates use CNAB, Cloud Native Application Bundles to achieve this. We take a deeper look at how this is deployed and how you can use containerisation for your Highly Available Data Workloads.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95318</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95318</id>
          <name>Angela Henry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Profiling Your Data</title>
      <description>Have you ever started a warehouse or ETL project and realized that the data wasn't as "clean" as you were told?  If only you had profiled your data before you started then you wouldn't have to rework design elements, change code or redesign your database.  In this session we will talk about what data profiling is, why you should do it and how you can do it with tools that are already included in the SQL Server BI stack.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95725</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95725</id>
          <name>Andrew Collier</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Web Scraping</title>
      <description>There's a wealth of data available on the internet which can be used for data augmentation or to create entirely new datasets. The data might all be on one page (if you're lucky!) or distributed across multiple (possibly hundreds or thousands) pages. Web scraping allows you to gather those data and consolidate them in a convenient format. This will be a hands-on tutorial in R, so bring your machine and follow along.

Session code: 
https://github.com/datawookie/talks/tree/master/2019-09-07-sql-saturday-johannesburg</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96641</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96641</id>
          <name>Jeanne Combrinck</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference room 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure ML Studio for Beginners - Exploring, Creating  Training Models</title>
      <description>In this session we shall take a look at Azure Machine Learning Studio. We will import data sets, create models and train them. We will go over the fundamentals of Azure Machine Learning and what it has to offer.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95640</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95640</id>
          <name>Arohan Naidoo</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Paginated Reports in Power BI and SSRS</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn about use cases for paginated reports, working with sub-reports in SSRS to  build reusable sections which will form part of a dynamic which can be used to create a structured invoice or statement. We will then dive into the paginated report functionality in Power BI and learn more about SSRS features that are now available in Power BI.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96277</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96277</id>
          <name>Sandesh Nagaraj</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference room 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data wrangling using Power Query and M language</title>
      <description>In the age of Self-Service analytics. We often have to deal with "raw" data. 

Using Power Query and M language one can define a step by step process of transforming and mapping data from one "raw" data form into another format with the intent of making it more appropriate and valuable for a variety of downstream purposes such as analytics. 

The final transformed dataset is available one can use it to create visualizations that can be added to Power BI reports and publish to the Power BI service.

M stands for Data Mashup and M is a functional language.

In this session, I will demonstrate around 30 Things that one can do with Power Query</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95847</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95847</id>
          <name>Tinus Visagie</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Beginners guide to Data Modeling</title>
      <description>"Data is the new oil" - Everyone
 
It's a statement we've all heard before. No doubt people are realizing just how valuable data is becoming. Ultimately though for data to be valuable it needs to be usable.  With the growth of new technologies like AI, Data Lakes, IOT to name a few the modelling of data is even more important than ever.
Stop your data lakes from turning into data swamps.
 
This session will cover the basic terminology and methods of modelling data. It will also show some of the most common models and what they are best suited for.
 
Go from Zoolander too Right Said Fred and be Too Sexy for your data in 50 minutes.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95908</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95908</id>
          <name>Niels Berglund</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Lap Around SQL Server Big Data Cluster</title>
      <description>The new release of SQL Server; SQL Server 2019 includes Apache Spark and Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) for scalable compute and storage. This new architecture that combines together the SQL Server database engine, Spark, and HDFS into a unified data platform is called a “big data cluster.”
This session gives you an overview of what a SQL Server Big Data Cluster is, and what you can do with it. We look at the various components, (Kubernetes, Spark, HDFS, PolyBase, etc.), and what you can do with them.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95909</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95909</id>
          <name>Niels Berglund</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>What is the PiRate, Snake, and Cup of Coffee Doing in My Database?</title>
      <description>Have you ever been thinking that you would like to be able to do more in SQL Server than what T-SQL allows you to do? If that is the case, the this session is for you!
Here we look at the SQL Server Extensibility Framework, and we see how we can call out to external languages from inside SQL Server. We look at R, Python and Java, and what we can do from SQL Server having access to those languages.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95998</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95998</id>
          <name>Gail Shaw</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Hyperscale! Database at the speed of cloud</title>
      <description>At the recent Build conference, Microsoft announced the general availability of Azure SQL DB hyperscale.

What is this 'hyperscale' thing all about?

In this talk I'll show how the hyperscale architecture differs from a normal database architecture and why, in theory, it promises near infinite scalability for transactional workloads</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93950</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93950</id>
          <name>Angela Henry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Types Do Matter</title>
      <description>They're just numbers, right?  A date's a date.  It's just string data, who cares?  I can't tell you how many times I've heard these phrases.  This session will help you understand why choosing the correct data type for your data is so important.  It affects data quality, storage and performance.  It can even produce incorrect query results.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96649</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96649</id>
          <name>Buck Woody</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Day in the Life of the Data Scientist</title>
      <description>Data Science is a new field in technology, and has begun to mature, splintering off into many disciplines. Like any complex role, there isn't one single skillset and knowledge-base required for Data Science. Buck Woody, an Applied Data Scientist from the SQL Server Product Group at Microsoft explains Data Science using a "day" to show you the processes and procedures a Data Scientist uses, and how you can learn the skills, math, languages and platforms involved in a Data Science role.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 11:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 12:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>95999</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>95999</id>
          <name>Gail Shaw</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>There are Gremlins in my CosmosDB</title>
      <description>One of the models that CosmosDB offers is the Gremlin graph API. 

In this presentation I’m going to take you through the basics of what CosmosDB is, show how to create and configure a database. Once we've got a database, we'll look at the the gremlin api, including how to create and query the graphs.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96480</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96480</id>
          <name>Alain Dormehl</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Auditorium 2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Fully Managed Cloud Born DBaaS - Azure SQL DB Managed Instance</title>
      <description>This session will be presented by the Microsoft Azure SQL Database Product Group and will cover a deep dive into the architecture for Azure SQL Database Managed Instance 

Azure SQL Database Managed Instance is a new deployment option for Azure SQL Database, that enables easy SQL server applications migration from on-premises to a fully managed platform as a service.  Managed Instance provides SQL Server application compatibility, security isolation with VNET support.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 10:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 11:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>96937</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>96937</id>
          <name>Vernon Du Preez</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference room 4</name>
      </location>
      <title>How to Become Microsoft Certified</title>
      <description>Do you want to boost your IT career, or thinking about starting a new career?
Then Microsoft Certifications are for you. In this session, we will look at the different types of certification paths and what you can do to pass the exams. I will take you on the journey to selecting the right exam for you and assist you to pass these exams with confidence.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>93987</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>93987</id>
          <name>Steve Simon</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Information Delivery</track>
      <location>
        <name>Conference room 3</name>
      </location>
      <title>DAX and the tabular model</title>
      <description>With the advent of the tabular model in SQL Server 2012, another analytical option has opened to the BI Specialist. We shall be looking at what critical factors should be analyzed prior to opting for the model and that done,  how to extract data from a tabular model using Data Analysis Expressions (DAX).
We shall discuss many of the often used functions, discuss their 'overloads' (utilizing several practical examples) and see how to turn the extracted data into valuable information that may be used by decision makers to help the enterprise achieve its corporate goals.</description>
      <startTime>9/7/2019 9:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/7/2019 10:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>