<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #196 - Denmark 2013</name>
    <startDate>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>150</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+01:00) Brussels, Copenhagen, Madrid, Paris</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatDenmark</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Denmark</name>
      <street>Tuborg Boulevard 12</street>
      <city>Hellerup</city>
      <state>, Denmark</state>
      <zipcode>2900</zipcode>
      <longitude>12.5807505</longitude>
      <latitude>55.7271614</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>536</importID>
      <name>d60</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.d60.dk/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsug.dk/sponsors/Logo_d60.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>780</importID>
      <name>KMD A/S</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.kmd.dk</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.kmd.dk/PublishingImages/Kommunikation/Billedarkiv/Logoer/72dpi/logo_72.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>773</importID>
      <name>Kapacity A/S</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.kapacity.dk</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/963/EventSponsor_14529.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>354</importID>
      <name>4D Konsulenterne</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.4d.dk/Pages/Default.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsug.dk/sponsors/4d_269x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>999</importID>
      <name>Rehfeld</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.effektor.bi</url>
      <imageURL>https://static.wixstatic.com/media/8b2c2c_11cc3c8918e04b4d8b652e020ded1179.png_srb_p_1660_651_75_22_0.50_1.20_0.00_png_srb</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>25</importID>
      <name>Redgate Software (GAP)</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://rd.gt/2j7SNf9</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.red-gate.com/assets/interim/assets/community/images/rg-logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>652</importID>
      <name>Geniiius ApS</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.geniiius.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.geniiius.com/Uploads/GeniiiusLogo_170x60.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1069</importID>
      <name>SolidQ Nordic</name>
      <label>Platinum</label>
      <url>https://www.solidq.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/988/EventSponsor_14821.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>8</importID>
      <name>FusionIO</name>
      <label>Platinum</label>
      <url>http://www.fusionio.com/solutions/microsoft-sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/files/18b704b1-226d-48fe-b0b8-f7b4d3443b3d.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>950</importID>
      <name>Platon</name>
      <label>Platinum</label>
      <url>http://www.platon.net/</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsug.dk/sponsors/platon.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>8807</importID>
      <name>Andreas Wolter</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Andreas Wolter is a Program Manager for SQL Server- and Azure Security at Microsoft. In this role he is working on Security features of SQL Server, Azure SQL Database and Managed Instance. He is currently focusing on “Separation of Duties”-concepts and RBAC-Integration. He has 18 years of experience with SQL Server before joining Microsoft and is the founder of Sarpedon Quality Lab, the Germany-based company specialized on SQL Server HA, Performance and Security. He is Microsoft Certified Master (MCM) for SQL Server and Microsoft Certified Solutions Master for the Data Platform (MCSM) and was recognized as MVP for multiple years in row.</description>
      <twitter>AndreasWolter</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/andreaswolter</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.andreas-wolter.com/blog/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=AndreasWolter</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14130</importID>
      <name>Emanuele Zanchettin</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Emanuele Zanchettin, after studying in Computer Engineering, began his career with DB2 in the banking sector in 1998. After a few years and a change of scope of application, he encountered Access and Oracle with which he subsequently worked for several years in data access tuning and database design for new application features. Since 2007 he has also launched into the SQLServer world 2K, 2005, 2008* and 201* and more importantly, since 2011, into Azure SQL Database (SQL Azure). In order to have a greater capacity for assessment and familiarity with the various technologies that the market offers, he has deepened his knowledge to include MySQL and DocumentDB. Today Emanuele is mainly involved in IT projects and database management.</description>
      <twitter>@_thinkIT_</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://it.linkedin.com/pub/emanuele-zanchettin/18/921/34/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@_thinkIT_</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>11827</importID>
      <name>Pedro Correia</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Pedro Correia was born in 1976 on the 265th day of that year. He has been working with SQL Server for over 12 years, since the days of SQL Server 7.0, and his specialties are security and performance tuning. He is also a SQL Server trainer and teaching is one of his passions. 2012 was a year focused on the certification of competences and skills gained over the years, namely becoming one of the few Microsoft Certified Master - SQL Server 2008 (llt;100 worldwide).</description>
      <twitter>pjcorreiasql</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pjcorreia</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sql.pt</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pjcorreiasql</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13182</importID>
      <name>Dennis Mark Thorsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Master of science in EconomicsIT Consulting since 2006Interests:SQL Server Business intelligence.NETData miningSharepoint</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.mining.dk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19595</importID>
      <name>Mark S. Rasmussen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mark S. Rasmussen, a SQL Server MVP, has worked extensively with SQL Server, primarily focused on performance optimization and internals. Besides SQL Server, he is also proficient in the Microsoft .NET development stack, with a decade of experience. Fueled by his interest in the nitty-gritty details, Mark started the OrcaMDF open-source project, which aims to provide a completely standalone parser for SQL Server MDF files. He actively blogs at http://improve.dk and tweets at @improvedk.</description>
      <twitter>@improvedk</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/markrasmussen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://improve.dk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@improvedk</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24151</importID>
      <name>Scott Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Scott Klein is a senior consultant with SQL Solutions Group with over two decades of experience working with Microsoft SQL Server. Prior to SSG, Scott spent almost 10 years at Microsoft, traveling the globe as a technical evangelist training and speaking about SQL Server and Microsoft’s Azure data services. Scott’s recent focus has been on advanced analytics, including big data and IoT, providing real-world training to help bring intelligence to your data. Scott has authored several books focusing on data and data analytics. Scott is continuously striving and looking for ways to help developers and companies grok the wonderful world of data.</description>
      <twitter>SQLScott</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/sqlscott</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLScott</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20274</importID>
      <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Mihail Mateev is a technical consultant, community enthusiast, PASS Regional Mentor for CEE, chapter lead, Microsoft Azure MVP, Microsoft Regional Director. He works as a Senior Solutions Architect at EPAM Systems, focused on Data Platform, IoT and cloud related solutions. He also worked many years like a Technical evangelist in the Infragistics. Last years Mihail was focused on various areas related to technology Microsoft: Data Platform, Visual Studio, ASP.Net, Windows client apps, Data Platform, and Microsoft Azure. Michael also has a PhD in cloud computing area. He is a university lecturer on Smart Homes and Smart Energy IoT Solutions.</description>
      <twitter>mihailmateev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mihail-mateev/1/6b3/4b1</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://mmateev.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mihailmateev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21440</importID>
      <name>Niels Leth Gammelgaard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niels Gammelgaard works as a consultant with Platon A/S in the area of BI and advanced analytics. With experience both as a predictive analyst and solution developer, he enjoys working will all aspects of value extraction from data. He holds a PhD in mathematical physics.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>26938</importID>
      <name>Salvatore Buccoliero </name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sr. Systems Engineer at Fusion-io since 2012.  Responsible for Scandinavian customers deploying low latency Nand flash.  Works as architect, consultant and trusted advisor.  Working topics range from Open source DB’s on all types of Linux flavors to Windows with SQL server.  Install types range from Single server optimizing Cubes to multiple broadcasting streaming servers over cloud based internet gaming communities.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>21032</importID>
      <name>Denny Cherry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Denny Cherry is the owner and principal consultant for Denny Cherry  Associates Consulting and has over a decade of experience working with platforms such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Microsoft SQL Server, Hyper-V, vSphere, and Enterprise Storage solutions. Denny’s areas of technical expertise include system architecture, performance tuning, security, replication, and troubleshooting. Denny currently holds several Microsoft Certifications related to SQL Server 2000 through 2019, including being a Microsoft Certified Master, Microsoft MVP and VMware vExpert Award.</description>
      <twitter>mrdenny</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrdenny</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.dcac.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=mrdenny</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>24150</importID>
      <name>Scott Klein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Scott Klein is a senior consultant with SQL Solutions Group with over two decades of experience working with Microsoft SQL Server. Prior to SSG, Scott spent almost 10 years at Microsoft, traveling the globe as a technical evangelist training and speaking about SQL Server and Microsoft’s Azure data services. Scott’s recent focus has been on advanced analytics, including big data and IoT, providing real-world training to help bring intelligence to your data. Scott has authored several books focusing on data and data analytics. Scott is continuously striving and looking for ways to help developers and companies grok the wonderful world of data.</description>
      <twitter>SQLScott</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/sqlscott</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SQLScott</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>14592</importID>
      <name>Gianluca Hotz</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Gianluca Hotz is an independent consultant, trainer, speaker and Mentor specialized in architecture, database design, high availability, capacity planning, performance tuning, system integration and migrations for Microsoft SQL Server. He has been working as a consultant in the IT field since 1993 and with SQL Server since 1996. He is among the original founders of ugiss.org, where he served as vice-president from 2001 to 2016 and he is now serving as president, for his contribution to the community he has been a SQL Server MVP since 1998.</description>
      <twitter>glhotz</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://it.linkedin.com/in/ghotz</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ghotz.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=glhotz</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>19146</importID>
      <name>Daniel Lewandowski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Daniel has been a college instructor and high school teacher, network engineer, and tour guide along the way to starting LewiCool Consulting.   MicroSoft Business Intelligence Consultancy with BI experience in enterprise organizations spanning multi-million dollar corportations to government, telecom, banking, industrial and  education.   Striving to enable business with technology, with secure maintainable sustainable solutions that help the business attain success in whatever the endeavor.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>34577</importID>
      <name>André Kamman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>André is a freelance SQL Server specialist. In previous roles he’s done a lot of DBA work on 100’s of servers where he discovered his love for Powershell and automating processes in general. Today the better part of his day he’s building and tuning ETL processes.
André is a SQL Server MPV, Dutch PASS Chapter Leader and organiser of SQL Rally Amsterdam and SQL Saturday Holland</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://andrekamman.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>17806</importID>
      <name>Jens Vestergaard</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jens performs the traditional BI disciplines from imports in Integration Services through data consolidation in Analysis Services to report in Reporting Services, Targit or similar tool. Jens has worked with The Stack since SQL 2000 and has a core competence in Integration Services and Analysis Services. Along with the certified skills in MS SQL Server, Jens has also worked with Microsoft. Net platform for more than 10 years. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.t-sql.dk</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10191</importID>
      <name>Belkis Ozhorasan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>-</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22177</importID>
      <name>Peter Larsson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Peter Larsson is a key player for performance written code. He can turn a 10 hour query into a 3 minute piece of code. Peter is also a SQL Server MVP since 2009. He often hangs out at SQLTeam.com (27k+ posts) and other various sites where he helps all people understand SQL Server.</description>
      <twitter>SwePeso</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqltopia.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=SwePeso</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10546</importID>
      <name>Bob Duffy</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Duffy is a SQL Server MVP from Dublin, Ireland who is MCA, MCM. and Analysis Services Maestro certified. 

Bob works as a Database Architect at the Prodata SQL Centre of Excellence where he specializes in business intelligence and performance tuning.</description>
      <twitter>@bob_duffy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=8301243amp;authType=NAME_SEARCHamp;authToken=MWkaamp;locale=en_USamp;srchid=83012431382480825815amp;srchindex=1amp;srchtotal=767amp;trk=vsrp_people_res_nameamp;trkInfo=VSRPsearchId%3A83012431382480825815%2CVSRPtargetId%3A8301243%2CVSRPcmpt%3Aprimary</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://blogs.prodata.ie/author/bob.aspx</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@bob_duffy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>20367</importID>
      <name>Michael Frandsen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael Frandsen is an Microsoft MVP on Cloud amp; Datacenter and the lead consultant on areas of technical consulting, performance optimization and migration/consolidation projects, with special focus on storage, scalability and virtualization.

He started with Windows NT 3.1 and SQL Server 4.21a and has been involved in Tech betas and TAP customers ever since.

He has also contributed to best-practices at Microsoft and HP, through working with Microsoft product groups and SQLCAT in Redmond and HP Ramp;D in Palo Alto and Houston</description>
      <twitter>@Guru_Frandsen</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/michaelfrandsendk/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Guru_Frandsen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>12425</importID>
      <name>David Smeets</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Smeets has been active as A BI professional for 10 years now. Currently he is working as a SharePoint BI Consultant at CTG Belgium where he has completed several SharePoint BI projects and assisted clients in improving their BI environment. In 2012 he was a speaker for the Belgium BIWUG and active as a speaker for Sharepoint Europe. In 2012 he also won the Belgium Microsoft contest: So you think you can demo (BI track) with a HealthCare BI solution.</description>
      <twitter>@SmeetsDavid</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://smeetsd.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SmeetsDavid</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>10991</importID>
      <name>Bruno Basto</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bruno Basto, senior consultant #160;and senior trainer #160;at Rumos. SQL certified since 6.5 version (1998). Work with MSFT tools and infrastructure since 1992 in the financial, banking and insurance areas. Responsible for several training projects for software solutions with MSFT infrastructure. Speaker at several MSFT and SQLPass events.
</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>13959</importID>
      <name>Erik Svensen</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Microsoft MVP - Dataplatform
Leader of Denmark - Power BI Usergroup

Passionate about Power *, Excel , Analysis Services, Reporting Services.

CTO @CatManSolution - delivering a BI as service solution for suppliers to FMCG Retailers based on the Microsoft BI Stack</description>
      <twitter>@donsvensen</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/eriksvensen</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://eriksvensen.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@donsvensen</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>22814</importID>
      <name>Regis Baccaro</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Regis has more than 15 years of experience with SQL Server, SharePoint and .Net as an architect and developer. R#233;gis is a SQL Server MVP since 2014 and a frequent speaker at SQL conferences, a PASS Regional Mentor and the founder of SQL Saturday Denmark community event. He is also a certified industry trainer on the APS/PDW platform. In his freetime he is an avid runner, cook and farmer.</description>
      <twitter>@regbac</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://dk.linkedin.com/in/regisbaccaro</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://theblobfarm.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@regbac</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>15398</importID>
      <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Niko Neugebauer is a Data Platform Consultant. A SQL Server MVP with over 20 years of experience in IT, he is passionate about the Microsoft Data Platform and community. Founder of the Portuguese SQL Server User Group and the main organizer of the first SQLSaturday event outside of North America (#78 Portugal), Niko speaks regularly at events such as PASS Summit, SQLRally, SQLBits, and SQLSaturday events around the world. Niko loves sharing information and knowledge and has authored over 130 blog posts on Columnstore Indexes, and regularly contributes to the open-sourced CISL library focused on Columnstore Indexes.</description>
      <twitter>NikoNeugebauer</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://pt.linkedin.com/in/webcaravela/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.nikoport.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=NikoNeugebauer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>16561</importID>
      <name>Jen Stirrup</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jen is a database strategist, small business owner, SQLFamily and community advocate, public speaker and blogger. Jen was elected Director-At-Large (elect) for the Professional Association of SQL Server, responsible for the EMEA regions plus the Virtual Chapter portfolio.  Jen is passionate about all things data and business intelligence, helping leaders derive value from their Microsoft SQL Server, SharePoint and Office365 investments. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.jenstirrup.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>18101</importID>
      <name>Kennie Pontoppidan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kennie Nybo Pontoppidan is a senior program manager in Microsoft working in the Dynamics NAV server backend team. He has worked in the dangerous field between developers, dbas, customers and project managers for many years and done his part of mistakes as a developer before that in his 15+ years in the it industry. He enjoys working with databases and really, really enjoys his daily dose of sql. Kennie has no humor.</description>
      <twitter>@KennieNP</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/kennie</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.pontop.dk/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KennieNP</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>16561</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>16561</id>
          <name>Jen Stirrup</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power View from the Data Visualisation Perspective</title>
      <description>Power View is Microsoft's Data Visualisation tool. Where does it get it right, and where does it get it wrong? Using demos, we learn about Power View whilst assessing it based on current cognitive research around Data Visualisation principles by luminaries such as Stephen Few, Tufte and others. We will:

- investigate Power View based on current cognitive research around Data Visualisation principles
- look at the features of Power View
- look at where Power View is supplemented by other parts of the Microsoft Business Intelligence stack

Come to this session if you really want to think about the best ways of presenting data to your Business Intelligence data consumers, and see how to apply these principles in Power View.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>17806</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>17806</id>
          <name>Jens Vestergaard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>The Power of Custom Assemblies in Analysis Service</title>
      <description>Sometimes you are stuck with customer demands where common solutions just aren't scalable
within the Analysis Services (SSAS) regular toolbox. This is where custom
assemblies come to save the day!  Custom assemblies allow you to extend
the power of SSAS by using other technologies, as in this case T-SQL and the
SQL Server relational engine.

This session will demonstrate how to utilize custom assemblies in Analysis Services to leverage the
power of the relational engine and use it directly in MDX. Through the .Net
framework and T-SQL we will be able to inject dimension member unique names
into MDX. Effectively we are replacing the MDX Crossjoins with the T-SQL Inner
joins, whereby gaining scalability and consistency in query perfo</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21032</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21032</id>
          <name>Denny Cherry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Getting SQL Service Broker Up and Running</title>
      <description>Microsoft SQL Server 2005 and 2008 include a fantastic feature that few people understand or use.  That feature is the Microsoft SQL Server Service Broker.  The SQL Service Broker is one of the least used features within the database engine, and that lack of use is simply from last of knowledge about the feature.

In this session we’ll dig into how to configure the service broker for not only intra-database message queuing, but database to database queuing as well as server to server database queuing.  We will also dig into a real life scenario where the SQL Server Service Broker was used to do ETL from an OLTP database to an OLAP database in near real time for near real time reporting (as time allows).</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>34577</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>34577</id>
          <name>André Kamman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>ETL Shootout, SSIS vs Powershell</title>
      <description>I know what you're thinking, Powershell is not an ETL tool. And you're probably right.
But I keep running into weird requests that were just easier to fix with Powershell.
I'll show you why some things are not easy in SSIS. 
I'll also discuss how you can work around a lot of that instead of switching to Powershell like I did.
This session will be around 70% "why is this hard in SSIS and can you work around it?"  and 30% "Look how cool Powershell is"</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>21440</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>21440</id>
          <name>Niels Leth Gammelgaard</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Decisions, Decisions...</title>
      <description>Decision-trees are the bread-and-butter of predictive modeling. Conceptually simple, fast to build and easy to interpret - yet quite powerful and versatile. They come in many flavors, from the smallest tree to vast (random) forests
This session will explain the basics of decision trees and demonstrate the process of building, interpreting, tuning, pruning and validating a simple model using the Data Mining components of SQL Server Analysis Services.
</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>12425</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>12425</id>
          <name>David Smeets</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data-driven Subscription using SSIS and SharePoint</title>
      <description>SQL Server Reporting Services provides data-driven subscriptions to render reports based on information in a database table. This is a very nice feature but the down side is that you are required to purchase an Enterprise license (or BI license in SQL 2012) of SQL Server in order to use this feature. Customers like this feature but don't want to pay for the Enterprise license so I searched for an alternative with standard licenses. In this session I will show the alternative where the end user can still create his own subscription in SharePoint. Step-by-step  I will create an SQL Server Integration Services package that renders reports to a SharePoint library on values stored in the database.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24150</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24150</id>
          <name>Scott Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Kung Fu Migration to Windows Azure SQL Database</title>
      <description>As cloud computing becomes more popular and cloud-based solutions the norm rather than the fringe, the need to efficiently migrate your database is crucial. This demo-filled session will discuss the tips and tricks, methods and strategies for migrating your on-premises SQL Server databases to Windows Azure SQL Database, AKA SQL Azure. Focusing primarily on SQL Server Data Tools and the DAC Framework, this session will focus on how these tools can make you a kung-fu migration master.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22814</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22814</id>
          <name>Regis Baccaro</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database development with SSDT</title>
      <description>SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT) is a toolset that allows professional database and application developers to carry out all their database design work for SQL Server and SQL Azure within Visual Studio. SSDT provides a rich SQL Server development experience with first class language services and VS integration, as well as declarative, model-based tools that can be utilized for both online and offline development. In this session we'll dive into Online and Offline development as well as the Productivity and tools that the SSDT team keeps providing to us.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20274</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20274</id>
          <name>Mihail Mateev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Spatial Data and Windows Azure SQL Database</title>
      <description>Spatial Data is very important for the new applications, related with Data Visualization and BI. Windows Azure offers possibility to use 
advantages of spatial data suing cloud computing. In this lecture will talk about the use of spatial data in the Windows Azure - loading data 
from Windows Azure SQL Database Spatial, optimizing Windows Azure applications and their use of different types of customers: WEB based, WPF, WP7. We will learn how to import spatial data in different formats in Windows Azure SQL Database Spatial and will create a several sample Windows Azure applications, that use this data.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19146</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19146</id>
          <name>Daniel Lewandowski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Securing the Cube; SSAS security framework</title>
      <description> Secure, Enable, Maintain, Sustain.   In depth discussion on a SSAS security framework with SSIS maintenance toolkits.   Create security roles in the cube that enable the business based on underlying data patterns.   Presentation covers creation of roles in the cube, with a demo creating SSIS roles with a toolkit based on the adventureworks db model and cube.   Using integrated security, service accounts and data sources in the presentation layers this we walk through a security model for end-to-end security as can be implemented in sharepoint integrated solutions and/or standalone reports.   This presentation provides real world application and an SSIS toolkit to take away and implement in your solutions. </description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>15398</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>15398</id>
          <name>Niko Neugebauer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Analyzing Twitter Data</title>
      <description>This session will concentrate on explanation of how to start using and analysing the data from one of the most popular social networks - Twitter. We shall take a look at the different dashboards and we shall try to understand some of the meanings. This presentation shall try to explore the best of the existing Microsoft technologies for an accessible Twitter data analysis. </description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>26938</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>26938</id>
          <name>Salvatore Buccoliero </name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Accelerating SQL 2012 Clustering with NAND Flash</title>
      <description>A DBA running SQL Server 2008 or above will often think he has no alternative to shared storage in order to run High availability Clustering in terms of both performance as well High Availability. Understand if it is worth trading high latency Shared Storage with low Price/GB to Local, Low latency OS integrated NAND Flash with high price/GB by trading Host Memory and CPU cycles for I/O Using NAND Flash from Fusion-io  Also, is there a potential License saving by running lower latency I/O and reducing CPU count?</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>8807</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>8807</id>
          <name>Andreas Wolter</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title> Tracing with Extended Events. - Adios Profiler</title>
      <description>“Hasta la vista, Profiler.”  – Introduction into Tracing with Extended Events. Focus: historical deadlock Analysis. - 
Extended Events, although in the product since SQL Server 2008 have been known to Insiders as an extremely well performing and flexible Tracing-Framework. Since SQL Server 2012 this important feature, which will replace SQL Trace, is available in SSMS.
In this introductory to advanced session we will also especially have a look at the System Health Session and how it can be used for historical deadlock-analysis right out of the box. („Hasta la vista, Profiler. Hasta la vista Traceflags 1204, 1222“)</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>18101</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>18101</id>
          <name>Kennie Pontoppidan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL anti patterns</title>
      <description>You can learn SQL in three days but it'll take you 10 years to become good at it. In this session we will have a look at some basic design errors and get a notion of the things that absolutely doesn't work. Antipatterns is a way of naming common design errors in order to make them easier to remember - even if you haven't done them yet.

We will become acquainted with antipatterns on a physical level, a logical level and an sql-queries and application level, and spice it up with some seriously foolish errors made by me and my colleagues. The session is relevant for developers and DBAs.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>22177</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>22177</id>
          <name>Peter Larsson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Remodel your old EAV design</title>
      <description>Sometimes you really need an EAV model. In most cases they are ugly and slow.
After this session you will have gained new insights how to turn your old, slow, EAV model into a slim superfast model.

There will be real life examples from a recent project. With the techniques displayed in the presentation, I cut the execution time down from 134 days down to 0.5 seconds and cut the storage need from 550GB to 45GB.
</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10191</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10191</id>
          <name>Belkis Ozhorasan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2012 Parallel Data Warehouse</title>
      <description>This session will give the attendee an overview on the architecture of Parallel Data Warehouse v2. It will give a perspective on where the PDW will fit in to the big picture of Big Data and the use cases where the PDW will be most efficient. The session will also include an introduction on how queries are built for the PDW solution.
</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>19595</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>19595</id>
          <name>Mark S. Rasmussen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Storing Character Data Optimally</title>
      <description>So you need to store character data in your database? Easy enough, you just create an nvarchar(MAX) field and you're done, right? It turns out, it's not so simple. First up you need to decide on a data type - should you use text? Char(100)? Varchar(100)? Or perhaps one of the (MAX) types? I'll go through the options we have, including a deep dive on how each data type differs in its storage on disk. Knowing this, we can make intelligent decisions on which type to use, as well as predicting actual performance implications. Knowing how to store character data optimally is an absolutely critical part of your job as a DBA.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>11827</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>11827</id>
          <name>Pedro Correia</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>CAST([Transaction Log] as T.SQL) </title>
      <description>The aim of this session is to take the audience in a quest for the original (or equivalent) T-SQL, that was in the origin of the different transactions recorded, by inspecting the transaction log records and dissecting its data. In a session that tackles several internals storage issues, needed to fulfill its objective, we will go in a travel that starts by the end of the log and will, hopefully, only end at the birth of the database.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10546</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10546</id>
          <name>Bob Duffy</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Migrating to the Azure and the Cloud</title>
      <description>So your CTO wants you to migrate your mission critical database application to the cloud. What's involved and what are the pitfalls?

In one hour we will take a sample ecommerce application and database, show tools available for both schema and data migration and the demo performance, scalability and monitoring impacts.
</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13182</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13182</id>
          <name>Dennis Mark Thorsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 3</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data mining with Analysis Services</title>
      <description>This will be an introduction to options available in Analysis Services for data mining. We will discuss Data mining project life-cycle (CRISP-DM), Target variables (categorical vs continuous), What models are available in SSAS and a bit on configuring them, Model viewing, Model evaluation , What is a categorization matrix and gain chart? DMX langauge and integration to SQL Studio and SSIS</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>13959</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>13959</id>
          <name>Erik Svensen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Design a Metro Style Dashboard with Excel  PowerP</title>
      <description>See how you can implement a Metro Style Dashboard in Excel based on a PowerPivot model in excel and how to make it dynamic with the Excel CUBE functions.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>20367</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>20367</id>
          <name>Michael Frandsen</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Windows Server 2012 Infrastructure for SQL Server</title>
      <description>With Windows Server 2012 a paradigm shift is occurring in how SQL Server platforms are designed and built. Come and hear why you no longer will need a SAN to create a high-available SQL Server, why I/O is no longer a problem and why Hyper-V v3 Means virtualising SQL Server has made a big leap forward</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>24151</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>24151</id>
          <name>Scott Klein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>Cloud Database Scalability with SQL Federation</title>
      <description>You have migrated your SQL Server database to Windows Azure SQL Database (AKA SQL Azure), and you have migrated your application to Windows Azure. Now what? As the load on your database begins to increase, the need to scale your new SQL Database instance becomes a realization. In this demo-filled session we'll explore SQL Federation, Microsoft's solution for cloud database scalability. This session will look at the scalability model for the cloud and how SQL Federation solves the scale-out issue. We'll look at the architecture of SQL Federation and you can apply SQL Federation to your cloud database solution.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>10991</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>10991</id>
          <name>Bruno Basto</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 2</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Internal Storage</title>
      <description>This session describes how SQL Server internally stores table data. Although you can use SQL without understanding the internals of data storage, a deep knowledge of how data is stored will improve the development of efficient applications. This session explores the basic of metadata that keeps track of data and index storage information. </description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14130</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14130</id>
          <name>Emanuele Zanchettin</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 4</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQLServer2012 as semantic search engine</title>
      <description>With the increase in the number of documents created, received and stored by computer, consequently increases the difficulty and time to retrieve these documents based on their content and meaning. With SQL Server 2012 and its new features of Filestream and FullText engine, it is possible to go beyond the "classical" management of key words and phrases linked to each document. Thanks to semantic search you can search for documents according to their meaning, find related documents and retrieve similar documents easily and effectively.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>14592</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>14592</id>
          <name>Gianluca Hotz</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Track 1</track>
      <location>
        <name>N/A</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2012 AlwaysOn</title>
      <description>Business continuity is becoming more and more a central topic for many companies. AlwaysOn is the new solution for high availability and disaster recovery introduced with SQL Server 2012. With the help of live demos, in this session we will cover in details this new technology that extends on the familiar concepts of database mirroring and failover clustering. We will also introduce some other engine enhancements that will help raising the overall service availability.</description>
      <startTime>4/20/2013 12:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/20/2013 1:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>