<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #487 - Ottawa 2016</name>
    <startDate>4/16/2016 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>150</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-05:00) Indiana (East)</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatOttawa</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Ottawa</name>
      <street>100 Queen St, Suite 500</street>
      <city>Ottawa</city>
      <state>Ontario, Canada</state>
      <zipcode>K1P 1J9</zipcode>
      <longitude>-75.696934</longitude>
      <latitude>45.422181</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>567</importID>
      <name>DevTeach</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.devteach.com/Index.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://devteach.com/images/devteachlogo.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41419</importID>
      <name>Paresh Motiwala</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Paresh Motiwala a Azure/Big Data enthusiast, Manager of Database Platform teams has led several large SQL implementations, migrations and upgrades. He has managed multi terabyte OLTP databases. He has also been a Sr. SQL DBA and a Solutions Architect in Fortune 100 companies.  He helps/organizes and speaks at many SQL Saturdays, Azure Bootcamp, Azure Datafests and User Groups(Boston BI UG, NESQL, PASS PD VG and PASS DBA VG).

He is certified in Big Data Analytics, FinTech, PMP, Public Speaking, Business Communications. He is a avid singer, cook, open networker, and stand-up comedian. 
He teaches public speaking, debating, interviewing and group discussion skills and mentors children around the globe via www.circlesofgrowth.com</description>
      <twitter>pareshmotiwala</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/pareshmotiwala</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://pareshmotiwala.wordpress.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=2amp;action=editamp;message=6amp;postpost=v2</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=pareshmotiwala</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46185</importID>
      <name>Chris Sommer</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris started in computing and I.T. in the mid to late 1990’s. After the dust had settled from Y2K, he found himself a bit more focused and working with database servers on the Unix platform. His first exposure to SQL Server was in 2007 and he has been working on that platform ever since. Chris is currently a Senior SQL DBA with a focus on reliability, stability and performance. He truly enjoys the building tools with PowerShell to help his fellow DBA#39;s manage their ever growing environment.</description>
      <twitter>@cjsommer</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/cjsommer</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.cjsommer.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@cjsommer</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>44731</importID>
      <name>Michael DeFehr</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Michael DeFehr is an independent SQL Server consultant based in Winnipeg, Canada. He is focused on database administration and development using Microsoft SQL Server.
A SQL Server MVP, Professional Engineer and MCITP in both Database Development and Administration, Mike has spent the past 15 years producing and maintaining database solutions. Mike specializes in the relational and storage engines and his solutions emphasize performance and simplicity.</description>
      <twitter>@mdefehr</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/mdefehr</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://mikedefehr.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@mdefehr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42508</importID>
      <name>Alejandro Cordero</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>DBA with Over 10 years of experience. Focused on SQL Server development , performance tuning, High Availability. Scrum Master Certified, MCTS, MCSA, Entrepreneur and Author at SQLTurbo.com. Currently working as technical leader for database consultants in Pythian Company.

Regular speaker at SQL Saturdays in Latin America ( Costa Rica, Guatemala, Colombia)  and virtual chapters( In-Memory chapter, Spanish Chapter). Have presented in SQL Saturday Ottawa in Canada.</description>
      <twitter>@ale_corderocr</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://cr.linkedin.com/in/alejandrocorderocr</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlturbo.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ale_corderocr</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>46476</importID>
      <name>Rayis Imayev</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Database professional with hands-on database design, data analysis, and reporting skills. I believe that I can help to make this intricate world of data to be more structured and well understood. Born in USSR; graduated and started my IT journey in Ukraine; now I work and live with my family in Toronto, Canada.</description>
      <twitter>rayisimayev</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/rimayev</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://datanrg.blogspot.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=rayisimayev</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>41441</importID>
      <name>Christian Cote</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Christian Coté is an IT professional with more than 15 years of experience working in data warehouse and business intelligence projects.  Christian developed an expertise in data warehousing over the years and designed many ETL/BI processes using a range of tools on multiple platforms. He's been presenting at several conferences and code camps. He currently co-leads the SQL Server PASS chapter in Montreal as well as Global French SQL PASS Chapter.  He is also a Microsoft Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP).</description>
      <twitter>Christian_SQL</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://ca.linkedin.com/in/ccote</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://bi-blogger.typepad.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=Christian_SQL</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42252</importID>
      <name>Warner Chaves</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warner is a SQL Server MCM, Data Platform MVP and Principal Consultant at Pythian, a global Canada-based company specialized in DBA services. A brief stint in .NET programming led to his early DBA formation working for enterprise customers in Hewlett-Packard ITO organization. From there he transitioned to his current position at Pythian, building and managing data solutions in many industry verticals while leading a highly talented team of Data Platform consultants.</description>
      <twitter>@warchav</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/warnerchaves/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlturbo.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@warchav</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>47205</importID>
      <name>Edwin M Sarmiento</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Edwin M Sarmiento is the Managing Director of 15C, a consulting and training company that specializes in designing, implementing and supporting SQL Server infrastructures. He is a 12-year former Microsoft Data Platform MVP and Microsoft Certified Master from Ottawa, Canada (but he’s originally from the Philippines) specializing in high availability, disaster recovery and system infrastructures running on the Microsoft server technology stack. His background in Unix has taken him to the world of DevOps and Docker to containerize SQL Server. He is very passionate about technology but has interests in music, professional and organizational development, leadership and management matters when not working with databases.</description>
      <twitter>EdwinMSarmiento</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/edwinmsarmiento</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.EdwinMSarmiento.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=EdwinMSarmiento</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>42249</importID>
      <name>Warner Chaves</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Warner is a SQL Server MCM, Data Platform MVP and Principal Consultant at Pythian, a global Canada-based company specialized in DBA services. A brief stint in .NET programming led to his early DBA formation working for enterprise customers in Hewlett-Packard ITO organization. From there he transitioned to his current position at Pythian, building and managing data solutions in many industry verticals while leading a highly talented team of Data Platform consultants.</description>
      <twitter>@warchav</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://ca.linkedin.com/in/warnerchaves/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlturbo.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@warchav</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>44265</importID>
      <name>Phillip Labry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Phillip Labry is a Senior BI Consultant and Trainer with over 20 years experience in SQL Server and over 30 in IT. He has been lucky enough to work on data projects spanning telecom, banking, retail, law enforcement, health care, insurance, financial services and energy sectors. As a national consultant he provides training and builds solutions utilizing the full MS BI stack. He is an active member of the Madison, WI PASS chapter and speaks at events in the USA and Canada.</description>
      <twitter>@philliplabry</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://phillip.labry.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@philliplabry</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>42252</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42252</id>
          <name>Warner Chaves</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>Time to Stretch: Scaling out and in with Azure DB Elastic Scale</title>
      <description>Elasticity is one of the main promises of cloud computing. The cloud has given us the ability to programmatically add or remove resources to an application and dynamically respond to our workload volume to allow for cost efficient, high performing solutions. However, achieving this elasticity in a transparent way can be a challenge in itself.

In particular, dynamically scaling the database tier can be difficult due to having to deal with distribution schemes, data movement, application routing and the actual increase or decrease of the database resources. Azure SQL Database and the Elastic Scale .NET API combine to provide a solution to these challenges in an easy to use but powerful set of capabilities. 

In this session we will demo the elastic scale API, elastic db pools, elastic query and elastic database jobs and how they combine to bring database elasticity in your own application and take advantage of true cloud optimized infrastructure!</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46185</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46185</id>
          <name>Chris Sommer</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 Automation with PowerShell</title>
      <description>DBA’s are constantly faced with challenges in maintaining a healthy SQL Server environment. Monitoring our database servers, deploying database code changes and performing database restores are just a few examples of a day in the life of a DBA. As workloads increase, performing these tasks manually introduces more opportunity for human error and time starts to become our bottleneck. The only option if you want to stay above water is to become more efficient at what you do. Enter automation. Enter PowerShell.

Initially released in 2006, PowerShell has grown to become Microsoft's premier scripting language on the Windows platform. This presentation will begin with a brief overview of the PowerShell language itself, but the primary focus will be on how to interface with SQL Server to help automate your database environment.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41419</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41419</id>
          <name>Paresh Motiwala</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>DBA to Project Manager in 60 minutes flat</title>
      <description>As DBAs we are often stuck at the mercy of higher ups and Project Managers for completion of our assigned tasks/ projects.
In this session we wil actually take an arbitrary application and its affiliated databases and go throught the tasks/resources needed to accomplish the task. We will think and act like a Project Manager and DBA rolled into one. This will surely help you advance your career within organization and help you think ahead of time.
</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 1:15:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 2:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>47205</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>47205</id>
          <name>Edwin M Sarmiento</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 New Features</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 New Features</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42249</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42249</id>
          <name>Warner Chaves</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server as a Cloud Service</title>
      <description>The war of the cloud providers continues and database services is one of the many arenas. These services provide a platform that reduces management by trading off detailed control of your underlying OS and hardware.

In this session we will do a comparison of the two most popular platforms for SQL Server: Amazon RDS and Azure SQL Database and explore the strengths and weaknesses of each one.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>44731</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>44731</id>
          <name>Michael DeFehr</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>TSQL Bullet-Dodging and Spoon-bending</title>
      <description>Did you think you could dodge bullets with SQL Server? Well, with some of these techniques, you won't have to. Learn some of the newer language elements in SQL server: Recursive CTE's, Composable DML, the MERGE statement, Row numbering and table-valued parameters. This fast-paced session that is almost exclusively demos is sure to leave you with a few ideas to make your TSQL development life easier.
</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 10:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 11:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>46476</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>46476</id>
          <name>Rayis Imayev</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Excel Power Map vs. Power BI Globe Map visualization</title>
      <description>You’ve crafted your geo data set in Power Query in Excel, then moved it to your Power Pivot model and joined with all other tables. Now you want to visualize your data points using Power Map in Excel or tempted to export your existing data model to Power BI and explore it using Power BI Globe custom visualization. Does Power BI Globe visualization replace the Power Map application in Excel? Can you explore your geo data facts sufficiently using the Power BI Globe only? And do Power BI Globe and Excel Power Map compete with each other or they’re just friends? Let’s try to explore this together.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 2:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 3:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>41441</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>41441</id>
          <name>Christian Cote</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Integration Services 2016 (SSIS) novelties and Azure Integration</title>
      <description>SSIS has been around for the past decade and this 2016 version brings a lot a interesting features. This session will talk about SSIS 2016 and how it can now interact with Microsoft Azure HDInsight and storage.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 9:15:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 10:15:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>42508</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>42508</id>
          <name>Alejandro Cordero</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room 1</name>
      </location>
      <title>UFC #1433 In-Memory tables 2014 vs. 2016</title>
      <description>In this session we will check the advantages of performance that In-Memory tables provides and how they evolved in SQL Server 2016. If you are planning to implement IN-Memory tables, check a performance comparison between 2014 and 2016, or just get to know how this technology works, this is the session you don#180;t want to miss. Let's Get Ready To Rumble!!</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>44265</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>44265</id>
          <name>Phillip Labry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Room2</name>
      </location>
      <title>Analysis Services 2016 - Tabular Jumpstart</title>
      <description>Analysis Services Tabular is an in memory analytics engine introduced in SQL Server 2012. It has shown to be a quick and effective way to transform your organization with modern analytics. Join Phillip and learn how easy it is to create a tabular solution and provide valuable insight into your organization's data.  This is a demo heavy session and you should be able walk away knowing how to create your own tabular model.</description>
      <startTime>4/16/2016 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>4/16/2016 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>