<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #651 - Houston 2017</name>
    <startDate>6/17/2017 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>300</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT-06:00) Saskatchewan</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsat651</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>San Jacinto College - South Campus</name>
      <street>13735 Beamer Rd</street>
      <city>Houston</city>
      <state>Texas</state>
      <zipcode>77089</zipcode>
      <longitude>-95.202972</longitude>
      <latitude>29.581348</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1272</importID>
      <name>WARDY IT Solutions</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.wardyit.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/986/EventSponsor_14725.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>449</importID>
      <name>Brent Ozar Unlimited</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.brentozar.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.brentozar.com/wp-content/themes/brentozar/img/logo.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1503</importID>
      <name>Improving</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.improving.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.allenkinsel.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Improving_SQLSAT514.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>607</importID>
      <name>DELL EMC</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.dellemc.com/en-us/index.htm</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/913/EventSponsor_14262.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>3</importID>
      <name>Idera</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</url>
      <imageURL>https://www.sqlsaturday.com/images/SQLSaturday/eventsponsors/IDERA170x60.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1495</importID>
      <name>MinionWare, LLC</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://minionware.net/?utm_source=SQL%20Saturdayutm_campaign=SQLSat613utm_medium=imageutm_term=MinionWare</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14696.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1817</importID>
      <name>SentryOne</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sentryone.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/908/EventSponsor_14257.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1552</importID>
      <name>467 - Tegile Systems</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.tegile.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://pages.tegile.com/rs/568-BVY-995/images/Tegile-systems_Logo_2.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1075</importID>
      <name>Sparkhound</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.sparkhound.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/899/EventSponsor_13753.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1764</importID>
      <name>Procure SQL</name>
      <label>Silver Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://procuresql.com</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/939/EventSponsor_14481.jpg</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1405</importID>
      <name>COZYROC</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://bit.ly/cozyrocssis</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlsaturdayfiles.blob.core.windows.net/978/EventSponsor_14586.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>1903</importID>
      <name>SQLDocKit by Acceleratio</name>
      <label>Bronze Sponsor</label>
      <url>https://www.sqldockit.com/</url>
      <imageURL>https://sqlcambs.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/logo-sponsor-sqldockit_trim.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63511</importID>
      <name>Roberto Cavalcanti</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Roberto Cavalcanti is an Azure Cloud Solution Architect with the Customer Architecture and Engineering team at Microsoft. He is a database specialist with 20+ years of experience. He focuses on helping customers to be successful in Microsoft's Azure cloud and on improving Microsoft Azure products. Roberto has written many articles about SQL Server/Azure SQL DB for MSDN/TechNet, SQL Magazine, and has been a speaker in events such as TechReady, Microsoft Insights/TechEd, SQL Saturday. He has delivered Azure training in multiple countries in the Americas, and in Europe. Roberto is based on the Microsoft Las Colinas, Texas, USA office.</description>
      <twitter>rocavalc</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertocavalcanti</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=rocavalc</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63549</importID>
      <name>Mike Byrd</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Former rocket scientist and USAF Fighter Pilot -- now a SQL Server geek (24 years)! Past opportunities include free-lance technical writer for PC Magazine, Senior Software Manager for government sponsored munitions effectiveness committee, and insurance company CTO.  Currently senior database engineer consultant for several Austin companies.  

Presenter at many SQL Saturdays over last 6 years in United States, Europe, and Australia.

Specialize in SQL Server performance tuning; database (OLTP  OLAP) architecture; trouble-shooting; teaching TSQL (Basic through Advanced).

Video presentations (for local SQL Server user groups or SQL Saturdays) can be found at http://usergroup.tv/videos/category/speaker/mike-byrd</description>
      <twitter>ByrdNest_TX</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mike-byrd/1/aa0/bbb</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://logicalread.solarwinds.com/?s=byrd, www.TSQLMentoring.com and SQLServerCentral.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ByrdNest_TX</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65390</importID>
      <name>Kris Hokanson</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Kris has been building databases for over 20 years. Since SQL Server 7 he’s been looking for ways to shave a second (or an hour) off any query he comes across. His work experience ranges from small construction firms to fortune 200 Oil amp; Gas corporations.  He has designed and administered everything from 10 MB single user databases to enterprise data warehouses using SQL Server and SSIS to consolidate data from hundreds of disparate ERP systems.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63529</importID>
      <name>Thomas Norman</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tom Norman is a Database Architect at KPA with a strong fervor to protect data. He works daily to review and improve data protection methodologies while reviewing governing laws affecting finance, healthcare, and personal data. His areas of expertise include encryption, auditing, data identification, and database object deployment. He is the current leader of the PASS Virtualization Group and Vice President of the TRIPASS user group. You can read his blog at https://armordba.com/ and reach him on twitter at @armordba. Tom speaks at a number of SQLSaturday events and SQL Server user groups.</description>
      <twitter>ArmorDba</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/armordba</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://armordba.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ArmorDba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63571</importID>
      <name>Thomas LeBlanc</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Thomas LeBlanc (Microsoft Data Platform MVP) is a Data Warehouse Architect in Baton Rouge, and uses his 30+ years in IT to develop OLTP systems with normalized databases for high-performing T-SQL and dimensional data marts. Development is done in SSIS, SSAS, SSRS, Power BI, and Excel. As a PASS volunteer, he is past chair of Excel BI and Data Arch VCs and is active in the Baton Rouge Analytics and SQL Server User groups, as well as SQLSaturday in Baton Rouge.
You can find his blog at TheSmilingDBA.BlogSpot.com and website at Thomas-LeBlanc.com</description>
      <twitter>TheSmilingDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=29648544amp;trk=hb_tab_pro_top</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://Thomas-LeBlanc.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=TheSmilingDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63544</importID>
      <name>William Assaf</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>William Assaf is a senior content developer on the SQLDocs team at Microsoft. Formerly a Data Platform MVP and a consultant for SQL Server, and before that a .NET developer, William currently works with Microsoft product groups on content related to the SQL database platform, specifically for SQL performance, Big Data Clusters, and Azure SQL DB. As a consultant for 13 years he worked with clients on SQL Server and Azure SQL platform optimization, management, disaster recovery and high availability, and led a crack multi-city team of consulting SQL DBA's. William has written for Microsoft SQL certification exams since 2011 and was the team lead author of the 2017 and 2019 editions of "SQL Server Administration Inside Out" by Microsoft Press. William is a past lead of the annual SQLSaturday Baton Rouge Planning Committee and supports the Baton Rouge User Groups.</description>
      <twitter>william_a_dba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamdassaf/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqltact.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=william_a_dba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63589</importID>
      <name>Trayce Jordan</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Working with SQL Server for almost 20 years, Trayce is one of the first certified masters, holding an MCM for SQL 2005 and has been working at Microsoft since 2006.   Prior to joining Microsoft, he worked for a major online travel company as well as financial institutions and has served as a consultant working with companies in many different industries.  His specialties include database performance tuning, operations management and support, high availability and disaster recovery.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63546</importID>
      <name>Brent Ozar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brent Ozar loves to make SQL Server faster. He created sp_Blitz and the SQL Server First Responder Kit. He shares what he's learned at BrentOzar.com.</description>
      <twitter>BrentO</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/brentozar</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.BrentOzar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=BrentO</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63590</importID>
      <name>Kevin Hill</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I have been working with Microsoft Database technologies since 1994, in Design, Data Modeling, Development and Administration.  18 years of that time have been with SQL Server, going all the way back to 6.5.   

I find that I am most passionate about the Admin and HA/DR side, but will still dive into design when called upon.   

The Azure cloud is exciting and I believe is the future of SQL Server.   I love teaching new and accidental DBAs all of the things I didn't know when I started.</description>
      <twitter>@Kevin3NF</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/Kevin3NF</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.dallasdbas.com/Blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Kevin3NF</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63797</importID>
      <name>John Cook</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Paul Cook is a psychiatric nurse practitioner and instructor of psychiatric nursing. He is former Data Platform Solutions Architect for Microsoft and before that a 9 time Microsoft MVP. John understands both the clinical aspects of healthcare and the technical aspects. He provides a unique perspective in being able to explain clinical concerns and issues to technical people. John is passionate about improving mental health in the community, including in the technical community.</description>
      <twitter>johnpaulcook</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-cook/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.red-gate.com/simple-talk/author/johnpaulcook-2/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=johnpaulcook</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63587</importID>
      <name>Steven Tidwell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>I am currently the Technical Lead for Client custom projects.  I have been writing SQL Code starting in SQL 7.  Over the years I have put on many hats, DBA, Developer, Web Developer, C#, VB.NET, Cold Fusion and Java.  But at the end of the day, I prefer to write SQL. Local Chapter Leader for the South Montgomery County SQL Server User Group in Montgomery County, Texas.</description>
      <twitter>@SQLCodeMonkey</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlcodemonkey</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.sqlcodemonkey.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@SQLCodeMonkey</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63726</importID>
      <name>Bob Ward</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Ward is a Principal Architect for the Microsoft Azure Data SQL Server team, which owns the development for all SQL Server versions. Bob has worked for Microsoft for 26+ years on every version of SQL Server shipped from OS/2 1.1 to SQL Server 2019 including Azure SQL. Bob is a well-known speaker on SQL Server, often presenting talks on new releases, internals, and performance at events such as PASS Summit, Red Hat Summit, Microsoft Ready, SQLBits, SQLIntersection, Microsoft Inspire, and Microsoft Ignite. You can follow him at @bobwardms or linkedin.com/in/bobwardms. Bob is the author of the books Pro SQL Server on Linux and SQL Server 2019 Revealed available from Apress Media.
Twitter: http://twitter.com/bobwardms.</description>
      <twitter>bobwardms</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/bobsql</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bobwardms</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64403</importID>
      <name>David Stein</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>David Stein - Agile Data Warehouse Architect and Independent Consultant - has more than a decade of experience working in SQL Server Business Intelligence. He’s designed multi-terabyte, multi-tenant Data Warehouses from scratch as well as saved projects in serious jeopardy.</description>
      <twitter>@Made2Mentor</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/david-stein/8/ba8/705</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.Made2Mentor.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Made2Mentor</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63723</importID>
      <name>Jamey Johnston</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jamey Johnston is a Senior Data Scientist/Engineer for a large independent OG company. For over 25 years, he has worked for Fortune 500 companies architecting successful platforms in the cloud, on the edge, and on-premises for BI reporting, statistical analysis, ML, and AI. Lately, he spends his time in Azure, Python, R, Power BI, MS SQL, and SAS JMP. He holds a BS in Spatial Analysis from LSU and a Masters of Science in Analytics from Texas AM. He is a professor at the Mays Business School at Texas AM in the MS Analytics program. He is active in his PASS Local Group in Houston, co-leader of the local Power BI users group and data analytics group. He regularly speaks and volunteers at PASS events. He is also a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.</description>
      <twitter>STATCowboy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jameyj</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://STATCowboy.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=STATCowboy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64358</importID>
      <name>Russel Loski</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Russ Loski is a SQL Server BI Developer based in Dallas-Fort Worth.  He current works as a Data Analytics Engineer for Navisite, a remote managed IT services company.   Twenty years ago, he began working with SQL Server 6.5. He has since continued to develop applications connected to all of the versions of SQL Server. He has worked with clients in industries from insurance to healthcare, from movie theaters to American football.  Russ is a regular speaker at SQLSaturday events, as well as the SQL Server Users Groups in the North Texas region. Russ likes working with data in various shapes.</description>
      <twitter>sqlmovers</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/russloski</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlmovers.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmovers</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63584</importID>
      <name>Robert Bishop</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robert has been working with databases since SQL Server 2005.  After 4 years as a .NET developer using SQL Server, Robert became a DBA out of necessity, a true "Accidental" DBA!   Robert has presented at his local SQL Server User group, SQL Saturdays and PASS Virtual Chapters.  As a Microsoft MSCA and an Idera ACE, Robert enjoys administrative tasks, configuring SQL Server for optimal performance, troubleshooting problematic SQL queries and making those query run faster than the speed of light.  In the event of "free time", Robert enjoys camping, playing his guitars and spending time with his family.</description>
      <twitter>http://twitter.com/sql_padre</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://sqlpadre.wordpress.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://twitter.com/sql_padre</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63725</importID>
      <name>Bob Ward</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Bob Ward is a Principal Architect for the Microsoft Azure Data SQL Server team, which owns the development for all SQL Server versions. Bob has worked for Microsoft for 26+ years on every version of SQL Server shipped from OS/2 1.1 to SQL Server 2019 including Azure SQL. Bob is a well-known speaker on SQL Server, often presenting talks on new releases, internals, and performance at events such as PASS Summit, Red Hat Summit, Microsoft Ready, SQLBits, SQLIntersection, Microsoft Inspire, and Microsoft Ignite. You can follow him at @bobwardms or linkedin.com/in/bobwardms. Bob is the author of the books Pro SQL Server on Linux and SQL Server 2019 Revealed available from Apress Media.
Twitter: http://twitter.com/bobwardms.</description>
      <twitter>bobwardms</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://aka.ms/bobsql</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=bobwardms</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65237</importID>
      <name>Robyn Fuentes</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Robyn Fuentes is an experienced software developer working as a Senior Consultant for Improving. Robyn has successfully lead technical teams for different enterprise products spanning multiple platforms and technologies. She enjoys problem solving and prides herself in formulating simple, yet effective and creative solutions for a wide variety of business needs.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/robyn-fuentes-a38a8174/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://medium.com/@robynfuentes</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63514</importID>
      <name>Naomi Williams</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Naomi Williams is a SQL Server professional working in the San Antonio area. Currently a seasoned Database Administrator  for both Oracle and SQL Server  doing database development, SSIS, SSRS and SSAS.  Naomi has been working with SQL Server for almost 15 years. Naomi is passionate about performance, high availability, and creative non standard solutions to complex problems</description>
      <twitter>naomithesqldba</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nfwilliams</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=naomithesqldba</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63550</importID>
      <name>Brent Ozar</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Brent Ozar loves to make SQL Server faster. He created sp_Blitz and the SQL Server First Responder Kit. He shares what he's learned at BrentOzar.com.</description>
      <twitter>BrentO</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/brentozar</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://www.BrentOzar.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=BrentO</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63691</importID>
      <name>Christopher Sims</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris is a software engineer and program manager with over 18 years of programming and 14 years of project management experience. Chris continually pushes his personal and professional boundaries by actively seeking out complex projects and applying innovative, sophisticated and elegant solutions to real-world problems. Chris is the technical principal of agile consulting firm, Sigao Studios. Sigao Studios specializes in offering modern responsive web solutions based on technologies that include Azure, CosmosDB and Azure Search. In addition to his technical pursuits, Chris enjoys stage acting and wood working in his free time.</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/sigaostudios</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopherpsims/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sigaostudios.com/blog</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/sigaostudios</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63616</importID>
      <name>Tim Mitchell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tim Mitchell is a business intelligence architect, author, and trainer. He has worked with SQL Server for over a decade, specializing in data warehousing, ETL/SSIS, and reporting. He holds a Bachelor’s Degree in Computer Science from Texas AM at Commerce, and is recognized as a Microsoft Data Platform MVP.  Tim is a business intelligence consultant and principal at Tyleris Data Solutions.

Tim is an active community speaker and volunteer, having spoken at over 100 events including the PASS Summit, SQLBits, Dev Connections, SQL Intersection, and scores of SQL Saturdays. He blogs at TimMitchell.net, and tweets at @Tim_Mitchell.</description>
      <twitter>@Tim_Mitchell</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/timmitchell/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.TimMitchell.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Tim_Mitchell</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63816</importID>
      <name>Dane Schilling</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>From modeling databases to writing complex reports Dane Schilling has utilized MS SQL Server nearly every working day for the last sevenyears.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.daneschilling.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64337</importID>
      <name>Amy Herold</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Amy Herold is currently a Premier Field Engineer with Microsoft, specializing in APS. Prior to this, she was a Sr. Database Administrator, focusing on PowerShell and automation. She is also currently the Director of Programs for the North Texas SQL Server User Group (NTSSUG). She frequently speaks at SQL Saturday and user group events across the United States and has also participated in numerous Women in Technology sessions as a panelist. Amy currently blogs at sqlkitten.com.</description>
      <twitter>@texasamy</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/aherold</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlkitten.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@texasamy</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63588</importID>
      <name>Shawn Weisfeld</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Shawn (http://www.shawnweisfeld.com, shawn@shawnweisfeld.com) is passionate about building awesome applications and websites with .NET technologies and Azure. He is currently a Technical Evangelist for Microsoft based in Austin TX and founder of http://UserGroup.tv. Read his full bio at http://about.me/shawnweisfeld</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/shawnweisfeld</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/shawnweisfeld</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.usergroup.tv</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/shawnweisfeld</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63778</importID>
      <name>Jennifer McCown</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Jen McCown is CEO of MinionWare, LLC; a Microsoft Certified Master for SQL Server; and an independent consultant. She is Senior Editor at MidnightDBA.com, where she creates training videos, the DBAs at Midnight webshow, blogs, reviews, and podcasts. Jen is a member, volunteer, and speaker in PASS, and the PASS Women in Technology Virtual Group.</description>
      <twitter>http://www.Twitter.com/MidnightDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/jennifermccown</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.MidnightDBA.com/Jen</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=http://www.Twitter.com/MidnightDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64178</importID>
      <name>Robert Stewart</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data and BI Architect at TDECU.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64410</importID>
      <name>Rick Lowe</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Rick is a Microsoft Certified Master with more than 20 years of SQL Server experience in a variety of roles. He currently lives in Washington state and works as an independent consultant providing remote performance DBA and performance tuning services for clients in the USA and Canada. His first exposure to SQL Server was as a database developer, but over time he became more and more interested in how the database engine operated... eventually specializing more on performance issues than code.

Rick will work with all things relational, but most enjoys helping smaller companies get better performance from MSSQL, as well as smoothing over relationships between DBA and development teams.</description>
      <twitter>DataFLowe</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rick-lowe/a/228/441/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://dataflowe.wordpress.com/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=DataFLowe</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63782</importID>
      <name>Sean McCown</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Sean McCown is a Certified Master with 23 years of experience in databases. He is also founder and co-owner of the MidnightDBA.com website, where he records free SQL Server training videos. He also writes the popular Minion Maintenance suite, the most configurable maintenance solution on the planet.</description>
      <twitter>@KenpoDBA</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.midnightdba.com/dbarant</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@KenpoDBA</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64259</importID>
      <name>John Sterrett</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>John Sterrett is a MCSE: Data Platform, Principal Consultant, and the Founder of Procure SQL LLC.  John has experience presenting at community events, including Microsoft Ignite, PASS Member Summit, SQLRally, 24 Hours of PASS, SQL Saturdays, PASS Chapters, and Virtual Chapter meetings. John is a leader of the Austin SQL Server User Group and is the founder of the HADR Virtual Chapter. John's community activities can be found at https://johnsterrett.com/community/</description>
      <twitter>JohnSterrett</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/johnsterrett</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>https://johnsterrett.com/community/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=JohnSterrett</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64442</importID>
      <name>Lance Tidwell</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lance Tidwell, from the Austin, TX, area, has worked as a SQL Server DBA for the last 11 years. During his time as a DBA he has found his passion for all things SQL, but specifically for performance tuning. He has a life-long quest to always be learning new things; currently this quest has lead him to explore more about the Data Analytics/ Data Science areas.</description>
      <twitter>@Lance_LT</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://lancetidwell.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@Lance_LT</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64346</importID>
      <name>John Harp</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>With 17 years in the technical support field and more than a decade working with Microsoft SQL Server, John has seen some of the weirdest errors and most spectacular failures SQL Server can generate. And he#39;s solved most of them, with a little help from his friends in the SQL Server Community. John is the Technical Support Manager for Idera#39;s SQL Server Products. </description>
      <twitter>@sekainohaten</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/pub/john-harp/0/914/179</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@sekainohaten</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64365</importID>
      <name>Anthony {Tex} Moreign</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>{Technologist | Speaker | Writer | Founder} … 25 years  counting …
– Founder  Chief Architect, Hybrid Decisions® Corp   (www.HybridDecisions.com  | 2005)
– Founder  President, Houston Cloud Computing User Group   (www.HCCUG.org  | 2008)
– for more info see http://linkedin.com/in/AnthonyTexM
«±»</description>
      <twitter>https://twitter.com/AnthonyTexM</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/AnthonyTexM</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.hccug.org</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=https://twitter.com/AnthonyTexM</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>65108</importID>
      <name>Chris Hyde</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Chris Hyde is a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and Microsoft Certified Trainer based in Albuquerque, New Mexico. He works as an independent SQL Server BI and DBA consultant, and is the leader of the Albuquerque PASS local user group. He is also part of the Friends of Redgate program and was a member of the Idera ACE class of 2018. He loves loud music and cricket, but usually not at the same time.</description>
      <twitter>ChrisHyde325</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/in/chris-hyde-3803706</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=ChrisHyde325</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64328</importID>
      <name>Lori Edwards</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Lori Edwards currently holds the position of Solutions Engineer for SentryOne. Prior to working with SQLSentry, she spent 11 years working as a production DBA.  She also has volunteered for PASS since 2009 on the Program Committee, ERC, Nomination Committee and speaking at SQL Saturdays.</description>
      <twitter>www.twitter.com/loriaedwards</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/loriedwards/</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlservertimes2.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=www.twitter.com/loriaedwards</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64022</importID>
      <name>Vicky Harp</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Vicky Harp is the Group PM Manager for the SQL Server Tools Team, which is responsible for the full set of experiences from drivers and scripting libraries, to GUI tools, to the Azure Portal. She has been building tools for SQL Server for 15 years.</description>
      <twitter>vickyharp</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://vickyharp.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=vickyharp</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>64120</importID>
      <name>Phillip Labry</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Phillip Labry is a Senior BI Consultant and Trainer with over 20 years experience in SQL Server and over 30 in IT. He has been lucky enough to work on data projects spanning telecom, banking, retail, law enforcement, health care, insurance, financial services and energy sectors. As a national consultant he provides training and builds solutions utilizing the full MS BI stack. He is an active member of the Madison, WI PASS chapter and speaks at events in the USA and Canada.</description>
      <twitter>@philliplabry</twitter>
      <linkedin>
      </linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://phillip.labry.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@philliplabry</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>63850</importID>
      <name>Ryan Adams</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Ryan Adams is a Senior Premier Field Engineer for Microsoft.  He works directly with customers to help them realize their business potential and accelerate their digital transformation on premises and in the cloud.

Previously, Ryan was a Microsoft Data Platform MVP and spent 19 years working for a fortune 100 company.  His passion is the SQL Server Engine, High Availability, and Disaster Recovery. He also served on the Board of Directors for the North Texas SQL Server User Group, was President of the PASS Performance Virtual Chapter, was a PASS Regional Mentor, and served as a Director for the PASS organization.</description>
      <twitter>@ryanjadams</twitter>
      <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanjadams</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.ryanjadams.com</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=@ryanjadams</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>63546</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63546</id>
          <name>Brent Ozar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.113</name>
      </location>
      <title>What to Do When SQL Server is Slow</title>
      <description>Someone comes running in and asks, "Are you doing something on the SQL Server right now? Can you take a look at it? It seems really slow."

It's one of the most common complaints we get about our databases - and yet, most of us don't have a written plan with what steps to take, in order.

I do this for a living, so I've had to make a written checklist to handle it. I'll give you the exact same checklist I use, then walk you through several performance emergencies. I'll show you how I use open source scripts like sp_WhoIsActive, sp_BlitzFirst, sp_BlitzCache, and more to find the root cause fast. We won't cover performance tuning - our goal in this hour is just to have a written triage process so we don't look like bumbling idiots. Let's get good at this!</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63590</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63590</id>
          <name>Kevin Hill</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Other</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.142</name>
      </location>
      <title>Backups for non-DBAs...the Why, not the How</title>
      <description>Join me and get some new perspective on what your DBA is doing, and why!

Targeted at the non-DBA such as BI/DW folks, Application Developers, Managers, and System Admins, this session will go over the reasons we back up our databases, our systems, etc.  Considerations such as Single points of failure, High Availability/Disaster recovery, Business Continuity and others will be discussed in this interactive conversation.   It will be conversation heavy, with supporting slides to download, and one Database backup demo at the end if time permits.

Everyone involved in a technical role needs to at least know that the things they have created will be recoverable in the event of a disaster, or even just an "oops" moment.   The CIO/CTO should know how long critical systems will be down when bad things happen.  Backups are everyone's responsibility...whether asking the right questions or implementing the process.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63571</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63571</id>
          <name>Thomas LeBlanc</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.115</name>
      </location>
      <title>Business Analytics in SQL Server 2016</title>
      <description>Ever wonder what’s going on with Microsoft Business Intelligence features? Is everything going to the Cloud, or can I still rely on my own servers to design systems? Well, this session is for you. 

We are going to spend hours on looking at the new features of SQL Server 2016 that will help you create on premise solutions for you company or clients that complement the solutions you have already built. SQL Server 2016 not only gives you new tools like R integration and Mobile Reporting, but enhances Analysis Services and Reporting Services you have been using for years.

You will leave with a comforting feeling that Microsoft is not leaving you behind if you do not or cannot go to the Cloud. Perhaps we shall see the thunder of BI love to what we know best and to succeed in the future.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63723</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63723</id>
          <name>Jamey Johnston</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.115</name>
      </location>
      <title>Code Like a Pirate ... Intro to R and Data Science Tools in MS</title>
      <description>R is the most popular statistics language used today. It is one of the most useful tools in the data scientist's tool belt. It is also integrated into the MS stack in tools like Azure ML, SQL Server and Power BI and can be used to take your data analytics to the next level.  
  
Come to this session to get an introduction to the R language including: 

  - installing and Configuring R and RStudio 
  - RStudio Overview and Debugging
  - how to Access and Manipulate Data 
  - install and Manage Packages 
  - create and Use Variables 
  - control Flows 
  - functions 
  - basic Graphing and Statistical Analysis. 

We will finish with a brief introductions of how R integrates in Azure ML, Power BI, and SQL Server 2016 using real demos.  
  
The focus of the session will be primarily on the introduction to the R language and getting attendees comfortable with using R to start the journey into Data Science!</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63550</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63550</id>
          <name>Brent Ozar</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.115</name>
      </location>
      <title>Free Scripts to Troubleshoot SQL Server: sp_Blitz, sp_BlitzCache, and More</title>
      <description>You inherited a SQL Server and a bunch of databases from The Last Guy, and you're pretty sure he was drinking on the job. You need to find out just how big of a mess he left you, and what you need to focus on fixing first. You don't want a generic health check - you only wanna fix things that users are going to notice.

In this all-demo no-slides session, you'll learn how to use the open source First Responder Kit: sp_Blitz, sp_BlitzCache, sp_BlitzIndex, sp_BlitzFirst, sp_BlitzWho, and more. Brent Ozar, one of the script authors, will show you what each script does and how to read the results. It's all completely free, maintained by community volunteers, no strings attached. Come see what the community has been working on lately!</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63529</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63529</id>
          <name>Thomas Norman</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.148</name>
      </location>
      <title>Database Project Makes Deployment Consistent</title>
      <description>The deployment process is frustrating; an object is missing, an object is deployed in the wrong order or an incorrect version. Deploying to multiple environments like Dev, QA, UAT and Prod is a challenge whither on premise or in the cloud. Source controlling database objects is paramount. Team development is required. Database code will only be deployed when changed. Proper security deployment will be repeatable per environment. Together, let us discover how using Database Project will help us with consistent releases. Deployments can cause you trouble but we will share a reliable deployment and version control process. Let’s see how Database Project can help us accomplish this goal.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63691</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63691</id>
          <name>Christopher Sims</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.115</name>
      </location>
      <title>I like big data for $400  - Exploring quiz show questions using Angular, DocumentDB and Azure Search</title>
      <description>In this talk, we will explore two powerful technologies from the Microsoft Azure Stack: DocumentDB and Azure Search. DocumentDB is Microsoft's NoSQL service for building globally scalable schema-free applications. Azure Search allows you to integrate the power of Microsoft's search and natural language processing abilities to explore your complex data stores. During this talk we will cover the benefits of implementing a schema-free database, we will learn how to replicate your data at a global scale with the ease of a simple configuration and we will cover various techniques of querying that data using SQL and the DocumentDB API. Once we have a large datastore in place (we will use 200k+ Jeopardy questions), we will apply the powerful natural language querying capabilities and faceted search features of Azure Search to quickly create an searchable data repository. All of this will be built and exposed using a cross-platform application built in Angular on the Electron framework.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64358</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64358</id>
          <name>Russel Loski</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.117</name>
      </location>
      <title>Querying Semistructured Data in Azure Data Lake with USQL</title>
      <description>Data is exploding across enterprises.  Much of it is semi-structured junk.  Or is it junk?  What are you going to do with it until you can find out?  Microsoft’s Azure Data Lake is a cloud storage and analytical service for parking a variety of data.  When you are ready, you can query that semi-structured data using an ANSI SQL language called U-SQL.  In this session I will demonstrate the similarities and differences between U-SQL and T-SQL.  I will demonstrate how easy it is to build a query against 21 GB of CSV files. Such queries can help you determine whether you have a gold mine in your data or a bunch of garbage before investing in a full data warehouse build.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63549</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63549</id>
          <name>Mike Byrd</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.113</name>
      </location>
      <title>A Rocket Scientist View on Indexes</title>
      <description>Indexes can be a boon or decrement for query performance. This presentation will present what they are (in layman’s terms) and how they may affect query performance – both from a read (SELECT) viewpoint as well as a data modification aspect (INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE).  This session will concentrate with a deep dive into clustered indexes and nonclustered indexes, their syntax and utilization, and their effect on performance in transaction and data warehouse databases.  Covering nonclustered indexes will also be examined in detail and the scenarios they should be applied.  There will be many query demos illustrating index utilization using statistics and query plans.  Attendee should have some TSQL and Management Studio experience.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63584</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63584</id>
          <name>Robert Bishop</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.147</name>
      </location>
      <title>You want me to Isolate what? An introduction into data integrity and Isolation Levels of SQL Server</title>
      <description>Isolation Levels in SQL Server can benefit your application and help control data integrity by managing concurrency effects but can also hurt your application if you are unaware of what they are and how they are used.  A review of SQL Concurrency issues and how SQL Isolation Levels can help eliminate them and keep the integrity of your data.  This presentation will demonstrate with queries what causes concurrency issues and what isolation levels will prevent them.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63725</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63725</id>
          <name>Bob Ward</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.148</name>
      </location>
      <title>Inside SQL Server In-Memory OLTP</title>
      <description>Based on the successful 500 Level talk at PASS 2016, this session will provide an internals view of how In-Memory OLTP works for SQL Server 2016. Because this session is Advanced, it is intended for those that understand the basic fundamentals of In-Memory OLTP but want to learn how the "Hekaton" engine works behind the scenes to deliver the amazing 30x performance improvements seen for customers moving to In-Memory OLTP. This session will include a look behind the scenes at threads, data and index design, transactions and concurrency, logging, storage, and natively compiled procedures. And since this will be an advanced level session, of course the demonstration of the looking at the Hekaton engine with the debugger is a must.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63616</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63616</id>
          <name>Tim Mitchell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.117</name>
      </location>
      <title>Exploring the All-New SSRS 2016</title>
      <description>For years, SQL Server Reporting Services chugged along with very few updates. Although it remained a reliable and popular reporting tool, the feature set largely remained unchanged for a decade. With the release of SQL Server 2016, everything changed. Microsoft delivered a brand new SSRS. This session will review and demonstrate the new features of SQL Server Reporting Services 2016. You'll walk through the essential changes in SSRS, from the new report manager to the new visualizations. You'll also discuss the SSRS ecosystem and how it fits together with Datazen, PowerBI, and other Microsoft reporting/analytics platforms.

You will learn:

The scope of changes to the new SSRS in 2016
See these new features in action with several realistic demos.
How the all-new SSRS fits in with Datazen, PowerBI, and other Microsoft reporting</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63797</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63797</id>
          <name>John Cook</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.142</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Graph Database</title>
      <description>The next version of SQL Server will run on either Windows or Linux and includes new functionality including graph database features. Graph databases are ideal for those cases where there is a relationship that exists but it doesn't fit the rigid hierarchy of a relational table. Graph databases easily manage data where there are differing degrees of separation - the so-called Kevin Bacon problem. The degrees of separation problem is highly relevant to important real world problems such as root cause analysis, bill of materials, parts explosion, where used queries, route planning, and fraud detection just to name a few. New syntax exists is take advantage of storing and processing relationships. Learn how this transformative technology works and then update your resume!</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64365</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64365</id>
          <name>Anthony {Tex} Moreign</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.147</name>
      </location>
      <title>Big|Small|Tiny Data  +  The Hybrid Cloud</title>
      <description>CRUX:   The focus of this talk is Data (Big Data, Small Data, Tiny Data, Micro Data)  –and–  The Hybrid Cloud (Microsoft  non-Microsoft) Offerings available as of this point-in-time (Jun-2017).       Pre-requisites required:  none, other than just your interest.

AUDIENCE:  This talk is for anyone, irrespective of whether you are — just entering the industry, updating/expanding your skills, or just seeking answers to questions like:
1.  Big Data?  Small Data?  Tiny Data?
2.  Cloud? Hybrid Cloud? Global Hybrid Cloud? 
3.  Why should I care?   What’s in it for me?  Where do I go from here?

NOTE:  The presenters, Tex (20+ year technologist)  Sons (Valentino  Zane, budding technologists), are with Hybrid Decisions® Corp and are presenting on behalf of  www.HCCUG.org  (Houston Cloud Computing User Group)
«±»</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63544</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63544</id>
          <name>William Assaf</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.142</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Permissions and Security Principals</title>
      <description>A ground-floor introduction to SQL Server permissions starting with the basics and moving into the security implications behinds stored procedures, views, database ownership, application connections, consolidated databases, application roles and more. This class is perfect for DBA's, developers and system admins, and includes information on securing Azure SQL databases!</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63589</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63589</id>
          <name>Trayce Jordan</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.115</name>
      </location>
      <title>Finding root cause for unexplained Availability Group failover</title>
      <description>In this session, we will walk you step by step showing how we determine root cause analysis of an unexplained failure in an Availability Group.  Whether the databases simply became unavailable, synchronization stopped, or there was an unexplained failover.   We will show you specifically what we look for in the OS Cluster logs, SQL error logs, Extended Events and other sources of information.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63587</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63587</id>
          <name>Steven Tidwell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.115</name>
      </location>
      <title>Dynamic SQL: Tables, Pivots</title>
      <description>Dynamic SQL is a scripting language that helps you design flexibility into your code. It allows you to design solutions, pass parameters and allows you build a single query on values passed.  Dynamic SQL has both pros and cons to it's design, but can also be a helpful tool. This presentation will walk through the steps of building dynamic tables, aggregating data in a pivot format and give you the first steps of writing a Dynamic Query. There are hundreds of task that will benefit from the use of Dynamic SQL.  From parameter based searches to building dynamic SELECT statements at run time.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63726</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63726</id>
          <name>Bob Ward</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.148</name>
      </location>
      <title>Inside SQL Server Machine Learning Services: Database Intelligence at Scale</title>
      <description>You are a DBA of SQL Server deploying or considering SQL Server 2016 or SQL Server 2017. Your manager says that Data Science is the “new thing” and there are Data Scientists in your company that need your help. SQL Server 2016 introduced a new capability called SQL Server R Services and you need to evaluate whether this feature is something your company can trust to deploy in production for an enterprise environment. SQL Server 2017 expands this feature to include Python and what we now called SQL Server Machine Learning Services. We will explore and understand exactly how SQL Server Machine Learning Services works behind the scenes so you know how to install it, manage it, optimize it, and have confidence to use this in real prediction analytic workloads. We will use demos so you understand all the components and look at a real enterprise customer case study as part of this talk.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64259</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64259</id>
          <name>John Sterrett</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.113</name>
      </location>
      <title>Table Partitioning: the Secret Weapon for Your Big Data Problems</title>
      <description>Is big data starting to slow you down? Is data growth putting your maintenance tasks in danger of not meeting your service level agreements? Do you wish you could archive old data with minimal impact to your tables during the archive process? Do you wish you could eliminate the majority of the data in your tables when you query them? If so, it's time you consider implementing table partitioning to help with your general performance and to reduce your maintenance window for completing your maintenance tasks. 

In this session, you will learn how table partitioning works and when it should be implemented. You will be able to understand how to initially configure partition functions and partition schemes to have a rock solid partitioned table. You learn how to implement new features added in SQL Server 2014 to improve table partitioning.  Finally, you will learn how to implement an automated sliding window to maintain your partitioned tables for ensuring optimal performance.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64178</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64178</id>
          <name>Robert Stewart</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.148</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Warehousing 101</title>
      <description>In this session, we will cover the basics of building a data warehouse. We will look at the Kimball and Inman methodologies and see what will fit the situations in building a data warehouse most effectively. We will also cover doing a slowly changing dimension that will load in seconds instead of hours.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64410</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64410</id>
          <name>Rick Lowe</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.147</name>
      </location>
      <title>Why should I care about ... the plan cache?</title>
      <description>SQL Server is a huge product, with many different places a DBA can go to look for information on how the server is performing. So many in fact that they can often overlap, which sometimes makes it hard to understand why tackling a new tool is worth the effort. In this installment of Rick's "Why should I care" series, he lays out a case for why working knowledge of the plan cache is critical for performance tuning efforts in real world environments. A review of relevant views and functions is included for the (newly?) motivated audience.

Perfect for those who are relatively new to performance tuning concerns, or advanced DBAs trying to figure out how to have a similar conversation with their less experienced peers, or developers who are curious as to why their DBAs drink in the morning (allegedly). This is not a deep dive into the cache, it really is primarily a session exploring _why_ these DMOs are worth slogging through.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63588</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63588</id>
          <name>Shawn Weisfeld</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.142</name>
      </location>
      <title>Intro to Azure SQL Data Warehouse</title>
      <description>In this session we will introduce Azure SQL Data Warehouse and provide the basics you need to get started. Azure SQL Data Warehouse combines the SQL Server relational database with Azure cloud scale-out capabilities. Built on our massively parallel processing (MPP) architecture, SQL Data Warehouse can handle your enterprise workload.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63778</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63778</id>
          <name>Jennifer McCown</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.117</name>
      </location>
      <title>Beginning T-SQL</title>
      <description>If you work with SQL Server at all, you need to know Transact-SQL, the SQL Server programming language. During this session, we’ll design and create our own table to demonstrate key concepts, query syntax, and more. If you’ve been meaning to learn T-SQL, here’s your chance!</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65108</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65108</id>
          <name>Chris Hyde</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.147</name>
      </location>
      <title>Python in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2017 is right around the corner, bringing with it a host of exciting new features.  Of particular interest to BI practitioners and data scientists is the integration of the Python programming language into the SQL ecosystem.  This integration opens up a number of possibilities for in-database analytics and intelligent database applications, so let's get started!

In this introductory session we'll briefly introduce the Python language and then look at how to install and administer Machine Learning Services.  We'll start to demonstrate the power of Python by showing you how to create and run simple scripts from within T-SQL.  We'll then discuss some of the powerful open source packages that are available to aid your data analyses.  Finally, we'll go through some examples of how to use Python to integrate data analytical methods in real-world situations, and wow your customers with the power of analytics!</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63514</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63514</id>
          <name>Naomi Williams</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.142</name>
      </location>
      <title>SQL Server Internals</title>
      <description>How does SQL do what it does? Take a look under the hood at how the SQL database engine works with the storage engine. What causes those waits and where do we look to resolve them!</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64120</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64120</id>
          <name>Phillip Labry</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.148</name>
      </location>
      <title>Analysis Services is in Azure? Seriously!? Let's build a model!</title>
      <description>Have you used SSAS before? Have you created reports using T-SQL and Group by? Are you interested in Power BI? Do you you have a need for analysis  services but don't want to have to deal with the hassle of buying and installing a server?  Is your organization using Office 365?  If you answered yes to any of these questions, you might need Azure Analysis Services.  The wait is almost over! Azure Analysis services is the platform as a service version of the wildly popular Analysis Services Tabular product. Join Phillip as he builds and deploys an Azure Analysis services solution.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63511</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63511</id>
          <name>Roberto Cavalcanti</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.142</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure SQL Database - Lessons learned from the trenches</title>
      <description>In this session you will learn the best practices, tips and tricks on how to successfully use Azure SQL Database on production environments. You will learn how to monitor and improve Azure SQL Database query performance. I will cover how Microsoft CSS has been using Query Store, Extended Events, DMVs to help customers monitor and improve query response times when running their databases in the Microsoft Azure cloud. These learnings are fruit of Microsoft CSS support cases, and customer field engagements. This session includes several demos.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 9:45:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 10:45:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64022</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64022</id>
          <name>Vicky Harp</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.147</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to SQL 2016 Temporal Tables</title>
      <description>SQL Server 2016 introduces the concept of temporal tables, also called system-versioned tables. This new feature allows SQL Server to automatically keep track of the history of rows in any table for which it is enabled. In this session we'll cover the basics on how to create and work with temporal tables, including the new FOR SYSTEM_TIME query clause, and we'll discuss some of the ways that they may or may not fill a need in your environment.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64346</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64346</id>
          <name>John Harp</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.115</name>
      </location>
      <title>Crappy Queries: A Beginner's Guide to Hunting in the Field</title>
      <description>When all you have is a hammer, everything looks like a nail. But what if you had two hammers? Or three? Let John add just a couple of native tools to your belt in this session, and you should have a better starting ability to distinguish a criminally crappy query from an innocent one, a perpetrator from a victim. We'll delve into some older technology like SQL tracing, its much newer, hotter sibling Extended Events, and even leverage some native DMVs in a hunt to pin down a few T-SQL malefactors.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63850</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63850</id>
          <name>Ryan Adams</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.117</name>
      </location>
      <title>Install an AlwaysOn Failover Cluster and Availability Group</title>
      <description>You have decided to install and deploy a Failover Cluster Instance and an Availability Group but don't know where to start. This complicated architecture has many moving parts (including Windows Clustering), and you are overwhelmed. How do you install these features? This session walks you through a complete AlwaysOn environment, in which we install and configure an AlwaysOn Failover Cluster Instance and an AlwaysOn Availability Group across 5 nodes. We use both the GUI and T-SQL so that you know how, why, and when to use each method.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 8:30:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 9:30:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64337</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64337</id>
          <name>Amy Herold</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.113</name>
      </location>
      <title>Deadlock, Block  Two Smoking Barrels: Breaking Down Blocking and Deadlocks</title>
      <description>While blocking and deadlocks are part of the territory for a DBA, dealing with them can be another story. In this session we will break down locking types, capturing and identifying deadlocks and the code behind them, and things you can do to resolve and prevent blocking and deadlocks. If you are frequently dealing with deadlocks in your databases this session is for you.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 1:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 2:30:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64403</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64403</id>
          <name>David Stein</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.148</name>
      </location>
      <title>Agile Data Warehouse and ETL Design with Biml</title>
      <description>Business Intelligence Markup Language is literally changing the way we think about Data Warehouse design and ETL. In this interactive presentation you'll see how you can rapidly iterate through the Data Warehouse Development Cycle and provide ROI almost immediately.  Learn how you can use BimlScript to automatically create staging tables, SSIS Packages, and other necessary objects during the modeling process.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65390</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65390</id>
          <name>Kris Hokanson</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.147</name>
      </location>
      <title>Random Acts of Senseless Databasing</title>
      <description>After years of snake oil salesmen and good-meaning but part-time developers, Acme Oil  Gas company’s databases have become something Rube Goldberg would be proud of and they've hired you to sort everything out. What are some of the things you can expect to find and how can you fix them? From spaghetti code that references views inside of views nested in other views, to overly indexed tables that generate 10x the disk IO and contention they should, we’ll talk about database development, administration, and plenty of things in between.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64328</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64328</id>
          <name>Lori Edwards</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Professional Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.117</name>
      </location>
      <title>Do More Than Just Talk</title>
      <description>Most of us can talk - we've been doing it since we were young.  Unfortunately there can be a huge gap between talking and effective communication.  While not all of us will be chosen for TED talks, there are methods we can use to keep our audience engaged and help our message to be understood whether you're asking your boss for a raise or presenting a session at the PASS Summit. Understand the barriers to effective communication and learn to use words, tone, expression and behavior to enhance your communicate skills.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63782</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63782</id>
          <name>Sean McCown</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.117</name>
      </location>
      <title>Loading SQL Server Data with Powershell</title>
      <description>Powershell has become the defacto standard for scripting Microsoft products.  However, putting data in text files doesn’t scale.  Here I’m going to show you the ins and outs of loading data into SQL Server using Powershell for the purpose of centralizing collections.  We’re going to cover RBAR as well as bulk operations and the types of things you need to take into consideration in an enterprise setting.  This is a no holds barred session taught by an enterprise SQL Server scripting expert.  You can’t afford to miss this session if you do any level of scripting in your shop.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 4:00:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 5:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>64442</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>64442</id>
          <name>Lance Tidwell</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Enterprise Database Administration  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.113</name>
      </location>
      <title>Introduction to Execution Plans</title>
      <description>In this session we will take a look at the basics of execution plans.    We will discuss what they are, how they are made, and how they are used.  We will explore some of the common operators seen in execution plans and their functions.   Next we will look at the differences between estimated and actual execution plans. Throughout, you will be getting insight on how to read execution plans to help tune your queries.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 11:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 12:00:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>63816</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>63816</id>
          <name>Dane Schilling</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.113</name>
      </location>
      <title>MS SQL - Review, Renew, and Reveal</title>
      <description>We will begin the session by reviewing a few things about MS SQL  T-SQL that you should know (CTE's, window functions, etc). Our next step will be to explore some of the newer features within the SQL verse and how we can use them to write cleaner and more explicit T-SQL (date and string functions + more). We will close out the session exploring some of the newest features released with MS SQL Server 2016.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 2:45:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 3:45:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>65237</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>65237</id>
          <name>Robyn Fuentes</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>1.117</name>
      </location>
      <title>DevOps for Migratory Deployments</title>
      <description>In an automated world, it’s easy to feel like we are losing the tight control we used to have on some of our daily processes. Other processes have remained manual out of fear of losing that same control. What if there was a way to keep the control and automate the process at the same time? In this session, I go over my experiences with different ways of managing schema changes over the life of a project and explore a controlled and automated approach.</description>
      <startTime>6/17/2017 12:30:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>6/17/2017 1:15:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>