<GuidebookXML>
  <guide>
    <name>SQLSaturday #450 - Bucuresti 2015</name>
    <startDate>9/19/2015 12:00:00 AM</startDate>
    <attendeeEstimate>90</attendeeEstimate>
    <timezone>(GMT+02:00) Harare, Pretoria</timezone>
    <description>SQLSaturday is a training event for SQL Server professionals and those wanting to learn about SQL Server. </description>
    <twitterHashtag>#sqlsatBucuresti</twitterHashtag>
    <venue>
      <name>Microsoft Romania</name>
      <street>Piața Presei Libere 3-5</street>
      <city>Bucuresti</city>
      <state>Bucureşti, Romania</state>
      <zipcode>013702</zipcode>
      <longitude>26.07142473308</longitude>
      <latitude>44.4771748524044</latitude>
    </venue>
  </guide>
  <sponsors>
    <sponsor>
      <importID>845</importID>
      <name>Microsoft Corporation (GAP)</name>
      <label>Gold Sponsor</label>
      <url>http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/sql-server/</url>
      <imageURL>https://geeks.ms/johnbulla/wp-content/uploads/sites/199/2016/04/Microsoft_logo_2012.svg_.png</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>60</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>170</imageWidth>
    </sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <speakers>
    <speaker>
      <importID>37379</importID>
      <name>Tanja Vukov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tanja Vukov, PhD – research associate at Institute for Biological Research, University of Belgrade. She is an expert in biostatistics and her role is to transform data into meaningful scientific conclusions. As a bio-analyst she helped to develop new practices in a field of agriculture and medicine. She published more than 20 papers in leading international scientific journals. She was a speaker on using different Azure technologies. She holds a PhD in Evolutionary biology. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/public-profile-settings?trk=prof-edit-edit-public_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>38028</importID>
      <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data Philosopher. Since 2006 invariably awarded Microsoft Most Valuable Professional title in the Data Platform category. A speaker at numerous conferences across Europe, as well as at user groups meetings. The author of many books and articles devoted to Microsoft Data Platform. An independent consultant, database-centric application practitioner and architect totally focused on SQL Server and Azure. Huge fan of Data Science and Machine Learning.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/marcinszeliga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>38120</importID>
      <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>My experience surrounded with high focus on the data platform with a track record of defining strategy, designing and delivering digital transformation  migrations with major enhancements to current working methods.  Worked in a capacity of Head of Data Engineering, Enterprise Data Architect and Solutions 

Key career accomplishment  recognition as an industry expert  technical excellence from the Microsoft as Data Platform Most Valuable Professional (MVP) recognition since the year 2006 (13 years as MVP and counting), which recognizes exceptional technical community leaders worldwide who actively deliver, present  share their extraordinary contributions, high quality, and real-world expertise.
Twitter pod (http://twitter.com/sqlmast</description>
      <twitter>sqlmaster</twitter>
      <linkedin>https://uk.linkedin.com/sqlmaster</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://www.sqlserver-qa.net</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=sqlmaster</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39130</importID>
      <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Catalin Gheorghiu is a solution architect from Romania. He has more than 15 years of experience in developing solutions, especially on Microsoft technologies in very demanding environments. Is contributing articles and blogs to several user groups (MrSmersh), lecturing all over Romania and abroad, is also RONUA Timisoara (PASS Chapter) user group leader. Since 2011, every year he was awarded the Microsoft MVP Award.</description>
      <twitter>MrSmersh</twitter>
      <linkedin>?https://ro.linkedin.com/in/catalingheorghiu?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ronua.ro/author/catalin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MrSmersh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>38034</importID>
      <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Data Philosopher. Since 2006 invariably awarded Microsoft Most Valuable Professional title in the Data Platform category. A speaker at numerous conferences across Europe, as well as at user groups meetings. The author of many books and articles devoted to Microsoft Data Platform. An independent consultant, database-centric application practitioner and architect totally focused on SQL Server and Azure. Huge fan of Data Science and Machine Learning.</description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://pl.linkedin.com/in/marcinszeliga</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>39129</importID>
      <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Catalin Gheorghiu is a solution architect from Romania. He has more than 15 years of experience in developing solutions, especially on Microsoft technologies in very demanding environments. Is contributing articles and blogs to several user groups (MrSmersh), lecturing all over Romania and abroad, is also RONUA Timisoara (PASS Chapter) user group leader. Since 2011, every year he was awarded the Microsoft MVP Award.</description>
      <twitter>MrSmersh</twitter>
      <linkedin>?https://ro.linkedin.com/in/catalingheorghiu?</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>http://ronua.ro/author/catalin/</ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=MrSmersh</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
    <speaker>
      <importID>37380</importID>
      <name>Tanja Vukov</name>
      <label>
      </label>
      <description>Tanja Vukov, PhD – research associate at Institute for Biological Research, University of Belgrade. She is an expert in biostatistics and her role is to transform data into meaningful scientific conclusions. As a bio-analyst she helped to develop new practices in a field of agriculture and medicine. She published more than 20 papers in leading international scientific journals. She was a speaker on using different Azure technologies. She holds a PhD in Evolutionary biology. </description>
      <twitter>
      </twitter>
      <linkedin>https://www.linkedin.com/profile/public-profile-settings?trk=prof-edit-edit-public_profile</linkedin>
      <ContactURL>
      </ContactURL>
      <imageURL>https://api.twitter.com/1/users/profile_image?screen_name=</imageURL>
      <imageHeight>48</imageHeight>
      <imageWidth>48</imageWidth>
    </speaker>
  </speakers>
  <events>
    <event>
      <importID>38028</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>38028</id>
          <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>BI Platform Architecture, Development  Administration</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cinema</name>
      </location>
      <title>Easy ETL with Biml</title>
      <description>Can ETL be fun? Unfortunately, very often creation of ETL layer is time-consuming, tedious, error-prone task. What’s more, any change in requirement needs most of the work to be redone. In our session we’ll present new approach to creating BI solutions using Biml language and Mist programming environment. They greatly simplify the process, allowing for amazing flexibility, and make the ETL work more pleasant. We will show real examples of how Biml and C# generates hundreds of usable SSIS packages in just couple of minutes. We will also cover integration of ETL with TFS and CI for ETL. Everything with 100% compatibility with unmodified SQL Server. Join us and see how BI just became fun again</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2015 2:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2015 3:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>38120</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>38120</id>
          <name>Satya Jayanty</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cinema</name>
      </location>
      <title>Power BI- best practices to deliver just-in-time insights</title>
      <description>We will overview a detailed options about how to deploy Power BI, how to implement configuration parameters and package BI features as a part of Office 365 roll out in your organisation.

Having said that, cloud computing is another aspect of this technology made is possible to get data within few clicks and ticks to the end-user. Let us review how to manage  connect on-premise data to cloud capabilities that can offer full advantage of data catalogue capabilities by keeping data secure as per Information Governance standards.  Not just with nuts and bolts, performance is another aspect that every Admin is keeping up, let us look into few settings on how to maximize performance to optimize access to data as </description>
      <startTime>9/19/2015 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2015 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>39130</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39130</id>
          <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown</name>
      </location>
      <title>IoT and SQL (Server)</title>
      <description>Or IoT for DBAs
And we are not talking about Oracle Index Organized Tables, we are talking about Internet of Things. This buzzword you hear almost everywhere, and for sure needs databases. So let’s take the Microsoft vision of IoT and see the database side of it. We will talk about the vision of IoT and the real world practicalities of it. The presentation goal is to provide a DBA all he/she needs to know to support an IoT application.  And to make you curious we will cover topics such SQL 2014 for Embedded Systems or the Azure offerings (and their SQL connections), and I will try full demos with IoT hardware.
</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2015 2:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2015 3:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>37379</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>37379</id>
          <name>Tanja Vukov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Analytics and Visualization</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown</name>
      </location>
      <title>Saved by the Cloud</title>
      <description>Its quite easy to find business cases where IoT, Stream Analytics, Machine Learning and PowerBI are used as standalone technology or in a synergy. As environmental biologist I am using “Microsoft glasses” to look, understand, and change ecosystems around me. By using this technologies I will show you that their purpose is not just to make your business better but to make our planet a safer place to live.
</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2015 10:00:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2015 11:00:00 AM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>39129</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>39129</id>
          <name>Catalin Gheorghiu</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Application  Database Development</track>
      <location>
        <name>Cinema</name>
      </location>
      <title>Databases on mobile devices</title>
      <description>You are a Windows Phone developer or just a mobile developer and you need a database locally, on the device, a database, what are your options? And really how do you sync you data with the big database? What you can do, what you cannot do, and how? How cloud is changing this story?  These are a few of the questions this presentation will try to answer, the focus be on Windows Phone (the easiest to demo, but not ignoring the “others”). The actual industrial devices will be also covered. 
And of course all with as much demoes and code as possible.
</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2015 1:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2015 2:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>37380</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>37380</id>
          <name>Tanja Vukov</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Cloud Application Development  Deployment</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown</name>
      </location>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning - drag, drop, predict</title>
      <description>Microsoft Azure Machine Learning (AML) changes the way we work with data and what knowledge and skills are required in order to predict outcome of future events.  AML is a comprehensive “drag, drop, predict” technology with all the benefits of the cloud.  The transfer of machine learning to the new platform with ability to use R programming language makes common machine learning tasks very simple for the different customers and academic community.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2015 11:05:00 AM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2015 12:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
    <event>
      <importID>38034</importID>
      <speakers>
        <speaker>
          <id>38034</id>
          <name>Marcin Szeliga</name>
        </speaker>
      </speakers>
      <track>Advanced Analysis Techniques</track>
      <location>
        <name>Downtown</name>
      </location>
      <title>Data Science approach for (Azure) Machine Learing</title>
      <description>„Knowledge is power” said Sir Francis Bacon two hundred years ago. Now prediction is power. That is the reason why data science is so needed. If you want to know what is Data Science, what are reasons for Machine Learning, who is Data Scientist and how to become one of them, join this session. We are going to design an sample experiment using Azure ML score them, publish model as Web service and consume it.</description>
      <startTime>9/19/2015 1:05:00 PM</startTime>
      <endTime>9/19/2015 2:05:00 PM</endTime>
    </event>
  </events>
</GuidebookXML>